<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Robert L. Simpson</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Robert L. Simpson.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Robert%20L.%20Simpson.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Robert L. Simpson.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Oct 1971 18:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 1971 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>“Strengthen Thy Brethren”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brethren of the priesthood: I am grateful to my Heavenly Father for this opportunity. We of the Presiding Bishopric commend you young men of the Aaronic Priesthood for being here tonight. The Lord is pleased to have you where you belong at th</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03012_000_5030" doc-version="2" hash="3p6T2A"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="OGTP7nhmlEmxlhtq1K138A" hash="Bt7A-A">“Strengthen Thy Brethren”</h1><p class="authorName" guid="bba9c1c2-025d-41b7-8bdf-78662d0234f6" pid="JNnxTVzMf06PjLaKD_xhfw" hash="_EZcfw">Robert L. Simpson</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="34ba6316-55b5-4915-8990-21349d309120">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-35ae.jpg" alt="Conference photo" guid="bc9a2934-0cda-4e11-9573-8188596d351b" pid="u9Oueee6e0ehppCpkQFNsw" hash="MxZN0Q" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p1" guid="4774bfc5-26c8-4721-8f42-cd7334be0e72" pid="RTAI37iSEkyPBGHDUDKMEA" hash="IIdeUg">My dear brethren of the priesthood: I am grateful to my Heavenly Father for this opportunity. We of the Presiding Bishopric commend you young men of the Aaronic Priesthood for being here tonight. The Lord is pleased to have you where you belong at this hour. Perhaps a mental checklist might not be out of order to set the stage for the few thoughts I would like to leave with you.</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.f1"><p pid="KSNHXmvoQkmqERzhYYI8-Q" hash="tV4sCA">Would you check yes or no by the following statements concerning your attendance at this priesthood meeting:</p><ol class="number" guid="7ee490ee-2d4f-43f1-9308-9323bec0035d"><li guid="fe53390e-832f-4dcc-bd02-6da6a0d6d797" pid="2sfJEEqChEK6Lgm0Ufjy4g" hash="uDJkzQ">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p guid="9ed402b6-e7f8-41bc-9ae8-96c43f48b247" pid="QrRvpDbjGUeOlpujkVKdiw" hash="flukZg">I am here because others of the family came.</p>
        </li><li guid="0cadccca-d8ae-46c8-a3f0-abb224eb5e0e" pid="dbmo6Udm-kOj-mop90MTBA" hash="QXsbLg">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p guid="b0854c67-2ebb-4b61-b053-61b7d75a92ad" pid="jA62H8pURkim47M8K3jeiw" hash="mf0D7A">I am here because there are no football games on TV tonight.</p>
        </li><li guid="cd78c942-4127-4f5b-907e-46c8aa6fa0fc" pid="SPJFhld8bE-CtW8ORwmfxQ" hash="NcgP2w">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p guid="d801b28d-c153-4754-be35-aee576092e1b" pid="FrTsA1xSGECIHBuAvNErtw" hash="Z6YZhQ">I am here because Dad said, “You are going to priesthood meeting or else.”</p>
        </li><li guid="9cedb176-1cf3-43a9-96ff-6816e385053c" pid="FELytSY9ZkCY_MkRKWwryw" hash="uG749g">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p guid="71b282e7-d209-403b-a739-2d4e6d0acf47" pid="ed1uCdWVNEKL8gObi7IX4A" hash="DU-_8w">I am here because I love the Lord and recognize the priesthood I hold as the most important power for good in the universe.</p>
        </li></ol></div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p2" guid="3caf6bb7-dee5-418a-b0a0-0209ac778c0c" pid="AaTO7va-YkKpyt-Txe2_lA" hash="ehf4PQ">Whatever your answer might have been to the foregoing statements, the Lord is pleased you are here, and you have already been richly rewarded by listening to some direction from the Lord through a living prophet. I also commend you because for every one of you in attendance at one of several locations tonight, there are four priesthood holders who thought they had more important things to do or who did not have someone who cared enough about them to offer the encouragement they needed to join with us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p3" guid="e88502f8-85cf-43d9-96fc-9fecf307389a" pid="WZ9_YarJNkewWAu7UQmKvg" hash="ytKBVg">Just in case you are not very excited about being part of the largest priesthood gathering in the history of the world, let me give you five important things to think about that have direct relationship to this meeting and what goes on here.</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.f2"><ol class="number" guid="59eb4c9d-8dfe-435f-b475-bc30a5819f6c"><li guid="eb9f5e0e-c829-4004-ade4-2e2169c649bf" pid="25A4wUdKsESp6bbPjgm5bg" hash="IZAXdw">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p guid="fddc4485-31db-40fa-abe1-a3c16ff80dfe" pid="HmbloauV0EWpzUthLqBQRA" hash="ecDNOg">God the Father and his Son Jesus Christ have appeared in this time of the world’s history.</p>
        </li><li guid="48ee44ba-1c93-461c-ba06-ae2a144b8c1c" pid="ITnIztb79kiEvapTgxVQ7w" hash="N1vvfA">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p guid="ddb03d77-44cf-4ba8-8956-430af2524302" pid="LbwLxd9-HEmpVOCAtR8TpA" hash="6OcKRw">All of the keys and powers of the eternal priesthood of God, with all of its attendant authority and blessings for mankind, have been restored to the earth, nevermore to be removed.</p>
        </li><li guid="33e8e32b-7e16-46c3-bd88-57f7d1a03c54" pid="d8JePkAjrk-cuLfZTNDNKA" hash="3ftgJw">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p guid="60ec8683-5397-42da-9ac8-f775d8063373" pid="F1cPrmAHVkm8iGZyB9x2jA" hash="44oVBw">No less than nine heavenly beings have appeared by assignment in our time of the world’s history to assist in this restoration. Let me name them: God the Father, his Son Jesus Christ, the apostle Peter, accompanied by James and John, John the Baptist, Moroni, Elijah, and Elias.</p>
        </li><li guid="89513082-8bee-4b9b-bfdc-16cb9d6f826e" pid="48_yj0ybxE-ni2_idXwppA" hash="on0ZRA">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p guid="df221d02-380a-4f5d-9b77-96c749d4edaf" pid="BttgDEvnBEqquXoISK2fIQ" hash="lIB2oA">Three additional books of scripture, totaling 835 pages, have been revealed for the further guidance of mankind and to lend additional direction in these perilous times.</p>
        </li><li guid="8837b848-845b-42fd-9d81-3e7ddfa6e809" pid="suBX0uQTukuSc0RhuoUfxQ" hash="WaXwfQ">
          <span class="label">5.</span>
          <p guid="b1450428-4ddd-4908-9775-f6b764858809" pid="cFNoDzn860SdOeomFyBczQ" hash="Vm5BAQ">Last but not least, a living prophet stands at our head and presides over this meeting and has just given us the will of the Lord; up-to-the-minute evidence of continuous revelation.</p>
        </li></ol></div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p4" guid="ce4b242a-6092-4c26-ae64-49dd4d08ea3d" pid="oxcQSP_nBUSBTqIfkuyvPQ" hash="-oBvfQ">Now, any one of the foregoing facts should rate banner headlines in every newspaper in the world, but about the only response we get from more than three billion people who are supposedly thirsting for truth is, in effect: “Don’t rock the boat,” or “Who do you think you are to make such fantastic claims as visits from on high, the only true priesthood, additional scriptures, and a living prophet?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p5" guid="ec1d4909-0b17-41ae-9dd8-a4366d7c586b" pid="YFURS9bXGUOnXwP_HHciEw" hash="C6yRRA">Young men, I do not know all there is to know, but there are a few things I do know by personal revelation, and I think the Spirit of the Lord is anxious to confirm these same truths within each of you if he has not done so already.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p6" guid="4f2ea535-96ea-4a3f-b1fb-d195b91bf439" pid="q1xlBBIOZESBxkJm6utl_A" hash="ht8AoA">The scriptures declare that “many are called, but few are chosen.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.40" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:40</a>.) Do you think that there might be a possibility that you have not only been called but may be chosen as well? Why not! You are one out of five who made a decision to be here in this great meeting. For each of you here, four others who were invited apparently decided that there was something more important to do than attend this priesthood meeting. I do not know how you answered those previous statements about your attendance here tonight, but one thing is crystal clear to me: either you wanted to be here or most certainly the Lord wanted you here, and you had better get excited about it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p7" guid="718253bb-91c5-471c-9ea0-e66e4402584b" pid="_SsKlrXETEeTVtWV-oX8bQ" hash="aq0w0A">“Behold, there are many called, but few are chosen. And why are they not chosen?” The Lord tells us why they were not chosen, and here are his reasons:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p8" guid="45dd80bd-ecc9-4f4b-8fae-180d08877ae0" pid="zaIjHM_jNEmsQzyqL5rUdA" hash="yQDnYw">“Because their hearts are set so much upon the things of this world, and aspire to the honors of men, that they do not learn this one lesson—” And what is this one great lesson? Listen carefully, young men. This could well be one of the most important lessons of your life, and it comes directly from the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p9" guid="6f7c1e5e-6cf3-4b6f-8e41-7dc829ef20e8" pid="9YR3kTyb9EuOQaYEAU87Gw" hash="ujiU5A">“That the rights of the priesthood are inseparably connected with the powers of heaven, and that the powers of heaven cannot be controlled nor handled only upon the principles of righteousness.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.34-36" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:34–36</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p10" guid="3cf715bc-09aa-4b52-b5ed-663628cca063" pid="W2bGBjbCBki9-OOJad-KOQ" hash="4fhwZw">Well, it is exciting that you are here; you are special! And furthermore, the Lord has something in mind for you to do about it starting right now. The Church has need of every member, and that means not only you but also four of your friends who should be sitting by you in this meeting tonight but who are missing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p11" guid="92b276b6-2508-4e01-a680-8d16d267887b" pid="MwHwFH1zKkaSbpLoNClhVg" hash="Isvp6w">A recurring theme during the life of the Savior as he taught the people was that each man is his brother’s keeper. No priesthood obligation is more important. The scriptures say something very similar but in another way that I like very much: “… when thou art converted, strengthen thy brethren.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/22.32" class="scriptureRef">Luke 22:32</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p12" guid="03145b5d-c89c-4cec-8ee2-fabf16cdc880" pid="7tiQIPmw8UeZS-9scbN1Rg" hash="WlPVRQ">No one takes upon himself the covenant of baptism nor the honor of the priesthood except he also receives the obligations associated with Church membership and priesthood affiliation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p13" guid="890375fc-54be-412a-b135-2694c49ec848" pid="l5zkf2mNTEaVqj7C-gdtDA" hash="aPgqdA">The world today tells you to leave your friend alone. He has the right to come and go as he pleases. The world tells you that persuasion to attend church or priesthood meeting or to discard a bad habit might lead to frustration and undue pressures; but again I repeat the word of the Lord: You are your brother’s keeper, and when you are converted, you have an obligation to strengthen your brother.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p14" guid="4d1b78a3-ba9d-485d-8932-e8e676caac5e" pid="Vf6fJ79bJkGsB9j5J60DAQ" hash="VX9JjQ">“But bishop,” you say, “I wouldn’t know what to say or how to go about it. I am just a deacons quorum president.” And to this the Lord answers that he gives no assignment to the children of men except he prepares a way for them to accomplish that which he has given them to do. He also says: “Therefore, verily I say unto you, lift up your voices unto this people; speak the thoughts that I shall put into your hearts, and you shall not be confounded before men;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p15" guid="2606a7e9-5327-40dd-9eb9-e2175378edeb" pid="tUUbnuoEwk20Vr-M6fXodg" hash="6l5LsA">“For it shall be given you in the very hour, yea, in the very moment, what ye shall say.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p16" guid="65ad7ecd-c190-4731-a4cb-775be14e803c" pid="y9CdUYin8EqRfqj6SZ8hTg" hash="uBMTsw">Now at this point the Lord gives a commandment that we must speak in his name with solemnity of heart and in the spirit of meekness, and then he concludes with this promise:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p17" guid="91752946-6f51-4bd8-920f-982035a6d4fa" pid="8MHmacsIPEGnrrqp3pu78A" hash="xKdjwA">“… inasmuch as ye do this the Holy Ghost shall be shed forth in bearing record unto all things whatsoever ye shall say.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/100.5-8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 100:5–8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p18" guid="c5a10ca0-6a45-4fe3-8938-4621e592e433" pid="weuuB-ugwE2-aMb8eC_PrA" hash="3BQlXA">Following this divine formula will take your contact with a friend out of the usual lip-to-ear communication category. With the help of the Holy Ghost, there will be a penetration into the heart of your friend. He will be persuaded through a wonderful spiritual process that is reserved for worthy members of the Church. It is the same process by which converts are brought into the Church and will be an important spiritual gift for each of you to develop and improve on a continuing basis.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p19" guid="80c1040f-abc5-4c91-a781-4f022ccd1b65" pid="D-eHftWq6kmdDIxX0evocA" hash="VsTh3Q">Yes, the Church has need of every member, and the list of indifferent members is much too long; it concerns the First Presidency; it concerns the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p20" guid="1361e977-8a7b-43ba-b153-b69315d14b25" pid="Qi0mg3L6ukKBVjdYAyAGSQ" hash="8hfx-Q">There will not be a sign or miracle in the heavens to wake people up. It was decided aeons ago that people would be helped by people so far as the Lord’s work is concerned. This is an eternal principle and process: “… when thou art converted, strengthen thy brethren.” The task is largely up to those of us who are here tonight, and the responsibility is upon the newest deacon as well as the high priest of longest standing. While I have directed my comments primarily to the Aaronic Priesthood—Youth, certainly every principle applies to all of us involved in this great work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p21" guid="d490e0f0-31a7-4c9b-aaa5-7752bf6b3995" pid="ra43lmsSk0uHLzMf8MWt6Q" hash="ntoxAA">May I conclude with a word of caution as the Lord gave it to the Prophet Joseph Smith. He said this: “What I say unto one I say unto all; pray always lest that wicked one have power in you, and remove you out of your place.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/93.49" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 93:49</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p22" guid="4f189076-79ad-4ac4-898e-0b0bde0e4c7a" pid="J1dDtdAjKkieGlRdgAHI5Q" hash="i-evpA">“Many are called, but few are chosen.” What a tragedy to be foreordained or to be chosen or to be called and ordained only to have the adversary “remove you out of your place.” Don’t you allow it to happen. Live beyond his grasp, for I can promise you that there are limits beyond which Satan cannot reach. He will not have claim on the righteous. The challenge for each of us is to stand worthy that we might better assist our brother back into the circle of activity, and may our efforts to do so be centered in that glorious revelation which is pure poetry in a scriptural setting:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p23" guid="414e533d-7e79-4c37-ad97-f40548365b82" pid="WCmaum20VkuhtmpkZ2OyVg" hash="mG0s4Q">“… let virtue garnish thy thoughts unceasingly; then shall thy confidence wax strong in the presence of God; and the doctrine of the priesthood shall distil upon thy soul as the dews from heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p24" guid="980a5d60-aea2-4068-b456-922456f95e4c" pid="snlOXTeKt0GZyte7E1dsKA" hash="KnSnqA">“The Holy Ghost shall be thy constant companion, and thy scepter an unchanging scepter of righteousness and truth; and thy dominion shall be an everlasting dominion, and without compulsory means it shall flow unto thee forever and ever.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.45-46" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:45–46</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p25" guid="b810aab5-1682-4e20-9d4e-c76d5ba8bcb7" pid="g1OIVL5TFke0axlzvVPdbg" hash="gzL_2w">What a promise! What a challenge! Are you special young men? Why, of course, you are! You are one out of five faithful enough to be here tonight.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p26" guid="d16d6730-485e-41ee-aae7-db8bcd5067b9" pid="QzzyjGZ-Qk68Yxx7f38G0w" hash="G7J8jw">Are you your brother’s keeper? Most certainly! If not you, who? Who else would do it if you didn’t do it as a priesthood holder?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren.p27" guid="a410f6cb-3048-4f52-aac1-220f2985204f" pid="-sGmmhlOZkS69Rw_0Ni6MA" hash="4A5qRQ">Are you converted? You most certainly are, whether you recognize it or not, and “when thou art converted, strengthen thy brethren”—for the Church has need of every member. That it might start with more than 100,000 faithful priesthood holders attending priesthood meeting tonight is my humble prayer, and I ask it in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1971/10/strengthen-thy-brethren</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1971-general-conference/1971-10-5030-bishop-robert-l-simpson-64k-eng.mp3" length="6094555" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 1971 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Courts of Love</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My beloved brothers and sisters, I am so grateful to my Heavenly Father for the spirit of this day and especially that I have been preceded by these lovely Primary sisters. The Primary has meant so much to me in my responsibilities of the past few ye</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03020_000_2010" doc-version="2" hash="BdIsxQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="7qSiFALuIUW1aXEwufQ9DQ" hash="nHVGmg">Courts of Love</h1><p class="authorName" guid="bba9c1c2-025d-41b7-8bdf-78662d0234f6" pid="Ssz60zzKDUS-K_0X_AxBtg" hash="_EZcfw">Robert L. Simpson</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="83d23f19-876e-41a4-b071-e44664c57cb8">
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.t1">
			<img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26ea.jpg" alt="Elder Robert L. Simpson" guid="0dd34174-94ea-4fbf-a1d5-27c579210469" pid="9rGPXAHqsUiLjAGXzjPAoQ" hash="6kp0Yg" />
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p1" guid="d94ca498-05da-4895-ad08-df4d0b75f148" pid="6mBhjAdgzU6IjJ7yDPMPNA" hash="wgsViQ">My beloved brothers and sisters, I am so grateful to my Heavenly Father for the spirit of this day and especially that I have been preceded by these lovely Primary sisters. The Primary has meant so much to me in my responsibilities of the past few years, and their singing has given me the peace and feeling that I need at this moment.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p2" guid="da72f6f3-d50d-4009-9963-6b649769a500" pid="KLC6OdsIdkCYsh7H68EJWw" hash="qHyjVw">How thrilling it has been to sit here today and look down at our ever-expanding section of overseas leaders; and I am sure that the Lord’s word is being fulfilled, as found in the 33rd section of the Doctrine and Covenants, when he said:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p3" guid="8b699e6d-775f-408d-80fe-945637d34c4a" pid="sv_Pq-A1KE2iLLZIs-1Y1A" hash="u5qy0Q">“And even so will I gather mine elect from the four quarters of the earth, even as many as will believe in me, and hearken unto my voice.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/33.6" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 33:6</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p4" guid="823ac46b-5322-42a9-8e27-b610f712f59b" pid="YB8GputSQ0O_33KxdCR_zg" hash="swNz7A">And how thrilling it is to see these leaders who have listened and who have hearkened and who have become faithful and true and are found worthy to be counted as leaders in their areas.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p5" guid="29d72678-afd6-4a3f-982e-d0bd62ca0356" pid="Ji_LjZFmo0mTPH7HUHF5Rg" hash="AF9Chg">As we listened to the prophet this morning and as we listened to the other brethren who have responded, I was also struck by the great scripture that we hear so often: “What I the Lord have spoken, I have spoken, and I excuse not myself; … whether by mine own voice or by the voice of my servants, it is the same.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.38" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:38</a>.) Indeed, it is the same, and as a prophet of God talks to us, we are hearing the will of the Lord without question.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p6" guid="24536017-eb61-41af-bb19-b04079e6c12a" pid="ZHFa72w0EEOvl6GOZ7WaoQ" hash="5tG8vQ">May I just take a brief second to pay personal tribute to two of the greatest men I have known in my life, Bishop Vandenberg and Bishop Brown. These two great companions have meant so much and have given so much to me in my life, as they have given to you as they have traveled throughout the Church.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p7" guid="e58ac141-d572-4056-b0a8-8e4806de5d05" pid="lR9fRgSB1EmYF5K0VUxyew" hash="3SbLgQ">I have never known a man of greater courage and integrity than Bishop John H. Vandenberg. I have never been with a person so qualified in administrative and organizational ability as Bishop Victor L. Brown. These men are great assets to the work of the Lord, and I am so grateful for the blessing that came in my association with them.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p8" guid="48122f5c-17d4-4b15-be3c-50619075b609" pid="MSBe42fpQkqbTiCFzbHdGA" hash="tZICEw">In traveling around the Church for the past ten and one-half years, what a joy it has been to meet so many of our bishops, stake presidents, men who have been designated as common judges in Israel, men who are guardians over the flock, men who have been given a charge and a responsibility that is second to none. May I take a few moments at this session of our conference to discuss what I believe is perhaps the most misunderstood meeting of all the meetings that convene in the Church. I refer to the bishop’s court. I would like to begin by relating a story.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p9" guid="c2fe32f4-bf1c-44f7-83c3-02123af49d3c" pid="LhVfQIiu_kWlq6CFqQFVeA" hash="2szO6w">The brief episode I am about to relate is true, and the facts are accurate because those who were present will never forget them.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p10" guid="5bb329a6-c804-4df1-a296-f824bac0489c" pid="t90W0zh9H0-oyd0MWx6TYA" hash="pTPkkA">The hour was very late; the room was quiet except for the audible sobs of a young man who had just received the verdict of a Church court. Justice had taken its true course. There was apparently no alternative. The unanimous decision, following serious deliberation, fasting, and prayer, was excommunication.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p11" guid="c6f6df30-2c6c-4206-be41-c07569cf11e9" pid="JeijBkYIpEqaPlKpwPBBZQ" hash="FXKm2g">After several minutes, a weary face looked up, and the young man’s voice broke the silence as he said, “I have just lost the most precious thing in my life, and nothing will stand in my way until I have regained it.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p12" guid="728508ad-6f0c-40e9-853c-39b59b590210" pid="QntwDKOxUk-gJEdn9eWJlA" hash="PMtLTw">The process leading up to the court was not an easy one. Certainly, courage is a most important factor for every person who has seriously slipped but wants to get back on the Lord’s side.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p13" guid="593883ac-6020-423e-9c88-cad2da3ca64c" pid="sbY9BhxQI0SJr_hjjNcwZw" hash="4PildQ">After the meeting was finished, the communications that followed the young man’s dramatic statement of hope for the future were so reassuring. From some there were firm promises of help during the ensuing months of continuing repentance; from others a pat on the back and a handshake, with an eye-to-eye assurance that conveyed a feeling of confidence and the hand of fellowship. There was complete knowledge among all present at that meeting that all could be regained in the life of this young man if it were done in the Lord’s way.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p14" guid="0a703d8a-b288-4d8f-8ef0-be9504d8a3dc" pid="mTOlV1PAE0WQGujJLEuZ4A" hash="rP6OMQ">This young man had just taken his first giant step back. As an excommunicated member of the Church and with his heart determined to make things right, he was far better off than just a few days before with his membership record intact but carrying deceit in his heart that seemed to shout the word <span class="emphasis">hypocrite </span>with every move he made toward doing something in the Church.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p15" guid="c7fe80bf-ad9a-470c-b949-bda6473d7fac" pid="7qOa3ekRvkGyIF16FbchKA" hash="vmYX5Q">This episode took place a few years ago. The young man’s pledge has been fulfilled, and in my opinion, no member of the Church stands on ground more firm than the man who has had the courage to unburden himself to his priesthood authority and to set things in order with his Master. What a relief to have once again the peace of mind that “passeth all understanding.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p16" guid="587ad5dc-c153-40fe-9506-a87171997364" pid="E9ai5jRGkkaG-dQy2aisDw" hash="gePUSA">Priesthood courts of the Church are not courts of retribution. They are courts of love. Oh, that members of the Church could understand this fact.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p17" guid="0e94187d-c558-4f2d-a0fe-5f44afa0a14f" pid="bOuvhIg7okuls4ESy_xKJg" hash="2kBhXA">The adversary places a fear in the heart of the transgressor that makes it so difficult for him to do what needs to be done; and in the words of James E. Talmage, “As the time of repentance is procrastinated, the ability to repent grows weaker; neglect of opportunity in holy things develops inability.” (<span class="emphasis">Articles of Faith, </span>p. 114.) This simply means that doing what needs to be done will never be easier than right now. As in all other paths and guideposts that have been provided for us to achieve our eternal destiny of exaltation, there are no shortcuts.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p18" guid="36cd177c-53d5-46e8-8fad-0f72da18c4c5" pid="YbRiSgrtvEyiaWYnPWgOsA" hash="bdFlWQ">Heavenly Father is not antiprogress: he is the author of eternal progression. In his own words, “For behold, this is my work and my glory—to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.39" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:39</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p19" guid="7ebad227-8677-4e8f-a60a-5d6cdcc74384" pid="g_vt85eSV0up4LlGvzgqqA" hash="UiJXjw">Our achievement of eternal life adds glory to his name and is the only ultimate objective acceptable to a true Latter-day Saint.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p20" guid="389c7b2a-1026-4c1a-8811-5d24126b20a9" pid="NraizD5ZcEmVH3_b3U886A" hash="D73N0Q">Reduced to its simplest terms, our mission here in mortality is to overcome weaknesses of the flesh and all irregularities in our lives, to the point that our control of personal desires is sufficient to bring about a daily living and thinking pattern that will be compatible with his holy presence.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p21" guid="1230fa3f-00a1-4b76-a05c-882e2b314101" pid="5zpEVoyluk6gqDfoFoeqLQ" hash="2CS3qg">Be not disillusioned by doctrine of the adversary that there will likely be a magic point in eternity when all of a sudden selfish and improper actions are automatically eliminated from our being. Holy writ has confirmed time and time again that such is not the case, and prophets through the ages have assured us that now is the time to repent, right here in this mortal sphere. It will never be easier than now; and returning to Brother Talmage’s thought, he who procrastinates the day or hopes for an alternate method that might require less courage waits in vain, and in the meantime, the possibilities grow dimmer. He is playing the game as Satan would have him play it, and exaltation in the presence of God grows more remote with each passing day.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p22" guid="528d6a45-dc4b-45dd-bce4-e7ff8b396a5c" pid="N2eMJdul1Eiq_Vh3AAqAPA" hash="VKsLXQ">Now bishops, be available to your people. Let them know about the kindness and compassion that dominates your soul. Don’t become so caught up in the business affairs of your ward administration that you fail to convey to your people all of those wonderful attributes referred to in the 121st section of the Doctrine and Covenants. I am talking about the attributes of kindly persuasion, long-suffering, gentleness, meekness, and love unfeigned.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p23" guid="1ea3535b-cbe2-4124-b54e-bd09b6f86801" pid="NgHKX-8ODkuOcTBIVY7BMQ" hash="Uwa4lg">Bishops, learn the great principle of delegation so that your heart and your mind can be free to counsel with the Saints. You are their common judge. There is no one else in the entire ward so designated by the Lord. It is you they must turn to. You must be available to listen, and, equally important, you must live in such a way that the voice of heaven will find utterance through you for the blessing and edification of your people.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p24" guid="8b3e8798-34fa-426a-8ec5-2a22826bca58" pid="lyMKOp2LN0uRsM4seOc8Rg" hash="fPc8CA">I am certain that a basic cornerstone of true justice is compassion. Perhaps even more important than the transgression itself is the sensitivity of a person’s soul and his desire to repent and to follow the Master.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p25" guid="aeb36434-d66e-489b-b10b-94ac308ab0af" pid="P7mrQOdlqUuJ8IqI0YTfeA" hash="EL-1QQ">It would be so much easier to talk about serious transgression to someone you had never seen before and would likely never see again; or better still, to talk in total seclusion to an unseen ear and receive your forgiveness then and there from unseen lips. But in such a process, who would then be at your side in the struggling months ahead, as you attempt with great effort to make your repentance complete, as you strive to prevent a tragic recurrence?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p26" guid="16f91ea8-61e2-4936-93b0-7081ba35727f" pid="21GOoS_q8E6IGC7jh1F9XQ" hash="NaGxhQ">Few, if any, men have the strength to walk that hill alone, and please be assured, it is uphill all the way. There needs to be help—someone who really loves you, someone who has been divinely commissioned to assist you confidentially, quietly, assuredly—and may I reemphasize the word <span class="emphasis">confidentially, </span>for here again, Satan has spread the false rumor that confidences are rarely kept.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p27" guid="95f34d42-5491-4f74-b4f2-73e538159580" pid="o2mDWPh75kKgJPS9GHMGwg" hash="9-vsqw">May I assure you that bishops and stake presidents are not in the habit of betraying these sacred confidences. Before being ordained and set apart, their very lives have been reviewed in that upper room in the temple by those divinely called as prophets, seers, and revelators. Without question, they are among the noble and great ones of this world and should be regarded as such by the Saints.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p28" guid="7ffc36b9-47e1-4a53-b123-3dd09309bc96" pid="tYnqIa9zi0CeOD6GTqzXiQ" hash="4OjtlQ">What a glorious plan this is! How reassuring to know that we all have hope for a total blessing, in spite of all the mistakes we have made; that there might be complete fulfillment; that we might enter his holy presence with our family units.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p29" guid="585d2c08-36ee-42ad-a8b7-fad60286be94" pid="AnfmbPK1tE29Qaaix1Gr1g" hash="cVpZ-g">Even excommunication from this church is not the end of the world; and if this process is necessary in carrying out true justice, I bear you my personal and solemn witness that even this extreme penalty of excommunication can be the first giant step back, provided there follows a sincere submission to the Spirit and faith in the authenticity of God’s plan.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p30" guid="7deedc2d-1bee-4e4c-9cae-03bddc4fe3e4" pid="9xT2T_MyQkmkrtNmWEGaIQ" hash="PN_zog">These processes can only be carried out in this church through properly designated priesthood authority, for his house is a house of order. All of this is made very clear in the Doctrine and Covenants. May I quote:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p31" guid="80dc9a20-e5cc-419b-b5cf-06e74053fb1c" pid="WzemaoKmvEqt2q-C3iC57g" hash="cTEvqw">“And again, verily I say unto you, that which is governed by law is also preserved by law and perfected and sanctified by the same.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p32" guid="04138fb5-220f-4d8e-b459-964ed9d05f03" pid="FWImJMk5AUqbxcFqJpi_KQ" hash="wZqdsw">“That which breaketh a law, and abideth not by law, but seeketh to become a law unto itself, and willeth to abide in sin, and altogether abideth in sin, cannot be sanctified by law, neither by mercy, justice, nor judgment. Therefore, they must remain filthy still.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p33" guid="6e3ab9d8-6c43-4dd2-ab8f-02e7e56efea5" pid="QSuyRBxmAUOtv1DM3f9zsw" hash="W9crBg">“All kingdoms have a law given;</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p34" guid="6b01ff9e-cf35-4a1d-a7f3-a0aad90b30a9" pid="vGiAqK_kOUW_EoAzf4rCiw" hash="FLtjZw">“And there are many kingdoms; for there is no space in the which there is no kingdom; and there is no kingdom in which there is no space, either a greater or a lesser kingdom.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p35" guid="b8de00b7-23f2-4efe-993e-2e306a3b160e" pid="FdlwW6Nn7UeMkGtYD3JJRw" hash="jYkVJQ">“And unto every kingdom is given a law; and unto every law there are certain bounds also and conditions.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p36" guid="29a9dc7d-6c21-43f0-a500-ce848db5ec7e" pid="DXqNM7jxDE--XiotkhTq-w" hash="Aj0QEA">“All beings who abide not in those conditions are not justified.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.34-39" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:34–39</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p37" guid="f874c2d0-ca19-4d85-acc3-75c11cc4cc48" pid="FGifvJfU6U2NovUwP-8Ovw" hash="p8vwZQ">In other words, brothers and sisters, all beings who abide not in those conditions, all who fail to correct infractions of the eternal law by proper priesthood procedures that have been established for such corrections, are not acceptable to the Lord and will likely never be eligible for his presence.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love.p38" guid="21fdee04-938f-4fbc-840c-acab232c5166" pid="mioYSCqkukqvafzGR2yonA" hash="JCiYYA">God bless us to accept eternal law and understand that there can be no other way is my humble prayer, and I ask it for each and every one in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
		</div>
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1972/04/courts-of-love</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1972-general-conference/1972-04-2010-elder-robert-l-simpson-64k-eng.mp3" length="7426362" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 1972 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pollution of the Mind</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Oh, that the three billion people in this world could have heard what we just heard from the lips of a wonderful man, Elder LeGrand Richards; and oh, that three billion people could have heard what the priesthood heard last night from the lips of a l</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03027_000_6030" doc-version="2" hash="TG-7qA"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="6-yDF72wVkW6_zuGJC6gpg" hash="jNgqnQ">Pollution of the Mind</h1><p class="authorName" guid="bba9c1c2-025d-41b7-8bdf-78662d0234f6" pid="pzKu2E7WVESkbbQvPw0HLg" hash="_EZcfw">Robert L. Simpson</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="ee191e35-cdac-47e4-9776-1b4f6498b32a">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p1" guid="29c9be4b-871b-49c8-bddc-6ba30c8771e1" pid="f58LX65u50C2XaZnj7jC_g" hash="Sti3lQ">Oh, that the three billion people in this world could have heard what we just heard from the lips of a wonderful man, Elder LeGrand Richards; and oh, that three billion people could have heard what the priesthood heard last night from the lips of a living prophet, President Harold B. Lee. Through the mind of the Lord, President Lee was able to identify many of the problems confronting mankind today. I would like to discuss for just a moment, if I may, one of the very important problems that seems to be filtering into our homes and into our communities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p2" guid="61caf601-3409-4423-9d43-8eb54a78f31f" pid="AaNRevg7IUG3hrs7CG9zzw" hash="Ei5Hdw">Before drawing the breath of life on this earth, we were all spiritual beings living in the realm of God, the Eternal Father. Scripture reveals that even before our spiritual birth, each of us had individual identification as an intelligence. Before all else could take place, there had to be that beginning spark of light, that spark of intelligence or, if you please, the marvelous mechanism that controls our every thought, that controls our every act. We might think of this spark of intelligence as perhaps the nucleus of a human mind.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p3" guid="74b44b15-e3b1-4c77-869e-6b7ca594dcb6" pid="zDDCmCM-t0qQWNZnJ459Jw" hash="4gIN-g">No wonder it has been said: “As a man thinketh, so is he.” The master control center within each individual must be regarded as the key. Signals flashing out to the various parts of the body bring instant reaction; in sum and substance, this center dictates the character, the conscience, the strength, and yes, even the weaknesses of every man.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p4" guid="16e38082-cca1-4b49-abcd-3db53c056a89" pid="FitZEeKSr0SQVv6aquOg8A" hash="MDr-4Q">From the beginning of time, there has been a never-ending struggle to influence and control the human mind. Too often, the false promises and enticements of conspiring men have been successful. How much more effective to capture the control center than a mere outpost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p5" guid="f9a4e778-60c3-44fe-ad56-c029cda34598" pid="Z5DxjTMqc0GTnZREYa7t_A" hash="wR7bMQ">The mind of man must first depend upon quality input before it can be counted upon to render good decisions. Like the most sophisticated computer, only with its properly designed control panel in proper place and in working order can the system be depended upon to produce the desired results.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p6" guid="38b7806c-bf8e-47a3-aa1c-1079b3fb42d5" pid="woKZcrDCqE27Mj0w2WmaBQ" hash="5AGQYQ">It was Paul who made the observation that the whole must be fitly framed before the properly functioning church can be recognized and identified. It must naturally follow then that the pollution of a single church member’s mind will indeed affect the whole. If pollution touches even a segment of the church, then the entire church is weakened. The church can be no stronger than its members. By the same token, the degradation of a family member weakens the entire family unit. Applied to a nation, when a segment of its citizenry becomes contaminated by frequenting the cesspools of its society, that nation indeed is weakened.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p7" guid="25c559e3-b514-4ade-be90-73d52c132466" pid="9nfUSAhupUSgFET8iNXm8A" hash="RNWB2Q">Thousands have said: “Printed filth will never become an obsession with me. I am a mature adult, and I have the right to see what is going on in the world without becoming trapped.” But hardly a day passes that we don’t listen to alcoholics and drug abusers who are now looking back with regret on their beginning days of social drinking and mild drug experimentation just to satisfy a so-called mature curiosity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p8" guid="2fdde25f-3c43-4eda-91c6-40f2e21e0999" pid="UeLFo_TRfUi_R5xOAtXbDA" hash="8e3lFg">Evidence is conclusive that mind-polluting pornography is just as addicting and just as devastating as Satan’s other tools of destruction and degradation. As expressed in the last line of Alexander Pope’s poem: “We first endure, then pity, then embrace.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p9" guid="5d1f9e64-3753-42e2-b426-1f0e3b363f96" pid="0BsDUcIbFEqGuUjIl9Y2aA" hash="pzPI-Q">The gradual infiltration of this mind-polluting material has quietly engulfed us on a wide front. Today’s so-called acceptable motion picture would have been banned from public viewing just a few short years ago. Many of the recommended reading lists of our public schools would have been classified as unacceptable less than a generation ago. All of us, by the flip of a switch, allow much highly questionable and some downright objectionable filth to occupy the center stage of our family circle. Public attitude against smut has very gradually been lulled into a state of mild resistance—so mild, in fact, that the adversary has already won a major victory whether we are ready to admit it or not.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p10" guid="2a87b356-e37a-4a69-8cc4-81bce86f94bd" pid="nK8qQXzgy0yp-ffbPrFw2w" hash="iScGNg">Now the question follows: Is there really anything that can be done? Why, of course there is, and if every God-fearing citizen would band together on a few fundamental steps, this entire trend could be turned around.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p11" guid="ad853a99-c779-457c-ba6e-3f90e65f1c6b" pid="m-xPerzzLU-uOqrTIhe-BQ" hash="EWX1Dg">How about taking a few minutes, for example, to voice objection to the local supermarket manager about easy availability and prominent display of unacceptable material on his periodical display rack.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p12" guid="ff5ad18f-a26f-4327-8a22-bafa51063189" pid="QmowKQ7xFE-5I4zW9s44lQ" hash="Xm-YdA">How about taking just five minutes each week to review the TV log and then establishing a few rules that all the family agrees to concerning viewing time and on which channel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p13" guid="53233b7f-ebf3-4efd-bc2a-1996c95ee1aa" pid="i_JSV_0JBUKVmtUL0kkFLQ" hash="60cRyA">Why not make some effort to find out something about the next movie that will engage your family’s undivided attention for two and a half or three hours and will probably cost you far more than you contributed to the poor and the needy that month. It goes without saying that all X- and R-rated movies are automatically eliminated.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p14" guid="69de44cf-3cb5-43e0-8881-e695f140ad52" pid="jv7OH-8XbkyyU6PptWmcDw" hash="KfrMpw">Perhaps we should all become a lot more interested in what the school is recommending and making available to our children. How many school meetings or visits did you make during the past year?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p15" guid="acefe577-efab-4640-9757-7fafe231dfec" pid="krX2CHv7tUKDtvYgzjY0xg" hash="miMa9g">Do the men you vote for feel as you do on these vital matters? Is there some legislation that needs to be encouraged, some petitions that need to be circulated, some telephone calls that need to be made? God gave us a democratic process for a good reason. Do we use this process to help his cause? Not enough! The opposition is certainly misusing it, all in the name of free speech. You and I must keep the record straight on what God intended by freedom of speech and some of the obligations connected with it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p16" guid="00355e15-8a63-41fa-a6b1-294389930a08" pid="0NdYay15GkKMBSmaQ39cPw" hash="mRvgNQ">Satan is the master of deceit. He perverts man’s God-given attributes from their noble and divine purpose onto a downward track. All seem to agree that one of man’s most demanding and ever-present drives is centered in his desire for companionship and sexual fulfillment. To have this highly sensitive and divine human mechanism falsely aroused by unnatural processes creates a serious conflict in that vital control center, the mind. Rationalization quickly rallies to the side of the victim of off-color literature, because rationalization helps him to live with his conscience. He tells himself that his drives are God-given and, therefore, not that bad. He also tells himself, “Nearly everybody does it. I am not so different,” and while he may not be so very different, he is just exactly 100 percent wrong in the eyes of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p17" guid="f5930949-7aed-40e9-ae0f-51ffb4db5d95" pid="fkios3RzA0qVD2h2lAGVSA" hash="jxSYjg">Now a mind that has been deceived into receiving trashy input cannot but send false signals to the feet, the hands, and the tongue. Future decisions will all be colored by the impurity allowed to enter that control center of his entire being.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p18" guid="ba355b1e-c8a0-47f3-93c4-1c0514fdc2e0" pid="Tral7Yc2BUaoCD9-oBK_yg" hash="sfAJBg">As you invite unclean thoughts to become a part of your total being, be assured some of your faculties will become considerably sharpened. Your temper will be sharpened. Your tongue will be sharpened. Your desire for more trash will be sharpened. Your ability to shade the truth will be sharpened. Yes, just about every negative part of your character will be enhanced.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p19" guid="01d22c71-880b-416c-a4c9-55ac00905c1a" pid="16NGuo2RRUWdGIk9bGRDgg" hash="rdeeSQ">There will also be a noticeable diminishing effect in your life. Your personality will be diminished. Your family relationships will be impaired. Your ability to pray will be lessened. Your spirit will be affected adversely, and your testimony of the truth will start to slip away, probably so gradually at first that you won’t even realize it is happening until it is too late. The Lord has said: “… Be ye clean that bear the vessels of the Lord.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/38.42" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 38:42</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p20" guid="c023d6ba-0769-42b2-b839-2787c5312175" pid="GidoB6y-okiYdNRCSJcwcg" hash="O7o0vg">Every prophet from the beginning of this earth has had foreknowledge of our day with its pitfalls and hazards. The scriptures alone give us the formula for avoiding disaster. I like what the Lord says in the 121st section of the Doctrine and Covenants: “… let virtue garnish thy thoughts unceasingly; then shall thy confidence wax strong in the presence of God; and the doctrine of the priesthood shall distil upon thy soul as the dews from heaven.” (Verse 45.) [<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.45" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:45</a>]</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p21" guid="ea5ac963-4aa1-40d0-a119-7e5339192555" pid="J7rDeotpIEG5jlO0VNJlwQ" hash="5Bgm-g">We have been admonished to read good books and to avoid idleness, and as President David O. McKay used to say so eloquently: “The true measure of a man is how he spends his time when he doesn’t have to do anything.” This, of course, brings us around to self-discipline, which is the major key in the total avoidance of illicit literature.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p22" guid="d363974f-504b-408a-9cbf-19d9f5505a17" pid="8L-CVPw7AUGyXAvq6OIJYw" hash="3IEH_w">Are there any books or literature in your possession that would have no place in the personal library of President Harold B. Lee? Someone has said: “Which way to go, the leader will know.” Don’t you think we should follow his example? Do you allow material to enter your mind that would be incompatible with entrance into the celestial kingdom of God?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p23" guid="395ff39e-7327-457f-a549-be74b839619e" pid="Gxi9ghDw_EWG3GE1hZpn9g" hash="0E6_iA">Church membership contemplates only one thing—to qualify for his holy presence. Why jeopardize that possibility? The oft-quoted wisdom of President Heber J. Grant bears repetition here: “That which we persist in doing becomes easier for us to do; not that the nature of the thing itself has changed, but the power to do is increased.” (Ralph Waldo Emerson.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p24" guid="f7af5e80-2c56-4668-98f6-6c5eec698c8c" pid="Bwk60n7rWEOGhE3pgQZq8Q" hash="xGVK_w">It works in both directions: the power to accept pornography, as our senses become numbed, or the power to reject as we declare with Joshua of old: “… choose you this day whom ye will serve; … as for me and my house, we will serve the Lord.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/josh/24.15" class="scriptureRef">Josh. 24:15</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p25" guid="6e90dcd1-9c82-446e-a4b1-fccf7d0ecdcd" pid="ZP-eIdaCCky1DD8PvRO1BA" hash="sN9--A">To whom shall we turn for our direction in these vital matters? A prophet of God has spoken within the past few days. Here are the exact words of the First Presidency on this vital subject: “Pornographic filth continues to flood this country as well as other nations of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p26" guid="be26b64d-e15c-465f-b4be-9d6b8976cb30" pid="WiKxY9ivL0i5eMlL5pq0Kg" hash="1yWr9g">“There is abundant evidence of the damaging effect of obscenity on the solidarity of the family, on the moral fiber of the individual.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p27" guid="58b924d0-77ba-4eff-9a8e-23a601447406" pid="MY7-PT87uEeIwqZmlW9hAA" hash="3LqoQw">“We, with many leaders outside the Church, are deeply concerned about this growing obscenity in print, on record and tape, on television, and in motion pictures.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p28" guid="7ed02e67-ca5d-4fb9-adf4-95e4fa7e2dd0" pid="U_xku2cir066YSBzGxo6Sw" hash="A0TrqQ">“We therefore urge Latter-day Saint parents to teach their children to avoid smut in any of its many insidious forms. ‘Let virtue garnish thy thoughts unceasingly.’ (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.45" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:45</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p29" guid="4d9d623c-e157-4604-b8c9-0dcaf46c7472" pid="IjAh38NG7UmPQddvQ-7Z7A" hash="uQzU-g">“The Lord has also said: ‘Set in order your houses; keep slothfulness and uncleanness far from you.’ (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/90.18" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 90:18</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p30" guid="34c04edf-f17f-4813-8b11-c03461e2028a" pid="AE3_O2ArFk2erIOVukC-2Q" hash="ucbSDw">“We also encourage Latter-day Saints as citizens to exert every effort to fight the inroads of pornography in their communities. History is replete with examples of nations which have fallen in a large measure through licentiousness.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind.p31" guid="06d2afb3-67ee-4871-a57b-650a782e792e" pid="1HGyqKsfc0KTYC_VeaDU4Q" hash="n75Khw">May we accept this timely counsel. Your personal welfare and the eternal future of your entire family unit may depend upon it, and I say it in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1972/10/pollution-of-the-mind</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1972-general-conference/1972-10-6030-elder-robert-l-simpson-64k-eng.mp3" length="12780152" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 1972 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Go, and Do Thou Likewise”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My beloved brothers and sisters: I am grateful for this opportunity and with each of you express gratitude for this lovely choir. I always have a little glimpse into heaven as I listen to them sing, and I feel lifted up. This entire conference has be</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03033_000_1040" doc-version="2" hash="f_cPUA"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="hKrYo8Z9N0W2w8R0b8Zc2w" hash="IRo2bA">“Go, and Do Thou Likewise”</h1><p class="authorName" guid="bba9c1c2-025d-41b7-8bdf-78662d0234f6" pid="KSaLJNWiTUW43qO-qCDTLQ" hash="_EZcfw">Robert L. Simpson</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="21929eb7-2c6f-4e65-bbc9-55e7b9b85dc0">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p1" guid="bd56f903-afd0-4c2f-83ae-a4209a493e38" pid="_Ce9YQEwkUabWUuulTt0Ew" hash="KUXAgQ">My beloved brothers and sisters: I am grateful for this opportunity and with each of you express gratitude for this lovely choir. I always have a little glimpse into heaven as I listen to them sing, and I feel lifted up. This entire conference has been lifted and edified by their great singing this morning.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p2" guid="a689f3f6-0dd0-4037-beb3-752f6d48ae9d" pid="2JYWVZ36Dk6bVEqQWGiy1w" hash="NG3Z-g">I feel closer to heaven and have better insight as to what heaven might be like as I feel the spirit of you wonderful leaders assembled here today. There is a feeling of unity, a feeling of strength, a feeling of wanting to do that which the Lord has asked us to do. I am grateful to be in your presence. I often think of President David O. McKay’s great observation that heaven would be just an extension of the ideal home. I believe that with all my heart, and it is that feeling that I sense with us here.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p3" guid="2db0c0cf-1e4c-4663-a301-0229d04fae1d" pid="viMBOwvKVE6f0QqnwDTKGA" hash="VYAROQ">Speaking of heaven and the hereafter, I would like to address my remarks to things I feel would be imperative in order that we might have the great privilege of one day living in the very presence of our Heavenly Father, which should be the objective of every Latter-day Saint.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p4" guid="312001a5-2c7b-4c48-8c7b-2d3744f7b88d" pid="mJ2BNi1MB0WeiX-xklccOA" hash="JirsrQ">It has been truthfully said that the Savior is even more concerned for our success here in mortality than we ourselves are, the reason being, of course, that he has greater capacity for concern and love than do we mortals. He also has a superior knowledge of the gospel plan and man’s potential in God’s divine, eternal scheme. As stated by one prophet, God’s work and glory is achieved through our attainment of immortality and eternal life. (See <a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.39" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:39</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p5" guid="a705b24e-c676-4066-98f1-26d80d31824e" pid="bNbnEMJcdkmkgLpi7fSrKQ" hash="qvfzOw">Someone once suggested that it would be relatively simple for Christ to do all of the religious teaching here on earth. How easy it would be for the Creator to deliver every sermon and to teach every Sunday School class by means of closed-circuit television! Each religious meeting place could be equipped with a large video screen, and the master teacher of all time could then present every gospel lesson and deliver every sermon in a way that would hold us spellbound and indeed convert even the most critical. I suppose it would also be within his power to take over all of the compassionate service for mankind, but such is contrary to the development of God’s children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p6" guid="632933c9-decb-4c15-90ab-796a438fdd2d" pid="Shl1NI8L0keLLZl88dDF8g" hash="LrjyGg">Before the foundations of this earth were laid, a glorious decision was made allowing you and me to be our brother’s keeper. By faith and service we would be able to achieve a degree of glory in the hereafter suited to our Christlike efforts and our Christlike attainments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p7" guid="a97fb400-a101-42df-80c0-0e220200f1a5" pid="16BJAp8iWEOQryib_7CXkA" hash="5eiDQQ">Adversity, heartache, bitter disappointment, grievous transgression, and disability are but a few of the obstacles that beset the inhabitants of this world. Few, if any, escape. None would have to linger in despair for long, however, if man could just bring himself to heed that one great teaching recorded in the 25th chapter of Matthew. You all remember it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p8" guid="54683e23-6285-4c48-b124-cd0d40915003" pid="7jsXJUBRXkKuLf78UAoUhQ" hash="kn3ZzA">On this occasion the Savior was describing the day of judgment, wherein those to be judged were divided, some on the right hand and some on the left. Finding themselves in a favored position, those on the right expressed surprise and wanted to know why the reward had come to them. The Savior replied:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p9" guid="7dd83cd0-ecd7-4afb-a47a-f7191dc818e1" pid="u0XPoFi0X0S-L2_BIgFUwA" hash="ad-a6Q">“For I was an hungred, and ye gave me meat: I was thirsty, and ye gave me drink: I was a stranger, and ye took me in:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p10" guid="5331aa92-8dbd-484d-9f7a-a832632e06b3" pid="DOOqqTzZfkSeLG_MA4mWnA" hash="algxTw">“Naked, and ye clothed me: I was sick, and ye visited me: I was in prison, and ye came unto me.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/25.35-36" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 25:35–36</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p11" guid="23d216c9-203d-461e-b695-452e469cfee3" pid="UipfwgihOkSaprAbgsVyUw" hash="rvToJA">Then the righteous answered, stating that not once had they found him hungry or thirsty or a stranger; and then the Savior’s classic teaching: “Verily I say unto you, Inasmuch as ye have done it unto one of the least of these my brethren, ye have done it unto me.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/25.40" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 25:40</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p12" guid="95691767-0951-413f-a7de-dd5e8249b1e6" pid="9hU7eQiHGUaK9k50h-rcGQ" hash="NXThgQ">Other expressions of the Savior further confirm the same charges. He said: “Feed my sheep” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/21.16" class="scriptureRef">John 21:16</a>); “… all things whatsoever ye would that men should do to you, do ye even so to them” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/7.12" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 7:12</a>). Then, having set the perfect example of service during his ministry, he concluded by saying, “Go, and do thou likewise.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.37" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:37</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p13" guid="cdeaf4a1-08f3-4ee5-ba88-b0c572d1676e" pid="y5L017xkqUeQZ_s8c0Itxw" hash="wynAhw">During the past 12 months it has been my privilege to work closely with many emotionally disturbed people; others who have transgressed; some who have found themselves out of harmony with society; still others who were lonely and afraid. It has not been a year of discouragement and despair, however, because the vast majority of these people have made an important decision, and they have said: “I want to change my life. I am ready to take direction from someone who really cares.” And in this church, we have bishops and stake presidents who really care.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p14" guid="85d29787-9f97-4931-8beb-0df65c49ad4b" pid="RPcndqvd9kSTEIuk6jwWFg" hash="g1mrug">How touching it was to hear a hardened prisoner say: “That is the first time anybody ever told me they loved me.” This was after a six-year-old girl kissed him on the cheek during a Church-sponsored family home evening visit in the prison.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p15" guid="b5d9dcbe-b280-4b62-a6d2-96fc89d26ca9" pid="gdIG57XsbkeTt94Ih97tNA" hash="kU-wNQ">Consider with me an unwed mother who came to her bishop with some reluctance. Her heart was belligerent, and she also had a drug problem; but months later, following compassionate service by many, she was heard to say: “Life was over for me. I didn’t want to live anymore, but things are different now, and I know the true meaning of God’s love.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p16" guid="60ef0b0c-5fae-4d71-b579-dcb0bfad1ca7" pid="1W_9DPw_0EW1FHZ4MNFNOg" hash="Ej0A5g">A confirmed alcoholic found a new lease on life because an assigned couple had won his confidence, and they were there when he needed them. His problem is now history. His own family is back together for the first time in years.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p17" guid="d8c18c34-cce5-4c77-a93f-1962e2787f8a" pid="1KUeZdHF4k-vWMgbZAxzMA" hash="bBwktQ">A sexual deviant discovered with help that his problem was not God-given, as so many had told him in the past, but rather self-acquired from an early age. He recently declared with confidence: “I have conquered Satan himself. Nothing can stop me now.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p18" guid="2a8d480b-ae8a-4f36-8013-cd57fc46e8aa" pid="IQRuMPOs40CT6fFISKu-wA" hash="8rw2OQ">Every success story of the past year has been the result of special effort on the part of people who cared. They cared enough to give some time and to be sincere and compassionate; in other words, to follow the great example set by the Savior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p19" guid="328d8185-ccff-47f0-b8b7-44978fb0f8a9" pid="rvKyumOs602RbOHp-rICIg" hash="NHx2bw">The only joy that is comparable with the joy of the one receiving the help is the glow that seems to emanate from the one who has given so unselfishly of his time and strength to quietly help someone in need.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p20" guid="d631bd8e-ea12-4b7e-8ea7-1917729e4857" pid="Y5lvfeyiX0afbPUoWb_ODQ" hash="RBK-6g">The Savior did not seem to be so much involved in giving money. You will remember that his gifts were in the form of personal attention, in performing an administration, and in sharing the gifts of the Spirit. In fact, it was the Savior who said: “Peace I leave with you, my peace I give unto you: not as the world giveth, give I unto you. …” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.27" class="scriptureRef">John 14:27</a>.) We could add to peace the gift of love, the gift of immortality, the gift of eternal life, the gift of understanding, the gift of compassion, the gift of eternal justice. All of these gifts are beyond monetary consideration and could well be our gift to someone sometime, if we weren’t “too busy.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p21" guid="3d9fe0c5-e0c3-48f6-a78a-e2ab2e67fab9" pid="bgEouZV7vkaSa-uJSysARg" hash="jAH0qw">Members of this church understand clearly that baptism is essential for entrance into the celestial kingdom. We also know and understand that total fulfillment can only be found in that ultimate celestial state called eternal life or exaltation, which, of course, is to live eternally in his holy presence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p22" guid="1176b653-5a31-4266-89f6-87a83972c1c6" pid="SmRLEZ9odEWslq5Z-8qX2A" hash="qNuT8Q">Only those who have been justified and sanctified through service to their fellowmen can hope to reach such a lofty goal. To be justified is to be found acceptable in our “good works” as well as by our superior faith. James used this excellent example:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p23" guid="370447d0-6f93-4951-a502-eb065a4797e8" pid="45Eh-NBU5US4ZR8Ys6-U3A" hash="lwpEBQ">“If a brother or sister be naked, and destitute of daily food,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p24" guid="f0d48613-6083-4076-a57a-291648c2860c" pid="595bThSh4Umk-pRYEV22fQ" hash="dda-HA">“And one of you say unto them, Depart in peace, be ye warmed and filled; notwithstanding ye give them not those things which are needful to the body; what doth it profit?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/2.15-16" class="scriptureRef">James 2:15–16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p25" guid="02f882ca-8b5a-4f62-9237-ee6bc4340a7d" pid="EBPwGqDgtUaULMMUvc3PaA" hash="8IErmw">After citing other similar examples, he concludes with this thought: “Ye see then how that by works a man is justified, and not by faith only.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/2.24" class="scriptureRef">James 2:24</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p26" guid="a90ee027-2e9f-46ce-b5aa-3731b0c01755" pid="8zqXvCTmtEaTbDM5qfZ7rQ" hash="p0tX3w">Moroni explained that we are sanctified “by the grace of God” as we become “perfect in Christ” and “deny not his power.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.33" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 10:33</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p27" guid="d5fd617d-5ff0-4fcf-aa1b-24ee78026622" pid="H6Ey2nPG1UKVWHE84ljSYQ" hash="Q1i9Mg">No man can become “perfect in Christ” without a deep, abiding, and sincere concern for his fellow beings. This example just read from James cites physical needs. However, there are also emotional problems about us in every direction. Loneliness and discouragement, for example, are two of Satan’s most effective tools against us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p28" guid="6c726f65-e809-4905-9a83-2265a7461567" pid="W7bi6d4nLEyPWVdY7KLH6g" hash="7uVZPQ">Is there someone you know who needs a friend, a friend who is willing to listen to him? The Church is reaching out to such people as never before. Resource volunteers are being organized throughout the Church to help carry out one of the Savior’s most sacred challenges.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p29" guid="b191ee6a-e86f-40f6-a0a7-72acbf12a007" pid="720LKkyGv0ufG2iw9z_aTw" hash="kxGMUQ">There are those who associate high calling in the Church with guaranteed rights to the blessings of heaven, but I wish to declare without reservation that the ultimate judgment for every man will be on the simplest terms, and most certainly on what each has done to bless other people in a quiet, unassuming way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p30" guid="7230f320-29a8-4e0a-bbe3-2852754b4572" pid="kCmDF7fSeEWv1zcMQf8w8w" hash="OWZ9BA">If this life’s effort is to be justified, then there should be a major and continuing attempt to justify or, in other words, to conform our actions with the example of the Master. The central theme of his mortal span was purely and simply serving those about him. He fulfilled an eternal truth which should be a part of your life and my life. “And whosoever will be chief among you, let him be your servant.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/20.27" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 20:27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p31" guid="b88b0370-f7e9-4ac4-b2cb-6731c6f92bec" pid="F-z49zPpL06i_idN7OQHrg" hash="55C-9g">If our life’s effort is to be sanctified or, in other words, ratified by the standards of eternal truth, then our actions must be in harmony with the sanctifying principles of the gospel, which most certainly includes sincere concern for others and a concerted effort to alleviate their problems.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p32" guid="e9698f0c-b797-44a2-936d-deec3a8c0c1b" pid="tyskFslanUyM6u77-iiFFQ" hash="1VrvmQ">I can think of no better guarantee for the future, your future and my future, than to follow the admonition of the Savior when he said at the beginning of his ministry: “Come and follow me” (Matt. 19: 21); and then, after showing the way, he said very simply, “Go, and do thou likewise.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise.p33" guid="6fa01f7e-478a-46c0-8a71-934a93259d6f" pid="XB3Z-vMmekyRI6rTl5LDUQ" hash="9X9XyQ">Brothers and sisters, may we go and do likewise, is my fervent prayer in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1973/04/go-and-do-thou-likewise</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1973-general-conference/1973-04-1040-elder-robert-l-simpson-64k-eng.mp3" length="6054207" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 1973 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Fundamental Obligation: The Priesthood</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Tonight we meet in what is possibly the largest gathering of priesthood members in the history of this world. May we congratulate each of you for being here where the Lord would have you be. Your very presence is an indication of your faith and your </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03040_000_5020" doc-version="2" hash="CVktnw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="gyRbd0ZaHk69lEE8Abj1Bw" hash="mARD3w">Our Fundamental Obligation:</h1><p class="subtitle" pid="9t4zk9WNMUOy4gk-EEdAeA" hash="R3U68A">The Priesthood</p><p class="authorName" guid="bba9c1c2-025d-41b7-8bdf-78662d0234f6" pid="3J34APbFDk6slgbNQbyuaA" hash="_EZcfw">Robert L. Simpson</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="d0a062dd-b5cf-4d3c-8280-140b2fefb35d">
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.t1">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p1" guid="584ee63f-ab5c-49da-9d8f-44828ee6858c" pid="CjRKf6KdQUSA4YMfRZg4tg" hash="leED4Q">Tonight we meet in what is possibly the largest gathering of priesthood members in the history of this world. May we congratulate each of you for being here where the Lord would have you be. Your very presence is an indication of your faith and your desire to be a vital part of the kingdom of God.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p2" guid="2dfbc2d0-91c9-4704-a3a5-ffc423fe8a23" pid="LKgFOoMGeUuOiB_O3oJwqw" hash="nWeRQA">Our message to the world is that he lives, that the heavens have been opened, that priesthood authority has been restored, and that a living prophet stands at our head.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p3" guid="66f212a6-a1fd-4f9b-9dad-ac32ee9feaf6" pid="jPyYsgcBUketUJACYIUwYw" hash="80BdtA">We regard as scripture that chapter of the Pearl of Great Price that records the precious thoughts and words of the Prophet Joseph Smith as he recounts the astounding events that occurred in the spring of 1820. He said he did it to “put all inquirers after truth in possession of the facts, as they have transpired. …” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.1" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:1</a>.) He further states: “… I shall present the various events … in truth and righteousness. …” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.2" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:2</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p4" guid="91c3233c-2402-4102-9db1-09f440a61227" pid="Waa5y_8ykEq7cGU9cTlaIw" hash="7bMIKw">You will remember that, after recounting some family history and commenting about religious unrest in the community, the Prophet tells of being impressed by the scripture found in James, chapter 1, verse 5, which reads: “If any of you lack wisdom, let him ask of God, that giveth to all men liberally, and upbraideth not; and it shall be given him.” [<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/1.5" class="scriptureRef">James 1:5</a>] Then the Prophet said:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p5" guid="a00a10ff-141e-49b1-9c2b-036548e8bfae" pid="LDetGA8R4UORRoqzlQg1oQ" hash="U4tJ7A">“Never did any passage of scripture come with more power to the heart of man than this did at this time to mine. It seemed to enter with great force into every feeling of my heart. …</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p6" guid="1f0e4e99-b55c-4bea-811d-a67dd3b7c2e1" pid="NDVPE2gHLU-5iu6J9p-f_A" hash="0Gp72Q">“… I at length came to the determination to ‘ask of God,’ concluding that if he gave wisdom to them that lacked wisdom, and would give liberally, and not upbraid, I might venture.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p7" guid="2fa4902e-03ea-467a-a857-e8691c352bcf" pid="fyLnawL3aUuQNtVXF6FQTQ" hash="BC2b6w">“So, in accordance with this, my determination to ask of God, I retired to the woods to make the attempt. It was on the morning of a beautiful, clear day, early in the spring of eighteen hundred and twenty. It was the first time in my life that I had made such an attempt, for amidst all my anxieties I had never as yet made the attempt to pray vocally.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.12-14" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:12–14</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p8" guid="4689689f-e8e6-4798-9c2e-2a55e19935a7" pid="Z66o5GJ5JEqzfqdWnGiHcQ" hash="Yiskdg">Does this sound like a 14 1/2-year-old boy? Then he said:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p9" guid="69081413-23d3-47ad-bb28-ca327e54f211" pid="97hjL7nt6U-allFbHDYQsg" hash="E_coPg">“After I had retired to the place where I had previously designed to go, having looked around me, and finding myself alone, I kneeled down and began to offer up the desire of my heart to God. I had scarcely done so, when immediately I was seized upon by some power which entirely overcame me, and had such an astonishing influence over me as to bind my tongue so that I could not speak. Thick darkness gathered around me, and it seemed to me for a time as if I were doomed to sudden destruction.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p10" guid="2be976d9-6941-4004-b275-411d6656b1d6" pid="PVs48irGeEuu4Cd190UMAQ" hash="H6NmOg">“But, exerting all my powers to call upon God to deliver me out of the power of this enemy which had seized upon me, and at the very moment when I was ready to sink into despair and abandon myself to destruction—not to an imaginary ruin, but to the power of some actual being from the unseen world, who had such marvelous power as I had never before felt in any being—just at this moment of great alarm, I saw a pillar of light exactly over my head, above the brightness of the sun, which descended gradually until it fell upon me.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p11" guid="cb0e4cc8-3a62-42a5-971b-54e2db0928c9" pid="HhHOkgOMf0-mLZ5JfFTEEA" hash="NBFhAQ">“It no sooner appeared than I found myself delivered from the enemy which held me bound. When the light rested upon me I saw two Personages, whose brightness and glory defy all description, standing above me in the air. One of them spake unto me, calling me by name and said, pointing to the other—<span class="emphasis">This is My Beloved Son. Hear Him!</span>” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.15-17" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:15–17</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p12" guid="1c0091bc-da82-40f0-a411-9effd8c2eb07" pid="qkVGcGQ630KU6kZH1cAg0Q" hash="dvJE4A">Now, brethren, we have just recounted together the most significant singular event in the world since the resurrection of the Lord and Savior Jesus Christ. The First Vision is the very foundation of this Church, and it is my conviction that each member of this Church performs his duty in direct ratio to his personal testimony and faith in the First Vision. How well do you believe this story? No man having heard the Joseph Smith testimony can, in good conscience, remain on neutral ground.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p13" guid="3fb2e72a-cf62-4197-a136-d4a188d597da" pid="NrPLDMl_tkyGlgCLdXQgBA" hash="YE2V4A">Joseph Smith was an ordinary boy with a rather ordinary name, but he was now to become an extraordinary prophet. For nine long years following the First Vision Joseph prepared for the privilege of the priesthood. As you remember, it was John the Baptist who appeared on the banks of the Susquehanna in answer to a fervent prayer offered by Joseph Smith and Oliver Cowdery. How simple the words for such a historic occasion:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p14" guid="77d8758c-d4ea-4587-a6e2-312844ce85c5" pid="NWRxSTtY9EuOTuUwVdBFSQ" hash="2xc1MQ">“<span class="emphasis">Upon you my fellow servants, in the name of Messiah, I confer the Priesthood of Aaron, which holds the keys of the ministering of angels, and of the gospel of repentance, and of baptism by immersion for the remission of sins; and this shall never be taken again from the earth until the sons of Levi do offer again an offering unto the Lord in righteousness.</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p15" guid="3c368093-cd7f-46a2-a07a-36ba6c077776" pid="cJSIKnDC7UGfE-hsYIH4mg" hash="ShxYgg">“He said this Aaronic Priesthood had not the power of laying on hands for the gift of the Holy Ghost, but that this should be conferred on us hereafter; and he commanded us to go and be baptized, and gave us directions that I should baptize Oliver Cowdery, and that afterwards he should baptize me.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p16" guid="3dc19e50-48da-434f-a884-0adc1c6eeec5" pid="VxikjI1jfE-vohlJmZ124w" hash="9KnU4g">“Accordingly,” continues the Prophet, “we went and were baptized. I baptized him first, and afterwards he baptized me—after which I laid my hands upon his head and ordained him to the Aaronic Priesthood, and afterwards he laid his hands on me and ordained me to the same Priesthood—for so we were commanded.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.69-71" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:69–71</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p17" guid="16b3a60c-5bb2-438f-934e-02828d6795cd" pid="ZvUdXYh63Ey2n_XO4XwG-Q" hash="XKjEqQ">It was just a few weeks later that Peter, James, and John appeared to confer the Melchizedek Priesthood and the apostleship upon these same two men. That priesthood authority remains today in an unbroken chain. How reassuring to know that God’s house is a house of order and that the same great leaders of 2,000 years ago were privileged to reestablish true priesthood authority on the earth. The logical sequence of events and the personages involved help to confirm the divine nature of all that transpired on that historic occasion.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p18" guid="a035c61d-330b-4f20-8a3b-daecd0e04e29" pid="oP3nK3OBDU6oJ91U9PcqeQ" hash="ERYZBA">It was in the following year, 1830, that the Church was organized. At last truth was established and continuing revelation was assured.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p19" guid="1f880c70-f011-4f0f-b00e-ac0597a042bd" pid="UIIgfl9n0UOk90x9sPDbBw" hash="CNDKAg">Then nearly six years later at the Kirtland Temple on a Sabbath afternoon, the Lord himself appeared in glorious vision to Joseph and Oliver. That same day Moses, Elias, and Elijah also appeared, each ancient prophet restoring an important function of the gospel. Listen again to the glorious description of the Savior’s appearance as recounted by the Prophet Joseph Smith:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p20" guid="fe6641e1-648a-4a95-a40e-9b8c2a230196" pid="uA6oJZC1A0et5-SJqwu3rQ" hash="t95bqA">“The veil was taken from our minds, and the eyes of our understanding were opened.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p21" guid="19815020-1fd8-43f7-872d-2251e58c1890" pid="OdXfNeH8DUuzVPa9dQv1Og" hash="3ytSuA">“We saw the Lord standing upon the breastwork of the pulpit, before us; and under his feet was a paved work of pure gold, in color like amber.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p22" guid="ba219f6e-0b85-43ae-946e-3f3cc0fb9daa" pid="kPnOXpBTLUeXxG0G9rjS3A" hash="RXkRLA">“His eyes were as a flame of fire; the hair of his head was white like the pure snow; his countenance shone above the brightness of the sun; and his voice was as the sound of the rushing of great waters, even the voice of Jehovah. …” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/110.1-3" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 110:1–3</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p23" guid="5f9bcf96-266c-493f-a879-dff9c8a48ada" pid="Y-yxESWY7k6ftau9AbEysg" hash="PHJxBQ">The Savior then delivered a message that we should all read on occasion. It is recorded in the 110th section of the Doctrine and Covenants. [<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/110.title" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 110</a>]</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p24" guid="189cc2fd-d410-41a9-88b1-d641da43cb31" pid="8PWh8CqhxE6lfCSnC2w8dw" hash="gjAnow">We attending this meeting tonight have accepted the obligation of priesthood. The commitment has been made, and there is really no excuse for failure because “… the Lord giveth no commandments [or commission] unto the children of men, save he shall prepare a way for them that they may accomplish the thing which he commandeth them.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/3.7" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 3:7</a>.) With a promise like that, there is really no excuse for us to fail.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p25" guid="8cfe59bd-8a7b-4d52-8c9b-3a4cdf0c936d" pid="B6g6BoBpkEK2_7GuwUcK9g" hash="Eo4NAQ">Now, brethren of the priesthood, after reviewing these divine appearances—God the Father; Jesus Christ, his Son; John the Baptist; Peter, James, and John; and other ancient prophets—doesn’t this make you excited about this great work!</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p26" guid="e0d22a6c-d18a-496e-8e18-7566db588421" pid="DD_L0KPGLEWNh8BaFX7z0Q" hash="2l86SQ">Knowing that these events transpired, if I were a young deacon all over again, I would pass the sacrament like it was one of the most important things I had to do all week. My every act and my appearance would be in strict harmony with the dignity and honor of the position entrusted to me by the Savior.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p27" guid="6e3659de-2c76-4f30-a1d2-61e69153653d" pid="wMmFj40PTk6ps7ySLL3a3g" hash="3Y8g_A">The gathering of fast offerings would take on a rich, new meaning, and I would remind myself as I approached each home that I was the bishop’s personal representative, that poor and needy people would be blessed more abundantly as a result of my efforts to participate in what James described as “pure religion and undefiled.” (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/james/1.27" class="scriptureRef">James 1:27</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p28" guid="788dc7d2-47e0-479c-8014-bfb0b8594b53" pid="BPTEs-gvyk26MBfHq5shvg" hash="EHnXcg">If I were a young teacher or priest again, I would strive to really be an asset to my home teaching companion. I would try harder to cement friendships with the members we visit. I would attempt to lift people like the Savior did. My responsibility toward the sacrament would be regarded as a rich, spiritual experience, never to be taken lightly. To participate in a sacred ordinance with anything but our highest respect and best effort is a disservice to the people of the ward and a betrayal of the true Spirit of Christ.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p29" guid="5aa6f9d4-d3d6-4357-97c5-23a5ffdce4ab" pid="-vqkiswAn0eoBoBXKc0lGg" hash="sO4nNg">If I were one of you young adults over 25 and still unmarried, I would start looking for someone who has the potential for perfection instead of someone who has already achieved it. Just off the record, and quite confidentially, it is my understanding that there is only one perfect girl produced in each century, and I have already found her; she is all mine.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p30" guid="f6be6623-7d06-4d59-a7f2-dd1b47293ea2" pid="jCNizIa0N02VK-DxVG1Wzg" hash="6HEJZw">If I were a young father just starting out, I would practice kindness, patience, and love unfeigned. I would check my priority system constantly just to make certain that my course was true and that eternal life was my destiny.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p31" guid="a26cc197-0763-42f5-85fb-c4bed92a3a68" pid="ergcBRV9-ECcSG0oVky77A" hash="mSrS4Q">If I were a prospective elder, I would give myself to some kind of Church service and at the same time set out to improve my gospel scholarship on a daily basis so that my family could be sealed to me for all eternity.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p32" guid="bc26ad56-3828-4e29-a3ac-055a5a34ea8f" pid="gyJv6L2PsU6IZ56i4C1lJg" hash="Vj1zVg">If I were an active Melchizedek Priesthood holder, high councilor, member of the stake presidency, member of a bishopric, and especially if I had children at home, knowing all that I know about eternity, I would remember above all else the wise counsel of the past: that if you spend all your days and save the whole world but lose your own family, you will be counted as an unprofitable servant.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p33" guid="b6cd6174-3141-4d77-b1d6-08dcadff96e4" pid="mtcdcc6IVEqMSck_-OAcbA" hash="ibyLGg">Brethren, four great statements I leave with you to ponder. First, the words of God the Eternal Father, “This is My Beloved Son. Hear Him!” [<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.17" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:17</a>] Not 2,000 years ago, but in our time.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p34" guid="5ecbedfe-9b1b-4549-8641-1b9b3bae8529" pid="1-kfLsOR6EiHeSAtiESxHw" hash="PU6utw">Next, the memorable words of John the Baptist who declared with authority: “Upon you my fellow servants, in the name of Messiah I confer the Priesthood of Aaron …” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/13.title" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 13</a>) in our day.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p35" guid="d381e735-d6bf-42a5-923d-32474d72f8f5" pid="mdVaKx3GHEi3N6dIfaVmyA" hash="2ezQmA">Third, the Savior’s statement about: “Peter, and James, and John, whom I have sent unto you, by whom I have ordained you and confirmed you …” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/27.12" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 27:12</a>) happening in our time of the world’s history.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p36" guid="63e10a7b-d759-4da9-9bcb-3058631f881b" pid="xKWd-cr4iEGKooPSlFXN4A" hash="IEsDig">And fourth, from Kirtland, as recorded by the Prophet Joseph: “We saw the Lord standing upon the breastwork of the pulpit, before us; and under his feet was a paved work of pure gold, in color like amber.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/110.2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 110:2</a>.)</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p37" guid="fc3130a0-1cfc-4b42-abf7-a1cba82940e0" pid="3W3K9ZZh_USPRYA1QjCZZg" hash="aozoaw">Indeed, fellow priesthood holders, these statements are not the idle words of men. We live in a remarkable time. The Lord has spoken in our day. You and I have received the message. Our fundamental obligation is to the priesthood of God which cannot be regarded casually, as though it were a man-made club or a mere fraternal organization.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood.p38" guid="6aa4dbcb-7a7c-4ed0-a3c9-bf83f45d8d8c" pid="pGP5VU-pAESiOC47_nJf3Q" hash="e1WXvA">I testify with all the sobriety of my heart and soul that we are committed, that we are depended upon. All things are possible in the Lord; President Lee made this crystal clear this morning in his masterful discourse at the welfare services meeting. As we unite in our faith and determination, His work will be accomplished. May this obligation burn within us. May it never be dimmed. May we be excited about the opportunity that is ours as we move forward deliberately, in humility, and with constant preparation, and do what we have to do. And I pray it in the name of Jesus Christ, the Master. Amen.</p>
		</div>
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1973/10/our-fundamental-obligation-the-priesthood</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1973-general-conference/1973-10-5020-elder-robert-l-simpson-64k-eng.mp3" length="7803759" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 1973 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Most Vital Information</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My beloved brothers and sisters, I am grateful for this opportunity and for the spirit of the testimonies that have been borne here this morning.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03050_000_019" doc-version="2" hash="LFCBhw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="iqbYwZjBuUqlDLRQviGXVA" hash="EQ8qWw">The Most Vital Information</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="xknZ541e2UergauFQNflGQ" hash="_EZcfw">Robert L. Simpson</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26ea.jpg" alt="Elder Robert L. Simpson" pid="HW27vmjzHEKxKNEPG-HMdg" hash="6kp0Yg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.p1" pid="d25rQCtC1U6q_TiiCYsKlg" hash="W06kGQ">My beloved brothers and sisters, I am grateful for this opportunity and for the spirit of the testimonies that have been borne here this morning.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.p2" pid="8GfmOa8VG0iUPBoSODKgvA" hash="NLjbZQ">Just a couple of weeks ago I was passing through the Salt Lake airport and had a less-than-five-minute contact with a young man that impressed me very much. During our brief contact he found out about my affiliation with the Church. He found out that the yellow pad that I had in my hand was in preparation for some thoughts to give at the Saturday morning session of general conference.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.p3" pid="XGHd0yaXO0G4lhLm8iWGqg" hash="ixrHNQ">I observed a tenderness between him and his wife and his three children. And I knew that he was a man with deep spiritual sensitivity. But having only three or four minutes to chat, as I boarded my aircraft, I discovered that I didn’t know his name, I didn’t have his address. But I want you to know that much of what I say this morning is because I know he is listening to this particular session of conference.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.p4" pid="jWn5X6AtQU-eSqH1YlkX4w" hash="_V-NoQ">We are met here this morning hopefully that we might communicate well about the Lord Jesus Christ, because incorporated in his precious teachings are the most urgent, the most important, and the most vital of all information pertaining to the ultimate happiness and eternal destiny of man.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.p5" pid="XatHpmnmE0GgDQ8ZnBeRNg" hash="si2kfA">I earnestly seek his divine help and guidance that the intent of my heart will not be misunderstood, and perhaps our communication can be like the prophet Isaiah when he said, “Come now, and let us reason together” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/1.18" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 1:18</a>); and this for one purpose only, that we might all be blessed more abundantly.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.p6" pid="0yeWvi_t1kOeBZOBITzyhA" hash="ZvzEyw">As I proceed now to share these few thoughts with you, I declare with the apostle Paul as he taught the saints of Rome:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.p7" pid="JvVXkepgCUK0SDkjWRPc_g" hash="S-7bRw">“I am ready to preach the gospel to you. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.p8" pid="JGW2s9i9GUW5t95BOr8syg" hash="ax2dVA">“For I am not ashamed of the gospel of Christ: for it is the power of God unto salvation.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.p9" pid="UIy69PdurU25jQB4JRJIPg" hash="E3qEUQ">Then he concluded, “It is the power of God … to every one that believeth.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rom/1.15-16" class="scriptureRef">Rom. 1:15–16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.p10" pid="RrK_JLz-vEm7j9R20YB6ow" hash="hf_B5Q">And I promise you that the Holy Ghost stands ever ready to bear witness to all who earnestly seek the truth that they might recognize that truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.p11" pid="XilpGEXMVU2BG7qbL5GXUw" hash="tX-Vaw">A Protestant minister who was somewhat perturbed about losing some of his parishioners to the Mormon Church asked one of our missionaries: “Why do you proselyte amongst my people? They are all good Christians. You should be spending your time with the heathen nations.” And the reply came: “If you, sir, knew for certain that God the Father and his Son Jesus Christ had shown themselves and spoken again in this time of the world’s history, restoring vital information and also restoring true priesthood authority to man, would you be able to remain silent?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.p12" pid="7bUfkeE0g0G0h2rdnkcCdg" hash="B2cc4A">No man could, and so it is with some 18,000 young men and young women throughout the world today who seek the singular privilege of sharing with as many as will pause to listen, that in very deed God the Father and his Son did appear to a young lad in this day and age, all of which was preliminary to the second coming of the Lord and Savior as foretold by the prophets.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.p13" pid="G9AeSXYOk02WXWt3LsyHFQ" hash="UM_tXw">These same missionaries proclaim to the world that, following this remarkable visitation by two members of the Godhead, priesthood authority was restored to the earth through special heavenly messengers. Who else but John the Baptist would be better qualified for the honor of restoring the Aaronic Priesthood, the authority to baptize by immersion? For it was he whom the Savior sought out when the Savior felt the need to establish the example of baptism by immersion and by proper authority.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.p14" pid="EFbLoKY1cEuhtR1ooeu8nA" hash="tnrkKA">Who else but the apostles Peter, James, and John would be more appropriate or better qualified to restore the Melchizedek Priesthood just a few weeks later? Yes, those same great apostles who walked and talked with the Savior during his brief ministry, returned to earth for a specific purpose in our time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.p15" pid="Uame3C9T3k-61Xfuzl3g7A" hash="nurW1A">Yes, with all of the soberness of my soul, I declare that God’s house is a house of order. His holy purposes are not carried out by man’s whim or fancy but, rather, in this church which bears his name, sacred ordinances can only be performed by proper authority. We agree with Paul that “no man taketh this honour unto himself, but he that is called of God, as was Aaron.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/heb/5.4" class="scriptureRef">Heb. 5:4</a>.) Priesthood authority of the Lord Jesus Christ was restored by John the Baptist, by Peter, James, and John in the spring of 1829.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.p16" pid="3XrT8Q3b5EuJqGHHiRzlWg" hash="Dpb6wg">Since the reestablishment of the Lord’s true church 144 years ago, there has been a driving compulsion among the members of the Church to share their good feeling with their neighbors, with their friends, and abroad. “Every member a missionary” has become a byword in this Church, as thousands can be found throughout the free world bearing witness, explaining the restoration, and radiating the Spirit of Christ unto all who will listen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.p17" pid="Jdb30v7oFUyPHlNHeuXctg" hash="FZ_cEw">Words can hardly convey the joy and the fulfillment that accompany conversion to the truth, all made possible by the miracle of forgiveness, as repentance paves the way for baptism.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.p18" pid="1H7YMRQgQUqw_KpJEVHDYg" hash="XazyCw">May I invite you to participate on a rapid world tour as we glimpse quickly at just a sample or two of what is happening everywhere as this great latter-day missionary momentum rolls forth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.p19" pid="j4U4V4uRd0a8xRPzhfmwjQ" hash="kYLeLg">I am thinking, first of all, of a South Pacific family of 14 whose family unit had been so badly broken through parental indifference and irresponsible acts that four of the older children were in reform school and three youngsters were in foster-home custody. Today you will find a solid family unit headed by parents who have goals, proper discipline, and great love for their children, who have been sealed to them for eternity in the temple of God. The two oldest boys are full-time missionaries, striving to bring the same hope to many others. All of this because a desperate father, contemplating suicide, listened to two young men—one 19 and the other 20—and he believed what they told him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.p20" pid="e1CsLeOWwk6dfqIDU66TRA" hash="AVeHkw">Not long ago I listened to this testimony from a black man nearing the end of a long prison sentence: “I found the truth behind these prison bars,” he said. “There has been plenty of time to study and to think. My one ambition now is to qualify for baptism, after my debt to society has been paid, and then go back home to Mississippi to tell my people about this great church.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.p21" pid="skba-mwbq0iE7KIV7iZk2A" hash="Ki2UFA">While winging across the South Pacific, an airline stewardess asked me and my wife if we were Mormons after our third serving of milk. Receiving a positive answer, she said with a radiance we shall never forget: “I can hardly wait to get back to California after this trip because I am scheduled for the third discussion from the missionaries, and I already know that it is true.” Yes, she was baptized. She found a young man to match her faith. They have a beautiful little family. They’re on their way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.p22" pid="G4h_f_sJCkmsLrZ7gacQmQ" hash="Orjntg">May I introduce you to a successful young executive who writes: “Our family had it made. My wife and I were close, the three children were well adjusted, and then it happened. Jeff and Angela started to attend Primary with the neighbor’s children. From then on each Primary day our dinner hour became an instant replay of Primary. As parents, we couldn’t believe the great thoughts and attitudes—yes, and ‘a little child shall lead them.’ [<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/11.6" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 11:6</a>.] Well, that was the beginning, [he writes], and now after two years as members of the Lord’s true church, we really do have it made. Our family didn’t really know what family unity and true happiness were all about until Mormonism came into our family circle.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.p23" pid="PadoZU7N-U6QySQlYUMuJg" hash="F5Y7Zg">One woman in a South American country, intrigued by the sincerity of the Mormon missionaries, invited them back to meet the family that evening. But unfortunately her husband did not share her feelings, and the young men were greeted by a note on the door turning them away. She fasted and prayed that the Lord might intercede. And you know, it was just about six weeks later that the husband told her about two fine young men he had met on the bus coming home. He arranged for them to share their message with the family, and all six were baptized. It was not until then that the wife explained that these were the same two young men whom she had tried to introduce him to earlier. “God moves in a mysterious way his wonders to perform.” (See <span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 48.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.p24" pid="vdImNYwJoUieIldcp19LaQ" hash="G4O6Aw">Most people agree that Mormons are happy people, Mormons are stable people, and Mormons are dedicated people. Mormons are trustworthy people, and Mormons are healthy people. And yet I hear you saying, “Ah, but I know a Mormon who does thus and so.” My testimony to you today is that if you know a Mormon who is doing wrong, it is not because of his religious teachings. It is in spite of his religious teachings, and we sincerely hope that he will repent soon, for where much is given, much is expected.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.p25" pid="Mfsn5eY68EqpmQkbYUpRoA" hash="umIOTg">“Try me and see,” says the Lord. Whether your life be racked with profound problems or whether you think you have it made, I declare with total confidence that your life can only find genuine and lasting fulfillment in the restored gospel of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.p26" pid="Uf7a2dAf60-ruOHEEL54Bw" hash="kU2ydg">Why not use the same formula suggested by the Savior to test the truth of his church? My witness to you here today is the same as his declaration to a group of well-meaning critics 2,000 years ago, when he said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.p27" pid="VRT7_PcrCEO2NKPX_ivlqg" hash="PvjNRg">“My doctrine is not mine, but his that sent me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.p28" pid="_W1y5oULDkiYm_S4tzLSJw" hash="ubI3BA">“If any man will do his will, he shall know of the doctrine, whether it be of God, or whether I speak of myself.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/7.16-17" class="scriptureRef">John 7:16–17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information.p29" pid="xICqckyoAUqCVGO08gdQVg" hash="0ztwdQ">I declare in all kindness and sincerity that your eternal life and the salvation of your family depend upon what happened in the life of Joseph Smith, a prophet of God. May you find out soon is my humble prayer in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1974/10/the-most-vital-information</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1974-general-conference/1974-10-3050-elder-robert-l-simpson-64k-eng.mp3" length="5665231" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 1974 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do It</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1975/10/do-it?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My beloved brothers and sisters, it’s been some time since I’ve attended a general conference of the Church, and this morning I bring you reconfirmation that the gospel is true in London, England; the gospel is true in Auckland, New Zealand; it’s tru</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03063_000_006" doc-version="3" hash="CrH5UA"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="FAzpbPI7yk6kvI0ZzGFfYA" hash="D9S9hg">Do It</h1><p class="authorName" pid="pLZSWESKZE6HIyWqwF-fJg" hash="_EZcfw">Robert L. Simpson</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26ea.jpg" alt="Elder Robert L. Simpson" pid="ShZgK2ldH0mkNBB-_f3z7g" hash="6kp0Yg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p1" pid="JTkglgyyyEun_B5LyU-oMg" hash="1TWCwQ">My beloved brothers and sisters, it’s been some time since I’ve attended a general conference of the Church, and this morning I bring you reconfirmation that the gospel is true in London, England; the gospel is true in Auckland, New Zealand; it’s true in Nuku‘alofa, Tonga; and it’s true in Salt Lake City, Utah. And I’m grateful to be here.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p2" pid="Z6SY2cavvkaMO2taI811hg" hash="cT4gpA">President Kimball, for the past several months, I have been carrying your message of love and greeting to Church members across the sea; and now here this morning I bring to you the sincere affection and continuing loyalty of more than 100,000 members of the Church in the South Pacific area. They are anxiously counting the days until your arrival next February to conduct the most ambitious and widespread series of Church conferences ever undertaken.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p3" pid="0dp153j5wEaWgGOfRgfQdw" hash="VvfaMA">The mere contemplation of forty-four conference sessions in seventeen days at nine different locations staggers the imagination; and if that doesn’t do it, just add the thought of approximately 28,000 miles of air travel while changing your clock eighteen times to accommodate the different time zones.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p4" pid="0loy1iRPuE66uBuRoThT2A" hash="MAxvXw">Such is the schedule of a man who has challenged a people to “lengthen their stride.” Such is the schedule of a man who declares not only, “Do as I say,” but more importantly, “Do as I do.” It is so much easier to respond when the trump gives us that certain sound of example.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p5" pid="-CqWdYWtdkKJHk4nvIV9tQ" hash="KCIrzA">Prominently displayed on President Kimball’s desk is a slogan which reads simply, “DO IT.” With this inspired leader, personal convenience comes second. Everything is done to meet the Lords convenience. His example for work has become legend and establishes an example for us all to follow.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p6" pid="magvp_kyZk2Z0bn6y48AJA" hash="WW05Yg">While I was stationed at an air base in Wyoming during World War II, it was announced in our branch sacrament meeting that the following week a branch conference would be held and that there was a good possibility that the mission president would bring a visiting authority from Salt Lake City with him. As we came to branch conference the following Sunday morning, we were introduced to that visiting authority, a man that none of us had ever seen before. It was Elder Spencer W. Kimball, the newest member of the Twelve out on one of his very first assignments. His manner was kindly, his testimony so sure, but he expressed concern that such a high calling should come to one such as he. Then with renewed confidence, he said in effect: “Brothers and Sisters: I don’t know exactly why the Lord has called me, but I do have one talent to offer. My father taught me how to work; and if the Lord can use a worker, I’m available.” Yes, the Lord could use a worker! In fact, he needed a hard worker that might possibly be ready to assume prime responsibility at a most significant time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p7" pid="XfoDSjixBkCIcda4Vi3q0g" hash="SfTYqg">Now is that time, and a prophet who knows how to work is leading the way. But one fact is certain—this latter-day work requires thousands of us who are willing to match stride with the prophet.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p8" pid="eeaqccshkkmsmsqL5kCx5w" hash="Htj7vQ">A prophet who walks alone can do little more than mark time. Every dispensation has had the crying need for hard-working, qualified disciples. President Kimball is calling for the greatest army of hard workers in the history of the Church on earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p9" pid="T8Fie-XgbUSwNXMfy-zNgw" hash="JvAYfw">May we consider together these three objectives as a starting point in our preparation to match stride with the prophet:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p10" pid="LLAamB88tUKQHs-10NtvGw" hash="p7_uKA">First, we must be better informed about the doctrine; second, we must be more willing to just DO IT; and third, we must be more readily available to the gifts of the Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p11" pid="sjnKorhFIE6q_tYmYbaFjQ" hash="e_9SNQ">A great teacher once said, “He who does not read has no advantage over him who cannot read.” Illiteracy in the gospel seems almost inexcusable in this day of enlightenment and modern teaching techniques, especially among those of us who are committed in the waters of baptism and who reconfirm that commitment each week as we partake of the sacrament.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p12" pid="Tt-xCvF8hESNM48cOokT9Q" hash="t9EJTw">On point number two—being willing—it always thrills me to meet with the missionaries all over the world. Is it ever convenient to pick up in the prime of life, to set schooling or an apprenticeship aside for two years, to leave family, friends, and personal interests to respond to a call from the prophet? Convenient, no. Soul satisfying, yes. And when you believe in something, you just DO IT!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p13" pid="ZueTpJx39USA7h4Np4rpIw" hash="we8naQ">I would like to pause for a moment and just share some notes that I made while I was attending a function in the South Pacific just a couple of weeks ago. The counsel received from the prophet should never be taken lightly. The Nuku‘alofa Tonga Stake followed President Kimball’s counsel to organize choirs in every ward and branch and then to invite their neighbors to join with them in these choirs. Just last month Sister Simpson and I thrilled at this stake’s choir festival. Every unit participated. One small branch came with a choir almost as large as the total branch membership. Each choir had a significant number of nonmembers. At least one choir consisted of one-third investigators. All choirs had recently baptized members singing with them. Almost all of them had been baptized as a direct result of choir participation. They were all dressed in white; they were well trained. It was an outstanding evening of spiritual uplift; it was an outstanding example of the blessings that can come by following the direction of a prophet. Does your ward or branch have a choir? Do you invite nonmembers to participate with you? Let’s DO IT!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p14" pid="oCzwTqkRv0adMgzBx_xQ3Q" hash="Qs3uCw">And then this little thought—you know, we have more than 7,000 wards and branches in this church. What if every one of those wards and branches set out to bring in just one family in the next year—twelve months to do it. We could invite a man and his wife and maybe they will have two or three children. If this family of five could be invited to sing with us, and if they could be converted, we could take five times 7,000, and you know we would have 35,000 new converts in addition to all else we are doing. This is significant! And these are the rewards that come from doing what a prophet has asked us to do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p15" pid="3_nCbZ5YqkSMgwIGhiDDbg" hash="3dWaGQ">Those who become candidates to inherit all that the Father has must learn early that a home teaching assignment is more important than any TV program or any other worldly interest. When the still small voice prompts us, let’s DO IT and DO IT NOW!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p16" pid="pVsmZOxmk0mE88p28aPSjA" hash="aqzmDw">Spiritual sensitivity is a gift, freely given, to all who are willing to do their best. It is for those who have a desire to serve and the fortitude to take the first step, even when it doesn’t seem personally convenient to do so. As we complicate our lives, we discourage the gifts of the Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p17" pid="Z1kdqXRBikG3xA613HcH7A" hash="8cDpCg">The Savior taught so simply, so beautifully, but so-called modern civilization has brought so many frustrations into our lives. Today’s social environment seems to demand a sophistication in our living patterns that is too often incompatible with more important eternal objectives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p18" pid="RQQWyHKj9kqCXquYqi9xrw" hash="LbIlJw">As Sister Simpson and I walked along lower Queen Street in Auckland, New Zealand, the other day, we came to a particular place not far from the wharf. There we paused for a few moments as I related to her the incident that took place at that very spot during my first mission.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p19" pid="VCvVPNSIPkqiAQMmpeeTtg" hash="8n6aqg">I could still see in my mind’s eye a very old Maori couple who stood at the curb with thousands of others waving farewell to the Maori Battalion as they marched down to their troop transport and off to war.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p20" pid="AXXREBa4ekqIj5EONPFwXw" hash="dlf1QA">The old couple became very excited as one young soldier glanced their way with a big smile. From their Maori conversation, it became apparent that this was their great-grandson going off to war.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p21" pid="s1j2WH2lm0K4sgHXeM7KKQ" hash="yMFJsA">His would be an atomic war with sophisticated equipment capable of killing by the thousands—so unlike the Maori wars of the late 1800s that the old Maori had participated in as a young tribal warrior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p22" pid="LQAlE9QnA0KHx3vdPy7Amg" hash="ZWBGMA">Soon the boy was gone from view, and it was then that the old man turned to his wife and said (perhaps a little cynically), “Ka tahi kua pakeha tatou,” which in effect means, “So now we are civilized.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p23" pid="EMQrhop3gkO6Trl0PUteGw" hash="6Io7sg">What is civilization? What is progress? Just exactly what is important and what isn’t? Scriptures teach that God’s ways are not man’s ways. Nothing has ever been truer than this.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p24" pid="1ioH5J0yy0aEqjKt1oDH5g" hash="0Yg0gQ">According to the revealed word of God, there is really and truly only one simple overall objective for this world of ours, and that is the accomplishment of immortality and eternal life for all of those who come here to live for a few years.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p25" pid="KYEAciUyu06S5ypMDskPCA" hash="2TBlcw">As we know, the first part of immortality has been accomplished through the atoning sacrifice of the Savior. Everyone, regardless of race, color, creed, or performance, will live beyond the grave and benefit by this unconditional and divine gift.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p26" pid="_EBVcPqPv0OWMWKMTT82IA" hash="0NZ-hw">The further possibility of eternal life or exaltation simply calls for an individual and personal conformity to Christ’s teachings and priesthood principles. But unlike immortality, each person needs to be convinced or converted to the disciplines and life-style that need to be learned and lived in order to achieve this ultimate goal of all eternity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p27" pid="Mrg7uqmsSkac-2VKc3DaBQ" hash="riAvOQ">Most impressive is the universal acceptance of gospel truths in the hearts of honest people. The Savior excluded no one from his circle of influence. So it is in his church today. I know a banker in Boston who will hurry home next Monday for family home evening (he does this every Monday); just exactly like another good brother I know of who owns a small farm in the mountains of Peru. I know a young father who lives on the island of Vava‘u in Tonga who goes out faithfully making his home teaching calls in his outrigger canoe; but his faith is no different from that of the young business executive I know in London who loves the work and does his home teaching faithfully—both willing to DO IT.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p28" pid="RGEtwttWeUakRISYWK2E0g" hash="nkjSfg">That old Maori great-grandfather had every right to question the true values of so-called civilization that had been thrust upon him. Our jet age of atomic power and automatic everything can be helpful if used properly.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p29" pid="-nWLQLhowEOq_XiQRe19MA" hash="jIofZA">If sophisticated methods and automatic equipment can provide us with more time to teach mankind eternal principles of God, then we are blessed most abundantly. If it only enables us to “lengthen our stride” in some devious direction, the adversary has won another round.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/do-it.p30" pid="LKn8_Rb3MEOkiSsgyzgXTw" hash="vuw-2g">May we be blessed with the ability to touch hearts and lift up as we follow the life of the Master and the example of his living prophet on earth today as we just simply DO IT is my prayer in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1975/10/do-it</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1975-general-conference/1975-10-1040-elder-robert-l-simpson-64k-eng.mp3" length="12049013" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 1975 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>These Four Things</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My beloved brothers and sisters, the gospel is true and we rejoice in that knowledge. What a lovely sweet spirit we have had at this conference. And how wonderful and true all the messages have been.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03070_000_027" doc-version="2" hash="CsNoaQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="OS5jfPWrOUC-vkDz32q0DA" hash="PjOrXA">These Four Things</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="fADLGGXEV0WT71LR_UUguA" hash="_EZcfw">Robert L. Simpson</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26ea.jpg" alt="Elder Robert L. Simpson" pid="XK3avrhchUK4qfzOfMPIwA" hash="6kp0Yg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p1" pid="I3w9QI5t5U2TApBegazyog" hash="3BE4qg">My beloved brothers and sisters, the gospel is true and we rejoice in that knowledge. What a lovely sweet spirit we have had at this conference. And how wonderful and true all the messages have been.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p2" pid="AjzxGTeR60Sro1lGE0PYxg" hash="7rVkPw">May I first of all bring each of you the love from the people of the South Pacific. And when you bring love from that area, you have to carry a couple of extra bags. I bring you that love and I want you to know that these people are filled with love and faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p3" pid="P_y3_faXJEi_KP60A38Ktw" hash="Z0BWnA">We meet as disciples of the Lord Jesus Christ. We love him, and we want to help him in doing that which has to be done. And Heavenly Father loves his children—those who live now, those as yet unborn, and those who have lived and died. We can be part of that process through our commitment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p4" pid="oMI2qpiFVU-u30c47wx89w" hash="AdaVIw">The fifth chapter of Ecclesiastes, verses four and five, states:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p5" pid="G5GLTZ2V_EWO200m7uW3Bw" hash="kBieTQ">“When thou vowest a vow unto God, defer not to pay it; for he hath no pleasure in fools: pay that which thou hast vowed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p6" pid="nxWAB9xUMkiJk2CUpiurMg" hash="2uI_FQ">“Better is it that thou shouldest not vow, than that thou shouldest vow and not pay.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/eccl/5.4-5" class="scriptureRef">Eccl. 5:4–5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p7" pid="62kNg4ny0kSU0p-DpOUHjg" hash="_MtRyA">Every member of this Church takes upon himself a sacred vow as he submits himself to the waters of baptism. One day in seven, each Sabbath day, we assemble to renew that sacred vow and commitment as we partake of the sacrament.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p8" pid="83JONI-CR0mHpT_ECUo3HQ" hash="tFHIDg">I would like to suggest that as Church members we keep four prime objectives uppermost in our minds. All four of these objectives involve people, for his church is a people-oriented church. Just as people were the main concern of the Savior, so it should be with each of us, if we are to assist the Master in achieving his end result: to “bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.39" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:39</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p9" pid="xatRFQdvoUSsZmN0IOLrbg" hash="Lm17wg">Eternal life for the individual requires priesthood. It requires priesthood action; it requires conformity to priesthood principles. The four people-oriented objectives in the life of those who profess to call themselves members of his church are these:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p10" pid="nLviEpSbU025lW4K_fWY3Q" hash="ZNYRdw">
        <span class="emphasis">First,</span> the obligation to prepare one’s self and one’s immediate family for the presence of the Lord;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p11" pid="Q0LHJ6yaGEy0H7RuJYOT7w" hash="n8anWQ">
        <span class="emphasis">Second,</span> the obligation to be our brother’s keeper and to lift other Church members;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p12" pid="Ot5BO7mgRk-6a5xKlniRjQ" hash="-fsRhw">
        <span class="emphasis">Third,</span> the obligation to share the most precious gift we have, the gospel, with those who have not yet caught the vision; and</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p13" pid="wF_JRFBfAUWMp0QvewpV9g" hash="sbQSCg">
        <span class="emphasis">Fourth,</span> the obligation to provide an opportunity of eternal blessings for our kindred dead.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p14" pid="O0G_TZeGXEufTY-T8CSb9A" hash="c0eVZA">Please note that your own personal welfare was first on the list, because the last three great obligations can only be accomplished from a source of strength and confidence. The world has too many cases already of “the blind leading the blind.” Our source of knowledge is light and truth. It is the word of God in the beautiful framework of continuing revelation. Truth and light must indeed be received before there can be a dissemination of it. The Savior provided living water to the spiritually deprived. We should strive for that capability also. Ours is not the role of the book vendor who merely carries out an exchange. As we convey properly, we must give of ourselves. Truth travels best on the wings of personal testimony and individual worthiness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p15" pid="84-A0agO5k27dvDn5bLS1g" hash="hrILkg">The Lord said to Peter, “When thou art converted, strengthen thy brethren.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/22.32" class="scriptureRef">Luke 22:32</a>.) And just as important is the response given the Lord by Peter on that occasion, when he vowed: “Lord, I am ready to go with thee, both into prison, and to death.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/22.33" class="scriptureRef">Luke 22:33</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p16" pid="2YodDA7Iyk-gxtWETez9jA" hash="VoBSNw">God’s work and glory starts with our preparedness. He counsels: “Let every man learn his duty.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/107.99" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 107:99</a>.) It requires dedication: “Seek ye first the kingdom of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.33" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 6:33</a>.) It demands conformity, the singular way: “Come … follow me.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/19.21" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 19:21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p17" pid="OMJSuyjT506cGw_vTbFF1A" hash="q_aZLQ">Only after true conversion, exemplified by a demonstrated willingness to improve our lives, can we be counted on as one standing on solid ground, as one ready to respond to the call, as one prepared to lift others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p18" pid="sNotXNdnBkezq7jSllOZTg" hash="7mOAvQ">Our second obligation is to be our brother’s keeper, to be our sister’s keeper, to seek after the lost sheep, to teach one another the doctrines of the kingdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p19" pid="PVboATN8OEaKXsC2Yhs-rA" hash="IrJBXA">I bear testimony to you that home teaching is the divinely inspired method by which we can best touch lives within this Church. Right beside this tremendous priesthood process is Relief Society visiting teaching. Paul had the spirit of home teaching and visiting teaching when he wrote to Timothy: “And the things that thou has heard of me among many witnesses, the same commit thou to faithful men, who shall be able to teach others also.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-tim/2.2" class="scriptureRef">2 Tim. 2:2</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p20" pid="8DeCTokrSUajlZkcFSb75Q" hash="d6pEGg">And now, listen to this, directly from the Lord: “And I give unto you a commandment that you shall teach one another the doctrine of the kingdom.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.77" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:77</a>.) This is not a mere suggestion, but listen: “I give unto you a <span class="emphasis">commandment</span> that you shall teach one another.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p21" pid="BlWbVHSsEku1-uqT9IPGTA" hash="vxslqw">I like the analogy I once heard about home teaching. The speaker held up a piece of Scottish plaid and suggested that in our minds we think of each color in the plaid as a separate program of the Church. Then he asked the question: “Which color is home teaching?” The answer: “Home teaching is not a single color; it is the total fabric.” Home teaching, properly carried out, could well involve every facet of the Church according to the varying needs of each family. I like that! Too often we think of home teaching as “just another program.” It can, and should, be as long and as broad as the entire Church spectrum.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p22" pid="wdEJffKPpki7avXo7kiZog" hash="bqxxPw">Now, all four billion souls now living on the earth are very dear indeed to our Heavenly Father. They, also, need what you and I have. To see that they have an opportunity to hear, and hopefully accept, is another of our important responsibilities. Thus we help Heavenly Father to further accomplish his work and his glory—to assist in bringing all of his children into the circle.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p23" pid="3YDOmFpFLEGuQ8e_jU5_Mg" hash="Y90QVw">So, the third great objective and vow that we have taken upon ourselves involves these four billion souls. It means continually seeking out and teaching those who might be ready now. This teaching is best done in an appropriate, orderly, and sincere way that will lead to their unqualified acceptance of gospel truth. The Savior said: “Go ye into all the world” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/16.15" class="scriptureRef">Mark 16:15</a>), and we <span class="emphasis">are</span> going, some 23,000 strong. We are now carrying the truth of the gospel to some fifty nations. But even today’s effort is not enough, says the prophet. Every single person in the Church twenty-five years and younger should be considered as a prospective missionary and the rest of us should become involved in training them, in encouraging them, and in helping them to save funds that they may be self-financed as far as possible.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p24" pid="ZQEAMuF9pUyf86Wh0ZpTVQ" hash="KNtrOg">During the recent tour of area conferences in the South Pacific, President Kimball was obviously impressed as we met dozens of Indian converts in Fiji. He recognized these pioneers of their race as the possibility for a future thrust into the masses of India when the time is right.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p25" pid="JiVTpjDZ6kSgnznb2sE1BA" hash="asz7AQ">The first hour of our Sunday morning session in Sydney was carried live on national television into tens of thousands of homes across Australia. The talks were superb, and the choir sang beyond their natural abilities. It was a miracle that we were meeting in the Sydney Opera House, a dramatic story in itself. Just in a word, the Sydney Opera House is normally booked two to three years in advance. There is an impressive history of practically no cancellations. And less than two months prior to conference time, there was a cancellation that no one can really explain—no one except the Lord, that is! You see, it just so happened to be on our weekend! The Lord moves in mysterious ways, his wonders to perform. The possibility of a national telecast was largely made possible by the acquisition of the Opera House as the conference location.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p26" pid="mebmLPXJ2ky0gXC75xk5Rw" hash="TovkSw">Listen to a few typical nonmember responses sent in from all over Australia after viewing that telecast.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p27" pid="WMuqxjvw7EWWffCt4lPTJg" hash="mCP7PA">The first one: “Well, how real can you get? It was simple and kind towards the family tie, of love between one another, even a little old-fashioned. There was a spiritual understanding for me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p28" pid="6ZPMaQ0D10CNa7Z_aLjBLA" hash="kjXcaQ">Another person said: “Even though I am not a Mormon, I found a deep sense of wisdom in this program.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p29" pid="1St7nCPHTk-ojlr2e39b0Q" hash="pyjlcA">Still another: “I learned more about your Church from the address of your president than any literature could convey. I enjoyed the choir and the message; great work.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p30" pid="gK9s0TbI6EOrWx6cOOhGVw" hash="Xg1-yg">Listen to this one: “What an inspiring message I heard this morning. I was only sorry I could not have watched right through, but was going to my own church.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p31" pid="poNgdqkJcU2xoj5aWdiV6g" hash="_9L3Hg">And another person wrote: “I would be interested in any literature you may care to send—but no callers—yet.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p32" pid="w93Qot9cTUGGyv56vW0kFA" hash="Lg9KhA">And still another: “My heart is filled with the love of God and fellowmen after viewing your inspirational telecast.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p33" pid="guFopkk83kOmQAYQ5hSg1w" hash="5zznyA">And finally this one: “If one could imagine heaven, then these wonderful people have given me a glimpse. I realize now I am desperate for salvation. Here truly must be the answer. Help!!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p34" pid="yy0y7RzKcEatLnGa-fcYdg" hash="kFjk1Q">The whole world is crying for help! Isn’t it thrilling to be a part of this significant surge forward! There must be rejoicing in the heavens as well. You and I have a commitment to be missionaries; and if that message isn’t clear, you haven’t been listening!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p35" pid="k0kT99CsaEOzSrT4rND0rw" hash="iGstYw">The largest segment of Heavenly Father’s family that needs our help is our kindred dead. To suppose that we as baptized members of the Church can turn away from our forebears is the surest way I know of becoming ineligible for the ultimate blessings we all seek so earnestly. The Prophet Joseph Smith recorded this in the 128th section of the Doctrine and Covenants as he wrote to the Church members in 1842 under the spirit and direction of the Lord:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p36" pid="YPHKHLo1fE26cuZ_jIWAgw" hash="WFUkEg">“And now, my dearly beloved brethren and sisters, let me assure you that these are principles in relation to the dead and the living that cannot be lightly passed over, as pertaining to our salvation. For their salvation is necessary and essential to our salvation, as Paul says concerning the fathers—that they without us cannot be made perfect—neither can we without our dead be made perfect.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/128.15" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 128:15</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p37" pid="JDp4yImefUaD-Nmyk9dUew" hash="9iPbkQ">We seek exaltation. To achieve that means perfection, and the direction is clear. We cannot be made perfect without our dead. We must seek them out; we must do for them that which they cannot do for themselves.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p38" pid="CU0Ghejgn0Gpj2afsaV2Xg" hash="L52c1w">Many of us are coasting along under the false illusion that now the computer and the microfilm will do it all for us! Though these modern methods are essential and helpful, no machine will ever be able to provide salvation for any man unless that man does what he must do himself. There are no shortcuts to exaltation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p39" pid="aiskuYqtNU2PRfI4WbrqRQ" hash="U9zeNQ">Brothers and sisters, save our dead? we must—such is our commitment. Carry the gospel to every nation, kindred, tongue and people? we must—such is our commitment. Be our brother’s keeper and teach one another? we must—such is our commitment. Learn our individual duty well and teach our families, as we overcome petty weaknesses? we must—for such is our commitment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p40" pid="ccxN-8YJ4kO8KC-8J8tJow" hash="zHZXew">Yes, it all starts right here with you and me and the commitment or vow that we have made with our Heavenly Father, for he said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p41" pid="w7l-Qf5pOkud8Ebq-eKStQ" hash="Xp1lWA">“When thou vowest a vow unto God, defer not to pay it; for he hath no pleasure in fools: pay that which thou hast vowed.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/eccl/5.4" class="scriptureRef">Eccl. 5:4</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things.p42" pid="mFRVaZCvvk6zz475eehBzg" hash="rhi88w">And this is my hope and prayer for all of us, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1976/04/these-four-things</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1976-general-conference/1976-04-4040-elder-robert-l-simpson-64k-eng.mp3" length="13165895" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1976 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Lord’s Support System</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1976/10/the-lords-support-system?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My beloved brothers and sisters, I sincerely pray that in this balcony and listening on the radio and on television there might be those who are serving in the Church as ward librarians, Primary teachers, ward clerks, stake clerks, those who don’t ha</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-lords-support-system" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03076_000_041" doc-version="3" hash="1_IjMg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-lords-support-system.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="Ge1wNZQ-8UCKoYaQsEdb9A" hash="PolKow">The Lord’s Support System</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="rQGAgn6dO02uPC3ULZiSEg" hash="_EZcfw">Robert L. Simpson</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-lords-support-system.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26ea.jpg" alt="Elder Robert L. Simpson" pid="Jyyu85DsakSD1W27MQ9Tdw" hash="6kp0Yg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-lords-support-system.p1" pid="1QtFRUL6bEKYUaT0z6BPHQ" hash="zx0c4g">My beloved brothers and sisters, I sincerely pray that in this balcony and listening on the radio and on television there might be those who are serving in the Church as ward librarians, Primary teachers, ward clerks, stake clerks, those who don’t have much opportunity to preside, but who love the Lord and love the work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-lords-support-system.p2" pid="aguA1_5uE0q4RXxWwkPIQA" hash="aO4GBw">One of the most devastating experiences of our space age is when a multi-billion-dollar space effort is on final countdown—only to be placed on “hold” due to a technical failure. Unless the problem can be identified and corrected within a very short time, the mission will need to be scrapped and perhaps rescheduled weeks later when the moon phase comes right again. The cost of that technical failure becomes astronomical in terms of manhours and money. It was reported on one such occasion that the malfunction turned out to be caused by a small transistor worth about thirty cents.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-lords-support-system.p3" pid="IVyi-1pWMUSf2qy_-NjmaA" hash="H0iyHw">Just as space probes depend upon tens of thousands of other lesser components in their so-called support system, so does the Lord depend upon tens of thousands in His support system, that His ultimate objective of blessing the lives of people and qualifying them for eternal life might be accomplished on schedule.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-lords-support-system.p4" pid="R_Q4fTVmKk6k-4x7P3esyA" hash="hE3LJQ">Today I would suggest a sincere tribute to the tremendous priesthood support system in operation throughout the Church, people in so-called “lesser” callings, individuals who carry on week after week, month after month without fanfare, and too often without even a simple “thank you.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-lords-support-system.p5" pid="tmyKBRGAGUSdW07MviAYLQ" hash="zGp50g">Today, may we say thanks to building custodians all over the Church who dust and dust, who sweep and sweep, who clean and clean; and there it is again the next Monday, the building in total disarray; and the process starts all over again, just as on every previous Monday. Money cannot buy the kind of love and devotion that is required to face those Monday mornings. Building custodians have strong testimonies like you and me. If they did not, they could not possibly face the awesome task of keeping our places of worship as they need to be at the appropriate hour. Without testimony, they could not remain pleasant when we perform a thoughtless act that adds to their burden.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-lords-support-system.p6" pid="8xcPuHMe7UCZYW5qQbdhFA" hash="pdWIFA">Oh that every ward and branch had greeters and ushers assigned for each worship service! Where members are so assigned and carry out their responsibilities properly, a reverential setting is assured. It can make such a difference when Saints are greeted at the door ever so cordially but in quiet, subdued tones, that each one might be reminded, that each one might begin to get in tune even before the meeting begins. We need more of that in the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-lords-support-system.p7" pid="M3zz9T_r6k2qo9zPIlaiug" hash="PIOu5g">As we wait for the service to begin, we must make the transition from worldly cares and concerns. May we pay tribute to a multitude of organists who play ever so softly the heavenly music that mellows the heart and brings a peace of mind compatible with the teachings we seek.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-lords-support-system.p8" pid="70PlpFXtpEu9xx287w3n7g" hash="cd4Jpw">We offer very little thanks to our teachers throughout the Church. Each good teacher spends hours in preparation—not minutes, but hours. Scriptural references and concepts are pondered. The right words need to be found. Then those right words need to come out modulated by the Spirit, for this church has always been taught, “If ye receive not the Spirit ye shall not teach.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/42.14" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 42:14</a>.) May we ever bless the name of those who convey the truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-lords-support-system.p9" pid="fLBCvsMsVka0e8e-kGS_PA" hash="xX4pkg">In one of Carol Lynn Pearson’s poems, she likens eternity to a school play. Reference is made to the unlikely persons who frequently receive the starring role and how they seem to invariably rise to the occasion and develop beyond expectation because of the confidence that someone has placed in them. I think Heavenly Father is a lot like that. Ours is a church of involvement. On a continuing basis, we are witnesses to those who have responded to a divine calling as we mumble to ourselves, “Why him? Why her?” A short time later, it is all too obvious, as we note the personal growth taking place—as hidden talents begin to develop. Were it not for the inspiration connected with a Church calling—if we were forced to use the yardstick of the world in measuring the potential of an individual—our progress would be greatly impaired, for it is true: “Where there is no vision, the people perish.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/29.18" class="scriptureRef">Prov. 29:18</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-lords-support-system.p10" pid="8u-VHUKOhEOdHUjLdjmvgw" hash="SomBtg">In the work of the Lord we don’t seek positions, nor should we refuse the opportunity to serve when called. The story is told of one good brother, obviously quite new in the Church. He was most eager to serve in the <span class="emphasis">front</span> ranks. Between conference sessions, he had the good fortune of shaking hands with President Hugh B. Brown and immediately asked, “President Brown, how does someone get to be a bishop in the Church?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-lords-support-system.p11" pid="It9VJSelvkmjySLiektL5w" hash="TIz9jQ">“Well,” answered President Brown, “the process is very simple. You just have to be invited by the Lord.” What a tremendous goal for every Latter-day Saint—to qualify in every way to be worthy of an invitation from the Lord, no matter what that calling may be.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-lords-support-system.p12" pid="Rkx4S9zGikOxVL8V4hKa1Q" hash="KX02Dw">Sister Pearson’s poem also makes allusion to the so-called spear carriers in the school drama. This church, like the school play, would indeed lose its savor without the “spear carriers,” those who make the scene complete although they all but lose themselves in the background. These are the faithful members who are so important and form the Lord’s support system in the greatest space probe of all time. Every great Church leader of today was a “spear carrier” yesterday. That is what eternal progress is all about. This divine process of human development is the very foundation of the gospel plan.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-lords-support-system.p13" pid="2X7omTIx-kW7vnY-xvQdvQ" hash="8NAcLQ">May we also pay tribute to thousands who have stepped back momentarily from the front ranks to pick up a spear for the final scenes, at least in this life. I know a former mission president who now serves willingly and capably as a ward clerk. A former stake president is now the deacons quorum advisor and is preparing young men for missions as they have never been prepared before. We reflect on one of the great observations of this dispensation: “It doesn’t matter where we serve, but <span class="emphasis">how</span> we serve.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-lords-support-system.p14" pid="LlP7RVNPB0SghvHbkaPfFQ" hash="koM0LA">Ask any parent how important a good Scoutmaster is. Ask any bishop how important his ward clerks are. Ask any teacher how indispensable the ward library staff is. It’s too bad we can’t ask someone who lived 300 years ago how important he thinks a genealogical researcher is.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-lords-support-system.p15" pid="tp6t9epef0ScwOIQDoOmzQ" hash="8Uvihw">Some of the more glamorous “spear carriers” in Heavenly Father’s army we call “counselors.” What a choice spirit these people have, always keeping themselves just a half step behind their file leader—always ready to express an opinion, ever willing to accept a final decision, even though that final decision be in a totally different direction.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-lords-support-system.p16" pid="5rD7M-rR10y7tYbKJEMRaQ" hash="TkFCUg">Gospel concepts as taught by the Savior are sometimes difficult for the mind of mortal man. You see, God’s ways are not man’s ways, and all of us need to learn that lesson well. I suppose some of what we have been talking about here today is involved in the divine truth that “the first shall be last, and that the last shall be first.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/29.30" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 29:30</a>.) There could be many surprises in the hereafter as we look up ahead and exclaim in our amazement, “But he was only a home teacher.” You know and I know that if he was the kind of home teacher that the handbook talks about and if he lived worthily, that man could likely stand eligible to inherit <span class="emphasis">all</span> that the Father has. And there is no greater blessing than that.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-lords-support-system.p17" pid="foI4vO3Quk-IO69kh39kuA" hash="3unNrw">It is also interesting to note that these brethren who sit behind me are bound by the exact same set of eternal standards as every other member of the Church. In that final judgment that is just and true, there will be one set of rules and one only—and God is no respecter of persons. And how significant that there is no private access to the scriptures. Holy writ is the same for the newest convert as for members of the First Presidency.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-lords-support-system.p18" pid="YZyE3b8Jj0WXSvF0hHn28Q" hash="-2_Mmg">To every “spear carrier” in the Church, we express a sincere <span class="emphasis">thank you</span> from the bottom of our hearts. Thank you for the way you carry out your responsibility for the Lord. Thank you for the support and sustaining influence that we feel as we visit among you. Without that support, there would be no Church organization as we know it today. People’s lives would not be blessed so abundantly.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/10/the-lords-support-system.p19" pid="7W77HJf11UKs-X23X9pKyw" hash="uV9GhQ">That we may all go forth willingly, effectively, full of faith, with an eye single to His glory is my prayer in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1976/10/the-lords-support-system</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1976-general-conference/1976-10-7030-elder-robert-l-simpson-64k-eng.mp3" length="4957071" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 1976 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The House of the Lord</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord?lang=eng</link>
      <description>During these few moments I would like to bear witness to the fact that God’s laws are anchored firmly and securely in place by eternal priesthood principle. Gospel truth stands as a pillar of peace, security, and freedom for all who would avail thems</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03128_000_006" doc-version="2" hash="QB9SIw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="B1LGZ28C0kKoMYWjwXY3MA" hash="JRUv6w">The House of the Lord</h1><p class="authorName" pid="a5xQsx_3NkajDgKCFTQZ2g" hash="_EZcfw">Robert L. Simpson</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26ea.jpg" alt="Elder Robert L. Simpson" pid="69xUigNfG0aJXsfRa5vDXg" hash="6kp0Yg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p1" pid="O-CriAz5WEWKYT3exADINQ" hash="U9B5Ew">During these few moments I would like to bear witness to the fact that God’s laws are anchored firmly and securely in place by eternal priesthood principle. Gospel truth stands as a pillar of peace, security, and freedom for all who would avail themselves. And I further attest that the ultimate in revealed truth, light, and eternal assurance is inseparably connected with the temple. Those sacred buildings are reverently and accurately referred to as the house of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p2" pid="s-k6DkzlBE-EVpAsz3yDog" hash="UiMwBg">A temple of God in this day and age? How can this be? Most God-fearing folks think only in terms of ancient temples built when prophets lived among the people more than two thousand years ago.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p3" pid="AQh5mYDIAECREXVYkl4Urw" hash="RcCO_g">Come with me inside the temple—a modern temple in our day; a temple that has been dedicated to the Lord, just as ancient temples were; a special building where sacred ordinances are performed by those who have been commissioned with appropriate, divine authority. The temple is indeed a house of quiet worship—everyone speaks softly, usually in whispers. All who participate dress in white. All who come have been found worthy and clean.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p4" pid="UQ46l-XR7ES8JmxRVYSBkw" hash="nb2LxA">The temple is a house of prayer, for Heavenly Father is glorified by every ordinance performed therein. He who enters for the first time receives a pronouncement of special blessings that are not available outside the temple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p5" pid="dJw3_1j8_kq0BUqZxGtBdw" hash="Q6a78Q">The temple is a house of instruction—yes, even divine instruction—about God’s eternal plan for his children. In the temple one gains a superior perspective about his personal relationship with his Maker and with the Savior—yes, special knowledge about God and Jesus Christ, which is essential to the obtaining of life eternal. “And this is life eternal, that they might know thee the only true God, and Jesus Christ, whom thou hast sent” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/17.3" class="scriptureRef">John 17:3</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p6" pid="eahxj0Edy0GSRT_SMEyMWQ" hash="BqTahw">The temple is a house of revelation—yes, continuing revelation. Whether that revelation be to a prophet or a member who seeks after truth, all who come to the temple seeking are continually taught and edified.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p7" pid="psWAQ1ejl0i2uZRnlT0yYw" hash="1tcsGw">The temple is a house of commitment and sacrifice, for it is truly stated that there can be no true worship without sacrifice; indeed, as the Saints sing, sacrifice brings forth the blessings of heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p8" pid="syaopV64Xk-IQSxOs5dvSA" hash="fQ50pQ">The temple is a house of solemn covenant where one appropriately commits himself to live a more Christlike life. Oh, that four billion people on earth could enter into that kind of covenant!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p9" pid="AHZ8lrC0h0OKqo2EW9mhRQ" hash="C4egTA">The temple is a house where young people are married for time and for all eternity. Thus, a common bond is formed, a bond that transcends the earthly pitfalls of misunderstanding, distrust, and, too often, divorce.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p10" pid="uAWURGV9rUqAJ9MeW7UWOA" hash="o1rgbA">The temple is a house of eternal relationships, a place where families can come for the purpose of transforming their family circle into an eternal family unit, where all of a sudden “together forever” becomes far more important than the next trivial family difference. You see, eternal families reason together in family council with dad at the head.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p11" pid="qCL2iL047kGpjAdD9HdjeQ" hash="NhaGyQ">The temple is a house of God where all of those declared worthy are extended the privilege of performing the sacred ordinances of the temple on behalf of their forebears, that in very deed the hearts of the children might be turned to their fathers, as foretold in the holy scriptures (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/mal/4.6" class="scriptureRef">Mal. 4:6</a>). Like all of Heavenly Father’s blessings for his children, the eventual realization is always on condition of faithfulness and conformity to priesthood principles.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p12" pid="E3Uo0Z21q0ingEIH6fBSwQ" hash="1ExAZA">The ultimate blessings of the temple are centered in the love and devotion between husband and wife. They must set the example—they are the core. The scriptures say it best of all: “Nevertheless neither is the man without the woman, neither the woman without the man, in the Lord” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/11.11" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 11:11</a>). Everything in this world that is counter to a tender and loyal husband-wife relationship is a tool of the adversary. Everything that promotes and perpetuates family unity—mother, father, and children properly endowed with and motivated by the light and truth of Christ—is in harmony with the Lord’s plan for mortal man.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p13" pid="Op0fIPgEbUqMKkyVql9Mjg" hash="zu2lig">Husbands, love your wives; wives, honor your husbands. Look to the gospel for all solutions to your problems; be a proper example to your children. That is where it all starts. The poet Longfellow expressed it well in these words:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="fKXL6-ljXUWuRaJhTxAL2Q" hash="5SWmmg">
            <span class="emphasis">“As unto the bow the cord is,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="AG2dJ0AO_kSMQ2AT3vaRHQ" hash="wRVKoQ">
            <span class="emphasis">So unto the man is woman;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="pawpKleey0GdL6R_6BYTrQ" hash="JRuK8Q">
            <span class="emphasis">Though she bends him, she obeys him,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="Fxqm2f8BD0yPxLqalZlmRw" hash="HD5pPA">&amp;gt;<span class="emphasis">Though she draws him, yet she follows;</span></p>
          <p class="line" pid="82QgM2KshkaGAF6IeSufeA" hash="BxkO8w">
            <span class="emphasis">Useless each without the other!”</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p14" pid="FWnIcTGUL0KLnSXJTYUH_g" hash="DFXXJw">These poetic phrases are in harmony with temple teachings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p15" pid="WbRET2N9_U2izfFoT9wnOw" hash="w7gyBg">Just hours after a disastrous flood in Idaho a few years ago, one man who had apparently lost every earthly possession wept bitterly. His despair was not so much over the temporal loss he had suffered, but rather, and far more important, his lovely wife and four children were unaccounted for and presumed drowned. But, within the hour good news came: his family had been miraculously saved and were waiting for him at a nearby emergency facility. The reunion that soon followed was a scene of supreme joy and happiness. His comment in the midst of the jubilation was classic: “I have my family again, and although I stand without one earthly possession left to my name, I feel like a millionaire.” Each family member nodded concurrence. For, you see, this family was a very special family; they had recently been sealed together for time and for all eternity in a temple of the living God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p16" pid="SfABp09QI0qqJMFv3yh-xw" hash="NX4uzQ">Just yesterday it was my special privilege to be present as a lovely young couple knelt at the altar of the temple. Each was dressed in robes of sparkling white. They were surrounded by a host of family and friends as these special words were spoken as part of the marriage covenant: “For time and for all eternity.” You see, such was the precise nature of their <span class="emphasis">forever</span> marriage.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p17" pid="MzE1Dddh6k-r1AP2iQz_MA" hash="qb8xmQ">Oh, that all people everywhere could be touched by this divine teaching of light and truth that makes such a union possible, not for just a select few, but for any and all of God’s children who might properly prepare themselves. But it must be done in <span class="emphasis">His</span> way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p18" pid="FYA8i48dtkeW4M0OlSC6oQ" hash="01rfTA">Eternal marriage is so sacred that it can only be performed within the walls of the temple, and only by those who have been endowed with proper, divine authority to bind or seal on earth that which will be bound in heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p19" pid="9fStPYlTxE-uOKA8fDEVRg" hash="ZZJS3Q">“Whatsoever you seal on earth shall be sealed in heaven; and whatsoever you bind on earth, in my name and by my word, saith the Lord, it shall be eternally bound in the heavens” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/132.46" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 132:46</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p20" pid="N3cGXo5WxkqZjUrTDw5qcg" hash="btoNIg">Now, let me introduce you to a group of twenty-five teenagers who have come to the temple at dawn to participate in the sacred ordinance of vicarious baptism. These young people had been found morally clean and worthy by their bishop. You see, bishops today are bound by the same guidelines as bishops of old, who were also taught: “Who shall ascend into the hill of the Lord? or who shall stand in his holy place? He that hath clean hands, and a pure heart; who hath not lifted up his soul unto vanity, nor sworn deceitfully.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/24.3-4" class="scriptureRef">Ps. 24:3–4</a>.) There has always been a standard in the house of the Lord: that standard is purity and cannot be compromised.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p21" pid="Qn0uLqb6Okm_geHJmjygUQ" hash="v7N_Fg">These teenagers come in a spirit of reverence with the desire to do something for others who have lived before. One teenage girl made this comment: “Being baptized by immersion for one of my ancestors, who lived in the 1700s, made me very proud. I felt that she was right there with me. I know she was pleased and accepted the work that I did for her.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p22" pid="LjWi3nrQPkOWjQEWv_Lo3A" hash="4uVGTQ">These teenagers were performing an ordinance that was practiced during Paul’s ministry, for he wrote to the Saints of Corinth: “Else what shall they do which are baptized for the dead, if the dead rise not at all? why are they then baptized for the dead?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/15.29" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 15:29</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p23" pid="j2U4hVsBIkCGFq2OKYDXzA" hash="v3hKLA">This vicarious work for the dead, which was obviously practiced during New Testament times as attested by Paul, was obviously an important ordinance taught by the Apostles of the Lord Jesus Christ following his crucifixion. Proof of this is found in Paul’s own words as he bears testimony to the Galatians: “But I certify you, brethren, that the gospel which was preached of me is not after man. For I neither received it of man, neither was I taught it, but by the revelation of Jesus Christ.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/gal/1.11-12" class="scriptureRef">Gal. 1:11–12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p24" pid="6h8UE6EwiUi5_jjyc7pU-w" hash="15YGLQ">Thousands work long hours in the temples to perform not only baptisms but other vicarious ordinances as well for those who had not the opportunity while in mortality. “If it were not so,” the scriptures attest, “the whole earth would be utterly wasted at his coming” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.39" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:39</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p25" pid="UaUjuLuD4UiAsad50cYWPg" hash="Ftspfg">The Savior had the power to provide immortality for the entire human race; we have the power to do vicarious work for only one at a time, but it is for the same glorious purpose and made possible by the same authority. Again, I quote the voice of the Lord: “For if you will that I give unto you a place in the celestial world, you must prepare yourselves by doing the things which I have commanded you and required of you” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/78.7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 78:7</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p26" pid="wZEskZYmzE2y3MPUhjPyYA" hash="3VYnyA">May I declare without apology that every living person should seek earnestly for the blessings of the temple as his ultimate goal. For there you will find peace; there you will come to know what security really is. There, in the house of the Lord, you can learn what you need to know to be truly free. There, tucked away from turmoil and strife, is the chance to be totally unselfish—a rarity in today’s world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p27" pid="_FskD4b6GUGz7m1CRJPuYg" hash="R1Jaww">I conclude with the loving counsel of the Savior, who said, “Therefore, fear not, little flock; do good; let earth and hell combine against you, for if ye are built upon my rock, they cannot prevail” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/6.34" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 6:34</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord.p28" pid="5ugrMNm3jkaLnT5dRpifNg" hash="h-2ktA">There is no foundation more secure than the temple. The work accomplished there transcends all other human effort. May we remove all obstacles to realize temple blessings; for I testify, He waits there for each of us, His children. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1980/10/the-house-of-the-lord</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1980-general-conference/1980-10-1040-elder-robert-l-simpson-64k-eng.mp3" length="5331915" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 1980 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Lasting Marriage</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My thoughts today are centered in the concern we all share over a growing crisis in today’s world, a sort of spreading cancer which continues to eat away at the family unit, which has been ordained of God.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03148_000_011" doc-version="2" hash="AiT-LA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="OcPbOafil0GFk5fdWDxGkA" hash="3ZPinA">A Lasting Marriage</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="3QElklpj0k6ogLS3wlD7RA" hash="_EZcfw">Robert L. Simpson</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26ea.jpg" alt="Elder Robert L. Simpson" pid="WQUdj3JWmEie8Fk_G6y-Ew" hash="6kp0Yg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p1" pid="6E1rRNZJZEuAUHgxdUn1aA" hash="x7ZFwA">My thoughts today are centered in the concern we all share over a growing crisis in today’s world, a sort of spreading cancer which continues to eat away at the family unit, which has been ordained of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p2" pid="g-Wdfnz8YEOh1DkkSh9_gg" hash="I_B2Sw">Divorce, with all of its diabolic side effects, threatens the very foundations of society. President Joseph F. Smith observed: “Marriage is the preserver of the human race. Without it, the purposes of God would be frustrated; virtue would be destroyed to give place to vice and corruption, and the earth would be void and empty.” (<span class="emphasis">Gospel Doctrine,</span> 5th ed., Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Company, 1939, p. 272.) Each prophet of this dispensation has said essentially the same thing in his own way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p3" pid="1xvxw1KKsUC39XvMqmBD9Q" hash="z9PB6g">According to data from the National Center for Health Statistics, nearly two million divorces are being granted this year in the United States. This is the highest number ever recorded and three times the number reported just twenty years ago. Most nations of the world seem to be following a similar trend. Today, more than one out of every three marriages is terminating in divorce. Families within the Church, unfortunately, are following this world pattern to an alarming degree, and it should not be so.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p4" pid="ulSiefNe40-aW4SY3SJmdw" hash="1jsG1Q">
        <span class="emphasis">U.S. News &amp; World Report</span> recently quoted Herbert A. Glieberman, a recognized authority on divorce and domestic relations, as follows: “The biggest rise in the divorce rate has been among couples married 10 years or longer. It’s not uncommon today for couples 25 and 30 years into their marriage to seek and obtain a divorce.” He then identifies the main cause:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p5" pid="MGJSkbazMUCsGmrgc7TrUQ" hash="x7hFwQ">“No. 1,” he states, “is the [couples’] inability to talk honestly with each other, bare their souls and treat each other as their best friend. … They [talk] about mostly superficial things in order to impress one another.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p6" pid="mshGBEW8uEiuGrp7rH92Nw" hash="xyKgcg">And then he continues, “I find that too many people talk right through each other rather than to each other.” He concludes: “The lack of communication brings on drinking, infidelity or physical or mental abuse. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p7" pid="cNRHAqHITUKHAuC5zBd_fg" hash="BhcyrA">“For many, there is a lack of tolerance, an inability to bear discomfort or to recognize that they’re not perfect and neither is their mate.” (“Why So Many Marriages Fail,” <span class="emphasis">U.S. News &amp; World Report,</span> 20 July 1981, pp. 53–54.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p8" pid="UeZYtJXiJEmwtZSPEqgxLw" hash="CZ_yOg">There is really only one way to ensure good family communication, and that is the Lord’s way. He advocates the council method.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p9" pid="dplJ-vuTH0-rjN9oof5SeA" hash="4PUvRA">The Church is made up of councils. Certainly, one of the most important of all Church councils must be the family council, presided over by the husband and the wife. In this council parents should stand equally yoked together, just as they are meant to share equally in every priesthood blessing that accrues to their family circle. Through the eternities the Lord’s eternal objective for a married couple is that they become one!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p10" pid="l0-owAciTkKU-KQcBcbQ8Q" hash="JRfFLQ">Next, the Lord instructs us to “reason together” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/50.10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 50:10</a>)—no arguing, no haranguing, no backbiting, but rather reasoning together with soft-spoken voices. What a great example for the children! How can a family go wrong if each major decision is carefully measured by gospel teachings? And then, after reasoning together, the decision can be made to move forward confidently and in harmony with divine law.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p11" pid="hO8r2eZVz0Ov34_a-GADaA" hash="2JyvHQ">The Savior taught the extra mile (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.41" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:41</a>), which means unselfishness. By just going the extra mile almost every couple could make their marriage relationship successful. But an extra effort on just one side of the boat means imbalance, and a capsized marriage is likely. Unselfishness must come from both sides.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p12" pid="dLhacuUqJEicTEDLIiTgIw" hash="k9JdOw">Every couple, whether in the first or the twenty-first year of marriage, should discover the value of pillow-talk time at the end of the day—the perfect time to take inventory, to talk about tomorrow. And best of all, it’s a time when love and appreciation for one another can be reconfirmed. The end of another day is also the perfect setting to say, “Sweetheart, I am sorry about what happened today. Please forgive me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p13" pid="mCY1mVKnkU-9rUPLMDMg3A" hash="0jDx3A">You see, we are all still imperfect, and these unresolved differences, allowed to accumulate day after day, add up to a possible breakdown in the marital relationship—all for the want of better communication, and too often because of foolish pride.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p14" pid="O_PdyfX5xEamlo9S8rt2Fg" hash="VgmMfg">The Church has always taken a firm stand against dictatorships of any form. Any man who chooses to administer the office of his calling as a priesthood leader in the home by dictatorial methods is out of harmony with gospel teaching. He will not enjoy the spiritual rewards of reasoning together. His pillow talk will cease to be a two-way communication, and rebellion will usually follow.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p15" pid="dM76gbTVRU6q7l4hDFSr8g" hash="GGQTrQ">Dictators are always quick to issue an ultimatum; and in case you have not discovered, an ultimatum to today’s youth is almost guaranteed failure. It is the equivalent of waving a red flag; it is like declaring war on those you love.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p16" pid="06aBZ4G5lEKBxGN0Q1cp1g" hash="Rld_ow">The Lord warns us that “no power or influence can or ought to be maintained by virtue of the priesthood, only by persuasion, by long-suffering, by gentleness and meekness, and by love unfeigned:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p17" pid="HA-ZFvdlt0ixfDzaVAsGgQ" hash="KXlapw">“By kindness, and pure knowledge, which shall greatly enlarge the soul without hypocrisy, and without guile.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.41-42" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:41–42</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p18" pid="25rbo4l0eUWCS1bTOOcF8Q" hash="06RTtQ">I like the advice given by President Joseph F. Smith. He said this to fathers: “It is only when men depart from the right spirit, when they digress from their duty, that they will neglect or dishonor any soul that is committed to their care. They are bound to honor their wives and children.” (<span class="emphasis">Gospel Doctrine,</span> p. 285.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p19" pid="leEdJzHAbE2UROoRPo1d-Q" hash="6SALHA">There is yet another major cause for divorce that should not go unattended: the mismanagement of family financial resources. To pay tithes and offerings while ignoring the balance of Heavenly Father’s advice concerning sound judgment in family finances will probably cause the windows of heaven to stick a little bit. The promised blessings will not likely be forthcoming as expected.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p20" pid="ofIZoIET2UygEJb1jfIx4Q" hash="iN6KPQ">Every prophet in this dispensation has taught in clear, unmistakable terms that the Saints should stay out of debt (we heard it again this morning from President Kimball), that we should not participate in “something-for-nothing” schemes, which has been stressed today. He advises us to be frugal, to save, and to earn our money the old-fashioned way, by the sweat of our face. We are admonished to teach our children the ethic of work. We have been encouraged at every turn to set the proper example of industry and thrift and also to be generous and consistent in our offerings to the poor and the needy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p21" pid="6GPj01a6h0eu3skrIcLSQg" hash="JUn33g">During these days of a strained economy it is imperative that the family live within these divine injunctions. Each husband and wife needs to reason together about the family budget on a regular basis. If downward adjustments need to be made in the family spending habits, it is far better to do what needs to be done now rather than build up to an impossible financial crisis later on—a crisis that too often leads to the divorce courts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p22" pid="o5KoD4lfh0mjdYX_vA4uZQ" hash="zGEhkw">Few things are as destructive in a marriage as the statement, “Sweetheart, I just signed up today for a $200 course at the local health spa.” A well-planned health course may be just the thing, but not as a surprise addition to an already strained budget. This could have been and should have been a prime topic for pillow talk beforehand. As Elder Neal A. Maxwell told us so well recently, “If your companion is going to participate in a crash landing, then she should also help file the flight plan.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p23" pid="nquZ5WCLcUmSz9NbfKc1EA" hash="FNvWLA">Now, quickly, just to mention three items as foundation stones to a secure marriage:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p24" pid="AT07rzwmSkOrb3fS-mFm_A" hash="PVvIPA">First: <span class="emphasis">faith,</span> the first principle of the gospel. It must be the first principle of your marriage—not only faith in God and in His beloved Son, not only in the living prophet, but, may I also suggest, a sincere and ever-growing faith in each other, and also in your children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p25" pid="QUAg7nlXLE6G_DmaLVx5dQ" hash="OZzQ9g">Second: <span class="emphasis">obedience,</span> often referred to as the first law of heaven. Without obedience to God’s laws there could be no blessings. Obedience to our covenants with the Lord is a prerequisite to peace and love within the family circle.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p26" pid="t2cDtaqzIUqeObIbt_9KBg" hash="zmzP9Q">Third: <span class="emphasis">loyalty.</span> Loyalty to a companion through thick and thin will develop a basic character trait so strong that loyalty to the Church and true principles will follow just as naturally as the night follows the day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p27" pid="OvYtIpS0PkSiqbvqDxj4-g" hash="fRRu0Q">The law of chastity is one of the Ten Commandments. This demands loyalty in marriage. Brothers and sisters, protect this sacred principle as though your life depended upon it, because gospel truth confirms that your eternal life most certainly does depend upon fidelity in your marriage.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p28" pid="5XqbCqxN_keoaY9aImQ4pg" hash="TaM-JQ">The scriptures confirm the eternal truth that “marriage is ordained of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/49.15" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 49:15</a>.) And then this: “Neither is the man without the woman, neither the woman without the man, in the Lord.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/11.11" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 11:11</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p29" pid="jxjjVYPIkkm7nDETS6pfEw" hash="7sa_DQ">And according to a prophet in this dispensation, “God not only commends but he commands marriage. While man was yet immortal, before sin had entered the world, our heavenly Father himself performed the first marriage. He united our first parents in the bonds of holy matrimony, and commanded them to be fruitful and multiply and replenish the earth. This command he has never changed, abrogated or annulled; but it has continued in force throughout all the generations of mankind.” (Smith, <span class="emphasis">Gospel Doctrine,</span> p. 274.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p30" pid="Py-On1yaiE2sCqMoXFGSrw" hash="7aja_A">Mark confirms: “What therefore God hath joined together, let not man put asunder.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/10.9" class="scriptureRef">Mark 10:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p31" pid="cp3KOg5UG0WBWv53dNPhJg" hash="hSgoPw">Now, brothers and sisters, every divorce in the Church affects the work of the kingdom adversely. There needs to be greater effort on the part of each companion threatened by divorce. There needs to be more counseling, not only one with another, but also with appropriate priesthood leaders. There needs to be a more universal understanding about the eternal nature of the marriage covenant.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p32" pid="nfoG2iUreEK0kWd-NwQ4cQ" hash="eVIdgQ">Time and experience have proven that unselfishness is the key to successful marriage, for, you see, unselfishness invites reasoning together.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p33" pid="t3I6IK_Yj0Wi-Y6JMwMlRA" hash="RK2heQ">Unselfishness insists on an extra-mile effort.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p34" pid="IudcCR_OI0mAGL0WNTpILA" hash="q_Dmcg">Unselfishness paves the way for family financial security.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p35" pid="rALQ69J4H0ujppsGu5WvWA" hash="NLP6xw">Unselfishness stops divorce.</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.f2">
	<p pid="cEWHuSEwfkC22XGY9EjChA" hash="SNwHug">And don’t you agree that perhaps the most important questions that will need to be answered by a divorced person in the hereafter will be these:</p>
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="F6Msp2v4wk2Mmh-AvKDGNg" hash="aVen8A">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="8BZTmUlA6UWf25bkI_Gt5A" hash="fxyDnQ">“Did you do everything possible to save your marriage?”</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="yyuhjqGhyUmM6C-nYjGeMA" hash="Mc-EBw">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="1jQ8WYTcHkyZ-0ZPR6h3lw" hash="7cRW2A">“Were gospel truths applied to the fullest?”</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="UIYwWYSmIUuIyy06z7KKQg" hash="upGSyQ">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="GXj5afvia0WN9m2PhPA-mw" hash="7o4aww">“Did you seek out, listen to, and abide by priesthood counsel?”</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p36" pid="JVhzWlezJUKr7OQDifwWUQ" hash="kLbNLg">May He bless us to regard every marriage as an act ordained of God; for, as President Joseph F. Smith said, it is the hope of the human race.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage.p37" pid="MH7Nxd7IMU6pwG7k7SUkCA" hash="fiZmwQ">And these thoughts I leave with you in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1982/04/a-lasting-marriage</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1982-general-conference/1982-04-2040-elder-robert-l-simpson-64k-eng.mp3" length="5851504" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 1982 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Simplicity of Gospel Truths</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Yesterday morning Elder Durham introduced his theme by quoting a bumper sticker message. From a graffiti wall in Los Angeles comes this one: “You can beam me up now, Scotty. I find no evidence of intelligent life down here.”</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03174_000_027" doc-version="2" hash="QzFNWw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="v9Plhqe8r0C4mJV2awdgLQ" hash="8yyEcw">The Simplicity of Gospel Truths</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="MdMTg7D5VEenFuQlVKTNiw" hash="_EZcfw">Robert L. Simpson</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26ea.jpg" alt="Elder Robert L. Simpson" pid="0E-rmJrWFk6okaMCPSrkIw" hash="6kp0Yg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p1" pid="kqJp24AgY0Wg1goJIIpT8w" hash="8_BMIw">Yesterday morning Elder Durham introduced his theme by quoting a bumper sticker message. From a graffiti wall in Los Angeles comes this one: “You can beam me up now, Scotty. I find no evidence of intelligent life down here.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p2" pid="PpQZkr7V2kSN3HC7TJZ8vQ" hash="nGC3NQ">Now, brothers and sisters, there is indisputable evidence of intelligent life down here because, thank goodness, Heavenly Father has told us that “the glory of God is intelligence, or in other words, light and truth.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/93.36" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 93:36</a>.) Those who accept and live the simple light and truth of the gospel are indeed living an intelligent life. And that theme—of simple light and truth—which I would like to share with you this morning, was brought to my attention while serving as a young missionary under President Matthew Cowley, later to become an Apostle of the Lord. He taught us on frequent occasion that “the gospel of Jesus Christ is beautifully simple and simply beautiful.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p3" pid="FlAY2wiAzEao8rCn4CAPgg" hash="zhmIbw">The truth of that statement was reamplified earlier this year as some of our family and a few friends had the privilege of walking where Jesus walked. We marveled at the city of Old Jerusalem. Shepherds were still tending their flocks near Bethlehem. We strolled along those very same paths on the Mount of Olives. Then, after traveling north, we beheld peaceful Galilee. What had transpired here two thousand years ago suddenly took on rich, new meaning, as we paused to reread and ponder anew each appropriate scripture reference along the way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p4" pid="km5KPz6DHkygPRn1LM7JqQ" hash="aXrmSg">The “living water” that Jesus talked about at Jacob’s well with the woman from Samaria became current and real. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/4.10" class="scriptureRef">John 4:10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p5" pid="kMVV3ZXWZkWt1Xw6fShtCA" hash="tJftZA">There were tears as we stood in Gethsemane and pondered again those immortal words: “Father, if thou be willing, remove this cup from me: nevertheless not my will, but thine, be done.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/22.42" class="scriptureRef">Luke 22:42</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p6" pid="Ch3nqsxkMESfCI_ub9LH5g" hash="9-1lGQ">Also that simple but profound teaching at Calvary: “Father, forgive them; for they know not what they do.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/23.34" class="scriptureRef">Luke 23:34</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p7" pid="0qDniuPUuU6JYa9NFBnCfQ" hash="ewuZNg">As we stood by beautiful Galilee, we marveled at the simplicity of His unique but meaningful invitation to those being called. “Follow me,” he said, “and I will make you fishers of men.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/4.19" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 4:19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p8" pid="jun9rrzgSkyjfqtyHWcbYA" hash="AtP5fA">Such quotes are typical of the Master Teacher, He who taught pure and plain truth, spoken in humility and with beautiful simplicity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p9" pid="ySBH6exGSEiG72-KJlnOHQ" hash="cGjgBw">This reawakening to the superb teachings of the Savior while we were in Israel was most reassuring. How simple and pure are the concepts he left us. Indeed, Paul held the same view as he wrote to the Saints of Corinth, “For God is not the author of confusion, but of peace.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/14.33" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 14:33</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p10" pid="UKxb-68_lk2jjGNFzhIn7w" hash="ycEptQ">James said it another way: “But the wisdom that is from above is first pure, then peaceable, gentle, and easy to be entreated, full of mercy.” (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/james/3.16-17" class="scriptureRef">James 3:16–17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p11" pid="X9roWIq6M0yo_B8rJjkmmA" hash="rav-Fg">Indeed Elder Cowley was right: the gospel of Jesus Christ is beautifully simple and simply beautiful. Even simple enough that a Primary child can have a good idea of gospel basics by the time of that eighth birthday and the privilege of baptism comes along.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p12" pid="js4tTZhwdEGNgTgMTgueSg" hash="jochFA">The faith of children was the center of some of the Savior’s most significant teachings. Remember that occasion recorded in Matthew when the disciples asked him, “Who is the greatest in the kingdom of heaven? (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/18.1-4" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 18:1–4</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p13" pid="592PnSOmFkiv4Jv7xoN9-w" hash="iOmpoA">“And Jesus called a little child unto him.” (I can just see the Savior as he tenderly lifted that child onto his knee in order to lend power to that teaching moment.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p14" pid="E2UdYGQvHki71HBe8ZdVTA" hash="x9a00A">Then he answered them: “Verily I say unto you, Except ye be converted, and become as little children, ye shall not enter into the kingdom of heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p15" pid="Zm2glKlXHUSqYaD4GLYmGA" hash="OzMLzw">“Whosoever therefore shall humble himself as this little child, the same is greatest in the kingdom of heaven.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/18.1-4" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 18:1–4</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p16" pid="Q4CLTLyJZkiIpcsPB08YrA" hash="DWxmlg">Without doubt the Savior had in mind the implicit faith and sincerity of a little child as he answered his disciples on that occasion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p17" pid="VLXJl9i8T02zPF_gnP2UFA" hash="ZDvJ2g">Perhaps we should all take heed as we listen to our children pray. I remember well Elder Monson’s story yesterday. When our daughter, Christine, was still very young she was always invited to take her turn praying in the family circle. We as a family always prayed that we might be a healthy family. Some of her words came with difficulty. She couldn’t say “healthy,” and it always came out, “Bless us, Heavenly Father, to be a wealthy family.” That sounded good to me—we just let her go on like that—but Heavenly Father knew what she meant, and wealth has eluded us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p18" pid="sDoQoxhUQkykPefWv2Vi6Q" hash="9gXvkA">That wise and noble prophet and teacher King Benjamin taught his people about putting off the natural man and becoming a Saint through the atonement of Christ the Lord. Then he added that we must become as a child, “submissive, meek, humble, patient, full of love, willing to submit to all things … , even as a child doth submit to his father.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/3.19" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 3:19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p19" pid="0D2p2AQ6X0qFBgttNDqL9g" hash="MzVX0g">We have always been taught that the gospel of Jesus Christ embraces all truth, wherever that truth is found. This should also include truth found in science. The simplicity of basic truth in the fields of chemistry and physics has always intrigued me. For example, there is the simple expression that H<unknown name="sub">2</unknown>O is the chemical formula for water. Also fascinating is the fact that Einstein could express his mind-expanding theory of relativity by the simple equation E = mc<sup>2</sup>. It almost appears that the closer we approach a basic truth, the more simply it can be expressed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p20" pid="SPjNvcL22U2e2s7qTbXqEQ" hash="sGk-GA">The best example of this in religious truth is perhaps the oft-repeated scriptural passage found in Moses in the Pearl of Great Price, wherein God states in a single sentence the total objective of all eternity: “For behold, this is my work and my glory—to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.39" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:39</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p21" pid="aqmMjLu55Ue2XZH0cOQnsw" hash="hsjjvg">Imagine, just twenty words to summarize the entire plan of eternal progression and salvation. I like that, because it is true. The statement is fundamental; it makes perfect sense. It isn’t superfluous; it establishes a goal by which everyone can achieve success. All of Heavenly Father’s children become candidates for exaltation, and in the process Deity is glorified by our success.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p22" pid="wNgHxlW9DUyZJIV4ps1K5w" hash="BiTgkQ">Most eternal truths are so simply stated that no one should misunderstand them, except perhaps a few like those of Jacob’s day who “despised the words of plainness, and killed the prophets, and sought for things that they could not understand.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/jacob/4.14" class="scriptureRef">Jacob 4:14</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p23" pid="bnkqFGIKU0C5qUns03pvOQ" hash="5f43ww">Please consider for a moment these simple gospel truths, which are paraphrased in the interest of time:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p24" pid="aGUnkwTQPkepRPUBCIpy3g" hash="NoY2vw">The contribution of tithes and offerings will open the windows of heaven. (See <a href="/scriptures/ot/mal/3.10" class="scriptureRef">Mal. 3:10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p25" pid="vVKvdDWVrk-DkuMj8-dmag" hash="tfNKTw">Conformity to the Word of Wisdom ensures better health, wisdom, and well-being. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/89.title" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 89</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p26" pid="Qky90tiT3UqRHbUW9PbkEQ" hash="euzypA">Confession to one’s priesthood authority and then doing the sin no more can provide total repentance for all who are willing. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.43" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:43</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p27" pid="hyNkqO9KQEm-40M4WGnMmA" hash="zwak5Q">“Is any sick among you? let him call for the elders of the church.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/5.14" class="scriptureRef">James 5:14</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p28" pid="pGcF_dbmu0ySXTqKMZ-gkQ" hash="qon8mg">A celestial glory can be the reward for all who repent, are baptized, and continue in faith. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/18.22" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 18:22</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p29" pid="cCQ07kBIzEGF5bj2gJplEg" hash="6zhmUQ">As Paul declared so firmly and simply, “One lord, one faith, one baptism.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/4.5" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 4:5</a>.) Nothing has ever been able to alter these simple truths.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p30" pid="I099UIU_xEm7PK9EvXSPaA" hash="gFOQ3Q">And finally one of my very favorites: “And the truth shall make you free.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/8.32" class="scriptureRef">John 8:32</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p31" pid="33RIoJuxtUuMJU18riYTdA" hash="tfK9Iw">Everyone wants to be free—free from guilt, free from selfishness, free from the bondage of bad habit. Yes, even political freedom is possible through God’s plan of simple truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p32" pid="fsSNiz678U6S9sIJMut6sA" hash="Q30yrQ">But, of course, all of the foregoing about the importance of simplicity and plainness would be meaningless unless the end result were joy and fulfillment for Heavenly Father’s children. How thrilling it is to observe newly baptized Church members who have caught the Spirit—to see them respond to the gospel plan and, through their obedience to simple teachings, reap the promised blessings. This is especially apparent in so-called developing areas of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p33" pid="9slCIPvV3ESUmYwNA5ocNA" hash="kvn2fA">Oh, that I could take each of you to Coimbatore, India, to meet with more than one hundred members of the Church who live in the most meager of all circumstances. They possess hardly any of this world’s goods. Some days there is not enough food. Most have little or no education, but their lives have been changed for the better in a very short period of time through the restored gospel of Jesus Christ. Their general health level is improved; more are now attending school. They are singing the songs of Zion with enthusiasm, and they are smiling much more than before. They have found hope. These are deprived people being taught simple truths about the Savior. The gospel is not complicated. They can comprehend it, and they’re responding to it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p34" pid="hleYwXOTJ0qHkzE8l5ue8g" hash="e_M1gg">As we met with them recently in their little one-room meetinghouse (with a clean dirt floor, I might add), they seemed so anxious and eager to be taught. Curious neighbors could not resist the urge to linger nearby while meetings were in progress. They watched through open windows and through the open doorway. We were impressed by the contrast of those inside and those looking in. It was evident that gospel teaching had influenced not only the spirit that the members radiated, but also such things as personal hygiene, grooming, personal attitude, and a countenance that reflected a new-found something that was indeed beautifully simple and simply beautiful.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p35" pid="OKDpsJycuUmsL-cT4Sv2lg" hash="I4jEag">Few are aware of the pure Christian service being administered at refugee camps in Thailand and in the Philippines by our missionary sisters. Basically, these sisters are restricted to teaching the English language and Western culture, but there is a deeper teaching that takes place through their pure love and sweet attitude toward these displaced people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p36" pid="eLvMsgszpUmFs7ytaZQB5A" hash="oisXjA">The story is told of a young camp refugee from Cambodia who was relocated in California. He found his way into one of our Church meetinghouses because the name of the Church on the sign out front corresponded with the one he used to look at each day on the name tag of the wonderful missionary sister who taught him at the camp. People don’t soon forget acts of simple kindness. Pure love can transcend all differences.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p37" pid="oYnkiPtxzE61PshpugpGXQ" hash="HN23AQ">Yes, the Spirit giveth light in this church. I am thinking of a wonderful new convert in England. In response to my asking, he told me about his conversion. He explained how he was kneeling at his flower bed on a Saturday morning preparing the soil for spring planting. All of a sudden an unseen voice from behind asked the simple question, “Sir, do you love the Lord?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p38" pid="Df9ksV6bVUia8q0xtLHaxQ" hash="P-n1Uw">He said that he turned around, fully, expecting to see an angel standing there; instead there were two angels, two Mormon missionaries. And his response was, “Of course I love the Lord. Please come in the house so we can talk about it.” It was all so simple, so genuine. It was an approach that the Savior might have used.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p39" pid="5s44trDNsUiaxPSWdzEvng" hash="z_Ju2g">Not long ago a young American woman living in Taiwan felt that her taxi driver was taking her the long way around in order to increase the fare. She was in the process of venting her feelings in unmistakable terms when the young Chinese driver, obviously hurt by the accusation, stopped the cab, turned off the ignition, then turned around and said simply, “I would not do that. I am a Mormon.” Calmed down and totally disarmed by the sincerity of his statement, she then asked what a Mormon was. She obviously found out, as she joined the Church just three weeks later. It all happens so simply when the honest in heart are involved.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths.p40" pid="oWIa-ft3cEivYGzXF1jFuA" hash="fc_G2Q">Nephi, in foretelling the ministry of the Apostle John, described his teachings as “plain and pure, and most precious and easy to the understanding of all men.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/14.23" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 14:23</a>.) That our understanding and interpretation of truth may always be beautifully simple and simply beautiful is my sincere prayer for each of us, in the name of Jesus Christ, our Savior and Redeemer, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1984/04/the-simplicity-of-gospel-truths</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1984-general-conference/1984-04-4040-elder-robert-l-simpson-64k-eng.mp3" length="6815993" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 1984 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No Shortcuts</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My beloved Brethren, and you wonderful young men of the Aaronic Priesthood, I just can’t tell you how good you look. It’s wonderful to see you here, wonderful that you’ve met your appointment with the Lord in this important priesthood meeting.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03213_000_017" doc-version="2" hash="bXMRYg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="JhV3wTF-30iY6V8O-U0FwQ" hash="_RaqtA">No Shortcuts</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="wDTcSWPaokC2FWoodLXM3g" hash="_EZcfw">Robert L. Simpson</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26ea.jpg" alt="Elder Robert L. Simpson" pid="FQIugXzCPEWL1YTPKNyRPg" hash="6kp0Yg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p1" pid="bdS_u2DinUG5SvcTTWGWxg" hash="t9zYMg">My beloved Brethren, and you wonderful young men of the Aaronic Priesthood, I just can’t tell you how good you look. It’s wonderful to see you here, wonderful that you’ve met your appointment with the Lord in this important priesthood meeting.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p2" pid="pn0cMIdd80yG9lF82zT1KA" hash="GWOdlw">Where would we be without the faith of youth? I’m thinking of a boy named David in the Old Testament. I’m thinking of a young lad named Nephi in Book of Mormon history. I’m thinking of a young, fifteen-year-old named Joseph Smith, who had faith and who became the head of this dispensation. I’m so grateful for the zeal of youth and the faith and the discernment of youth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p3" pid="-cqnv4tS5kCB-Qx3RRwpUA" hash="7F_inw">One short story: a preacher finally came to the point where he felt that he had enough faith to walk on water. And so he sent the word out to all the land, and people came from far and near. There were thousands there. But right in the front row was a deacon from the LDS church. He had great interest in this kind of faith. He’d heard about it in Sunday School and in family home evening, and he was on the front row, not fifteen feet away.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p4" pid="7AimLmNz-UCxDMSJBL1WbQ" hash="6Sbm-g">As the preacher walked up to the water, he paused momentarily and as he bent down to roll up his trousers the boy said, “Mister, you’ll never make it.” And he didn’t.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p5" pid="lKMwyLUUEUOIml5e5Fe5jQ" hash="-e_02Q">Recently I was impressed by a group of teenage Aaronic Priesthood holders who were assembled together with their bishops and advisers for an informal gospel discussion. It was a small, relaxed gathering, just to talk things over, to reason together. By the initial comments and greetings, it became obvious that each young man respected his bishop and had appreciation for the quorum advisers. It was also clear from their comments that they loved the Lord. But with all of this, there were still some who were struggling and wondering about a few things. Three main concerns came out of the discussion that morning. First, the question: “Why does life have to be so hard?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p6" pid="BWZ_DzFZI0K45c43wqvxOw" hash="WcBZ6g">A little later, a boy about fifteen years of age, obviously worried about some mounting peer pressure at school, commented, “I am not so sure it’s worth it all.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p7" pid="pHaaJNRRe0yyfhpJD8qBFw" hash="2Wb8_Q">And finally this—they all wanted to know, “How can I be certain that the Church is true?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p8" pid="ya0nui8txU-ozeco2IHDlA" hash="6EJduA">These questions are not new. They are as old as man. Nor are they reserved for just a few. I doubt that there is even one in this vast congregation that has not been faced with these same recurring questions through the years.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p9" pid="6zrcJ-J0RUOSSa6ZGporcA" hash="si8Zcw">Let’s start with the first question about life being hard. I like what one of the seminary students said. He commented, “Life here in mortality is no different from the explanation we received in the premortal existence.” He went on, “According to our Sunday School teacher, we shouted for joy and not only agreed to come to earth but literally clamored for the opportunity.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p10" pid="B-EGbu48qkiBVhX7Yh10uQ" hash="b-L3Yw">One of the advisers turned to a scripture to show how the Lord is always there to help us over the rough spots if we do our part.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p11" pid="qXmCBJxBh0eibWhESUprEQ" hash="tWYCLw">He read: “Behold, I stand at the door, and knock,” said the Savior. “If any man hear my voice, and open the door, I will come in to him, and will sup with him, and he with me” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rev/3.20" class="scriptureRef">Rev. 3:20</a>). Did you catch the point, young men, that it is up to us to open the door? I think the Savior gives us another vital key as He declares, “For without me ye can do nothing” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/15.5" class="scriptureRef">John 15:5</a>). That’s powerful!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p12" pid="CDmnFFEFHUytenodQcO9sw" hash="UI0WNg">Remember the next comment? “I am not sure if it is worth it all.” One of the bishops was quick to ask this question: “Do you think it would be worth it to some day become eligible to receive all that the Father has?” He went on to remind us that to receive all that the Father has is the very essence of the oath and covenant of the priesthood. Let’s reread together those words given us in the eighty-fourth section of the Doctrine and Covenants with regard to that sacred obligation, an obligation that we all share alike. Please listen carefully. I’m going to start with the thirty-third verse:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p13" pid="A6dV2YMfEUeQ5nQQolprRA" hash="d3krkA">“For whoso is faithful unto the obtaining these two priesthoods of which I have spoken, and the magnifying their calling, are sanctified. …”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p14" pid="scjpnU4i90O8jVj8ancuRg" hash="HC6KLw">And then skipping down to the thirty-eighth verse:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p15" pid="vVTURMRUXUKZ9QIP7XEvXg" hash="gIjG3g">“And he that receiveth my Father receiveth my Father’s kingdom; therefore all that my Father hath shall be given unto him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p16" pid="g8SZopRxc0Kjtdsq9gYifg" hash="rXg_xg">“And this is according to the oath and covenant which belongeth to the priesthood” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.33,38-39" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:33, 38–39</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p17" pid="SOp9857ikEqSSfh_yOrLJQ" hash="lVRXVQ">My young friends, please realize that these conditions that we just read are set. They have all been affirmed. We have already had priesthood authority conferred upon us. The Lord has promised a guaranteed destiny for all who magnify that priesthood; and that destiny is eternal life, which, according to scripture, is the greatest of all the gifts (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/14.7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 14:7</a>). Because we have been ordained, we are on our way. Not only are we on our way, but it looks like we have reached the point of no return, for the Savior assures us that this is an oath and covenant of the Father “which he cannot break, neither can it be moved” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.40" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:40</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p18" pid="tey9CSAmNUmUItc6CyCvAg" hash="uQoxTA">Let me interject an interesting little sidelight. As we read that last scripture concerning the oath and covenant that cannot be broken and neither can it be moved, one of the lads said, “Hey, where is my free agency in all of this?” A boy who had just been ordained a priest then spoke up: “We exercised our free agency in the premortal existence; people agree to baptism before they are baptized; we choose to renew the baptismal covenant each week during the sacrament service; we agreed to the conditions of the priesthood during the bishop’s interview. No,” he concluded, “I don’t think our free agency has been violated.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p19" pid="Zixwzu7yykKBcMRd6NTUQA" hash="iqobFw">He was right. There has not been a violation of our free agency.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p20" pid="elvN_f5XIkG9uloCDQROjQ" hash="4bIQZw">I would hope that no one who has taken upon himself the sacred covenant of the priesthood would ever throw his hands up, walk away, and say, “I’m sorry, it’s just too difficult.” Nephi had problems galore: Laman, Lemuel, Laban, and so on down the list. But he realized in his hour of need that all the forces of heaven were available to him. Remember when he declared, “I will go and do the things which the Lord hath commanded, for I know that the Lord giveth no commandments unto the children of men, save he shall prepare a way for them that they may accomplish the thing which he commandeth them” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/3.7" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 3:7</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p21" pid="oZncTKmdgU2_-78gs0fxZw" hash="9Nf8qg">At this point, one of the young deacons quipped, “Yeah, but Nephi didn’t have to go to my school.” He was telling us that his problem was just about as big as Nephi’s but in a little different way. And he may be right, but the point is this: the Lord didn’t forsake Nephi. He didn’t forsake the Prophet Joseph Smith in Liberty Jail. And he won’t forsake a boy with peer pressure at school or with any other problem.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p22" pid="rx_Cvd-Z4EyyTeepOiA3hw" hash="ZeZRww">All of us who are to stand prepared for the great blessings associated with this priesthood authority that is ours must be sanctified from time to time by whatever process the Lord has in mind. Just as surely as we are assembled here, whether a General Authority, a bishop, an elder, a deacon, the process is exactly the same. We must try to understand that when adversity comes, it is likely a means of preparing us for something ahead. Yes, it’s worth it. Believe me, young men, it’s worth it all.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p23" pid="faLJdc6s702eIOxhmpJecQ" hash="fYf6Mw">Now the third great question: “How can we be certain that the Church is true?” Can anyone gain a so-called perfect testimony here in mortality? I think all of us here are still in the never-ending process of a developing testimony. Youth of Zion, forget about receiving a miracle, or the so-called sure sign from heaven. There are no shortcuts to eternity. Thus, extreme patience becomes another key factor as we develop our testimony over a lifetime. It is simply “line upon line, precept upon precept; here a little, and there a little,” just as the scriptures say (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/128.21" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 128:21</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p24" pid="TkBfQs7PhUGm1T23JQNEoQ" hash="W-IyEg">There are basic principles that never change in the development of a testimony.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p25" pid="2I_AsGmXHkK8Mws4YqJ3Lw" hash="_D8rOQ">Let’s use the Book of Mormon as an example. The great promise found in Moroni 10:4, [<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.4" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 10:4</a>] with which we are all familiar, states that we must read the book—then ask Heavenly Father about it with a sincere heart, with faith in Christ. Then He says when we have done this, the truth will be manifest to us by the power of the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p26" pid="fInttLlmMU6fCJj08ceV_Q" hash="vY_UYA">Now, whether it be a testimony about the Book of Mormon, tithing, the Word of Wisdom, the law of the fast, keeping the Sabbath day holy, or any other principle, the process is exactly the same. First we must understand it through the scriptures and then we live it to the best of our ability; then we ask Heavenly Father with a sincere heart, with faith in Christ; then the truth of that principle will be manifest to us by the power of the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p27" pid="SYy0oueq90inm_TSUkgC9Q" hash="2ep1_g">If you want to know the truth, you become informed, you be willing, and you be available.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p28" pid="01fMI_UFTkeKcydOFhfCUw" hash="tMrdZw">Be informed about truth by reading the scriptures and by listening to inspired leaders.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p29" pid="bmcgGuFdd0yKUdxR3k86qA" hash="pRdphA">Be willing to live that truth to the best of your ability.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p30" pid="PrfS0GQ3gkC2MFs6bzl9wA" hash="qjzC2A">And then be available to the gifts of the Spirit through your personal worthiness that you may be directed and that you may recognize the answer when it comes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts.p31" pid="GlAbjZL0WEOcshchR9rwPg" hash="VoYz6A">O youth of the noble birthright, you young men of a royal priesthood, become a modern-day Nephi in your faith. Yes, we all agree, it’s hard at times, but the rewards are overwhelming. And never forget this: anyone who has been foreordained as you have been, anyone who has been given the gift of the Holy Ghost as you have, and anyone who has had priesthood authority conferred upon him as you have, will surely find within his grasp the ability to acquire a strong testimony—a testimony that should never stop growing. As with Joshua of old, “Choose you this day whom ye will serve; … but as for me and my house, we will serve the Lord” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/josh/24.15" class="scriptureRef">Josh. 24:15</a>). And just as surely as you do that, the “doctrine of the priesthood shall distil upon thy soul as the dews from heaven” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.45" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:45</a>). May it be so, I pray humbly, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1987/04/no-shortcuts</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1987-general-conference/1987-04-3020-elder-robert-l-simpson-64k-eng.mp3" length="5949901" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 1987 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
