<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Robert J. Whetten</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Robert J. Whetten.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Robert%20J.%20Whetten.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Robert J. Whetten.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 1999 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>True Followers</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1999/04/true-followers?lang=eng</link>
      <description>As His true followers, the Savior wants us to love others as He loves them—more unconditionally, more purely, more perfectly.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/true-followers" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_99260_000_015" doc-version="2" hash="RY1Img">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/true-followers.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="ClYZuiVP-0S3lvNkFzfZXw" hash="TCSBCQ">True Followers</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="csJlflXJfkyyU9w_uORoqA" hash="wyQWag">Robert J. Whetten</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="2uKFBC_NLU6w_k3YuT4Aaw" hash="GXFSjw">As His true followers, the Savior wants us to love others as He loves them—more unconditionally, more purely, more perfectly.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/true-followers.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-e9.jpg" alt="Elder Robert J. Whetten" pid="9le5E6neFE2gva9UwBcukA" hash="9TTUOw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/true-followers.p1" pid="a-PU0Q1U1kOedBVMqYccqA" hash="Da6_5A">Alone in that upper room with the eleven, Jesus uses these last teaching moments of His mortal ministry to teach: “A new commandment I give unto you, That ye love one another; as I have loved you. … By this shall all men know that ye are my disciples, if ye have love one to another.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> He talks of His coming death and Resurrection: “Greater love hath no man than this, that a man lay down his life for his friends.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> He reaffirms His divine sonship: “I am the way, the truth, and the life: no man cometh unto the Father, but by me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> And He promises that the Father will send them another comforter, the Holy Ghost: “He shall teach you all things.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/true-followers.p2" pid="X9zM2fvbo0iuvBERfQc12g" hash="IOzx6Q">Jesus’ unconditional love for us motivated His atoning sacrifice for our sins. Without His love, we would be unable to return to our Heavenly Father. How He lived His life is the example we should follow. His way should be our way. “Therefore, what manner of men ought ye to be? Verily I say unto you, even as I am.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> He showed us that we must go about doing good, that the spiritual and physical welfare of our fellowmen is as important as our own, and that we should show genuine concern and compassion for all of our Heavenly Father’s children. Moroni defines Christlike love as charity. “And now I know that this love which thou hast had for the children of men is charity; wherefore, except men shall have charity they cannot inherit that place which thou hast prepared in the mansions of thy Father.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> It’s not enough to say we believe and that we love Him; we must be found possessed with His kind of love for others at that last day. It is not necessary for us to lay down our life for others as He did, but like the Savior, we should bless the lives of others by giving of what our life is made up of—our time, our talents, our means, and ourselves.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/true-followers.p3" pid="RS2IImxABUGPioGxIorodw" hash="d5iw1w">Mormon urges us to “pray unto the Father with all the energy of heart, that ye may be filled with this love, which he hath bestowed upon all who are <span class="emphasis">true followers</span> of his Son, Jesus Christ.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> Like faith, Christlike love is a gift of the Spirit, is granted upon the principles of personal righteousness and in accordance to our level of obedience to the laws upon which it is predicated. Like faith, love must be exercised to grow. We all live our lives one day at a time, and each of us, regardless of our age or circumstances, is presented each day with choices in our relationships with others. As we deny ourselves and reach out to serve others, the Spirit will refine us and teach us and we will come to learn what Paul meant: “But the fruit of the Spirit is love, joy, peace, longsuffering, gentleness, goodness, faith.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> Our compassionate service to others will grow into divine love and change us, “and when he shall appear we shall be like him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/true-followers.p4" pid="UvoZaElUk0Cht4wGvY02ow" hash="x9YTfg">Brigham Young taught, “We should commence our labors of love and kindness with the family to which we belong; and then extend them to others.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> King Benjamin counseled parents to teach their children “to love one another, and to serve one another.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> President Kimball taught that “God does notice us, and he watches over us. But it is usually through another mortal that he meets our needs. Therefore, it is vital that we serve each other in the kingdom.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/true-followers.p5" pid="D3KajEf0iEaw8GzAOb-A4g" hash="w8YL9w">Last January an earthquake in the central mountain region of Colombia left the city of Armenia devastated. Concerned stake presidents called the Area Presidency in Quito to find out what the needs of the members living in Armenia were. The district president confirmed that many Church members had lost their homes and had found shelter in the four undamaged chapels but urgently needed food and clothing. The Relief Society and priesthood leaders swung into action, and donations from members throughout Colombia poured into a designated chapel in each city. Seven-year-old Neidi had come with her parents to the chapel in the city of Cali and watched as Bishop Villareal received donations from members.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/true-followers.p6" pid="PP2WJ8HCw0GSG3tNxCWujQ" hash="IYCFaQ">“Bishop, how can I help the children in Armenia?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/true-followers.p7" pid="kZGCMDTCTk24KjVGnvrGQw" hash="ERVRgw">“Neidi, your parents have already helped.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/true-followers.p8" pid="78rmRBC9ekOsk1ZHAIn3Eg" hash="gOK9LQ">She went to the other end of the chapel and observed that little clothing and no shoes for children were being packed. Neidi came back to the bishop with her shoes in her hand. “Now I know how I can help. Please give these shoes to another little girl in Armenia who has lost hers.” Her bare feet made no sound as she slipped away.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/true-followers.p9" pid="tofHq491eE6EhfLcA4YCpw" hash="HM5Yrw">King Benjamin counseled his people to yield to the enticings of the Holy Ghost, put “off the natural man and [become] a saint through the atonement of Christ the Lord, and [become] as a child, submissive, meek, humble, patient, full of love.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/true-followers.p10" pid="fhbZcRt6cEKQ_6utRe0S4g" hash="yBkUeA">In the late spring of 1829, as the marvelous events of the Restoration were unfolding, the Lord told Joseph Knight through the Prophet Joseph, “And no one can assist in this work except he shall be humble and full of love.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> Today each worthy young man is asked to give two years in full-time missionary service. As missionaries teach His gospel and serve others, they are granted gifts of the Spirit, including a Christlike love for those they serve. Missionary service can and should become the foundation for a lifetime of happiness built on love and service to others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/true-followers.p11" pid="scTbYqBRykWxG9Qi7coEqg" hash="0cv5kg">And motherhood, like priesthood, is a divine call to serve and to nurture others. Who that has witnessed the pure love of a mother for her child can deny that this kind of love is of God? Sisters, this same kind of Christlike love can and should be extended to others throughout your life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/true-followers.p12" pid="1NCZkFaQr0KKYNto-PZfMw" hash="MZu2Kg">When the rich man who came to Jesus asked, “Good Master, what good thing shall I do, that I may have eternal life?” the Lord reiterated the commandments, and the man answered, “All these things have I kept from my youth up: what lack I yet? Jesus said unto him, If thou wilt be perfect, go and sell that thou hast, and give to the poor, and thou shalt have treasure in heaven: and come and follow me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/true-followers.p13" pid="mowcZHmMjk-BtjkmVc3DNQ" hash="ZvfSNQ">As His disciples today, we should ask, “What lack I yet?” You can go about doing good, you can love and serve others in your family, in the Church, and in the community. At some point you must be willing “to render to him all that you have and are.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/true-followers.p14" pid="DguUu8R620CeOCF6-HSNSA" hash="7O-oaQ">Some of the truest followers I know are couples that have put the anticipated ease and pleasures of retirement on hold and followed Him into full-time service in His kingdom. If your desire is to grow in your discipleship together, talk to your bishop about a mission. Every mission in the Church needs more missionary couples, and the soon-to-be 100 temples in operation need more workers. President Hinckley has asked:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/true-followers.p15" pid="AYNiBeG-3UWnb1ub1jGzAQ" hash="0DlOUQ">“Why are missionaries happy? Because they lose themselves in the service of others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/true-followers.p16" pid="N3o6pdiH7EWcCZgKb0zAyg" hash="V4vg-A">“Why are those who labor in the temples happy? Because their labor of love is in very deed harmonious with the great vicarious work of the Savior of mankind.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/true-followers.p17" pid="Uh1Lv5IYvEqOl_MJshO-Uw" hash="CijF7Q">I am grateful to have been surrounded by loved ones who have blessed my life with their love and service. Like the converts in Alma’s time, if we are to be called His people, we must be “willing to bear one another’s burdens, that they may be light.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> Each of us can think of true followers that have lifted the burdens of many through their Christlike love and service. Ernest LeRoy Hatch was the medical doctor in the community in which I grew up in northern Mexico. He was also my mission president, and served several other missions. For much of his life he carried with him the written words to the hymn “More Holiness Give Me.” The last two lines read: “More fit for the kingdom, more used would I be, more blessed and holy—more, Savior, like thee.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/true-followers.p18" pid="oqrEuxupQkGhmNt1ntA0zQ" hash="lrrIWg">As His true followers, the Savior wants us to love others as He loves them—more unconditionally, more purely, more perfectly. As in the past, His apostles and prophets in our day continue to exemplify and teach that this Christlike love is the very essence of His gospel. I have come to know and feel of their love one for another and for each of us. I bear witness that they are true disciples of Jesus Christ. This Church is His kingdom on the earth. We have His and their example of love and service. May we be true disciples as well, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1999/04/true-followers</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1999-general-conference/1999-04-2070-elder-robert-j-whetten-64k-eng.mp3" length="4494247" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 1999 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strengthen Thy Brethren</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren?lang=eng</link>
      <description>You must do what our Savior and His prophets … have always taught: serve, strengthen the faith, and nurture those who need your love and blessing.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10032029_000_032" doc-version="2" hash="PhD93w">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="klHNNUukX0KmxdmdHcyFaA" hash="Bt7A-A">Strengthen Thy Brethren</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="x9mv7dEQEUmC64P-SZagSA" hash="wyQWag">Robert J. Whetten</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="uBi7VMGpCkGUO-oGwJdmwg" hash="G6zVxA">You must do what our Savior and His prophets … have always taught: serve, strengthen the faith, and nurture those who need your love and blessing.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-e9.jpg" alt="Elder Robert J. Whetten" pid="hQBuewTJp0SBJ88i6Tuahw" hash="9TTUOw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.p1" pid="AMQ9EaV-GkKLYgwpclNfag" hash="V1YQHA">Responding to the question, “Master, which is the great commandment in the law?” Jesus answered: “Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy mind. This is the first and great commandment. And the second is like unto it, Thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself. On these two commandments hang all the law and the prophets.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.p2" pid="vKwcmEe3MUqt0xUFBRlLLw" hash="Vn-Lrg">To ancient Israel and down through the generations of time, His prophets past and present have always taught this all-encompassing eternal truth—that to inherit eternal life we must have love in our souls: love for God our Eternal Father and love for our fellowmen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.p3" pid="sKOi6aaRj0-0lPfrX0g2Wg" hash="evX0hg">In the closing hours of His earthly ministry, Jesus said to Peter, “But I have prayed for thee, that thy faith fail not: and when thou art converted, strengthen thy brethren.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.p4" pid="ztGQ1toTw0iZsqmyAgzfew" hash="5RuT8g">Peter had a testimony, borne of the Spirit, of the divinity of Jesus Christ. Peter knew and his knowledge came by revelation. But his conversion, the change in his whole way of life and the nature of his very being, was more evident after the day of Pentecost, after receiving the heart-changing gift and witness of the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.p5" pid="MizgVcKt3UOxPUGknkoohA" hash="q6rpwg">Yes, brothers and sisters, like Peter before, we have testimonies, but is conversion a continuing process in your life? Isn’t each of us a work in progress in the hands of our Maker? Is God blessing others through you? Do you pray and ask whom the Lord would have you bless by lifting another’s burden? Do you love others as much as you love yourself?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.p6" pid="QM6C7PmYUESH9DScVXbfpQ" hash="V_6nHA">When Jesus told the lawyer that in order to inherit eternal life he must love his neighbor as himself, the lawyer said unto Jesus, “And who is my neighbour?” Jesus responded with His parable of the good Samaritan and then asked: “Which now of these three, thinkest thou, was neighbour unto him that fell among the thieves? And he said, He that shewed mercy on him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> With this parable, Jesus taught that each of us should exhibit an active love and benevolence towards every one of His Father’s children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.p7" pid="CFmGlN_NukmIV6lXmPmzmA" hash="4rjYnQ">King Benjamin taught the Saints of his day: “For the sake of retaining a remission of your sins from day to day, … I would that ye should impart of your substance to the poor, … such as feeding the hungry, … visiting the sick and administering to their relief, both <span class="emphasis">spiritually</span> and<span class="emphasis"> temporally.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> Do you administer spiritual or temporal relief to those who need it? Do you reach out and strengthen the faith of those coming into the fold, as asked by the prophets of our day?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.p8" pid="9fKbmh3E30SFcYYFcqdiIw" hash="9eXvMw">Conversion means consecrating your life to caring for and serving others who need your help and sharing your gifts and blessings. The Lord didn’t say, “Tend my sheep when it is convenient; watch my sheep when you aren’t busy.” He said, “Feed my sheep and my lambs; help them survive this world; keep them close to you. Lead them to safety—the safety of righteous choices that will prepare them for eternal life.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.p9" pid="ZuHidGne2USOucFlJPRr2Q" hash="6oH5LA">Every unselfish act of kindness and service increases your spirituality. God would use you to bless others. Your continued spiritual growth and eternal progress are very much wrapped up in your relationships—in how you treat others. Do you indeed love others and become a blessing in their lives? <span class="emphasis">Isn’t the measure of the level of your conversion how you treat others? </span>The person who does only those things in the Church that concern himself alone will never reach the goal of perfection. Service to others is what the gospel and exalted life are all about.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.p10" pid="3D1GI4Aztkm1UM6H3Ox7Og" hash="PkK55g">In your journey through life, you are to reach out and bless the lives of your fellow travelers, to give of yourself to those who need you. “For whosoever will save his life,” the Master said, “shall lose it; but whosoever shall lose his life for my sake and the gospel’s, the same shall save it.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.p11" pid="KaIHekhtX0eO1bIWGG3HIA" hash="D2OAvg">James directed his epistle “to the twelve tribes which are scattered abroad.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> His teachings may be applied to us, the Lord’s people who in a latter day would accept the restored gospel. He teaches principles that should guide your relationships with other members of the Church. He considers the commandment to “love thy neighbour as thyself” to be the “royal law.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> To James, a testimony alone is not enough. The gospel has to become a living reality in your life. “And I will shew thee my faith by my works.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> “But be ye doers of the word, and not hearers only.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> James’s definition of the converted is: “Pure religion and undefiled before God and the Father is this, To visit the fatherless and widows in their affliction, and to keep himself unspotted from the world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> He ends his brief epistle with these words: “Brethren, if any of you do err from the truth, and one convert him; Let him know, that he which converteth the sinner from the error of his way shall save a soul … and shall hide a multitude of sins.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> By reclaiming an errant brother, you save both him and yourself. Your sins are hidden or remitted because you ministered for the salvation of another.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.p12" pid="t1cj7JxWk06l0mq-fBf1bg" hash="bUqY0A">Mine has been the great blessing of living my life in Latin America and witnessing firsthand the unfolding of the prophecies and promises made by His prophets and the Lord Himself.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.p13" pid="AbKGop9EAUi7ewDkwHeAuw" hash="zXVGWg">“I shall gather in, from their long dispersion, my people, O house of Israel, and shall establish again among them my Zion. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.p14" pid="qKhqCnOhr0KhnY7zzDYTGw" hash="3Bebcw">“… I will establish my church among them, and they shall come in unto the covenant and be numbered among this the remnant of Jacob, unto whom I have given this land for their inheritance.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.p15" pid="MuHRC9clTEubqqp5G77VNw" hash="qIXL_Q">Literally hundreds of thousands have been gathered in from practically every nation in Latin America. Prophecies assure us that this growth will continue. Growth is our greatest challenge but also the greatest opportunity for each of us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.p16" pid="40vjTnbWJky3Xkgo8qEhSg" hash="e-AtIQ">The Apostle Paul said to the new members in his day, “Now therefore ye are no more strangers and foreigners, but fellowcitizens with the saints, and of the household of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.p17" pid="QjRhwFDA20uv0Z5DYAGZJA" hash="llNdag">It seems that where the Church has experienced rapid growth, too many are still made to feel that they are <span class="emphasis">strangers and foreigners</span> and have been left by the wayside. If we are to see the promises fulfilled, we must do as Moroni described: “And after they had been received unto baptism, … they were numbered among the people of the church of Christ; and their names were taken, that they might be remembered and nourished … to keep them in the right way.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.p18" pid="vzSeacaxyUicqdct-HEg7w" hash="Bzy9GA">Many active members believe that the less-active members and new converts that fall by the wayside behave differently because they don’t believe the Church’s doctrine. Studies made do not support this assumption. They show that almost all less-active members interviewed believe that God exists, that Jesus is the Christ, that Joseph Smith was a prophet, and that the Church is true.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.p19" pid="k-IRFG2oI02YiNOuSq1zjA" hash="GEcFGg">In numerous wards and branches, there are many good, upright, honest men and women who just don’t know how to come back to church. There are good mothers and fathers among them. They have just left, and no one has come to check up on them, leaving them with the idea that no one really cares. When men or women of faith visit these individuals and become their friends, strengthen them, pray with them, and teach them the gospel, they and their families will come back. “Inasmuch as ye have done it unto one of the least of these my brethren, ye have done it unto me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> Who are “the least of these my brethren”? Might the Lord be referring to the newest coming into the fold or to those who have wandered into the shadows of inactivity and would return if extended the hand of true fellowship?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.p20" pid="IQ6eiNc6v0Wc5WISfRmXow" hash="ogQzLQ">In this great battle for the souls of men, the rules of engagement in missionary work are more clearly defined for each of us. Members are to accompany full-time missionary companionships as they teach the lessons and play a vital role in the conversion process of others. Missionaries are “to preach my gospel by the Spirit”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> with words from their own hearts, words of truth treasured up by much study and prayer. Our missionaries’ roles in the continuing conversion process of others do not end at baptism. They are to continue to teach new members and others who need spiritual nourishment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.p21" pid="Zh8E4PbEK0Sdw15qa8mPdw" hash="RN5Z_Q">Recent letters from the First Presidency remind priesthood leaders of their responsibility to strengthen and support new members. “Fellowship should be extended by all in the ward. … Home teachers and visiting teachers can play a valuable role.” New members should be given “opportunities … to serve and contribute to the strength of the ward.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.p22" pid="n1-wLtv5J0O1s3_ay7PWYA" hash="xacl-w">Brothers and sisters, if the conversion and transformation process is to continue in each of us, new members and old alike, we must love, serve, and give spiritual nourishment to others. We must help others receive the full blessings of the Restoration, including the blessings of the temple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.p23" pid="wFbQfbl_ZUitCcQS4leb2A" hash="l9Id0g">The Prophet Joseph Smith wrote a letter to the Saints in his day: “Dear Brethren:—It is a duty which every Saint ought to render to his brethren freely—to always love them, and ever succor them. To be justified before God we must love one another: … we can love our neighbor as ourselves, and be faithful in tribulation.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.p24" pid="S9ZIpaB6hUmLg4TyQLUcBg" hash="ZWgECw">Our own prophet, President Gordon B. Hinckley, has said: “I would hope, I would pray, that each of us … would resolve to seek those who need help … and lift them in the spirit of love into the embrace of the Church, where strong hands and loving hearts will warm them, comfort them, sustain them, and put them on the way of happy and productive lives.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.p25" pid="Z1DM1J-We0W_tqBtl3-aZg" hash="Xy0vwQ">Love is not just a word or a declaration, but the first and great commandment, a commandment that demands action—“If ye love me, keep my commandments”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> and “Lovest thou me? … Feed my sheep.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.p26" pid="Ht5GU3q_oEiVcz5aM0FaDg" hash="JCyWbg">You must do what our Savior and His prophets, both past and present, have always taught: serve, strengthen the faith, and nurture those who need your love and blessing. You have the Lord’s promise: “And whoso receiveth you, there I will be also, for I will go before your face … and my Spirit shall be in your hearts.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.p27" pid="UP92c7WS_06C61k-C3h2BA" hash="6fulBw">Brothers and sisters, as you reach out in love to bless the life of another, you both will be blessed with His Spirit. The Lord teaches that both will “understand one another, and both [will be] edified and rejoice together.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_24">24</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren.p28" pid="b3ju6mF8HEKFQEFo0g1Y3w" hash="vwctKg">It is my prayer that our Heavenly Father will bless each of us with that love for others “which he hath bestowed upon all who are true followers of his Son.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_25">25</span> I bear witness that His Son, Jesus Christ, lives and that His gospel is a gospel of love. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2005/04/strengthen-thy-brethren</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2005-general-conference/2005-04-5030-elder-robert-j-whetten-64k-eng.mp3" length="6127767" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2005 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
