<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Robert K. Dellenbach</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Robert K. Dellenbach.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Robert%20K.%20Dellenbach.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Robert K. Dellenbach.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Oct 1990 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 1990 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Hour of Conversion</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1990/10/hour-of-conversion?lang=eng</link>
      <description>May I tell you of the hour of my true conversion to the Lord Jesus Christ and his restored gospel. Perhaps my experience will strengthen those who desire a closer relationship with our Father in Heaven and a more profound testimony of the truthfulnes</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/hour-of-conversion" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_90911_000_012" doc-version="2" hash="avtkFA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/hour-of-conversion.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="dR7T3jprh0q_KgXRf-jXJQ" hash="aaKUMA">Hour of Conversion</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="NkMr6HwPk0KDivDfjeL1Bg" hash="u3ZfwA">Robert K. Dellenbach</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/hour-of-conversion.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-20f6.jpg" alt="Elder Robert K. Dellenbach" pid="JqcLjP61YkmsOY1odn4yKg" hash="DlcGWg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/hour-of-conversion.p1" pid="APSpYju99U679vEK2FmDwQ" hash="mBT3Mg">May I tell you of the hour of my true conversion to the Lord Jesus Christ and his restored gospel. Perhaps my experience will strengthen those who desire a closer relationship with our Father in Heaven and a more profound testimony of the truthfulness of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/hour-of-conversion.p2" pid="98T7Bm-sbUaULYbdjstrhw" hash="v4KZFQ">Some years ago while traveling to a mission in Germany, I found myself, in stormy November, aboard a ship sailing from New York to Bremerhaven. The ocean boiled with turmoil. We were all seasick. All we could eat was soda crackers and Zwieback. I was almost afraid I was not going to die!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/hour-of-conversion.p3" pid="ZMxzxw_Ox0GdQHyjIUGXTg" hash="AWuxvw">As the days passed it dawned on me—“I’m really going on a mission.” Do I truly have a testimony? Am I prepared to bear it “at all times and … in all places”? (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.9" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/hour-of-conversion.p4" pid="E0N7-yVRlk6oGgGZDyYN5g" hash="RQWbAg">I thought I had a testimony, but now the real trial of my faith was coming. I was going to a foreign land where the only words I could speak in German were <span class="emphasis">Volkswagen</span> and <span class="emphasis">auf Wiedersehen.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/hour-of-conversion.p5" pid="j2_MHqM7PEW-40_koK_jvA" hash="FiHPyA">During the voyage I realized my testimony was not a spiritual fire of conviction, particularly of the Book of Mormon. And so I knelt down on the cold steel floor of that rocking ship and begged the Lord with my tears. I prayed, “Dear Father, I have got to know that the Book of Mormon is true. I have read it, I think I understand it, but I desire the fire which helps a man know that the Book of Mormon is thy word. Please, Father, help me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/hour-of-conversion.p6" pid="UjSino17SkiGPuc-Y3_IFQ" hash="1gk-_g">Somewhere out on the lonely Atlantic, during those turbulent days, a sweet spirit and peace came to me—“the peace of God, which passeth all understanding.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/philip/4.7" class="scriptureRef">Philip. 4:7</a>.) I received a witness that the Book of Mormon is the word of God, and that supernal event became my hour of conversion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/hour-of-conversion.p7" pid="oUiSD7WPcECxSv1MRQMz2g" hash="rUZe6g">If you question whether you have a testimony of the restored gospel, I encourage you to read, ponder, and study the Book of Mormon. Why the Book of Mormon? Because this holy scripture is the great testifier and converter. This ancient record is a spiritual compass for us to follow. Joseph Smith said, “The Book of Mormon was … the keystone of our religion, and a man would get nearer to God by abiding by its precepts, than by any other book.” (<span class="emphasis">History of the Church,</span> 4:461.) When you come to know that this testament of Christ is true, you will know that Joseph Smith is the prophet of the Restoration and that Ezra Taft Benson is the Lord’s prophet today. The Book of Mormon was written for our day to convince us “that Jesus is the Christ.” (Book of Mormon title page.) If your soul is searching for a more profound testimony of Jesus Christ and his restored kingdom, I suggest, in conjunction with studying the Book of Mormon, there are four steps you can take which will lead you to your hour of conversion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/hour-of-conversion.p8" pid="XEvzrV1SsEGUKRH5VgEKtg" hash="vcgsQw">These four steps are (1) Desire, (2) Works, (3) Prayer, and (4) Trust in the Lord. Let me briefly explain.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/hour-of-conversion.p9" pid="IP-vMdZveE2QoT9e6vmMsg" hash="BM0zzw">
        <span class="emphasis">First, Desire:</span> Oliver Cowdery desired a more firm witness of the plates which contained the Book of Mormon record. The Lord said to Oliver: “If you desire a further witness, cast your mind upon the night that you cried unto me in your heart, that you might know concerning the truth of these things. Did I not speak peace to your mind concerning the matter?” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/6.22-23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 6:22–23</a>.) The Lord told Oliver that, first of all, a person needs to have desire.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/hour-of-conversion.p10" pid="Rn9WZS_rTEyWO6IhmkTgNg" hash="zDkD0g">Alma said, “Even if ye can no more than desire to believe, let this desire work in you.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/32.27" class="scriptureRef">Alma 32:27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/hour-of-conversion.p11" pid="K03n5qooMUa64_3cqMsEZA" hash="3ExahA">
        <span class="emphasis">Second, Works:</span> Oliver Cowdery took a positive action. He moved himself from thinking to doing. In my case, while on board that ship, I had more intimately studied and pondered the Book of Mormon. Young Joseph reflected on the Bible, then went into the woods to pray. Moses climbed Mt. Sinai. My Great-grandmother Nelson boarded a ship in Denmark, with a flock of little children, to join the Mormons in Utah. Righteous works yield a divine harvest. The Lord said, “He who doeth the works of righteousness shall receive his reward, even peace in this world, and eternal life in the world to come.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/59.23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 59:23</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/hour-of-conversion.p12" pid="dPdc6gYkrEGdbVWNxn9xGg" hash="jdYuLQ">
        <span class="emphasis">Third, Prayer:</span> “Prayer is the soul’s sincere desire, Uttered or unexpressed.” (<span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> 1985, no. 145.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/hour-of-conversion.p13" pid="ONPVhwyCBkyfQ0EqYBeeeA" hash="ybifjw">As we sincerely pray to the Lord and rely upon his divine whisperings, that still, small voice will come to us. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/5.30" class="scriptureRef">Hel. 5:30</a>.) We will receive a peace, knowing that God has answered our prayers. Remember the peace that Oliver received. These spiritual embers can grow into a flame of testimony. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/5.45" class="scriptureRef">Hel. 5:45</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/hour-of-conversion.p14" pid="KQewsWJkW0iV9fAfiZB9_A" hash="fVgfUQ">Alma, upon meeting the four sons of Mosiah, who had been on a fourteen-year mission, rejoiced at their knowledge of the truth. He said, “They had searched the scriptures diligently, [and] … they had given themselves to much prayer, and fasting, … [and] they taught with power and authority of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/17.2-3" class="scriptureRef">Alma 17:2–3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/hour-of-conversion.p15" pid="t_oXAmvDCUS6tpMRgYfACA" hash="6Skv8w">“Ask God, the Eternal Father, in the name of Christ,” counseled Moroni, “if these things are not true; and if ye shall ask with a sincere heart, … he will manifest the truth of it unto you, by the power of the Holy Ghost.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.4" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 10:4</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/hour-of-conversion.p16" pid="RAmUZubmg0WgE0YfZhsuFg" hash="aKP6IA">Surely the Lord would not ask us to pray if he did not intend to answer our prayers. “He is a rewarder of them that diligently seek him.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/heb/11.6" class="scriptureRef">Heb. 11:6</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/hour-of-conversion.p17" pid="9fYpaf9B2EG99FQlpmkW_Q" hash="vB0Qag">
        <span class="emphasis">Fourth, “Trust in the Lord with all thine heart; and lean not unto thine own understanding.”</span> (<a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/3.5" class="scriptureRef">Prov. 3:5</a>.) We can trust the Lord. He is our truest Friend. He always keeps his word. “Dispute not because ye see not, for ye receive no witness until after the trial of your faith,” admonished Ether. (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/12.6" class="scriptureRef">Ether 12:6</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/hour-of-conversion.p18" pid="7DPFC-O6I0WeAzjMetPzJw" hash="n_w7CQ">May I ask you to extend your trust in the Lord. Take the Book of Mormon into your hands. As you read it, ask yourself: “Could any man write this?” Then ask the Lord, “Is this thy word?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/hour-of-conversion.p19" pid="ItfBYxlW9UWr3X5IXv2VxQ" hash="tPlBhg">A word of caution: Satan wants to stop you. He will try to distract, deceive, and weaken your desire, your righteous works, your sincere prayers, and your trust in the Lord. Do not be afraid. We have already overcome the evil one at another time and place. We are told that in the great premortal war, “[we] overcame [Lucifer] by the blood of the Lamb, and by the word of [our] testimony.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rev/12.11" class="scriptureRef">Rev. 12:11</a>.) We had a valiant testimony in our preexistent state, and we can resist Satan and awaken that testimony again today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/hour-of-conversion.p20" pid="GyuKcnPKHEiU9zpd_UlCtg" hash="DfiFMg">The Book of Mormon is our testimonial Liahona. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/37.45" class="scriptureRef">Alma 37:45</a>.) This voice from the dust guides us to know that God lives, that Jesus is the Christ, and that his Church has been restored.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/10/hour-of-conversion.p21" pid="Uk07Odp1902tWhe7Y50zPA" hash="0YLJ4w">If you have even a small desire for a greater witness, please do the works of righteousness, trust in the Lord, pray and anxiously explore the Book of Mormon. I testify that it is the word of God. This iron rod marks the path that will guide your soul to your hour of conversion. I rejoice with you in that glorious event. In the name of the Lord Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1990/10/hour-of-conversion</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1990-general-conference/1990-10-2030-elder-robert-k-dellenbach-64k-eng.mp3" length="4512416" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 1990 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Translation Miracle of the Book of Mormon</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1995/04/the-translation-miracle-of-the-book-of-mormon?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters, do we realize the profound miracle that is the translation of the Book of Mormon? A miracle is “an extraordinary event manifesting divine intervention in human affairs” ( s.v. “miracle”). Consistent with that definition,</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/the-translation-miracle-of-the-book-of-mormon" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_95905_000_005" doc-version="2" hash="ELkaDw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/the-translation-miracle-of-the-book-of-mormon.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="FuSJttgIx0iefHxhMHNcTA" hash="V-0lNA">The Translation Miracle of the Book of Mormon</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="5vRix4-2skeMxyMSKH6-zQ" hash="u3ZfwA">Robert K. Dellenbach</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/the-translation-miracle-of-the-book-of-mormon.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-20f6.jpg" alt="Elder Robert K. Dellenbach" pid="QDQ6Sn9XIkSnHEM0W-Prqw" hash="DlcGWg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/the-translation-miracle-of-the-book-of-mormon.p1" pid="UHmBrCFoJku8RAW4BJPGwQ" hash="Fs2qmQ">My dear brothers and sisters, do we realize the profound miracle that is the translation of the Book of Mormon? A miracle is “an extraordinary event manifesting divine intervention in human affairs” (<span class="emphasis">Merriam-Webster’s Collegiate Dictionary,</span> s.v. “miracle”). Consistent with that definition, the translation of the Book of Mormon by Joseph Smith is indeed a modern-day miracle.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/the-translation-miracle-of-the-book-of-mormon.p2" pid="UgzUAJUuBkWCWV0lkDjfWQ" hash="FrJERw">The Book of Mormon is presently in print in over eighty languages and is now being translated or prepared for publication in many, many more. Consider the Church’s current process of translating the Book of Mormon from English into another language. The Church contracts capable, experienced member translators who are fluent in English as well as their native tongue who possess integrity and high moral character so that the spirit of inspiration will guide their work. Just as in Joseph Smith’s day, the ability to translate holy writ today is a spiritual gift from God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/the-translation-miracle-of-the-book-of-mormon.p3" pid="G_rENEAAdEW-DoK5gx53XQ" hash="ml0Xew">Unlike Joseph’s day, however, many of our modern translators utilize computers and word processors, lexicons and encyclopedias to help and guide them in their sacred assignment. The modern work is extensive, and each step must be critically analyzed by Church translation experts. Yet, even with the most competent member translators and advanced technology available, the entire process, from beginning to publication, requires approximately four years.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/the-translation-miracle-of-the-book-of-mormon.p4" pid="hnX-aH9d5UCbSi3OImwMSQ" hash="o0uxXQ">Now contrast the translation of the Book of Mormon by young Joseph Smith. Joseph was raised on a farm in upstate New York and was only twenty-four years of age at the time he completed his translation of this sacred record from reformed Egyptian to English.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/the-translation-miracle-of-the-book-of-mormon.p5" pid="row-JXSYDU6KUKtVOpO1Vw" hash="wQ6FGA">He had little financially and was busy supporting his wife and family. Of necessity, he planted and harvested crops, chopped wood, hauled water, and cared for animals.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/the-translation-miracle-of-the-book-of-mormon.p6" pid="h99XoL1PiEmevAHYY7LKSA" hash="oxFAwA">The conditions under which Joseph translated were less than ideal. His life was threatened and mobs tried to rob him of the plates, requiring him to hide the ancient records and often move them from place to place (see <a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.60" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:60</a>). Joseph had no telephone, no dictating equipment, fax, word processor, or copy machine—not even electric light.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/the-translation-miracle-of-the-book-of-mormon.p7" pid="KqK9jsmYck2GfDeYmI320Q" hash="fSsWgg">Joseph had little formal education, perhaps no more than three years of elementary school. Prior to his translation Joseph had not enrolled in a university. There were no literary magazines or academic periodicals delivered to his doorstep. He never visited South America or the Middle East. He belonged to no professional societies, had performed no extensive research projects, nor did he have learned colleagues with whom to discuss the ancient text of the plates. He may have studied basic reading, writing, and arithmetic and perhaps a little American history. We know he read the Bible in English, but by the standards of the world, Joseph was neither a scholar nor a theologian, much less a professional translator of holy scriptures.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/the-translation-miracle-of-the-book-of-mormon.p8" pid="XQpqLtOFoUyPxYzDG1bOoQ" hash="5jf9Hw">What skills did Joseph possess to aid in his translation? Oliver Cowdery, who was the principal scribe for the Book of Mormon, said of Joseph’s source of translating power that “the Prophet Joseph Smith … translated [the Book of Mormon] by the gift and power of God, by the [assistance or] means of the Urim and Thummim” (“Last Days of Oliver Cowdery,” <span class="emphasis">Deseret News,</span> 13 Apr. 1859, p. 48).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/the-translation-miracle-of-the-book-of-mormon.p9" pid="0ydIz3h7REiKbH41WtZC0g" hash="zTf0Og">Typically a literary work undergoes extensive revisions and editions before a final, finely tuned draft is completed. For example, Abraham Lincoln rewrote his Gettysburg Address five different times, each version varying slightly from the other (see <span class="emphasis">World Book Encyclopedia,</span> 1992 ed., s.v. “Gettysburg Address”).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/the-translation-miracle-of-the-book-of-mormon.p10" pid="jgrvc0DhOEyJQdlvHcwAoQ" hash="BCmgDg">In preparing for this conference address, I had the glorious experience of quietly examining several pages of Joseph’s original manuscript of the Book of Mormon, which is safely protected in the Church archive. I was overwhelmed at the purity of the transcription, which had only a very few insignificant corrections, such as a misspelled word. Joseph’s original manuscript is so perfect it could only have come from one source—divine revelation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/the-translation-miracle-of-the-book-of-mormon.p11" pid="Czy6oXh2G0e69_btzuT_EQ" hash="tyPteg">On Joseph’s shoulders rested not only the translation of the Book of Mormon but also the restoration and reestablishment of the Church of Jesus Christ. Even as Joseph translated, he received many revelations and visitations from heavenly messengers who gave him additional important assignments, such as the restoration of the priesthood and the revelation on baptism (see <a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.68-75" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:68–75</a>). Joseph’s many responsibilities often interrupted the translation process, sometimes for several months. Yet, once Joseph was free to dedicate his entire effort to translation, the work surged forward and he translated eight to ten pages a day, completing the preponderance of the Book of Mormon translation in approximately sixty-three working days (see John W. Welch and Tim Rathbone, “The Translation of the Book of Mormon: Basic Historical Information,” Provo, Utah: F.A.R.M.S., 1986, p. 14).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/the-translation-miracle-of-the-book-of-mormon.p12" pid="BEvJQS8MRUG-T4noxSLr9g" hash="3peJ5w">Oliver, reflecting on this miraculous event, testified, “Day after day I continued, uninterrupted, to write from his mouth, as he translated … the history, or record, called ‘The book of Mormon’” (<span class="emphasis">Latter Day Saints’ Messenger and Advocate,</span> Oct. 1834, pp. 14–16).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/the-translation-miracle-of-the-book-of-mormon.p13" pid="S7X-k-2CdEW1urG46Rwk0A" hash="FpplhA">Joseph was the first person in over fourteen hundred years to read the words of the Savior as written by Nephi, Alma, Mormon, Moroni, and the other prophets of the Book of Mormon. His ability to translate was nothing short of a “marvelous work and a wonder” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/25.17" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 25:17</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/the-translation-miracle-of-the-book-of-mormon.p14" pid="i98fxARGvES_TK2_BJ5Esw" hash="u0nYjA">Joseph’s original English translation, except for a few minor grammatical and textual emendations, remains the text that we use today and is the standard for all other language translations of the Book of Mormon throughout the world (see <span class="emphasis">Encyclopedia of Mormonism,</span> ed. Daniel H. Ludlow, 4 vols., New York: Macmillan, 1992, s.v. “Book of Mormon manuscripts”). As Nephi of old prophesied, his “words shall [whisper] forth unto the ends of the earth, for a standard unto [his] people” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/29.2" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 29:2</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/the-translation-miracle-of-the-book-of-mormon.p15" pid="KnpzCRZhvEmp3clFdPVz6g" hash="IlW_Zw">Could any one of us today produce such a work? Could a thousand of the world’s best theologians and scholars of ancient languages or antiquities write a similar book of such supernal, transcendent value?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/the-translation-miracle-of-the-book-of-mormon.p16" pid="Cu7q6pUPqEmPvrdsnJi4bQ" hash="UOeREw">No other person with such limited education and facility as Joseph has single-handedly translated in such a short period of time from ancient writings over five hundred pages of scriptural text. That translation now has seventy-three million books in distribution.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/the-translation-miracle-of-the-book-of-mormon.p17" pid="AzDI5UjCcUC-BF9wRdaLlw" hash="J1M4KQ">Joseph’s translation of this ancient, sacred scripture has withstood the scrutiny of many skeptics. The Book of Mormon stands as a miraculous work for the world to examine. This divine spark from heaven, over 165 years ago, has ignited a flame that is dawning a new day. No wonder “the Spirit of God like a fire is burning!” (<span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> 1985, no. 2). All over the world people are seeking the witness of Jesus Christ as found in the Book of Mormon. They come from every nation, kindred, tongue, and people. As was revealed to the Prophet Joseph Smith, “The ends of the earth shall inquire after thy name” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/122.1" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 122:1</a>). And why are they seeking after the name of Joseph Smith? Because the Book of Mormon testifies of the divinity and atonement of the Savior, Jesus Christ. Because Joseph is the prophet of the Restoration.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/the-translation-miracle-of-the-book-of-mormon.p18" pid="10gFzNUo2UeR6PZoJyXNFw" hash="6NQWUQ">With deep appreciation for the miracle that transpired through the translation of the Book of Mormon, we sing:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/the-translation-miracle-of-the-book-of-mormon.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="EHCXoLmBBkObjex4olTEog" hash="kzU6Eg">
            <span class="emphasis">Praise to the man who communed with Jehovah!</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="7ocWK-gfnkmxFnP_ATEC-g" hash="V7FhyA">
            <span class="emphasis">Jesus anointed that Prophet and Seer.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="z6IsMtQxTEWFWCCDwL9-ow" hash="TWPQzg">
            <span class="emphasis">Blessed to open the last dispensation. …</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="yRTDSZ6Ou0ayylEbHpu6-Q" hash="HQ9TUg">
            <span class="emphasis">Millions shall know “Brother Joseph” again.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/04/the-translation-miracle-of-the-book-of-mormon.p19" pid="2EHmCk7gxUqI6geQSfmfLQ" hash="ZYbyBA">I testify that the translation miracle of the Book of Mormon clearly evidences that Joseph is a prophet of God, called to “lay the foundation of [Christ’s] church, and to bring it forth out of obscurity and out of darkness, the only true and living church upon the face of the whole earth” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.30" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:30</a>). The Book of Mormon is the “keystone of our religion” and will bring us “nearer to God by abiding by its precepts, than by any other book” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of the Prophet Joseph Smith,</span> p. 194). May we appreciate this miraculous translation, and may it be our desire to come to know and follow the Savior through his teachings in the Book of Mormon, I humbly pray in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1995/04/the-translation-miracle-of-the-book-of-mormon</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1995-general-conference/1995-04-1030-elder-robert-k-dellenbach-64k-eng.mp3" length="4546291" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 1995 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sacrifice Brings Forth the Blessings of Heaven</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2002/10/sacrifice-brings-forth-the-blessings-of-heaven?lang=eng</link>
      <description>If we are caring, if we are charitable, if we are obedient to God and follow His prophets, our sacrifices will bring forth the blessings of heaven.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/sacrifice-brings-forth-the-blessings-of-heaven" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029898_000_013" doc-version="2" hash="vJd2cA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/sacrifice-brings-forth-the-blessings-of-heaven.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="mHiVCv2YKUCSKCyf3pOFnA" hash="F8L4rA">Sacrifice Brings Forth the Blessings of Heaven</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="cFDOiMDxRUyDQVgSY4UINg" hash="u3ZfwA">Robert K. Dellenbach</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="OAzXm9Tkhk27CXHrUAeDgQ" hash="hG5D9g">If we are caring, if we are charitable, if we are obedient to God and follow His prophets, our sacrifices will bring forth the blessings of heaven.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/sacrifice-brings-forth-the-blessings-of-heaven.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-f01.jpg" alt="Elder Robert K. Dellenbach" pid="P6oS1jKXuU-jJT79c_EduA" hash="8JSL6Q" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/sacrifice-brings-forth-the-blessings-of-heaven.p1" pid="IEKP7LBJ9UqLdbzPYMdqDQ" hash="tWtfkw">The words “sacrifice brings forth the blessings of heaven,” from the hymn “Praise to the Man,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> always stir my soul. Sacrifice is defined as “the act of giving up something valued for the sake of something else more important or worthy.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> Sacrifice comes in many forms and may not always be convenient. Latter-day Saints make a covenant with the Lord to sacrifice. By doing so, we surrender our will to His, dedicating our lives to building up His kingdom and serving His children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/sacrifice-brings-forth-the-blessings-of-heaven.p2" pid="Lquiul10vky-66ZxHCLTFA" hash="nglNfA">For those who faithfully sacrifice through an honest tithe, the Lord has promised that He will open the windows of heaven.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Not only does such sacrifice bless the individual and the family, but those voluntary contributions to the Church provide the energizing resources that help the kingdom of the Lord to perform miracles every day. King Benjamin said: “Consider on the blessed and happy state of those that keep the commandments of God. For behold, they are blessed in all things, both temporal and spiritual.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> The faithful contribution of tithes is an outward expression of an inner commitment to sacrifice.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/sacrifice-brings-forth-the-blessings-of-heaven.p3" pid="vVxyXXcPs0WGUwqQSaXqmQ" hash="LTut2A">Obeying the law of the fast is another form of sacrifice. The Lord asks us to set aside one Sunday a month to fast for two meals. We are invited to contribute the money saved on the cost of those two meals to the Church so it can assist those in need. Fasting and contributing a generous offering have a refining effect upon the soul. President Spencer W. Kimball stated, “Upon practicing the law of the fast, one finds a personal well-spring of power to overcome self-indulgence and selfishness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/sacrifice-brings-forth-the-blessings-of-heaven.p4" pid="MRMKhD89qUuCcK79T97RAQ" hash="_PGk2A">Temple and family history work is a sacrifice of love. Faithful Saints contribute millions of hours compiling family history. They research microfilms and records, and with pens and computers they record dates and events. In the temple they perform sacred ordinances for their precious ancestry. Like the Savior, this is an expression of sacrifice—doing something for others which they cannot do for themselves.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/sacrifice-brings-forth-the-blessings-of-heaven.p5" pid="xBWQJIubyEOdMO_JyBF6yw" hash="7eheaA">A few years ago, while on a Church assignment in St. Petersburg, Russia, my wife, Mary-Jayne, and I had the unique opportunity to feel the blessings of family history work. We visited the vital statistics archive to view the Church’s efforts to microfilm some of the records of western Russia. As I watched the archivist photographing pages of moldy old books from the city of Pskov, the names became real people. They seemed to leap right off the page and say: “You have found me. I am no longer lost. I know that someday, somewhere, someone in my family will take my name to the temple, and I will be baptized and endowed, and my wife and children will be sealed to me. Thank you!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/sacrifice-brings-forth-the-blessings-of-heaven.p6" pid="7aOIKnKuvkaXUzCKZzyiTw" hash="Qjn-nw">Joseph Smith’s life was an example of unselfish sacrifice for the gospel of Jesus Christ. Though the Prophet Joseph suffered greatly, he remained optimistic and overcame many persecutions. Parley P. Pratt tells of a heartrending experience of being with the Prophet in jail in Missouri in the winter of 1838–39. Those six months of suffering and confinement tutored this foreordained, preeminent Prophet.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/sacrifice-brings-forth-the-blessings-of-heaven.p7" pid="uggIT3WvZkG2KC-IS7Pz5w" hash="aRjv-A">In the jail the Prophet and his brethren had listened to the boasting and the despicable abuses the guards had committed among the “Mormons.” Finally the Prophet could abide their sordid cursing no longer. Suddenly, he stood and in “a voice of thunder” said: “ <span class="emphasis">‘SILENCE, ye fiends of the infernal pit. In the name of Jesus Christ I rebuke you, and command you to be still. …’</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/sacrifice-brings-forth-the-blessings-of-heaven.p8" pid="53X5RQRYzEeFB0iuJfeLbA" hash="nrTZIQ">“He stood erect in terrible majesty. Chained, and without a weapon; calm, unruffled and dignified as an angel. … [The quaking guards shrank] into a corner,” dropped their weapons, “begged his pardon, and remained quiet till a change of guards.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/sacrifice-brings-forth-the-blessings-of-heaven.p9" pid="3sPretRbh0mLBbEHhHaEKQ" hash="IunrcA">Brother Pratt writes further: “I have seen the ministers of justice, clothed in magisterial robes … ; I have witnessed a Congress in solemn session … ; I have tried to conceive of kings, of royal courts, of thrones and crowns … ; but dignity and majesty have I seen but <span class="emphasis">once,</span> as it stood in chains, at midnight, in a dungeon in an obscure village of Missouri.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/sacrifice-brings-forth-the-blessings-of-heaven.p10" pid="pmL_RXzbOES3FZ-GqYqGIQ" hash="cwTqqg">Some weeks after that event, in another dark hour, Joseph implored the Lord for guidance. The Lord answered, “My son, peace be unto thy soul; thine adversity and thine afflictions shall be but a small moment.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> Then the Lord said these intriguing words to the Prophet: “The ends of the earth shall inquire after thy name.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/sacrifice-brings-forth-the-blessings-of-heaven.p11" pid="dMRmRuSytUyDHTFSy1N8RA" hash="edXQnA">Five years later, looking back on the incomplete construction of the Nauvoo Temple, Joseph knew his journey’s end was near and that he was going “like a lamb to the slaughter,” yet he was “calm as a summer’s morning.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> With assurances for his protection, he submitted to one more arrest. However, his trust was dishonored. On June 27, 1844, he and his brother Hyrum were savagely murdered in Carthage Jail.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/sacrifice-brings-forth-the-blessings-of-heaven.p12" pid="9NlMNWiUR0KrR_v-OzHkEQ" hash="87HVmQ">The ends of the earth have inquired after the name of Joseph Smith, and today the sun never sets on the worldwide membership of the restored Church of Jesus Christ. These words about the martyred Abraham Lincoln also describe the majesty of the Prophet Joseph Smith:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/sacrifice-brings-forth-the-blessings-of-heaven.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="pr742C3IpUKJJ6KA1PJVzw" hash="Lef2Jg">
            <span class="emphasis">Here was a man to hold against the world,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="OntBBxgvn0eASEFbMcNeZw" hash="kjnrNg">
            <span class="emphasis">A man to match the mountains and the sea. … </span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="uss4Ep5AUkyCqd1NhEp-lw" hash="e5k-sQ">
            <span class="emphasis">And when he fell in whirlwind, he went down</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="QhcBFRGR8kSJACdW6kaH5A" hash="nP0IOw">
            <span class="emphasis">As when a lordly cedar, green with boughs,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="mfFiq8tYd0KGv6gD-Sh-QA" hash="KUmWPw">
            <span class="emphasis">Goes down with a great shout upon the hills,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="3N5JTl-n4EGEz2WI57FOSA" hash="sj-Scg">
            <span class="emphasis">And leaves a lonesome place against the sky.</span>
            <span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/sacrifice-brings-forth-the-blessings-of-heaven.p13" pid="RQSrUq2WBUKAtraJkZm8_A" hash="qCSiZg">There can be no sacrifice greater than the atoning sacrifice of the Savior Jesus Christ. His Atonement, though incomprehensible and without equal, was this world’s crowning event. Gratefully, because of His supreme offer of charity, there is no sting of death, and the grave has no victory.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/sacrifice-brings-forth-the-blessings-of-heaven.p14" pid="U8s6Z_b8Wky4RTij63l_yQ" hash="R_eWzQ">Our challenge is to unselfishly sacrifice all that we have been given, including our will. Elder Neal A. Maxwell rightly said: “The submission of one’s will is really the only uniquely personal thing we have to place on God’s altar. The many other things we ‘give’ … are actually the things He has already given or loaned to us.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/sacrifice-brings-forth-the-blessings-of-heaven.p15" pid="OineAWBM40GnVLlbgwe_Vw" hash="Kp2Ijg">Sacrifice is ultimately a matter of the heart—the heart. “Behold, the Lord requireth the heart and a willing mind.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> If we are caring, if we are charitable, if we are obedient to God and follow His prophets, our sacrifices will bring forth the blessings of heaven. “And ye shall offer for a sacrifice unto me a broken heart and a contrite spirit.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/sacrifice-brings-forth-the-blessings-of-heaven.p16" pid="05vIdijsY0qnVHjFJDmQmQ" hash="yGxDTw">In an unusual way, I experienced a glimpse of our Savior’s sacrifice of love for me. While in Jerusalem on Christmas Eve, my wife and I visited several of the sites where the Savior walked and taught. The agony suffered by the Savior brought deep sorrow to us as we stood in the dungeon below the palace of Caiaphas. It was there that our Lord was flogged and scourged. We saw the chain holes in the wall. With tears we sang “A Poor Wayfaring Man of Grief.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> He was so alone amongst vile perpetrators. With heavy hearts we prayed for courage to be His worthy servants.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/sacrifice-brings-forth-the-blessings-of-heaven.p17" pid="o6WJoP_SzU-cwB9X21t5gw" hash="Gg9Rfg">Shortly thereafter, we visited the empty Garden Tomb. The words from the scriptures “He is not here: for he is risen”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> resounded through our hearts. Eliza R. Snow penned:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/sacrifice-brings-forth-the-blessings-of-heaven.f3">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="kR1uHFOkB0uklq8XiGFejg" hash="vQWN8w">
            <span class="emphasis">Although in agony he hung,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="DMNMFwrMZU6BclQThF_7-w" hash="FkNZIg">
            <span class="emphasis">No murm’ring word escaped his tongue.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="PGOUPr0G8kCpiXDaWSlwEQ" hash="r8pNCQ">
            <span class="emphasis">His high commission to fulfill, … </span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="2aUV6iudYUSTaWWkiq8TrA" hash="-CkLwg">
            <span class="emphasis">He magnified his Father’s will.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="HLtx-7-iTUidu8gvXoUpIA" hash="UOB97g">
            <span class="emphasis">He dies a sacrifice for sin, … </span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="-i_4gMw4cU2v_RFxKGwPWw" hash="GRN7ww">
            <span class="emphasis">That man may live and glory win.</span>
            <span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/sacrifice-brings-forth-the-blessings-of-heaven.p18" pid="Dgfzl-UVwk-WB5dl78y0uA" hash="gNmeIQ">The Savior’s Atonement was the greatest act of charity known to mankind.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/sacrifice-brings-forth-the-blessings-of-heaven.p19" pid="01jMjR2NWEOoB2Ni1z1z_Q" hash="v89D9g">We sing these words from President Gordon B. Hinckley:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/sacrifice-brings-forth-the-blessings-of-heaven.f4">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="7EMzlREdpkeJyHJq2oNolw" hash="cMtUag">
            <span class="emphasis">He lives, my one sure rock of faith,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="kgOrvVVqP0KCjYypx4iA3w" hash="_TyJyw">
            <span class="emphasis">The one bright hope of men on earth,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="qi2_JrwRNEq2ARklphy9fg" hash="qdBuGg">
            <span class="emphasis">The beacon to a better way,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="78HhCLgCXUShaWSSVVHV-A" hash="T-Y64w">
            <span class="emphasis">The light beyond the veil of death.</span>
            <span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/10/sacrifice-brings-forth-the-blessings-of-heaven.p20" pid="anNeKfAqiEOnkmkQsodOwA" hash="VVDn3g">I sorrow that a single drop of His blood was shed for me. I pray that someday I will meet the Savior. I will kneel and kiss the wounded hands and feet, and He will wipe away my tears. I pray that He will say, “Well done, thou good and faithful servant.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> Because of His mercy, we have hope, brothers and sisters. He is the “fount of every blessing.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> Of this I testify in the name of the greatest example of sacrifice, even Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2002/10/sacrifice-brings-forth-the-blessings-of-heaven</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2002-general-conference/2002-10-2050-elder-robert-k-dellenbach-64k-eng.mp3" length="5573284" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2002 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
