<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Robert S. Wood</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Robert S. Wood.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Robert%20S.%20Wood.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Robert S. Wood.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 1999 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>“The Tongue of Angels”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1999/10/the-tongue-of-angels?lang=eng</link>
      <description>What we say and how we present ourselves not only betray our inner person but also mold that person, those around us, and finally our whole society.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/the-tongue-of-angels" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_99265_000_033" doc-version="2" hash="lObAcA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/the-tongue-of-angels.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="wAh1Q8cqjEiQdNmYzirz5w" hash="ik1rkQ">“The Tongue of Angels”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="-44sHKY8G0KH-DLDpC8sxg" hash="XWVqfQ">Robert S. Wood</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="0mB87_t8IEqRuLd_-pgr9Q" hash="78tgNg">What we say and how we present ourselves not only betray our inner person but also mold that person, those around us, and finally our whole society.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/the-tongue-of-angels.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-eab.jpg" alt="Elder Robert S. Wood" pid="2GXMVqrpZUCG4cwryS0InQ" hash="t1Hl5A" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/the-tongue-of-angels.p1" pid="sfmVn94ysUSUB3el2n4KQA" hash="vx7pXA">In contrasting the importance of some of the weightier things of the kingdom with the dietary code of ancient Israel, Jesus told His disciples: “Not that which goeth into the mouth defileth a man; but that which cometh out of the mouth, this defileth a man.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/the-tongue-of-angels.p2" pid="2Muw8ouDx0GCZ6v_d6s8wA" hash="eFLZwQ">“… Those things which proceed out of the mouth come … from the heart; and they defile the man” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/15.11,18" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 15:11, 18</a>). Our words and external expressions are not neutral, for they reflect both who we are and shape who we are becoming.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/the-tongue-of-angels.p3" pid="8Iv7k38MEUejkax10tf0Rg" hash="cEAefA">In latter days, the Lord has emphasized again how, in the words of the Book of Mormon, our “outward performances” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/25.15" class="scriptureRef">Alma 25:15</a>), are defiling or edifying. What we say and how we act will create an atmosphere welcoming or hostile to the Holy Ghost. In the 88th section of the Doctrine and Covenants, the Lord counseled us to avoid “light speeches” and an “excess of laughter.” He associated such expressions with defects of the heart—“lustful desires,” “pride,” and “light-mindedness”—that finally proceed to “wicked doings” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.69,121" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:69, 121</a>). I take “light speeches” to refer to irreverent and demeaning language and “light-mindedness” to what the Lord has called trifling with sacred things (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/6.12" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 6:12</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/the-tongue-of-angels.p4" pid="lO4F_rlruUytr8jNYCvjqQ" hash="QHOC0Q">On the other hand, the Lord has called for “cheerful hearts and countenances” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/59.15" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 59:15</a>). He has asked us to so speak and so act that we edify or build one another and has indicated that “that which doth not edify is not of God, and is darkness” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/50.23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 50:23</a>). At Winter Quarters, as the Saints were in the midst of an arduous exodus, the Lord commanded, “Let your words tend to edifying one another” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/136.24" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 136:24</a>). Nephi declared that the fruit of receiving the Holy Ghost and listening to the promptings of the Spirit is that we may speak with “the tongue of angels” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/32.2" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 32:2</a>). Thus we create a spirit of reverence and of revelation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/the-tongue-of-angels.p5" pid="ukb2f7Yrx0ux-9oRALVP8Q" hash="QM1Iaw">I recently overheard a conversation among some of our young grandchildren. One of them apparently used the word <span class="emphasis">stupid.</span> Eight-year-old Nicholas, recently baptized, commented that perhaps one should not say that, as it was a “bad word.” It was evident that there had been some good influence from Mom and Dad. I know there had been similar discussions about other expressions. Now some might think that these are small matters compared to the far more foul and demeaning expressions all around us. Yet, in small and in great ways, our words are creating an atmosphere in which we build or demolish. I recently commented to a friend from New York City that I thought the atmosphere had improved markedly in the city over the past years and wondered why. He noted that his wife is a municipal judge, and they were enforcing the little things, like ordinances against spitting and jaywalking, and the big things were being affected thereby. So in our daily speech and acts of edification, the Lord said, we invite the spirit of truth and righteousness in which we “may chase darkness from among [us]” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/50.25" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 50:25</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/the-tongue-of-angels.p6" pid="5hdGwO9dSkSDNZbvLDgNHA" hash="IjxD5g">I recall when I was in a freshman English class and the professor was insisting that, to describe a situation, one of the students must substitute a crude expression for one gentler. I was jarred at an expression which I had seldom heard and never in harmonious circumstances. Years later in graduate school I had a conversation with a friend who argued that one should be, as he called it, direct, even if rude and insensitive to others’ feelings. Unfortunately, the spirit animating these incidents has taken firm hold on society and is found even among the Saints. Over the years, there has been an increase in sexual innuendos, raucous humor, violent expressions, and great noise in talk, in music, in gestures. Much around us is crude and rude, with a corruption of moral behavior and sensitivity. Society has not been improved by our “light speeches” and our “light-mindedness.” Instead, our expressions have polluted our communities and corrupted our souls.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/the-tongue-of-angels.p7" pid="WpPCAEWY506d4DCcvL5XSw" hash="_n5FxQ">President Spencer W. Kimball warned of vulgarity of speech and expression and particularly counseled against speaking of sex glibly, which he associated with immodesty. “Lewd talk and jokes,” he said, “constitute another danger which lurks seeking as its prey any who will entertain it as the first step to dirtying the mind and thus the soul” (<span class="emphasis">The Miracle of Forgiveness</span> [1969], 228).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/the-tongue-of-angels.p8" pid="OoU-8wKSNEeC844UItLLiA" hash="PSop0A">What we say and how we present ourselves not only betray our inner person but also mold that person, those around us, and finally our whole society. Every day each of us is implicated in obscuring the light or in chasing away the darkness. We have been called to invite the light and to be a light, to sanctify ourselves and edify others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/the-tongue-of-angels.p9" pid="ZZu-8QpIfUqysw28FP9ibw" hash="olQmDQ">In his general epistle, James detailed many of the things necessary to becoming holy. Among these, he included the control of language and conversation. Indeed, he said that “if any man offend not in word, the same is a perfect man, and able also to bridle the whole body” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/3.2" class="scriptureRef">James 3:2</a>). In a seagoing analogy, he noted that as a small helm can drive a great ship, so the tongue might also set our course and fate (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/james/3.4" class="scriptureRef">James 3:4</a>). Improperly employed, the tongue “defileth the whole body, and setteth on fire the course of nature” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/3.6" class="scriptureRef">James 3:6</a>). How, he asks, can the same mouth issue forth blessings and curses? (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/james/3.10" class="scriptureRef">James 3:10</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/the-tongue-of-angels.p10" pid="tu5aBEsNrkqfCcsP1EjHGw" hash="u7q9oA">I’ve been struck by the fact that when Isaiah received his charge from the Lord, he bemoaned that he was “a man of unclean lips” and dwelt “in the midst of a people of unclean lips” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/6.5" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 6:5</a>). This sin too had to be purged from Isaiah if he was to bear the word of the Lord. Is it any wonder that psalmists and prophets alike have beseeched the Lord to “set a watch” before their lips and guard the “door” of their lips (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/141.3" class="scriptureRef">Ps. 141:3</a>), to help them sin not with their tongue (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/39.1" class="scriptureRef">Ps. 39:1</a>)?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/the-tongue-of-angels.p11" pid="4X4_cG027UO6LqY11SWybw" hash="zROTjQ">When we speak and act, we should ask whether our words and expressions are calculated to invite the powers of heaven into our lives and to invite all to come unto Christ. We must treat sacred things with reverence. We need to eliminate from our conversations the immodest and the lewd, the violent and the threatening, the demeaning and the false. As the Apostle Peter wrote, “But as he which hath called you is holy, so be ye holy in all manner of conversation” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-pet/1.15" class="scriptureRef">1 Pet. 1:15</a>). The expression <span class="emphasis">conversation</span> refers here not only to speech but also to our entire comportment. As Nephi, he is inviting us to so live that we may speak with the “tongue of angels.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/the-tongue-of-angels.p12" pid="V49DLx1kRUGkMeGWA7z9Hw" hash="ZVfB6A">I bear witness that God is indeed holy. He is our Father, we His children. We are His heirs and co-heirs with Jesus Christ of His glory. Christ has borne our sins and conquered death. He has invited us to be as He is and to edify in word and in deed. With John I believe that it is our destiny that “when he shall appear, we shall be like him; for we shall see him as he is” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-jn/3.2" class="scriptureRef">1 Jn. 3:2</a>). In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1999/10/the-tongue-of-angels</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1999-general-conference/1999-10-5040-elder-robert-s-wood-64k-eng.mp3" length="4213999" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 1999 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instruments of the Lord’s Peace</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2006/04/instruments-of-the-lords-peace?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Have we who have taken upon us the name of Christ slipped unknowingly into patterns of slander, evil speaking, and bitter stereotyping?</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/instruments-of-the-lords-peace" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00006561_000_032" doc-version="3" hash="bLQFSw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/instruments-of-the-lords-peace.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="S0Qq0Sm_N0Gv-xmH9dxP_A" hash="nnpwWQ">Instruments of the Lord’s Peace</h1><p class="authorName" uuid="62ec4d8b-37bd-4d50-9312-4293b948acef" pid="vDPkVugaaEq-cWG5hARQaQ" hash="XWVqfQ">Robert S. Wood</p><p class="kicker" pid="mLrddwSZ1EOuQ9H-FDQGCA" hash="5as6ww">Have we who have taken upon us the name of Christ slipped unknowingly into patterns of slander, evil speaking, and bitter stereotyping?</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" uuid="b110a8c2-9fd7-4f1d-a79c-754c0336500e">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/instruments-of-the-lords-peace.t1" uuid="">
      <img src="en2006lp.nfo-o-e3.jpg" alt="Elder Robert S. Wood" uuid="80eeb122-ddcf-458e-a36e-405528e28d5a" pid="l4YONwlBOEiZJ_dlrSfnSA" hash="iVlEPQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/instruments-of-the-lords-peace.p1" uuid="4121615e-5e97-4b99-b25d-e9877283f932" pid="Usj9vAirv0uwYNrAmaDxaw" hash="z2GcVQ">I have a friend who is a member of a political panel that is seen each week on national television. Explaining her role, she said, “We are encouraged to speak before thinking!” We appear to be living in an era in which many are speaking without thinking, encouraging emotional reactions rather than thoughtful responses. Whether it be on the national or international stage, in personal relations or in politics, at home or in the public forum, voices grow ever more strident, and giving and taking offense appear to be chosen rather than inadvertent.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/instruments-of-the-lords-peace.p2" uuid="4156e9fa-b1fb-4692-a211-c26194d01bad" pid="xJOXd5JXyEmPyw77yBxjtA" hash="8xTThw">The Lord has warned that from the beginning and throughout history, Satan would stir up people’s hearts to anger.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> In the Book of Mormon, Laman set a pattern of so murmuring as to stir anger, to stoke rage, and to incite murder.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> Time and again in the Book of Mormon, we find deluded and wicked men inciting rage and provoking conflict. In the days of Captain Moroni, the apostate Amalickiah inspired “the hearts of the Lamanites against the people of Nephi.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Amulon and the wicked priests of Noah; Nehor; Korihor; and Zoram the apostate (the dishonor roll goes on throughout the Book of Mormon) were agitators who inspired distrust, fueled controversy, and deepened hatreds.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/instruments-of-the-lords-peace.p3" uuid="14b0bb3b-67ac-4478-a8d2-70704febf0a5" pid="OpL2rUisMEOjXQs8sfQD2g" hash="CnisWA">In speaking to Enoch, the Lord indicated that both the time of His birth and the time preceding His Second Coming would be “days of wickedness and vengeance.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> And the Lord has said that in the last days, wrath shall be poured out upon the earth without mixture.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span><span class="emphasis">Wrath</span> is defined both as the righteous indignation of God and as the very human instances of impetuous ardor and deep or violent anger. The former arises from the concern of a loving Father whose children are often “without affection, and they hate their own blood,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> whereas the latter wrath arises from a people “without order and without mercy, … strong in their perversion.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> I fear the earth is experiencing both wraths, and I suspect the divine wrath is very much provoked by those who are stirring up the hearts of men to wickedness, slander, and violent hatreds.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/instruments-of-the-lords-peace.p4" uuid="b1459a8b-f56e-405b-9974-2992bcf974de" pid="xBNwNWaDK02n5QCMLm4z1w" hash="D38ejw">The first casualties of human wrath are truth and understanding. James counseled that we be “swift to hear, slow to speak, slow to wrath: For the wrath of man worketh not the righteousness of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> As Enoch observed, God’s throne is one of peace, justice, and truth.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> Whether they be false friends or unrighteous teachers, artists or entertainers, commentators or letter writers to local newspapers, seekers of power or wealth, beware of those who stir us up to such anger that calm reflection and charitable feelings are suppressed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/instruments-of-the-lords-peace.p5" uuid="20ab0654-0177-4077-a9ae-6440a120d0c5" pid="YoIx_jS2g0u4nC2U1ZlpEw" hash="ErG3ZA">Alma at the waters of Mormon invited those who would enter into a covenant relationship with God to stand as witnesses of God and to bear one another’s burdens.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> As those who have indeed entered into a sacred covenant, we must remain true to the way, the truth, and the life, who is Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/instruments-of-the-lords-peace.p6" uuid="dd74768e-c3fe-4594-b843-5910e68d8ce1" pid="QaDiVsOjok-YrFnovFhEuQ" hash="rLH6zg">Have we who have taken upon us the name of Christ slipped unknowingly into patterns of slander, evil speaking, and bitter stereotyping? Have personal or partisan or business or religious differences been translated into a kind of demonizing of those of different views? Do we pause to understand the seemingly different positions of others and seek, where possible, common ground?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/instruments-of-the-lords-peace.p7" uuid="79fc4c2f-f1d4-4c47-80f5-5a45309c2225" pid="jSNhvMZY_02uug9G-INTMw" hash="mBUMGQ">I recall that as a graduate student I wrote a critique of an important political philosopher. It was clear that I disagreed with him. My professor told me that my paper was good, but not good enough. Before you launch into your criticism, she said, you must first present the strongest case for the position you are opposing, one that the philosopher himself could accept. I redid the paper. I still had important differences with the philosopher, but I understood him better, and I saw the strengths and virtues, as well as limitations, of his belief. I learned a lesson that I’ve applied across the spectrum of my life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/instruments-of-the-lords-peace.p8" uuid="d3779340-7112-4ecf-9acd-a4e562c33c35" pid="f-T-LxnU5kGTNCd-LlWclQ" hash="eFjCLQ">General Andrew Jackson, as he walked along the line at the Battle of New Orleans, said to his men, “Gentlemen, elevate your guns a little lower!” I think many of us need to elevate our “guns” a little lower. On the other hand, we need to raise the level of private and public discourse. We should avoid caricaturing the positions of others, constructing “straw men,” if you will, and casting unwarranted aspersions on their motivations and character. We need, as the Lord counseled, to uphold honest, wise, and good men and women wherever they are found and to recognize that there are “among all sects, parties, and denominations” those who are “kept from the truth [of the gospel] because they know not where to find it.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> Would we hide that light because we have entered into the culture of slander, of stereotyping, of giving and seeking offense?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/instruments-of-the-lords-peace.p9" uuid="914c99d9-24ea-4585-8011-4d63ed7f2ec8" pid="aHyJXO-GyEOQzWoQzLl1QQ" hash="X2pyRA">It is far too easy sometimes to fall into a spirit of mockery and cynicism in dealing with those of contrary views. We demoralize or demean so as to bring others or their ideas in contempt. It is a primary tool of those who occupy the large and spacious building that Father Lehi saw in vision.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> Jude, the brother of Christ, warned that “there should be mockers in the last time, who should walk after their own ungodly lusts. These be they who separate themselves, sensual, having not the Spirit.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/instruments-of-the-lords-peace.p10" uuid="f5f9fc07-62a9-40af-a048-f2a893b7c0c7" pid="nrJBugFCYkmtA7cwkm8NaA" hash="0CNYqw">Closely related to mockery is a spirit of cynicism. Cynics are disposed to find and to catch at fault. Implicitly or explicitly, they display a sneering disbelief in sincerity and rectitude. Isaiah spoke of those who “watch for iniquity” and “make a man an offender for a word, and lay a snare for him that reproveth in the gate, and turn aside the just for a thing of nought.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> In this regard, the Lord has counseled in latter days that we “cease to find fault one with another” and “above all things, clothe [ourselves] with the bond of charity, as with a mantle, which is the bond of perfectness and peace.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/instruments-of-the-lords-peace.p11" uuid="513eba37-7c5a-43ba-a7f7-15d3a236d258" pid="Cjr7XIZRJUqb8hCgJdcj2Q" hash="2en8gA">President George Albert Smith observed, “There is nothing in the world more deleterious or harmful to the human family than hatred, prejudice, suspicion, and the attitude that some people have toward their fellows, of unkindness.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> In matters of politics, he warned, “Whenever your politics cause you to speak unkindly of your brethren, know this, that you are upon dangerous ground.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> Speaking of the great mission of the latter-day kingdom, he counseled: “This is not a militant church to which we belong. This is a church that holds out peace to the world. It is not our duty to go into the world and find fault with others, neither to criticize men because they do not understand. But it is our privilege, in kindness and love, to go among them and divide with them the truth that the Lord has revealed in this latter day.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/instruments-of-the-lords-peace.p12" uuid="b43acf0f-94cf-4087-9d75-2224ba52fee7" pid="1JYm7v3CTUiU8xArsGu5ug" hash="6Fl1ug">The Lord has constituted us as a people for a special mission. As He told Enoch in ancient times, the day in which we live would be one of darkness, but it would also be a time when righteousness would come down from heaven, and truth would be sent forth out of the earth to bear, once more, testimony of Christ and His atoning mission. As with a flood, that message would sweep the world, and the Lord’s elect would be gathered out from the four quarters of the earth.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> Wherever we live in the world, we have been molded as a people to be the instruments of the Lord’s peace. In the words of Peter, we have been claimed by God for His own, to proclaim the triumph of Him “who hath called you out of darkness into his marvellous light: Which in time past were not a people, but are now the people of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> We cannot afford to be caught up in a world prone to give and to take offense. Rather, as the Lord revealed to both Paul and Mormon, we must neither envy nor be puffed up in pride. We are not easily provoked, nor do we behave unseemly. We rejoice not in iniquity but in the truth. Surely this is the pure love of Christ which we represent.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/instruments-of-the-lords-peace.p13" uuid="92631328-8dc6-49ad-b9dc-8d8010a6b7df" pid="6dFWLQ7ffUWcP7UFm1B3iw" hash="dvjE8Q">In a world beset by wrath, the prophet of our day, President Gordon B. Hinckley, has counseled: “Now, there is much that we can and must do in these perilous times. We can give our opinions on the merit of the situation as we see it, but never let us become a party to words or works of evil concerning our brothers and sisters in various nations on one side or the other. Political differences never justify hatred or ill will. I hope that the Lord’s people may be at peace one with another during times of trouble, regardless of what loyalties they may have to different governments or parties.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/instruments-of-the-lords-peace.p14" uuid="3bf1a9c3-1aa4-462f-bdbc-cffee5f4d143" pid="T2sTyS7BzEC9bpyrc_KoDg" hash="fA5ucA">As true witnesses of Christ in the latter days, let us not fall into the darkness so that, in the words of Peter, we “cannot see afar off,” but let us be fruitful in the testimony of Christ and His restored gospel, in thought, in speech, in deed.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span> God lives. Jesus Christ is the way, the truth, and the life. Joseph Smith, the great prophet of the Restoration, was the instrument by which we have been constituted as a people, led even today by a prophet of God, President Gordon B. Hinckley. Let us daily renew in our hearts the pure love of Christ and overcome with our Master the darkness of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/instruments-of-the-lords-peace.p15" uuid="ed4e07ec-241d-4c71-a7f8-55c643cc1207" pid="Y8TKggJMcE6nwAwa4lwXCg" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2006/04/instruments-of-the-lords-peace</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2006-general-conference/2006-04-5040-elder-robert-s-wood-64k-eng.mp3" length="6272457" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2006 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
