<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Robert C. Oaks</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Robert C. Oaks.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Robert%20C.%20Oaks.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Robert C. Oaks.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2000 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Sharing the Gospel</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2000/10/sharing-the-gospel?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Given the importance of the message, the help offered by the Spirit, the number of the missionaries and the size of the field that is ready to harvest, 300,000 new converts per year is not nearly enough.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/sharing-the-gospel" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10028166_000_034" doc-version="2" hash="mEqNYA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/sharing-the-gospel.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="93iqdhsfE06idvbEIxShtQ" hash="lHYiXw">Sharing the Gospel</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="NyRbvCi73U2AKC4r55M9nA" hash="eKo_Zg">Robert C. Oaks</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="rvXdsQshxEOY5-SoBv_j-Q" hash="Py94rg">Given the importance of the message, the help offered by the Spirit, the number of the missionaries and the size of the field that is ready to harvest, 300,000 new converts per year is not nearly enough.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/sharing-the-gospel.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-dd.jpg" alt="Elder Robert C. Oaks" pid="UD55UZRQ60-y-f65jSNdGg" hash="Oo_rvA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/sharing-the-gospel.p1" pid="rxPc_-jQhUmW-SIBf5aZ1Q" hash="swz5HA">I thrill to hear the prophet stand at this pulpit and declare how he sees the work of the Lord rolling forth to fill the earth like that stone, cut without hands, that Daniel saw in his vision (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/dan/2.34-35" class="scriptureRef">Dan. 2:34–35</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/sharing-the-gospel.p2" pid="IVncDBm3XUq0U7ntkliEhw" hash="uRCtKg">This work is driven by the Spirit of the Lord and through the operation of priesthood authority given to man. But it moves forward on the wheels of missionary work by those who have responded to the Lord’s call to “go ye into all the world, and preach the gospel to every creature” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/16.15" class="scriptureRef">Mark 16:15</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/sharing-the-gospel.p3" pid="T0HCbGNggkm0fM4NVR71rQ" hash="QSfkLQ">The gospel of Jesus Christ with all of its purity, beauty, and simplicity has been restored to the earth in these latter days through the great prophet of this dispensation, Joseph Smith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/sharing-the-gospel.p4" pid="MaNIWvH6AE-KM93gNBqTmQ" hash="j5UQ1w">We who have tasted the sweet fruits of the gospel know it as a fountain of faith, hope, and peace—a constant source of joy. Indeed, it is a rare jewel to be treasured and a rare jewel to be shared. There are 60,000 full-time missionaries engaged in the sharing process. Their efforts, coupled with those of stake missionaries and members, yielded some 300,000 new converts last year.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/sharing-the-gospel.p5" pid="897IIntfkU6rYjBvcL1pIw" hash="S34bog">But this is not enough. Given the importance of the message, the help offered by the Spirit, the number of missionaries, and the size of the field that is ready to harvest, 300,000 new converts per year is not nearly enough.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/sharing-the-gospel.p6" pid="raoC-0p8EU-Kg18IqoyLEA" hash="BDwj-g">In fact, last year President Hinckley challenged Church members to significantly increase the number of converts. We are not yet on that prophetically prompted track.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/sharing-the-gospel.p7" pid="i6jhBgZHFkO8LM3DEDN7Rw" hash="AaUmhA">This is what prophets do; they help us reach up to new heights. President David O. McKay advised, “Every member a missionary”;<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> President Kimball: “Lengthen your stride”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> and “Do it now”;<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> President Benson: “Flood … the earth with the Book of Mormon”;<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> and now President Hinckley: Increase the number of converts and retain them. Do we need more specific instructions?</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/sharing-the-gospel.f2">
	<p pid="GQ8kniX02kGnFN-rnMdC7w" hash="DcNrcw">Let me review the four-step instructions we have received regarding member-missionary work:</p>
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="xqI3sflTEEu07fWJYWhJWw" hash="W2RKcQ">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="bgz1wBrj10CsR3jbzALSAg" hash="J5AmYQ">Identify prayerfully your friends and neighbors who would be the most receptive to the gospel message.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="iP9EusBLrEeky6nfI5l6Rg" hash="VXMNFQ">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="hCXbVz7k_k27fHWWCvFCBA" hash="EmmWeA">Introduce the identified individuals to the missionaries.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="7irPtKwkYkeoObgWWewrIQ" hash="uXIYiQ">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="UQ0UaQi03UyD7va71bvnqQ" hash="sWvBUQ">Involve yourself in the teaching of the gospel, preferably in your home.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="IaxAsuvCcUmZMLOCHEpeig" hash="1Aw0Bg">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p pid="jl9X8h3FCkezgu_F0pha5g" hash="9O1yWg">Integrate your friends and any other new members into the Church by being attentive and helpful.</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/sharing-the-gospel.p8" pid="kz1a0N42U0us7Ix035CoXQ" hash="Nake0g">Through this simple, compact process we <span class="emphasis">can</span> increase the number of converts, and, more importantly, we can help the new converts achieve full fellowship. Increased member involvement is the only way to increase our current conversion rate.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/sharing-the-gospel.p9" pid="GiGzJ60oNkCeN15jEjCTgg" hash="5UnzSA">We have heard all of this many times. Why don’t we do better in providing referrals? It is not laziness, because Latter-day Saints are not lazy people. I believe that the fear of rejection or the fear of hurting a friendship are the more common restraints to sharing the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/sharing-the-gospel.p10" pid="04WtKNOeEka69dsjGeundg" hash="mq-JWg">But are these fears valid? When you extend to a friend an invitation to meet with the missionaries, you are offering to share something that is most valuable and cherished. Is that offensive? Sister Oaks and I have not found this to be the case. In fact, we have found that when we offer to share the gospel, friendships are strengthened, even though the friends may not embrace the gospel message.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/sharing-the-gospel.p11" pid="QRT2CblHL0SdjT2vRD6J0g" hash="_giyQw">Consider that you are invited to a friend’s house for breakfast. On the table you see a large pitcher of freshly squeezed orange juice from which your host fills his glass. But he offers you none. Finally, you ask, “Could I have a glass of orange juice?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/sharing-the-gospel.p12" pid="wJhmNDkXvEyDrgx5gAwJLQ" hash="f-kdKw">He replies, “Oh, I am sorry. I was afraid you might not like orange juice, and I didn’t want to offend you by offering you something you didn’t desire.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/sharing-the-gospel.p13" pid="3VW7XWAYBUCb3-EkUfkjOg" hash="AB_xrg">Now, that sounds absurd, but it is not too different from the way we hesitate to offer up something far sweeter than orange juice. I have often worried how I would answer some friend about my hesitancy when I meet him beyond the veil.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/sharing-the-gospel.p14" pid="n80a52JhI0etRvwlV0KKBw" hash="QWMbAw">A story related by Elder Christoffel Golden, of South Africa, refreshed my concerns. He was recently in Lusaka, Zambia, attending a meeting of new converts. A well-spoken, well-dressed stranger with a Book of Mormon in hand walked in. He stated he had driven past the chapel many times and had wondered what church met there and what they taught for doctrine.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/sharing-the-gospel.p15" pid="g05nz9b4gUKh94D3klWlHQ" hash="oDEvMg">At the conclusion of the meeting, this gentleman stood up, raised his copy of the Book of Mormon high in the air, and asked, “Why have you kept this book hidden from the people of Lusaka? Why have you kept it a secret?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/sharing-the-gospel.p16" pid="kIAbxkPFfESLJxoXLsT2aw" hash="_rD_Xg">As I heard this story, I flinched that one day some friend might ask me, “Why have you kept this Book of Mormon, with its message of truth and salvation, a secret?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/sharing-the-gospel.p17" pid="m96eFQ7r-EmkZxUf3sbJjw" hash="Js4vfg">My reply, “I was afraid I would damage our friendship,” will not be very satisfying to either me or my friend.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/sharing-the-gospel.p18" pid="ZlZpv88zekCUS4hNn-Yj0Q" hash="mUjocQ">Brothers and sisters, I pray that we may put our fears and our hesitancy behind us and no more keep secret the great treasure that is ours.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/sharing-the-gospel.p19" pid="0TWv0Ctxu0au73RZMVFvQg" hash="Miw0Pw">One last thought regarding missionary work: During my short time in southeast Africa, I have been overwhelmed by the remarkable service rendered by senior couple missionaries. Daily, they make significant contributions to the strengthening of the members and to rolling that stone, cut without hands, forward on its eternal course. What a mighty team for righteousness they make when joined with the younger missionaries and the local members.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/sharing-the-gospel.p20" pid="FkSFKpSNvk6nIsaujoiVUQ" hash="YyOH0A">Whether in leadership, proselyting, temple, humanitarian, welfare, or Church education service, the contribution of these experienced, testimony-bearing souls is beyond measure. And without exception I see them deriving great personal satisfaction from their service.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/sharing-the-gospel.p21" pid="fcIBbNZfFkW1fpKhdO3Beg" hash="947S_Q">If you are retired, or retirement eligible, and wondering what useful things you might do with the rest of your life, contact your bishop. Let him share with you his exciting list of missionary opportunities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/sharing-the-gospel.p22" pid="Q6qDwWpNKEaGJVZYbvLYZA" hash="3oHINg">Today, take your spouse by the hand and see if you don’t agree that the best thing for all concerned, including your grandchildren, would be for you to accept an assignment to serve the Lord as missionaries. This is His work, and He beckons us to join Him in it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/sharing-the-gospel.p23" pid="7byd8_Ni2Uit10_4O5-RHA" hash="LTYFTQ">I testify that God, our Eternal Father, and His Only Begotten Son, Jesus Christ, live. Christ came to earth and fulfilled His calling as the Redeemer of all mankind. I testify that His gospel has been restored in its fulness and that there is a living prophet, Gordon B. Hinckley, guiding this work under the direction of the Father and of the Son. And I so do, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2000/10/sharing-the-gospel</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2000-general-conference/2000-10-5050-elder-robert-c-oaks-64k-eng.mp3" length="3641593" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2000 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who’s on the Lord’s Side? Who?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The Lord needs to know on whom He can rely.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10032029_000_020" doc-version="2" hash="DM8UIQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="Qbvll2AZ-Ua8crfht3n3Ow" hash="ONbe3A">Who’s on the Lord’s Side? Who?</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="dCMWT7d5wkmzzSWcqz8oXQ" hash="eKo_Zg">Robert C. Oaks</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="bj_FPvEQREaSPc8_O9QA8A" hash="N1Z9uw">The Lord needs to know on whom He can rely.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-dd.jpg" alt="Elder Robert C. Oaks" pid="Z6EMvEo1ZUSKHL2pHUv1Sw" hash="Oo_rvA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p1" pid="x204VK6MmESKg6tWpDr-aQ" hash="x-NVtw">This evening I would like to focus my comments on a favorite hymn’s rousing call to service: “Who’s on the Lord’s side? Who? / Now is the time to show” (<span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 260).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p2" pid="QAQU4F7K8ECa1iodk8JTuQ" hash="CgDDRw">In this, the dispensation of the fulness of time, as we prepare for the final satanic battles in anticipation of the return of Christ to the earth, it is very important to know who is on the Lord’s side. The Lord needs to know on whom He can rely.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p3" pid="D6B3WRAbK0uwnrhgXJftNA" hash="6ykjkw">You would hope that every priesthood holder could be counted on to show up for service in the ranks of the Lord’s army. Today in the Church there are about three million priesthood holders, split evenly between the Aaronic and the Melchizedek Priesthoods.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p4" pid="IBMJcwl7ikyUKvGLI9T2VA" hash="rmp1-A">Unfortunately, far too many of these men, young and not so young, are missing, absent without leave, AWOL.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p5" pid="0SObCrOxFUCBfM9iNlH7bg" hash="zBSF2w">One day they each sat humbly while men of authority laid hands upon their heads and conferred the priesthood upon them. That day they all made a covenant of obedience and service with the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p6" pid="ok1E7N4YxUKhr--EwUUFeg" hash="_bHwHA">To understand the importance of these covenants we need to ask ourselves, “What is the priesthood?” Every alert deacon knows the answer to this question: The priesthood is the power to act in God’s name.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p7" pid="0lvVstf5SE-Yb59hmouZNA" hash="oaBosw">What does this mean to you deacons, teachers, and priests? First, it means you are authorized to pass, prepare, and bless the sacrament. Is this a big deal? Absolutely!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p8" pid="WAB6sHp350yS85LZ4GDWIw" hash="GS2fvA">Who administered the first sacrament service that we have any record of? Of course the answer is the Lord Jesus Christ. The evening before His suffering in the Garden of Gethsemane, Christ prepared, blessed, and passed the sacrament to His disciples. So when we perform this sacred ordinance, we are actually standing in for the Savior Himself. That is special!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p9" pid="-KF15pdw1Eep5VvH6FnEgQ" hash="ReI2yg">John the Baptist laid his hands on the heads of Joseph Smith and Oliver Cowdery and conferred upon them the priesthood of Aaron and declared, “I confer the Priesthood of Aaron, which holds the keys of the ministering of angels, and of the gospel of repentance, and of baptism by immersion for the remission of sins” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/13.1" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 13:1</a>). That is a significant responsibility for men of any age. With that charge, we are clearly on the Lord’s side.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p10" pid="phQ1gc6Rv0e4A6S3GqtC8w" hash="YZzQQw">What of the Melchizedek Priesthood? The 84th section of the Doctrine and Covenants reads, “And this greater priesthood administereth the gospel and holdeth the key of the mysteries of the kingdom, even the key of the knowledge of God” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.19" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:19</a>). This priesthood holds the power to administer and lead, to bless and to heal, to teach and to seal. These priesthood service activities clearly place the practicing brethren on the Lord’s side.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p11" pid="_dITXxlNHk2Bn9Cf8xcPnQ" hash="Zq5AHA">One of the greatest examples of priesthood sealing power is the story of Nephi, son of Helaman. Because of his diligence in declaring the word of God, the Lord gave him sealing power that “whatsoever ye shall seal on earth shall be sealed in heaven; and whatsoever ye shall loose on earth shall be loosed in heaven” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/10.7" class="scriptureRef">Hel. 10:7</a>). Nephi would have been a mighty leader in the Lord’s army in any dispensation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p12" pid="lywIhe6MeEuIlb78inYTiQ" hash="RxG-Jw">What a great act of trust it is on the part of our Father in Heaven to share with us a part of His power, that we might assist Him in His grand work as it rolls forth to fill the earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p13" pid="1K_sMH_CIUCGTo7YhGUfng" hash="u9fyww">Note how carefully we have been instructed on how to confer priesthood authority. When I turned 12 years old, my father, Charles Oaks, and my bishop, George Collard, laid their hands on my head and conferred upon me the Aaronic Priesthood and ordained me a deacon.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p14" pid="aPjn6xguoEC97uuLcGYhkQ" hash="lpw3RQ">Several years later, then Elder Gordon B. Hinckley used this same heavenly directed procedure to ordain me a Seventy. Each ordination reflects additional divine trust and a new opportunity to serve on the Lord’s side.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p15" pid="dTNQcmJC9UaW5fHWNCYQCw" hash="bKnV6w">When armies are formed, battles are generally fought on vast battlefields. But this battle for souls is quite different. The conflict goes on each day in individual lives and pits the Lord’s troops against Satan’s forces of greed, selfishness, and lust.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p16" pid="vnIZLsXpL0CrYxzbsda9Cw" hash="6xR9AA">The muscular young men of Helaman’s 2,060 stripling warriors, shoulder to shoulder, imply the need for great physical strength to join their ranks. But there is room for every stout-hearted soul in this endeavor.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p17" pid="srxyD9ak_E2_sNXDlEltzA" hash="1EjllA">We have an 11-year-old grandson, Andrew, who is confined to a wheelchair, maybe for the rest of his life. He will be ordained a deacon in the fall and will join the priesthood army of the Lord. His physical handicap will not limit him in this war, because the weapons of choice are not spears and swords wielded on a chaotic field of battle.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p18" pid="0KYvmGLVMkGkdAccYKU2tA" hash="QWRnDg">Rather, the weapons of eternal worth reflecting the whole armor of God are <span class="emphasis">truth, righteousness, faith, prayer,</span> and the <span class="emphasis">word of God</span> (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/6.13-18" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 6:13–18</a>). These weapons are wielded in our minds, mouths, and movements. Every righteous thought, word, and deed is a victory for the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p19" pid="5HzaXvupoEass-0XDk_Awg" hash="a32Zmg">That is why Andrew has no handicap in this battle. His parents have taught him well. He stands ready to join the ranks of the priesthood brethren.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p20" pid="I4esHPXknECAcdcwFnLjyg" hash="dYYlxA">The stakes are extremely high. The prizes are the very souls of the sons and daughters of God, their eternal salvation. And these souls will be won or lost on the basis of virtue and cleanliness, on the basis of charity and service, and on the basis of faith and hope.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p21" pid="7y2QTyjlUEOjGEi5QR9mLw" hash="9bEC6Q">Andrew will join the deacons quorum in his home ward. They will teach him to pass the sacrament and to collect fast offerings. They will look after him, because that is what priesthood quorums are all about—caring for one another. In fact that is how the Lord’s priesthood army is organized, into quorums.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p22" pid="GEbmF1AU1U2gfuqk8RtUcQ" hash="FfCZgw">I spent a majority of my life as a pilot in the United States Air Force. The men of my squadron remain, to this day, a tight-knit group, keeping in close touch after 40 years.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p23" pid="WpkImeXCUUKx_wPaD89CYw" hash="UBIF5Q">In our training as fighter pilots, one of the first and most basic rules was, “Take care of your wingman. Constantly check his six o’clock to make certain no enemy is sneaking up behind him.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p24" pid="r2hDgEW1e0und3T09hCHHQ" hash="tjyAaA">If it is good advice to protect comrades in a fighter squadron, it is great advice to stay close to and protect our quorum members as we strive to stand firm on the Lord’s side. We should be eager to go out and find them when they stray.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p25" pid="MY6Je3rP-UCC0fo5lyAFFQ" hash="Ibr4BQ">Standing firm on the Lord’s side is especially valuable today. Our prophet regularly points out that these are the last days. We know from the signs of the times that the end is drawing near. And Satan knows it as well. He and his forces never seem to sleep.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p26" pid="pyo2P2Xa3UWfoTEMNOSjAw" hash="QMuCJw">In a worldwide priesthood leadership training meeting, President Hinckley, noting the immoral conditions in the world, stated, “I do not know that things were worse in the times of Sodom and Gomorrah.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p27" pid="eOQPK9BYw0u0x5jfw63N4A" hash="1A_F2A">He went on to say, “They and their wicked inhabitants were annihilated. We see similar conditions today. They prevail all across the world. I think our Father must weep as He looks down upon His wayward sons and daughters” (“Standing Strong and Immovable,” <span class="emphasis">Worldwide Leadership Training Meeting,</span> Jan. 10, 2004, 20).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p28" pid="wIc0r4AgZE24HxpgXVEx2A" hash="9ixwLA">I do not know how much more our prophet has to say for us to consider ourselves warned.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p29" pid="tZXBgfabR0OnGQ_Rne6FXg" hash="xUD2fg">In a recent conference talk, Elder Dallin H. Oaks stated: “These signs of the Second Coming are all around us and seem to be increasing in frequency and intensity. … While we are powerless to alter the fact of the Second Coming and unable to know its exact time, we can accelerate our own preparation and try to influence the preparation of those around us. We need to make both temporal and spiritual preparation for the events prophesied at the time of the Second Coming” (“Preparation for the Second Coming,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 2004, 7–9).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p30" pid="WNb1Hx4u10esELYZFAcIWw" hash="1ceU9Q">And these statements of warning came well before a season of unprecedented hurricane destruction in the Caribbean area and the tsunami devastation in East Asia.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p31" pid="Jsg0SD5Hmka4tYjfBu_ojg" hash="GZvBjg">Our hymn “Who’s on the Lord’s Side?” instructs us, “Now is the time to show.” Now is the time to stand fast in our faith and on our principles, as did Captain Moroni. We are needed <span class="emphasis">now,</span> deacons, teachers, priests, bishops, elders, high priests, and patriarchs. Now is the time to show our appreciation for the atoning sacrifice of our Lord Jesus Christ. Now is the time to show our faith through our obedience to such basic commandments as the laws of chastity and tithing, the Word of Wisdom, and keeping the Sabbath day holy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p32" pid="ZibCh16YzU2XcqGSCkb0IA" hash="wWzXMQ">Now is the time to warn our neighbors by sharing the gospel message with them. Now is the time to provide the world with an example of decency and modesty, an example of virtue and cleanliness. We should never squander our priesthood power, wallowing in the corruptive, corrosive filth and slime of pornography.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p33" pid="rxFk2rjVfE-QLYbXPW64Xg" hash="DLLYPA">Now is the time to review the covenants we have made with the Lord at the waters of baptism, covenants we made when we accepted the oath and covenant of the priesthood, and covenants we have made in His holy temples.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p34" pid="-6b4jbRQSE2dqrdFipmBvg" hash="N0hvkw">Now is indeed the time to show we are on the Lord’s side.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who.p35" pid="FuzFxbrGEE6cnQ3HdVdwcw" hash="3xbxGg">Brethren, this is His work. The gospel of Jesus Christ has been restored in its fulness in these last days through the Prophet Joseph Smith. Christ stands at the head of this Church, leading it forward through His living prophet, Gordon B. Hinckley. Christ will return to the earth to rule and reign, and we will each, one day, stand before Him to be judged on our thoughts, our deeds, and the desires of our hearts. He is our Savior and our Redeemer, and I so testify in His holy name, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2005/04/whos-on-the-lords-side-who</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2005-general-conference/2005-04-3030-elder-robert-c-oaks-64k-eng.mp3" length="5034154" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2005 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Patience</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Patience may well be thought of as a gateway virtue, contributing to the growth and strength of its fellow virtues of forgiveness, tolerance, and faith.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00006562_000_008" doc-version="2" hash="EtBW8Q">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="9CRIyJIm8EqVui3WBlpsZg" hash="InrpGg">The Power of Patience</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Rs0_YiVN7kKrblc47LFlYw" hash="eKo_Zg">Robert C. Oaks</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="8hOZYjN5qEucbL0030f0pg" hash="O2zqOg">Patience may well be thought of as a gateway virtue, contributing to the growth and strength of its fellow virtues of forgiveness, tolerance, and faith.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience.t1">
      <img src="OaksRC_all.ob.jpg" alt="Elder Robert C. Oaks" pid="k5Q0MLE47kuS5xK0WLjg2w" hash="8n0_hg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience.p1" pid="1C0t2ruopkSh20uD4soi5A" hash="xoht9Q">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="15"></span>How thankful I am for latter-day scriptures regarding core Christian virtues.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience.p2" pid="IlCwdJCbeEuokfUi36_DtQ" hash="QidkjQ">The Book of Mormon provides insight into the relationship between patience and charity. Mormon, after pointing out that if a man “have not charity he is nothing; wherefore he must needs have charity,” goes on to name the 13 elements of charity, or the pure love of Christ. I find it most interesting that 4 of the 13 elements of this must-have virtue relate to patience (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.44-45" class="scriptureRef">Moroni 7:44–45</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience.p3" pid="MAq6lh96W0q0YlKbcswZiQ" hash="xAxQfA">First, “charity suffereth long.” That is what patience is all about. Charity “is not easily provoked” is another aspect of this quality, as is charity “beareth all things.” And finally, charity “endureth all things” is certainly an expression of patience (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.45" class="scriptureRef">Moroni 7:45</a>). From these defining elements it is evident that without patience gracing our soul, we would be seriously lacking with respect to a Christlike character.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience.p4" pid="Xlp2FlpZX0-yMBjecVjang" hash="4MudmA">In the Bible Job offers the classic portrait of patience. In the face of losing his vast empire, including his children, Job was able, because of his unfailing faith, to proclaim, “The Lord gave, and the Lord hath taken away; blessed be the name of the Lord.” Through all of his tribulation and pain, “Job sinned not, nor charged God foolishly” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/job/1.21-22" class="scriptureRef">Job 1:21–22</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience.p5" pid="fc64MhzyU0KLCc73VnXHHg" hash="14yEVw">How often do we hear oppressed souls ask foolishly, “How could God do this to me?” when really they should be praying for strength to “beareth” and “endureth all things.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience.p6" pid="eZQSWYxQ-0Ck2FpzWVhXHw" hash="HVuDew">The greatest scriptural examples of patience are found in the life of Jesus Christ. His long-suffering and endurance are best demonstrated on that excruciating night in Gethsemane as He uttered, in His atoning agony, “O my Father, if it be possible, let this cup pass from me: nevertheless not as I will, but as thou wilt” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/26.39" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 26:39</a>). He truly suffered and bore and endured all things.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience.p7" pid="YCEmBBfz7kG1od01AYaySA" hash="r2eMGQ">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="16"></span>While nailed to the cross on Calvary, Christ continued in His perfect example of patience as He uttered the singular words, “Father, forgive them; for they know not what they do” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/23.34" class="scriptureRef">Luke 23:34</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience.p8" pid="6NJOeGTuhky9wygW_sUnmg" hash="J5Lgbw">These examples of patience have greater meaning for us when we consider the admonition found in 3 Nephi: “Therefore, what manner of men ought ye to be? Verily I say unto you, even as I am” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/27.27" class="scriptureRef">3 Nephi 27:27</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience.p9" pid="h2ofp-AHF0uo0wPgmRdPiQ" hash="TOMDVA">Several scriptures highlight the importance of patience. Let me mention a few:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience.p10" pid="QGm4XiLoTk-7PW7qgqkV9w" hash="-k4l2g">“Let every man be swift to hear, slow to speak, slow to wrath” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/james/1.19" class="scriptureRef">James 1:19</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience.p11" pid="GYfq8WlpnUeEt6HEtMFzZA" hash="XdJ4DQ">“Nevertheless the Lord seeth fit to chasten his people; yea, he trieth their patience and their faith” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/23.21" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 23:21</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience.p12" pid="tFzTacoj10-dVsgNnLUwog" hash="jP_esg">In Mosiah, King Benjamin instructs us that we will be a natural-man enemy of God until we yield to the enticings of the Holy Ghost through our patience, plus other virtues (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/3.19" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 3:19</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience.p13" pid="sR6qs0azwEiH0Gq1kT4jzw" hash="9xOOOw">Joseph Smith stated, “Patience is heavenly” (<span class="emphasis">History of the Church,</span> 6:427).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience.p14" pid="agKES3Vzg0WL7U5DlgC_Hg" hash="HQkbOA">Is patience important and worthy of our pondering and pursuit? It certainly is if we would avoid the demeaning classification of “nothing” used to label those without charity. It is if we desire to be less a natural-man enemy of God. It is if we would be heavenly. It is if we would seek to become after the manner of Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience.p15" pid="2QNlQ6hYMEi7H3ZKPFi1lQ" hash="w0Vn1g">The impatient, natural man is all about us. We see it manifest in news reports of parents, in a fit of rage, abusing a child, even unto death. On our highways, incidents of mobile impatience, or road rage, result in violent accidents and sometimes fatalities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience.p16" pid="1g54uAPNz0-LxGJ-Y3SsJg" hash="qrG3Gg">On a less dramatic but much more common level are flared tempers and harsh words uttered in response to slow-moving customer lines, never-ending telephone solicitation calls, or children reluctant to respond to our instructions. Do any of these sound familiar?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience.p17" pid="w3zY8zvZiE2K37OUqrwjEA" hash="rrpcoA">Fortunately, there are seldom-reported but marvelous-to-consider stories of great patience. Recently I attended the funeral of a lifelong friend. His son told a beautiful story of parental patience. When the son was in his youth, his dad owned a motorcycle dealership. One day they received a shipment of shiny new motorcycles, and they lined them all up in the store. The boy did what every boy would like to do, and he climbed up on the closest one. He even started it up. Then, when he figured he had pushed his luck far enough, he jumped off. To his dismay, his dismount knocked the first bike down. Then, like a string of dominoes, they all went down, one after another. His dad heard the commotion and looked out from behind the partition where he was working. Slowly, smiling, he said, “Well, son, we had better fix one up and sell it, so we can pay for the rest of them.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience.p18" pid="lqONVFTYvU-V3Gn0A0jNTw" hash="Gj3piw">I think my friend’s response personifies parental patience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience.p19" pid="xemn_A7EaEact_aHgQqIYQ" hash="NecdXA">Patience may well be thought of as a gateway virtue, contributing to the growth and strength of its fellow virtues of forgiveness, tolerance, and faith. When Peter asked Christ how many times he should forgive his brother, Christ replied, “Seventy times seven,” rather than the mere seven times that Peter had offered (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/18.21-22" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 18:21–22</a>). To forgive seventy times seven certainly takes a large measure of patience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience.p20" pid="RjdvyRhnOEOnMhqlRCtx3Q" hash="HUIC7g">Elder Neal A. Maxwell linked patience and faith together when he taught: “Patience is tied very closely to faith in our Heavenly Father. Actually, when we are unduly impatient, we are suggesting that we know what is best—better than does God. Or, at least, we are asserting that our <span class="pageBreak" page-number="17"></span>timetable is better than His” (“Patience,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Oct. 1980, 28).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience.p21" pid="ijsLZxYvdkah5meImSSEJQ" hash="j2hF6Q">We can grow in faith only if we are willing to wait patiently for God’s purposes and patterns to unfold in our lives, on His timetable.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience.p22" pid="1vtyMqir_ECij_oP9UfGyQ" hash="6FiqKw">Since impatience is so natural, how do we develop the divine virtue of patience? How do we move our behavior from that of the natural man to that of our patient, perfect example, Jesus Christ?</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience.f2">
	<p pid="LxxPRoeLYEWl0ug_G9P0dQ" hash="hqvvYQ">First, we must understand that to do so is necessary, if we desire to fully enjoy the blessings of the restored gospel. Such an understanding might motivate us to:</p>
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="llqGJCmNnUe1bxcXgbnjNA" hash="5KKnYw">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="5IHY26GmrEuUC3L26QGc5A" hash="HmPEDQ">Read each of the scriptures in the Topical Guide listed under the topic “patience” and then ponder Christ’s patient examples.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="WlREd7YOwEGSOA0S-Auk5Q" hash="PMsU5g">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="uzwkQvntlkCjcQZdWz6oUw" hash="JA1CJg">Evaluate ourselves to determine where we stand on the patience continuum. How much more patience do we need to become more Christlike? This self-assessment is difficult. We might ask our spouse or another family member to help us.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="4i_cL4qKR0aFZX-Q15AF0g" hash="IwsgGw">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="XGLG6Fo8c06_cHy20596EA" hash="3a7Rtg">Become sensitive to the examples of patience and of impatience that occur around us every day. We should strive to emulate those individuals we consider to be patient.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="-kjFRnckOkqSYc8wYg5hcA" hash="hiGC3A">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p pid="4CPjYemLDk-vu6IuLiJkZA" hash="U86Ogg">Recommit each day to become more patient, and be certain to keep our selected family member involved in our patience project.</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience.p23" pid="tpgtSNm_oU2fHVQp9Xj0gQ" hash="S72x3Q">This sounds like a great deal of work, but to achieve any worthwhile goal requires hard work. And overcoming the natural man and working to become more Christlike in our patience is a most appropriate objective. I pray that we will pursue this path with diligence and dedication.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience.p24" pid="o-GWqohR1U2Y-NQ35ue_Pw" hash="r4enyA">I testify that Jesus is the Christ and that He stands at the head of this Church, guiding us through a living prophet and blessing our every effort to become more Christlike. And I so testify in the holy name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2006/10/the-power-of-patience</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2006-general-conference/2006-10-1060-elder-robert-c-oaks-64k-eng.mp3" length="4350059" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2006 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
