<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Ronald E. Poelman</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Ronald E. Poelman.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Ronald%20E.%20Poelman.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Ronald E. Poelman.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Apr 1978 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 1978 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>“I Did Not Reach This Place By Myself”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1978/04/i-did-not-reach-this-place-by-myself?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The Savior of us all invites each of us individually to come to him and asks us to bring to him “a broken heart and a contrite spirit.” (.) Never before have I sensed the significance of that invitation and request to the extent that I do now. At the</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/i-did-not-reach-this-place-by-myself" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03096_000_017" doc-version="2" hash="cpXhRg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/i-did-not-reach-this-place-by-myself.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="nbmWzXHS-0Ofrq6WObBHiw" hash="Jb8FWg">“I Did Not Reach This Place By Myself”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="e8PPiSW75EuoOqyzU4WXXQ" hash="4c4ENw">Ronald E. Poelman</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/i-did-not-reach-this-place-by-myself.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2ab8.jpg" alt="Elder Ronald E. Poelman" pid="vkiK2Pspqk2pDQ-fv9PXsQ" hash="GUYPhA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/i-did-not-reach-this-place-by-myself.p1" pid="UiIKprqnNUieRoc6gQtcNQ" hash="79Xb5A">The Savior of us all invites each of us individually to come to him and asks us to bring to him “a broken heart and a contrite spirit.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/59.8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 59:8</a>.) Never before have I sensed the significance of that invitation and request to the extent that I do now. At the same time, I feel a surge of strength and renewal for which I am profoundly grateful.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/i-did-not-reach-this-place-by-myself.p2" pid="BeKDxZKLVUCGnsqxA0Na_Q" hash="cY1heg">I accept this calling with faith and hope. Like the little turtle who found himself on the top of a fence post, I know that I did not reach this place by myself.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/i-did-not-reach-this-place-by-myself.p3" pid="NZFTVdBQjka8OR1pkQhmUg" hash="2yP25w">To my beloved family, friends, teachers, leaders, and associates, I feel intense gratitude and devotion beyond my power to express. As I review my life thus far, it seems to have been much more difficult and much more fulfilling than I could have anticipated. I only pray that the cumulative experiences of this life have prepared me in some way for what lies ahead. For now, I am called by the prophet of God to full-time, lifetime service in the cause of the Savior, and I have a sense of inadequacy which makes me realize that the preparation for this service has only just begun.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/i-did-not-reach-this-place-by-myself.p4" pid="Spet2-opxkSTwE95VV0iPQ" hash="yaoiYA">To President Kimball, the other General Authorities, and to each of you, I feel great appreciation for your sustaining vote, and I pledge to you my best effort in any assignments which may come to me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1978/04/i-did-not-reach-this-place-by-myself.p5" pid="Fh44GdxTfEeLludqR_vGYA" hash="hOQQ8w">Nearly thirty years ago, in response to my earnest study and fervent prayer, the Holy Spirit confirmed to me the fact that Jesus of Nazareth is the Son of God, the Savior and Redeemer of each individual soul. From that conviction, and by that same Spirit, has followed the knowledge that his gospel is eternally true, that it has been restored to the earth, that the scriptures—which I love—including the Book of Mormon, are divine records, that Joseph Smith and his successors, including Spencer W. Kimball, are prophets of God, and that our Heavenly Father loves us individually. For this knowledge I give thanks and leave you my personal witness that these things are true, in the name of our beloved Savior, the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1978/04/i-did-not-reach-this-place-by-myself</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1978-general-conference/1978-04-2090-elder-ronald-e-poelman-64k-eng.mp3" length="1659351" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 1978 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Priesthood Councils: Key to Meeting Temporal and Spiritual Needs</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The ancient Nephite prophet King Benjamin counseled those who had accepted the Savior and received a remission of their sins with these words: “For the sake of retaining a remission of your sins from day to day, … I would that ye should impart of you</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03122_000_040" doc-version="2" hash="ASlNeg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="bMkM3DlxbU-VNfi7SzzsQA" hash="LRSchw">Priesthood Councils:</h1>
    <p class="subtitle" pid="xWMZVGKw_kWpeEYTeM7CPA" hash="VlfGFA">Key to Meeting Temporal and Spiritual Needs</p>
    <p class="authorName" pid="zYytamEsLUGw0DNmRztRiw" hash="4c4ENw">Ronald E. Poelman</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2ab8.jpg" alt="Elder Ronald E. Poelman" pid="Coz-JKHdrEa2xQ4F4pN6bQ" hash="GUYPhA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p1" pid="J5XUBB2P20mbBsNLBqPLSQ" hash="CG2Tqw">The ancient Nephite prophet King Benjamin counseled those who had accepted the Savior and received a remission of their sins with these words: “For the sake of retaining a remission of your sins from day to day, … I would that ye should impart of your substance to the poor, every man according to that which he hath, … administering to their relief, both spiritually and temporally. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p2" pid="6-8VVxp5GUGXFf-2rmVqXg" hash="DYsbzQ">“And see that all these things are done in wisdom and order” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/4.26-27" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 4:26–27</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p3" pid="bAJdQQJPSk-CC0G2P9DOEA" hash="K3m1ew">Our living prophet of God, Spencer W. Kimball, has said to us who also have hope in Christ: “Welfare Services is not a program, but the essence of the gospel. <span class="emphasis">It is the gospel in action.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p4" pid="L5k53Qr_0U-fetl1Fk5-qw" hash="hNebiw">“It is the crowning principle of a Christian life” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> 1977, p. 77).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p5" pid="tPIzqRmofE-qecmiTz7rcw" hash="Xfr-jQ">How then may we, in wisdom and order, most effectively use welfare services to administer to the spiritual and temporal needs of the poor?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p6" pid="lKNtPIf8UU6Ox4LskF4EsA" hash="ezx8pQ">The answer is found in priesthood councils.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p7" pid="Cg6UW9zl_UGZJKxPJ4oPLA" hash="cUS5Fw">One year ago the area council became the primary council in the field to correlate, coordinate, plan, and resolve problems. Now, a year later, we may consider how the area council is actually functioning, and, more specifically, its role in (1) welfare services master planning, (2) teaching gospel principles germane to welfare services, and (3) coordinating the welfare services efforts of temporal and ecclesiastical officers.</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="qZWDYwNwvEy44cCDDSauhA" hash="_ID_3w">How the councils work</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p8" pid="VIpFLwEV20-hDLG7xp1Pmg" hash="8AsJpw">Personal experience suggests that the principal, immediate benefit from a renewed emphasis on Church councils is the opportunity to coordinate the efforts of temporal and ecclesiastical officers. Through councils, Church leaders can better work together to teach the doctrines, principles, and practices of welfare services and to plan for a great upsurge in accomplishments. The enduring personal friendships which develop during this effort evoke our noblest sentiments.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p9" pid="-Xob6Bto_0OkFv4J4N7AJQ" hash="E9jTSQ">The Regional Representatives and General Authority Executive Administrator for an area, addressing their welfare services responsibilities, may rely heavily on the Welfare Services area director.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p10" pid="u2lYQE5aYEm5isg5mQSnDw" hash="nkv7UA">In our first area council meeting, an executive planning committee was appointed, including selected Welfare Services region agents and certain specialists chosen from the area. Also, a timetable was adopted.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p11" pid="68x13nVej0CqjZWKqeNKAw" hash="8g77Ow">Coordinated by this committee, the region agents identified needs and resources and received guidance from region councils and from individual priesthood leaders.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p12" pid="4FMyvA74-EKfW1UOhB4bLA" hash="b2vt4Q">The specialists then organized the information in a format provided by the General Welfare Services Committee and produced a proposed area-wide phase 1 (or strategic) master plan for consideration, modification, and, finally, approval by the area council.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p13" pid="6DX-YtsPkUufXAPlbKViMA" hash="LMXrVg">Following such approval, the proposed plan will be presented to each region council in the area, and then, by a Regional Representative, to each stake welfare services committee and bishop’s council for review and approval. Finally, this phase 1 (or strategic) plan will be submitted to the General Welfare Services Committee.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p14" pid="guqq33Z4BUyP00-0bPzokw" hash="QC22fQ">Once the approval of that committee has been obtained, we will begin phase 2, or the operational master plan.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="HbukQbOCPUezCOX2fk1mBQ" hash="k22ysg">Planning and goals</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p15" pid="z9zJaDuOz0ytuouazeIpYQ" hash="uOt8Zw">As planning develops, a need is recognized to perform more effectively that which the Lord has already taught us; for example, to provide meaningful work for more of those receiving assistance and to improve the productivity of our present resources.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p16" pid="6MvBRKWqP0i-SoJW45EiZQ" hash="GHcXtg">Both improving the present system and planning for additional accomplishment require that principles which pertain to welfare services be taught more effectively.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p17" pid="MyaMV1OjXU2d6WAlYUC4VQ" hash="5MX4Zg">Therefore, our area council adopted a formal teaching plan which includes specific doctrines, principles, and practices to be taught; identifies by whom, to whom, and when the teaching shall occur; and involves everyone in the priesthood line and Relief Society presidents.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p18" pid="HL_bSHLt1kaKkj9gdJ0RKg" hash="iNxqzw">Concurrently, a family guide for emergency preparedness is being compiled. Suggestions on how to implement it and a schedule for delivering it through the priesthood line into every home are also being prepared. This project, not yet finally approved by our area council, is intended to be a first step toward more complete family preparedness, the foundation of welfare services.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p19" pid="VH2FMHKT0EOCRkDQn3v8vg" hash="ngwaRg">Also, the first annual service evaluation of welfare services by ecclesiastical leaders was recently conducted to determine what is succeeding and what can be improved.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p20" pid="eTbxfBxicUWlBrD7Vd8ncg" hash="6awglg">A master plan is our principal tool in purposeful preparation. Its organized data, including a detailed capital budget, enables the council to make informed decisions, to accurately measure progress, and to wisely allocate resources according to correct priorities.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.t4">
        <h3 class="title" pid="KS2_cBZ920-utsgVanGbjA" hash="Amh7_Q">Spiritual preparation</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p21" pid="8w6KJWKhoEmi4Gd3Iu1Nng" hash="66VgyA">The plan defines goals and procedures which have been adopted by common consent, prepares us for a higher purpose, and enables us to serve more individuals in an expanding circle. Thus, the plan becomes the vision of the heart, and we have increased awareness of inspiring concepts which, though not new, come to us with invigorating freshness.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p22" pid="NXJ_BMajiE-cZpsKDhk3Pg" hash="25IkAQ">As we carefully and prayerfully develop a plan to prepare for the times of stress that are ahead, the magnitude of the challenge may seem overwhelming. Providing even temporary assistance to 15 percent or perhaps even 30 percent of the Church members may seem beyond our capability. However, in addition, we must plan to provide meaningful work for those who become unemployed and to assist with the physical, emotional, and social problems that inevitably accompany periods of economic stress.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p23" pid="pGbSnCQztESo7Q25PwwsOA" hash="VBsotw">However, “the Lord giveth no commandments unto the children of men, save he shall prepare a way for them that they may accomplish the thing which he commandeth them” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/3.7" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 3:7</a>). Coordinating our effort as temporal and ecclesiastical officers in area councils, we can accept the commandment and find the way.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p24" pid="HzOeDiiggUKFfoFz38u5hw" hash="aKn2BQ">The wisdom of Solomon advises that “where there is no vision, the people perish” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/29.18" class="scriptureRef">Prov. 29:18</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p25" pid="V076zZ_Vm0mCzU-Dfjls0A" hash="rYD_Yg">The Lord through his prophets has warned us of stressful times to come and has provided us with the organization, principles, and direction to prepare. When we seek the Spirit of the Lord in welfare services work we will be blessed with vision and the people will not perish. If we are prepared, we need not fear (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/38.30" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 38:30</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p26" pid="wy50zgg1fE6GzfBB20k3cA" hash="3c7Ctw">Spiritual preparation is not complete, however, until we have done all that we can to prepare temporally. Then what is lacking will be supplied by the Lord.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.t5">
        <h3 class="title" pid="hGTVlzFoL065EdAUVxtKKA" hash="N0unvw">Councils foster unity</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p27" pid="AUur5-yX00GDQqKDHCcqJQ" hash="8xQV7g">Unity in temporal matters, as in spiritual matters, is essential to our success. At each step, consensus of the council members must be obtained, through prayer and discussion, to achieve that unity which is prerequisite to the Lord’s help. To be effective, decisions must be reached by divine consensus, not by compromise. Participants are not competing advocates, representing special interests, but rather contributing members of a unified body.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p28" pid="XUFW3rVMUkyaSWn-eSj1hg" hash="Qb4hlw">The priesthood council is a form of management unique to the divine Church. It assembles to receive the Lord’s law by the prayer of faith, to agree upon his word, and to learn how to govern the Church and have all things right before the Lord (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/41.2-3" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 41:2–3</a>). The council’s strength and effectiveness derive from coordinating individual skills and abilities united with a shared purpose.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p29" pid="qV2mAPB16UqoDfnlefO2CA" hash="xKdUsw">“For all have not every gift given unto them; for there are many gifts, and to every man is given a gift by the Spirit of God.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p30" pid="EWXjGt4JAUKl5gOv8NSNbQ" hash="Kd-32w">“To some is given one, and to some is given another, that <span class="emphasis">all</span> may be profited thereby” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/46.11-12" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 46:11–12</a>; italics added).</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.t6">
        <h3 class="title" pid="xldyqTYN_Uy73lkjuREDqQ" hash="I49wmg">All things are spiritual</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p31" pid="wI421BzgS06Nwx3UoXsD3g" hash="tbxhSw">It is of fundamental importance to remember that there are temporal aspects to each spiritual calling and spiritual aspects to every temporal calling. In the words of Brigham Young: “If a man is called … to manufacture the clothing that is necessary for the Saints, and he goes at that business with his eye single to the building up of the kingdom of God on the earth he is entitled to the Spirit of the Holy Gospel, and he will receive and enjoy it just as much as if he were preaching the Gospel. … [He will have] the spirit to know how to raise sheep, to procure the wool, to put machinery in operation to make the clothing for the advancement, benefit and building up of the people of God on the earth. And the Spirit of the Lord is here in these labors—farming, merchandizing and in all mechanical business just as much as it is in preaching the Gospel, if men will live for it” (in <span class="emphasis">Journal of Discourses,</span> 11:293–94).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p32" pid="0EeRD7N-zE-N0PpZeNiYqQ" hash="8oeCKw">The challenge and opportunity of welfare services master planning become evident when, as the plan emerges, we realize that by mortal standards the task is impossible, the need too great, the resources insufficient. It is then we know that we must step up to a higher level spiritually.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p33" pid="0vXu0NWGMEeEsWO1iN6NCw" hash="YPszHg">The Lord tells us in section 70 of the Doctrine and Covenants that an abundance of the manifestation of the Spirit among us depends upon our willingness to share temporal blessings (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/70.12-14" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 70:12–14</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p34" pid="ZRTdyhXJ30u84A9L7wRHjw" hash="8VX3uQ">Therefore, we must sacrifice our narrow traditions, local interests, and selfish pride to achieve the love and unity indispensable in a Zion society. The principles of love, service, work, self-reliance, consecration, and stewardship must relate to a specific plan, in a particular area, to serve individual needs with well-managed resources. Personal and family preparedness and local self-sufficiency must be related to identified communities, families, production projects, and storehouses.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p35" pid="hdbjNk9ykkKPr5ciT5tZzQ" hash="85SGsA">The abstract becomes concrete when we identify welfare services principles with people, places, and things we know. Temporal application of spiritual laws transforms theology into religion.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs.p36" pid="AfeJSg90NEeNhhC23YD_9Q" hash="GlgbKw">Through priesthood councils we may, in wisdom and order, most effectively use welfare services to administer to the spiritual and temporal needs of the poor, thus experiencing the gospel in action and learning to live the Christian life, to which I testify in the sacred name of our Savior, Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1980/04/priesthood-councils-key-to-meeting-temporal-and-spiritual-needs</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1980-general-conference/1980-04-6050-elder-ronald-e-poelman-64k-eng.mp3" length="6904019" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 1980 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>God’s Love for Us Transcends Our Transgressions</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The Galilean fisherman Simon Peter, upon recognizing for the first time the divine power of Jesus, exclaimed, “Depart from me; for I am a sinful man, O Lord.” (.)</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03148_000_014" doc-version="2" hash="V0p_Gw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="xBcHbLaljEaF8POgP6jT4A" hash="rR_skw">God’s Love for Us Transcends Our Transgressions</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="O_tBhYmWa0qs_kPNR7bvmg" hash="4c4ENw">Ronald E. Poelman</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2ab8.jpg" alt="Elder Ronald E. Poelman" pid="fqSX8FUw_keV7nfkor8zMg" hash="GUYPhA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p1" pid="_zwF4uW1-UWMbP1YpKFKZw" hash="jOaIMQ">The Galilean fisherman Simon Peter, upon recognizing for the first time the divine power of Jesus, exclaimed, “Depart from me; for I am a sinful man, O Lord.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/5.8" class="scriptureRef">Luke 5:8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p2" pid="iEOpvzGSdE2GSxBhD_bd6Q" hash="PF9e6w">Each one of us, at times, may feel as Peter, conscious of our failings and uncomfortable at the thought of approaching the Lord. Transgression causes us to feel estranged from our Father in Heaven, and we feel unworthy of his love and fearful of his disapproval.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p3" pid="2avRW2Nv70qCpm0wgGSJiw" hash="teEGow">Yet, having transgressed his laws or disobeyed his commandments, we need the strengthening influence of our Father to help us overcome our weakness, to repent and become reconciled with him. Unrepented sin tends to become habitual and is frequently accompanied by a deepening sense of guilt which may make repentance increasingly difficult. This feeling of estrangement from the Lord becomes, itself, an impediment to repentance and reconciliation with him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p4" pid="BvYAfBy8c0CItrRNEha2Zg" hash="5Dlnnw">Knowing we have offended our Father in Heaven, we are afraid to ask his help, feeling that we don’t deserve it. Paradoxically, when we are most in need of the Lord’s influence we deserve it least. Nevertheless, in such circumstances he says to us, as Jesus said to the trembling Peter, “Fear not.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/5.10" class="scriptureRef">Luke 5:10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p5" pid="-qOXpREYp0G0TYyE9ZW-7w" hash="yrnFwg">My message today might best be illustrated through the experiences of a young couple whom I will call John and Gayle.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p6" pid="_NCDuPutmUqutLch5WaTNg" hash="5Kk_UA">John was a thoughtful, kind young man, affectionate, with a frank and open manner. He sincerely tried to obey the Lord’s commandments and found honest contentment in the joys of family life. Gayle, his wife, was young, attractive, high-spirited, but inclined toward more worldly interests and activities. The society in which they lived was, in general, one of affluence and materialism. People seemed preoccupied with temporal gain, social status, entertainment, and self-gratification. Religious leaders were concerned about the apparent breakdown in family life and moral standards.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p7" pid="rt4LZfKFGUuGY4jw3KzwNg" hash="vogJuw">In the early years of their marriage, John and Gayle were blessed with children, first a boy and then a girl; but Gayle seemed uninterested in her domestic responsibilities. She longed for glamour and excitement in her life and was frequently away from home at parties and entertainments, not always with her husband. In her vanity, Gayle encouraged and responded to the attentions of other men until eventually she was unfaithful to her marriage vows.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p8" pid="SeQ9P1Dik0SDM_4bFfE0ZA" hash="rTbmUw">Throughout, John encouraged Gayle to appreciate the joys of family life and experience the rewards of observing the laws of God. He was patient and kind, but to no avail. Shortly after the birth of a third child, a son, Gayle deserted her husband and children and joined her worldly friends in a life of self-indulgence and immorality. John, thus rejected, was humiliated and brokenhearted.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p9" pid="xnYcWRAEJE2t-51RTslKvQ" hash="nLlEIQ">Soon, however, the glamour and excitement that had attracted Gayle turned to ashes. Her so-called friends tired of her and abandoned her. Then each successive step was downward, her life becoming more and more degraded. Eventually she recognized her mistakes and realized what she had lost, but could see no way back. Certainly John could not possibly love her still. She felt completely unworthy of his love and undeserving of her home and family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p10" pid="rjqyvEG7pkmy26hUC3Qacg" hash="LW_COw">Then one day, passing through the streets, John recognized Gayle. Surely he would have been justified in turning away, but he didn’t. As he observed the effect of her recent life, all too evident, a feeling of compassion came over him—a desire to reach out to her. Learning that Gayle had incurred substantial debts, John repaid them and then took her home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p11" pid="zlQ-C4ico0CysSl9nOSwog" hash="iKJxLQ">Soon John realized, at first with amazement, that he still loved Gayle. Out of his love for her and her willingness to change and begin anew, there grew in John’s heart a feeling of merciful forgiveness, a desire to help Gayle overcome her past and to accept her again fully as his wife.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p12" pid="xOzu55L25ESHfSVYzhbw3g" hash="FAFyVQ">Through his personal experience there arose in John another profound awareness, a realization of the nature of God’s love for us, his children. Though we disregard his counsel, break his commandments, and reject him, when we recognize our mistakes and desire to repent, he wants us to seek him out and he will accept us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p13" pid="2N_415F23U2Dz7gEoOCdqQ" hash="SeFK0Q">John had been prepared, through his personal experiences, for a divine mission. Though I have taken some literary license in telling the story, it is the account, perhaps allegorical, of Hosea, prophet of the Old Testament, and his wife, Gomer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p14" pid="9FO0zfJXxU2yp9kgq6t4SA" hash="_uCskA">Portraying God to ancient Israel as a loving, forgiving father, Hosea foreshadowed, more than most Old Testament prophets, the spirit and message of the New Testament, the Book of Mormon, and modern revelation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p15" pid="vOw-IQQZpEe_1baxGZxufQ" hash="RDdEkA">In these latter days the Lord has said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p16" pid="Uat_7HsY4Ue_wcC1OpYaFQ" hash="5FZKwg">“For I the Lord cannot look upon sin with the least degree of allowance;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p17" pid="CSIHpdOu90e61ER-Ix4nAg" hash="I0JWRQ">“Nevertheless, he that repents and does the commandments of the Lord shall be forgiven.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.31-32" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:31–32</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p18" pid="wJ8pqebLQkqTEs8i4lK_jA" hash="ltyvdg">By disobeying the laws of God and breaking his commandments, we do offend him, we do estrange ourselves from him, and we don’t deserve his help and inspiration and strength. But God’s love for us transcends our transgressions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p19" pid="xORlBDZ9pUWkm6pBXm-Jxg" hash="QBK2Dw">When we disobey the laws of God, justice requires that compensation be made—a requirement which we are incapable of fulfilling. But out of his divine love for us, our Father has provided a plan and a Savior, Jesus Christ, whose redeeming sacrifice satisfies the demands of justice for us and makes possible repentance, forgiveness, and reconciliation with our Father. For indeed, “God so loved the world, that he gave his only begotten Son, that whosoever believeth in him should not perish, but have everlasting life.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/3.16" class="scriptureRef">John 3:16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p20" pid="Aqxo7wlnTESJF5duGwgh-w" hash="5-2qdA">We may accept this great gift through faith in Jesus Christ and repentance, followed by a covenant made with him through baptism of the water and of the Spirit. Then, each week, as we receive the sacrament, we renew our covenant that we will “always remember him and keep his commandments.” The promise attached to that covenant is that we “may always have his Spirit to be with [us].” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.77" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:77</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p21" pid="Tf-nPCC3RUSK8_ObdjGm3Q" hash="QoOh1g">Hosea’s ancient message is repeated and elaborated throughout the scriptures. Through Isaiah, another Old Testament prophet, the Lord said to his people:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p22" pid="D9iCqSrNk0GuEl7_iV8ocA" hash="RXcveQ">“Wash you, make you clean; put away the evil of your doings from before mine eyes; cease to do evil;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p23" pid="WNQi042ML0Wx_jgwS8P90g" hash="WWRHxQ">“Learn to do well. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p24" pid="B4jSxcvno0GP3rH6bbxccQ" hash="HX-jeA">“Come now, and let us reason together, saith the Lord: though your sins be as scarlet, they shall be as white as snow; though they be red like crimson, they shall be as wool.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/1.16-18" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 1:16–18</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p25" pid="J_lXl5AWSk2BZrxzdUVCXw" hash="k8hl5Q">The Lord, speaking to Alma, the Nephite prophet, says: “Whosoever transgresseth against me, him shall ye judge according to the sins which he has committed; and if he confess his sins before thee and me, and repenteth in the sincerity of his heart, him shall ye forgive, and I will forgive him also.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p26" pid="PJ8vr5J0TkaDCeDFVhK-kw" hash="bVFI5A">“Yea, and as often as my people repent will I forgive them their trespasses against me.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/26.29-30" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 26:29–30</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p27" pid="VeIaLRjTeU2aqIuDUe2yRw" hash="wawVIQ">Too often we make repentance more difficult for each other by our failure to forgive one another. However, we are admonished in modern revelation that “ye ought to forgive one another; for he that forgiveth not his brother his trespasses standeth condemned before the Lord; for there remaineth in him the greater sin.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p28" pid="HG-5X_NNvUakgvbQvccYFQ" hash="NMlpHg">“I, the Lord, will forgive whom I will forgive, but of you it is required to forgive all men.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/64.9-10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 64:9–10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p29" pid="Kq8ETInY00CGyzRF0tH2eA" hash="nLMJBA">Also from modern revelation comes one of the most comforting, hopeful pronouncements ever spoken:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p30" pid="T3cKe2uLm0eb_23usq0dKA" hash="4-glow">“He who has repented of his sins, the same is forgiven, and I, the Lord, remember them no more.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.42" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:42</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p31" pid="Gy7sJeZnVEirA44lis2teQ" hash="6m6xlA">God is our father; he loves us; his love is infinite and unconditional. His sorrow is great when we disobey his commandments and break his laws. He cannot condone our transgressions, but he loves us and wants us to return to him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions.p32" pid="4fDVUNVcgEKcD5CsvZPu5Q" hash="Zr9NXg">I know of no greater inducement to repentance and reconciliation with our Father in Heaven than an awareness of his love for us personally and individually. That such awareness may increase within each of us is my prayer, to which I add my personal witness to you individually that Jesus of Nazareth is the Son of God, the Savior of all mankind, and the Redeemer of each of us individually, in the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1982/04/gods-love-for-us-transcends-our-transgressions</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1982-general-conference/1982-04-2070-elder-ronald-e-poelman-64k-eng.mp3" length="5312690" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 1982 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gospel and the Church</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Both the gospel of Jesus Christ and the church of Jesus Christ are true and divine, and there is an essential relationship between them that is significant and very important. Understanding the proper relationship between the gospel and the Church wi</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03180_000_025" doc-version="2" hash="IRS6cw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="tlFCJQr1D0-R8Xwwhhc3gA" hash="yc8sug">The Gospel and the Church</h1><p class="authorName" guid="0bbd08d0-2795-4b92-baef-a60b0e7fce91" pid="Gm3W9iy_DEGgaNSlG4Xvxw" hash="4c4ENw">Ronald E. Poelman</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="f404c92e-5eb9-4c47-8a17-23d01aa0fba0">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2ab8.jpg" alt="Elder Ronald E. Poelman" guid="c081e307-496c-402c-8a5e-6dcefebff540" pid="pxaXamQQYUC7wtLDq9-Jzw" hash="GUYPhA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.p" pid="Do16YsX3mUuQKSq0hL5fnQ" hash="0yEIQA">Both the gospel of Jesus Christ and the church of Jesus Christ are true and divine, and there is an essential relationship between them that is significant and very important. Understanding the proper relationship between the gospel and the Church will prevent confusion, misplaced priorities, and failed expectations and will lead to the realization of gospel goals through happy, fulfilling participation in the Church. Such understanding will avoid possible disaffection and will result in great personal blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.p" pid="S8uOS72H7kqYD6Ao8S7pAA" hash="R5k2xw">As I attempt to describe and comment upon the essential relationship between the gospel and the Church, it is my prayer that a perspective may be developed which will enhance the influence of both the gospel and the Church in our individual lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.p" pid="JNVCLr9smESjrSCR9NxE5Q" hash="qGTmUQ">The gospel of Jesus Christ is a divine and perfect plan. It is composed of eternal, unchanging principles, laws, and ordinances which are universally applicable to every individual regardless of time, place, or circumstance. Gospel principles never change.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.p" pid="rK03srNuT0GB_6TOKPhkLA" hash="tQfOxg">The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is the kingdom of God on earth, administered by the priesthood of God. The Church has authority to teach correctly the principles and doctrines of the gospel and to administer its essential ordinances.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.p" pid="hto9Cvyn5UaS8-sKTVRoPA" hash="CK4M9w">The gospel is the divine plan for personal, individual salvation and exaltation. The Church is divinely commissioned to provide the means and resources that implement this plan in each individual’s life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.p" pid="_iR82dhIm0Gw-7CUi5zbaw" hash="HNSqAw">Procedures, programs, and policies are developed within the Church to help us realize gospel blessings according to our individual capacity and circumstances. Under divine direction, these policies, programs, and procedures may be changed from time to time as necessary to fulfill gospel purposes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.p" pid="dR3IibTLeUOgKJjGtK3ftA" hash="vhyV3A">Underlying every aspect of Church administration and activity are the revealed eternal principles contained in the scriptures. As individually and collectively we increase our knowledge, acceptance, and application of gospel principles, we can more effectively utilize the Church to make our lives increasingly gospel centered.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.p" pid="XWypsG4nvkC-1vsmJSGYkg" hash="mUUWig">The eternal principles of the gospel implemented through the divinely inspired Church apply to a wide variety of individuals in diverse cultures. Therefore, as we live the gospel and participate in the Church, the conformity we require of ourselves and of others should be according to God’s standards. The orthodoxy upon which we insist must be founded in fundamental principles, eternal law, and direction given by those authorized in the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.p" pid="6mJA9ORxSEqMJ433g5fjDg" hash="EF6nXg">A necessary perspective is gained by studying and pondering the scriptures. Reading the scriptures, we learn the gospel as it is taught by various prophets in a variety of circumstances, times, and places. We see the consequences as the gospel is accepted or rejected by individuals and as its principles are applied or not.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.p" pid="CabPo-2k3U6a9EV1TFsg4Q" hash="_yNaGA">In the scriptures we discover that varying institutional forms, procedures, regulations, and ceremonies were utilized—all divinely designed to implement eternal principles. The practices and procedures change; the principles do not.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.p" pid="T7F70ry1BU2Uh5QKhnhYjQ" hash="w1EBrQ">Through scripture study we may learn eternal principles and how to relate them to institutional resources. As we liken the scriptures unto ourselves, we can better utilize the restored Church to learn, live, and share the gospel of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.p" pid="dHIY_vnpbEaI-RHADp6nyQ" hash="ITCHwg">A favorite scriptural source for me is the Old Testament book of Leviticus. It is basically a handbook for Hebrew priests and contains many rules, regulations, rituals, and ceremonies which seem strange and inapplicable to us. It also contains eternal principles of the gospel which are familiar and very much applicable to everyone.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.p" pid="iaWmCvMfa0SSwjEIAehsSA" hash="UD4hww">It is interesting and enlightening to read the nineteenth chapter of Leviticus, noting both the principles and the rules and practices.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.p" pid="khv-Tujkc0Oi70CIKATKhg" hash="X60e3g">In the first two verses we read, “And the Lord spake unto Moses, saying, Speak unto all the congregation of the children of Israel.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/lev/19.1-2" class="scriptureRef">Lev. 19:1–2</a>.) Here is the principle of revelation. God speaks to his children through prophets. He does so today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.p" pid="aZA9Tesrr0ibC-TlGezayA" hash="ZYjdNw">Continuing, the Lord said to Moses, “Say unto them, Ye shall be holy: for I the Lord your God am holy.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/lev/19.2" class="scriptureRef">Lev. 19:2</a>.) Jesus, in the Sermon on the Mount, said, “Be ye therefore perfect, even as your Father which is in heaven is perfect.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.48" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:48</a>.) Here is an eternal gospel principle.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.p" pid="yKcXh_28XEGVHkGCEXkJzA" hash="ZGslNQ">There follow other eternal principles, some from the Ten Commandments. Also included are rules and programs intended to implement these principles among the ancient Hebrews in their particular circumstances.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.p" pid="lEJhv06UxkOk_tV7z4rSdQ" hash="dIdc8Q">For example, the divinely directed responsibility to care for the poor is taught. A program is presented, namely, providing food for the poor by leaving the gleanings of the crops and not reaping the corners of the fields. (See <a href="/scriptures/ot/lev/19.9-10" class="scriptureRef">Lev. 19:9–10</a>.) Current programs to care for the poor are much different. The divine law is the same. Yet another principle underlies both programs, ancient and modern: those being assisted are given opportunity to participate in helping themselves to the extent of their capacity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.p" pid="N31H_gbn8Uincbq-EcGPMA" hash="tqGKHg">In verse 13 the principle of honesty is taught, accompanied by a rule requiring employers to pay employees for their work at the end of each day [<a href="/scriptures/ot/lev/19.13" class="scriptureRef">Lev. 19:13</a>]. Generally, today that rule is not necessary. The eternal principle of honesty is implemented by other rules and practices.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.p" pid="I91FIW_lSESeg_4LChv0QA" hash="zSi8rw">Verse 27 contains a rule about personal grooming [<a href="/scriptures/ot/lev/19.27" class="scriptureRef">Lev. 19:27</a>]. It is clearly not applicable to us. However, we also have standards of dress and grooming. Neither is an eternal principle; both are intended to help us implement and share gospel principles.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.p" pid="GL8jChY3AEqfnjVaR8tFkQ" hash="fBxo-w">The principle of forgiveness is also set forth in the same chapter of Leviticus, verse 18, concluding with the second great commandment, “Thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself,” with the added divine imprimatur, “I am the Lord.” [<a href="/scriptures/ot/lev/19.18" class="scriptureRef">Lev. 19:18</a>]</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.p" pid="XHNuQY9HjkuBeOSEO3QQ6A" hash="_cPPOA">Every Church member has the opportunity, right, and privilege to receive a personal witness regarding gospel principles and Church practices. Without such a witness, one may feel confused and perhaps even burdened by what may appear to be simply institutional requirements of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.p" pid="8FnyaNs7z06npxk3TP1ByA" hash="YmRiWw">We should obey the commandments and counsel of Church leaders; but also through study, through prayer, and by the influence of the Holy Spirit, we should seek and obtain an individual, personal witness that the principle or counsel is correct and divinely inspired. Then we can give enlightened, enthusiastic obedience, utilizing the Church as a means through which to give allegiance, time, talent, and other resources without reluctance or resentment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.p" pid="12BO2Ucm5UywqfOWrpZtbQ" hash="kEeaFQ">Happy, fulfilling participation in the Church results when we relate Church goals, programs, and policies to gospel principles and to personal eternal goals. When we see the harmony between the gospel and the Church in our daily lives, we are much more likely to do the right things for the right reasons. We will exercise self-discipline and righteous initiative guided by Church leaders and a sense of divine accountability.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.p" pid="Fy6gEkLpQEqUQbWYHa5k-g" hash="5_Ughg">The Church aids us in our effort to use our free agency creatively, not to invent our own values, principles, and interpretations, but to learn and live the eternal truths of the gospel. Gospel living is a process of continuous individual renewal and improvement until the person is prepared and qualified to enter comfortably and with confidence into the presence of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.p" pid="hhlxrKRbcUecu1zvE17KBQ" hash="SL2Bag">My brothers and sisters, by inclination, training, and experience most of my life I have sought understanding by the accumulation of facts and the application of reason. I continue to do so. However, that which I know most surely and which has most significantly and positively affected my life I do not know by facts and reason alone, but rather by the comforting, confirming witness of the Holy Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.p" pid="F-wLm4A2rkuCWl0bggSUMw" hash="Gxhpuw">By that same Spirit I testify that God is our Father, that Jesus of Nazareth is the Only Begotten of the Father in the flesh, and that he is the Savior and Redeemer of all mankind and each of us. Through his atoning sacrifice, redemption and exaltation are offered as a free gift to all who will accept by faith, repentance, and sacred covenants.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.p" pid="0Fxn3LTMxECOv0vAQnDl3g" hash="cEgk5w">May each of us continue to learn and apply the eternal principles of the gospel, utilizing fully and appropriately the resources of the divine, restored Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church.p" pid="y7kmvQPQjkO7_JgZiT8oNw" hash="Pbb7AQ">In the words of the Nephite leader Pahoran “May [we] rejoice in the great privilege of our church, and in the cause of our Redeemer and our God.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/61.14" class="scriptureRef">Alma 61:14</a>.) In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div><div class="resources">
    <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2ab8.jpg" alt="Elder Ronald E. Poelman" guid="c081e307-496c-402c-8a5e-6dcefebff540" pid="PNoDedWgBkC6zn7TmI5bzQ" hash="GUYPhA1" />
    <unknown name="digitalAssets" guid="">
      <unknown name="assetGroup" guid="">
        <unknown name="path" guid="c081e307-496c-402c-8a5e-6dcefebff540"></unknown>
      </unknown>
    </unknown>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1984/10/the-gospel-and-the-church</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1984-general-conference/1984-10-4040-elder-ronald-e-poelman-64k-eng.mp3" length="6465848" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 1984 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adversity and the Divine Purpose of Mortality</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality?lang=eng</link>
      <description>“Happiness,” in the words of the Prophet Joseph Smith, “is the object and design of our existence; and will be the end thereof, if we pursue the path that leads to it.” ( 5:134.) Often that path includes affliction, trials, and suffering—physically, </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03239_000_012" doc-version="2" hash="M8S9Xw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="OANVOxtfHkygZM14TyJTUg" hash="iFdeZA">Adversity and the Divine Purpose of Mortality</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="YGAzGBSKakeZKuU0-hd9Vg" hash="4c4ENw">Ronald E. Poelman</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1d5e.jpg" alt="Elder Ronald E. Poelman" pid="eaYL5krimU-OX3f7hW5FEw" hash="HlaN0Q" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p1" pid="bCzmsyKJoU-TwcUXy5FhkQ" hash="Xcz0YA">“Happiness,” in the words of the Prophet Joseph Smith, “is the object and design of our existence; and will be the end thereof, if we pursue the path that leads to it.” (<span class="emphasis">History of the Church,</span> 5:134.) Often that path includes affliction, trials, and suffering—physically, mentally, and even spiritually.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p2" pid="Un3N2zVX30qAO3GhLqjFMg" hash="r4xYkQ">Adversity, or what we perceive to be adversity, enters into the life of every individual at various times and in various forms. Adversity may be the consequence of willful disobedience to the laws of God. However, my remarks are directed to those who with righteous desire seek earnestly to learn and strive diligently to do God’s will, yet nevertheless experience adversity. Much about this subject we do not understand, but let us consider some of what the Lord has revealed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p3" pid="x-l5otEkNE-VkmtyCAEhGQ" hash="VpaBIw">Adversity in the lives of the obedient and faithful may be the consequence of disease, accidental injury, ignorance, or the influence of the adversary. To preserve free agency, the Lord also at times permits the righteous to suffer the consequences of evil acts by others. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/18.16" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 18:16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p4" pid="WQCFxhjNr0SrECX7_NrluA" hash="mSit_w">Some may respond to such innocent suffering with resentment, anger, bitterness, doubt, or fear. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/17.20" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 17:20</a>.) Others, with a knowledge and testimony of the divine plan of salvation, often respond with faith, patience, and hope born of that “peace … which passeth all understanding.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/philip/4.6-7" class="scriptureRef">Philip. 4:6–7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p5" pid="cgPHySSj8UW0cjcSRedvRg" hash="wlrNKQ">The plan of salvation presented to and accepted by us in our premortal state includes a probationary period on earth, during which we experience opposites, make choices, learn the consequences thereof, and prepare to return to the presence of God. Experiencing adversity is an essential part of the process. Knowing this, we elected to come into mortality. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.11-16" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:11–16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p6" pid="SUKGebB6k0Kn4ifCYZOyBQ" hash="Mt7NFA">The Savior himself “learned … obedience by the things which he suffered.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/heb/5.8" class="scriptureRef">Heb. 5:8</a>.) Prophets and Apostles, ancient and modern, have struggled with adversity in their own lives, as well as with trials associated with their divine callings. No one is exempt.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p7" pid="Q2ZyOeorz0OncEiIqk1szA" hash="nrU1nw">However, Paul teaches “that all things work together for good to them that love God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rom/8.28" class="scriptureRef">Rom. 8:28</a>.) Similarly, the prophet Lehi assured his son Jacob with these words: “Jacob, … in thy childhood thou hast suffered afflictions and much sorrow because of [others].</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p8" pid="lsAvD9kqdEyUjpyFsaQYcQ" hash="AzIeYw">“Nevertheless, … thou knowest the greatness of God; and he shall consecrate thine afflictions for thy gain.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.1-2" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:1–2</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p9" pid="97YFIjkhDUCHW4_EQPjFzA" hash="ZirJCg">How, then, shall we respond to undeserved adversity in our own lives? How may our responses to affliction and suffering draw us closer to the Savior, to our Heavenly Father, and to the realization of our own celestial potential? May I suggest some examples and role models found in the scriptures.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p10" pid="wrkChjeB8Uqs36MUZd-J7A" hash="H_6kAw">The sons of Mosiah, in the course of their missionary labors, “had many afflictions … both in body and in mind … and also much labor in the spirit.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/17.5" class="scriptureRef">Alma 17:5</a>.) Partly because of such experiences, they became “strong in the knowledge of the truth; … men of a sound understanding … [who] searched the scriptures diligently, that they might know the word of God. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p11" pid="fPBPwaV0OkWzP86t4DON3w" hash="xiY0IQ">“They had given themselves to much prayer, and fasting; therefore they had the spirit of prophecy, and the spirit of revelation.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/17.2-3" class="scriptureRef">Alma 17:2–3</a>.) Through their positive response to adversity, they grew spiritually.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p12" pid="u2JN00NrrUu3Hntm9MgxBg" hash="5rNMpg">In the time of Nephi, son of Helaman, “the more humble part of the people … [suffered] much affliction”; but they fasted and prayed frequently and became “stronger in their humility, and … firmer in the faith of Christ, unto the filling their souls with joy and consolation.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/3.34-35" class="scriptureRef">Hel. 3:34–35</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p13" pid="ZOO70_27F0eGTT8bgL4ljA" hash="SMWiDQ">From their example, we learn some positive responses to our own undeserved adversity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p14" pid="vc6YjjVMHkaXg1ZgdAsqmw" hash="U9R9ow">As they did, we should look to the Savior for divine assistance. Paul reminds us that “we have a great high priest, … Jesus the Son of God, … [who is] touched with the feeling of our infirmities.” We are invited to seek his “help in time of need.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/heb/4.14-16" class="scriptureRef">Heb. 4:14–16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p15" pid="s6EAaUhickW0dJfqqWa15A" hash="DHvKHw">Because the Savior suffered “pains and afflictions and temptations of every kind … [taking] upon him the pains and the sickness of his people … [taking] upon him their infirmities … [he knows] according to the flesh how to [help] his people according to their infirmities.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/7.11-12" class="scriptureRef">Alma 7:11–12</a>.) Therefore, we should follow the counsel of Amulek: “Let your hearts be full, drawn out in prayer unto him continually for your welfare, and also for the welfare of those who are around you.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/34.27" class="scriptureRef">Alma 34:27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p16" pid="_5KpeESqdUOSgGomhPYM9g" hash="AhcbLg">Next, our prayers should be accompanied with daily scripture study. The eternal perspective attained thereby reminds us of who we are, what the true purpose of this mortal experience is, and who placed us here. The availability of divine help is repeatedly reconfirmed. Daily scripture study also makes us continuously conscious of covenants we have made with the Lord and of his promised blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p17" pid="SrW_gesbcUi7W1Dfj-V62g" hash="h3eXQg">As we fulfill our baptismal covenant, we “bear one another’s burdens, that they may be light,” and our own burdens are lightened. We “comfort those that stand in need of comfort,” and we receive comfort. When we “stand as witnesses of God … in all things,” we feel his redeeming love and see our present circumstances more clearly in the perspective of eternal life. (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.8-9" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:8–9</a>.) In a sense, we are thereby accepting the Savior’s invitation: “Come unto me, all ye that labour and are heavy laden, and I will give you rest.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p18" pid="rUl0Jx3LsEKE1tkyCSM5OQ" hash="NJrEVg">“Take my yoke upon you, and learn of me; for I am meek and lowly in heart: and ye shall find rest unto your souls.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p19" pid="toAoUwf4kUqJ16N26pJ8gw" hash="tewm4w">“For my yoke is easy, and my burden is light.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/11.28-30" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 11:28–30</a>.) Is it not probable that bearing his yoke and his burden includes forgetting self in service to others?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p20" pid="X7Ap7V-ygEy-AkMih0iCGQ" hash="xVQWRw">Patience must also be part of our response to adversity. Ammon, son of Mosiah, recalling personal challenges, acknowledged, “Now when our hearts were depressed, and we were about to turn back [or, in other words, give up], … the Lord comforted us, and said: … bear with patience thine afflictions, and I will give unto you success.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/26.27" class="scriptureRef">Alma 26:27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p21" pid="ZAghpDmbbEGwF-rX5zI1EA" hash="vuz_mA">In our day, the Lord has counseled, “Fear not, let your hearts be comforted; … rejoice evermore, and in everything give thanks;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p22" pid="vXPhyukOf0GxkdMnpylb3g" hash="aL2l3g">“Waiting patiently on the Lord. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p23" pid="rcKzfOQ9J02eGpAPOq68OA" hash="yUs7Iw">“And all things wherewith you have been afflicted shall work together for your good.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/98.1-3" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 98:1–3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p24" pid="VVgyLGo42k6Z3vYJqfxjpA" hash="G-tK4g">Repeated assurances have been given regarding the benefits and blessings of positive responses to adversity, however undeserved. The witness of the Spirit and the manifestation of greater things often follow the trial of one’s faith. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/12.6" class="scriptureRef">Ether 12:6</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/26.7-9" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 26:7–9</a>.) Spiritual refinement may be realized in the furnace of affliction. (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/20.10" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 20:10</a>.) Thereby we may be prepared to experience personal and direct contact with God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p25" pid="nyCB3krIzUS07lFHwxAHtg" hash="gIVCBQ">In modern revelation we are instructed, “Sanctify yourselves that your minds become single to God, and the days will come that you shall see him; for he will unveil his face unto you, and it shall be in his own time, and in his own way, and according to his own will.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.68" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:68</a>.) Ancient prophets teach us that “when he shall appear, … we shall see him as he is; … [and] be purified even as he is pure.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.48" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:48</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/nt/1-jn/3.2" class="scriptureRef">1 Jn. 3:2</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p26" pid="5Ym_VC1IXk2Ro3OSrINVTw" hash="eoJFlw">The Lord’s own way of preparing us to see him as he is may well include the refining furnace of affliction, that we may “offer a sacrifice [to him] … of a broken heart and a contrite spirit,” the promised reward being “peace in this world, and eternal life in the world to come.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/59.8,23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 59:8, 23</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p27" pid="4Zlo70csJE2Or1TzfKi20Q" hash="jRQWsg">Each of us is the spiritual offspring of God. We came to this earth to prepare to return to his presence, there to share a fulness—that is, eternal life. Without adversity, we may tend to forget the divine purpose of mortality and live our lives focused on the transitory things of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p28" pid="3AOpp1Qv1UmRTX1GoDT3wA" hash="PTtBkA">Should we therefore desire or seek to experience adversity and suffering? No! May we appropriately try to avoid it? Yes! Is it proper to ask for relief? Yes, always adding, in accordance with the Savior’s example, “nevertheless not as I will, but as thou wilt.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/26.39" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 26:39</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p29" pid="J12ki-1Il06wMe7HQ3kr3g" hash="wy6-jg">There are encouragement and comfort in knowing that we will not be tested beyond our capacity to endure, that we will benefit from our adversities, and that the resources and circumstances necessary for us to do so will be provided. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/10.13" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 10:13</a>.) From the Book of Mormon comes another illustration:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p30" pid="kPklld0sSkO8F2BFd6orxA" hash="tAsH6w">Those with whom Alma shared the inspired teachings of Abinadi entered into the baptismal covenant and began to live the gospel fully. There was no contention among them; they were knit together in unity and in love one toward another, caring for the poor and needy and for one another temporally and spiritually. Because of their industry and the harmony among them, they prospered. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/23.15-20" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 23:15–20</a>.) Certainly they did not deserve adversity. However, they were provided with the opportunity for further spiritual growth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p31" pid="RDjMM01JuEu9mz5ar03qxQ" hash="tMD3Gw">The scriptural account continues with these words: “Nevertheless, the Lord seeth fit to chasten his people; yea, he trieth their patience and their faith.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/23.21" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 23:21</a>.) Notwithstanding their righteousness, these faithful people suffered much affliction. Understandably, they pleaded with the Lord for relief, perhaps hoping that the burdens would be removed. In response to their pleadings, the Lord comforted them and assured them of his help. (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/24.8-14" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 24:8–14</a>.) Then he strengthened them “that they could bear up their burdens with ease, and they did submit cheerfully and with patience to all the will of the Lord.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/24.15" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 24:15</a>.) Eventually, because of their faith and patience, they were delivered from their afflictions. Having been further refined spiritually, and with increased faith, “they gave thanks to God.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/24.16-22" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 24:16–22</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p32" pid="oG1pkUAieUq6h61lSitZUA" hash="rYNQHQ">In the final days of the Nephite civilization, the prophet Mormon wrote a letter to his son, Moroni, describing the wickedness, cruelty, and depravity which caused innocent people to suffer. Then he added these words of admonition and comfort:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p33" pid="l-5xnlK-202f3vV5AZYeuA" hash="8ynVrQ">“My son, be faithful in Christ; and may not the things which I have written grieve thee, to weigh thee down … ; but may Christ lift thee up, and may his sufferings and death, … his mercy … and the hope of his glory and of eternal life, rest in your mind forever.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality.p34" pid="W-oibyMyokW_eqjTC0OqVg" hash="zQJpWQ">“And may the grace of God the Father … and our Lord Jesus Christ … be, and abide with you forever” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/9.25-26" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 9:25–26</a>), which is also my prayer for each of us, in the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1989/04/adversity-and-the-divine-purpose-of-mortality</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1989-general-conference/1989-04-2050-elder-ronald-e-poelman-64k-eng.mp3" length="5651551" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 1989 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Divine Forgiveness</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The Savior of the world, the Redeemer of all God’s children, Jesus of Nazareth, has power to forgive sins. His own witness of such power is recorded in the New Testament (see ; ; ). His Apostles Peter and Paul testified of this truth (see ; ; ), as d</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_93911_000_033" doc-version="2" hash="9AMzeg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="QwFlnN8kGU-xwJf9LsgA8Q" hash="R1-yfw">Divine Forgiveness</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="uPB6g7ab2UOn6MqHhkzf8Q" hash="4c4ENw">Ronald E. Poelman</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1d5e.jpg" alt="Elder Ronald E. Poelman" pid="Ar0Xyuk1IU-oFMIZX6E6kQ" hash="HlaN0Q" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p1" pid="6lGZ-TUkYkii8IUuneK4Wg" hash="B-sG9w">The Savior of the world, the Redeemer of all God’s children, Jesus of Nazareth, has power to forgive sins. His own witness of such power is recorded in the New Testament (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/9.6" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 9:6</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/2.10" class="scriptureRef">Mark 2:10</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/5.20,24" class="scriptureRef">Luke 5:20, 24</a>). His Apostles Peter and Paul testified of this truth (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/5.31" class="scriptureRef">Acts 5:31</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/13.38-39" class="scriptureRef">Acts 13:38–39</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/1.7" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 1:7</a>), as did also the prophets of the Book of Mormon (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/enos/1.5" class="scriptureRef">Enos 1:5</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/4.3" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 4:3</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/6.8" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 6:8</a>) and of modern times (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/61.2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 61:2</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p2" pid="djxcCR1ZX0GIMtWLrxtpPQ" hash="xfTTOg">Through the centuries, many have received great joy and peace of mind through understanding and accepting the Lord’s forgiveness. Yet, many others apparently continue to bear the burden of guilt, remorse, and self-doubt because of an incomplete understanding and testimony of the doctrine of Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p3" pid="Wh4t22hHQUCo3NvnK1bW5w" hash="Ge05ww">Recently I was in private conversation with one who, having committed a serious transgression, had also made intense effort to repent and receive forgiveness from those personally offended, from the Church, and from the Lord. When I asked, “Do you feel forgiven by your Heavenly Father?” he answered hesitantly with an affirmative but qualified response. “How do we obtain divine forgiveness?” I asked.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p4" pid="Vd4p9p4AM0--gZUDrmlllg" hash="xhuaaQ">He spoke of how he had forsaken his transgressive behavior of the past, confessed to proper priesthood authorities, and attempted to make restitution to those offended. He further described his efforts to live according to gospel principles and Church standards.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p5" pid="mjPIKolwyE-8paNBRH5mDA" hash="YQbdAg">The Savior and his atoning sacrifice were not mentioned. The underlying assumption seemed to be that divine forgiveness is obtained through those steps of repentance limited to changing one’s behavior. Despite the brother’s earnest efforts to repent, he appeared to be burdened still by remorse and regret and to feel that he must continue to pay for his sins.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p6" pid="EHB5kSEqaE65HWRs2W4r3g" hash="EuCGeg">Unfortunately, this is not an isolated case. Others, to my knowledge, are burdened by past mistakes, large and small, because of an incomplete or incorrect understanding of our Father’s plan of redemption and mercy. Those so burdened may unnecessarily struggle through life without the joy and peace of mind which are the intended result of true repentance and divine forgiveness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p7" pid="SNJzw8h57EqxV5APHViFiQ" hash="mvqZBw">One who assumes that he can or must pay the price for his sins and thereby earn divine forgiveness will not feel free to continue progress toward realizing his divine potential, that is, eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p8" pid="EvOkaprQq0yDz1cS7QUpCA" hash="APw5AQ">The fact is we cannot save ourselves.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p9" pid="uuzGo8w82kik7VrOKz1lJg" hash="WNXxHg">The best source through which a correct understanding of how forgiveness may be obtained is the Book of Mormon. Let us consider some examples of its teachings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p10" pid="IGMVPuYzFkeHg3ds8kFfCA" hash="xC1ukQ">Enos recorded for us his experience, alone in the forest, remembering the words of his father concerning eternal life:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p11" pid="78sIHJmtFE61xjyJw2S_6Q" hash="R5hqkA">“And my soul hungered; and I kneeled down before my Maker, and I cried unto him in mighty prayer and supplication for mine own soul; …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p12" pid="z8iuduAMy0u5rArSXz9S_w" hash="fnxTXA">“And there came a voice unto me, saying: Enos, thy sins are forgiven thee. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p13" pid="IRTZ9j-aD0eWOfaNBnoPww" hash="mZvTGA">“… Wherefore, my guilt was swept away.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p14" pid="fIioeHRxVkeR86GU--Kl1Q" hash="9CDJyQ">“And I said: Lord, how is it done?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p15" pid="zm9s-RAP1UyXsHjuU3Rayw" hash="bZjGsw">“And he said unto me: Because of thy faith in Christ” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/enos/1.4-8" class="scriptureRef">Enos 1:4–8</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p16" pid="5Un0ocQboECUU7Y7G8lrLg" hash="-RnI5w">How is it done? The question each of us may ponder. Again we turn to the Book of Mormon for additional understanding.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p17" pid="NpG_AQGCYkid4fLTpUVFmQ" hash="lP9ppQ">Father Lehi teaches us that the divine purpose of our mortal probation requires us to experience opposition in all things and, knowing good from evil, to exercise our moral agency, make choices, and be accountable for the consequences (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.title" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p18" pid="dfwnqhAVMU6s0u-QmmiyRA" hash="ZhxHZQ">We learn from the prophet Alma that we are subject to divine law, which all have transgressed in some respect, making us subject to the demands of justice (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/42.14,18" class="scriptureRef">Alma 42:14, 18</a>). God’s justice is based upon divine laws, under which we receive what we deserve according to our disobedience or obedience to the law.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p19" pid="EA2AQYGS4EuMJK-qJRx32w" hash="V16Nmg">Justice affords no forgiveness for transgressors but imposes penalties (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/82.4" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 82:4</a>). None is exempt (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/107.84" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 107:84</a>). After all we can do to repent, we are still subject to the demands of justice and its penalties, which we cannot satisfy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p20" pid="VDXX0wi_RE-9g4voa2WgRg" hash="G2PlcQ">However, we learn from Alma of our Father’s plan of mercy, whereby the Son of God would atone for the sins of the world and “appease the demands of justice, that God might be a perfect, just God, and a merciful God also” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/42.15" class="scriptureRef">Alma 42:15</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p21" pid="16md-ozbdE2ahw_GvNZhoQ" hash="JMr83g">The Savior’s vicarious sacrifice satisfies the justice of God. Therefore, God extends his mercy, whereby we may receive forgiveness of our personal transgressions through faith in the Redeemer, followed by obedience to the laws and ordinances of the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p22" pid="sWkGhOSwXE2ILsxHRkUtoQ" hash="Y8lrlg">Father Lehi taught his son Jacob:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p23" pid="4A7rF291m0qsajkckaWCOw" hash="jpnVLQ">“Wherefore, redemption cometh in and through the Holy Messiah; for he is full of grace and truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p24" pid="qPmB7PyUxkWib5smjJnXFw" hash="mXH6kQ">“Behold, he offereth himself a sacrifice for sin, to answer the ends of the law, unto all those who have a broken heart and a contrite spirit” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.6-7" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:6–7</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p25" pid="PR_9D2GVXkeqPkYq0ZA_Eg" hash="0W7Cug">The beginning and completion of repentance leading to forgiveness is faith in Jesus Christ, who is the “author and the finisher of [our] faith” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/6.4" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 6:4</a>). Our faith in him as Savior and Redeemer engenders in us godly sorrow for our transgressions, a broken heart and a contrite spirit, and a sense of personal accountability. There follows a change in attitude and a turning toward God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p26" pid="fLUDbRpN2EuhY6mvFzsDnQ" hash="tk_H5g">We resolve to forsake disobedience, even carelessness, and strive better to know and love our Father in Heaven and to obey his laws and commandments. Throughout, we pray for our Father’s forgiveness, for strength to resist temptation, and for inspiration to fill our lives with that which is good and pleasing to the Lord. We seek the forgiveness of individuals whom we may have wronged and attempt restitution to the extent possible.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p27" pid="JjOHxwuC2kCruLvNdlRq3w" hash="O-1TUg">If our past behavior is such as to affect our standing in the Church, we confess to appropriate Church authorities and, if necessary, submit to Church discipline, which is not for the purpose of punishment only but is intended to heal and renew.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p28" pid="1AgwiB2SMU-ZwMOi16lWJQ" hash="68kmzw">Throughout the repentance process we have feelings of regret, remorse, and guilt, which cause us to suffer. However, our individual suffering does not satisfy the demands of justice which follow disobedience to divine law. We cannot pay the price for our sins.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p29" pid="xZZX85nuuEa2trd4lvjzEw" hash="A39HOg">The resurrected Christ has said, “For behold, I, God, have suffered these things for all, that they might not suffer if they would repent” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/19.16" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 19:16</a>). To the Nephites he declared, “Return unto me, and repent of your sins, and be converted, that <span class="emphasis">I may heal you</span>” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/9.13" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 9:13</a>; italics added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p30" pid="w3d6sOx9fkGO-8EXvkr8tw" hash="KaSkyA">The Lord’s gift of forgiveness, however, is not complete until it is accepted. True and complete repentance is a process by which we may become reconciled with God and accept the divine gift of forgiveness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p31" pid="uU1suBJtvEKY2HW3TTH8sQ" hash="459Pvw">In the words of Nephi, “It is by grace that we are saved, after all we can do” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/25.23" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 25:23</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p32" pid="vhLqOaFKGkmP9b-3OLvfRA" hash="_UPp6w">The effect of the infinite, atoning sacrifice was twofold: First, resurrection and immortality for all, unconditionally granted. Second, eternal life for each one who fulfills the prescribed conditions, which are faith in Jesus Christ as Savior and Redeemer, followed by repentance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p33" pid="lNvvuKUM4ki_cTF37GC0lA" hash="0U4L9w">Then we must qualify for and receive the saving and exalting ordinances of the gospel with their associated covenants, continuously striving to keep those covenants and obey the commandments of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p34" pid="v0jRTmmfc0WETz99DD0AAw" hash="PI4nzA">Being mortal, and despite our resolve and efforts, we will continue to fall short of perfection. However, with Nephi of old, conscious of our weaknesses, temptations, and past mistakes, we may say, “Nevertheless, I know in whom I have trusted” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/4.19" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 4:19</a>). There follows a natural resolve to renew our efforts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p35" pid="t5mVQPfOekC0JbYYvWY9oA" hash="ZBcC9w">Essential to receiving divine forgiveness are personal, individual recognition and acceptance of our Father’s mercy, made available to us by the atoning sacrifice of Jesus Christ and a renewed covenant to obey the principles of the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p36" pid="Leex9NnkmUWlUgDWPS05gA" hash="KRmrYg">Examples of this process and its results are found in the Book of Mormon. Having been taught the doctrine of the Atonement, the people of King Benjamin, conscious of their past transgressions, pleaded for mercy that by the atoning blood of Christ they might receive forgiveness of their sins, for, said they, “We believe in Jesus Christ, the Son of God. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p37" pid="SWjGMbLJj0mWVz3fJfgirw" hash="Xf40FA">“[And] the Spirit of the Lord came upon them, and they were filled with joy, having received a remission of their sins, and having peace of conscience, because of the exceeding faith which they had in Jesus Christ” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/4.2-3" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 4:2–3</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p38" pid="_I7_UJTraESe3RgYuwTryg" hash="_QZd1w">Each of us may ask, “How may I know that I am forgiven?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p39" pid="MLwYt9hfN0O3u2XHrk1XzQ" hash="C-UJRw">Having completed the steps of repentance, relying upon the grace and mercy of God, it is natural for us to testify of the Savior and his atoning sacrifice and to strive to be an example of the believers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p40" pid="DbycWQfKMEepqlbGoUaC6w" hash="6pdbuQ">From Elder Bruce R. McConkie, an Apostle of Jesus Christ, we receive these comforting words:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p41" pid="aOEO3_WITEOfB2Hbu2sOXw" hash="9kCTlw">“The relationship between the bearing of testimony by the power of the Holy Ghost and the forgiveness of sins illustrates a glorious gospel truth. It is that whenever faithful saints gain the companionship of the Holy Spirit, they are clean and pure before the Lord, for the Spirit will not dwell in an unclean tabernacle. Hence, they thereby receive a remission of those sins committed after baptism” (<span class="emphasis">The Mortal Messiah: From Bethlehem to Calvary,</span> 4 vols., Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1980, 3:40–41, n. 1).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p42" pid="_LIuWVugRE6wgccA4L8ekA" hash="QnXMQg">The central core of the gospel is the vicarious sacrifice of the Savior, which satisfies divine justice and makes operative God’s mercy, resulting in a universal, unconditional resurrection and the possibility of eternal life for each one who accepts Jesus Christ as Redeemer and obeys the principles, ordinances, and covenants of the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p43" pid="Xn_wSLpDn0-j90ndkPuX0w" hash="sE5FIA">The ancient prophet Isaiah taught us, “Cease to do evil;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p44" pid="L57tOkCr6EuhNiIVePJoog" hash="WWRHxQ">“Learn to do well. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p45" pid="4QKDjIwQ00OoYfENXj3WHw" hash="2pNqyg">“Though your sins be as scarlet, they shall be as white as snow; though they be red like crimson, they shall be as wool” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/1.16-18" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 1:16–18</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p46" pid="j85C6Aa31kGtMlCiu6GiTw" hash="h2e-fg">And further, “Surely he hath borne our griefs, and carried our sorrows. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p47" pid="WMU1s99akUWVL8zRBP-UGA" hash="kt_cXQ">“He was wounded for our transgressions, he was bruised for our iniquities: the chastisement of our peace was upon him; and with his stripes we are healed” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/53.4-5" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 53:4–5</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p48" pid="dPrDK7BHdUWSzeS7gzaBdw" hash="KBPcVA">The prophet of this dispensation, Joseph Smith, and his companion Sidney Rigdon gave testimony of the gospel, as recorded in the 76th section of the Doctrine and Covenants. Each of us may receive <span class="emphasis">a similar</span> spiritual witness, and therefore I suggest that we may express their testimony as our own <span class="emphasis">in these words:</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p49" pid="MTFAnI4hvEOoqdjeCnKcCg" hash="Jx3tAQ">“And this is the gospel …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p50" pid="5HmuqWM2iEORpF7a4_OHlw" hash="ds6o3Q">“That he came into the world, even Jesus, to be crucified for [me], and to bear [my] sins … , and to sanctify [me], and to cleanse [me] from all unrighteousness;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p51" pid="fuxCknydMU2DX2UlZGumnQ" hash="_CIvwg">“That through him [I] might be saved” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/76.40-42" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 76:40–42</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p52" pid="BqGAxXdUGU-J49weacLNIA" hash="wmGASQ">In conclusion, these verses from a favorite hymn:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="gpBCC2bNCketLX_jPAZTXw" hash="rt9UxQ">
            <span class="emphasis">How gentle God’s commands!</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="HIKXDUoFF0CzTIF2w0pdig" hash="kzpfOQ">
            <span class="emphasis">How kind his precepts are!</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="LAPGgEa9OkO7PV3_h-J-XQ" hash="6g0C5Q">
            <span class="emphasis">Come, cast your burdens on the Lord</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="Yv91g4mTo0morbVcrZouTw" hash="h9v23w">
            <span class="emphasis">And trust his constant care. …</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="EUD-PRhXsUOyRPzlj194Zg" hash="Z19y5g">
            <span class="emphasis">Why should this anxious load</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="m1G9nAMvkE6TwkRfBFgTPQ" hash="C57Xcg">
            <span class="emphasis">Press down your weary mind?</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="9Opxf8RYL0erCddmhvlHSw" hash="q3DkSw">
            <span class="emphasis">Haste to your Heav’nly Father’s throne</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="_OMV2JyJyEeaabM5ac1VlQ" hash="L741bg">
            <span class="emphasis">And sweet refreshment find.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="ZBw5FbxDwka6SIeTx84Vzg" hash="Wl7rRg">
            <span class="emphasis">His goodness stands approved,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="B2wDbcdQuEerMI3OD5GcMg" hash="39so9w">
            <span class="emphasis">Unchanged from day to day;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="bJY31kDjmE6goZKHNDOZTA" hash="QX_5xA">
            <span class="emphasis">I’ll drop my burden at his feet</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="8smUN9_u_ECiZkILNfVdRA" hash="kE5Hbw">
            <span class="emphasis">And bear a song away.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness.p53" pid="thfSiHVob0GNj2T4NyOr2w" hash="FRadjw">To these truths which I have sought to teach I bear solemn, personal witness, in the sacred name of our Lord and Savior, Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1993/10/divine-forgiveness</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1993-general-conference/1993-10-5050-elder-ronald-e-poelman-64k-eng.mp3" length="6446710" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 1993 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tithing: A Privilege</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege?lang=eng</link>
      <description>You and I are now among those generations given the privilege to know and to live the law of the tithe. The blessings that flow from obedience to that law are both temporal and spiritual.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_98905_000_032" doc-version="2" hash="96G4Qg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="12ktqvfUMUasduEAQ01eTA" hash="CyL5QQ">Tithing:</h1>
    <p class="subtitle" pid="qPIhXIQCA0asscZ7mbYYLQ" hash="XCbwAQ">A Privilege</p>
    <p class="authorName" pid="CdJusy_OD0SybCT2Uk_o4w" hash="4c4ENw">Ronald E. Poelman</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="rjJZRaG_70-Potdm2zNbfw" hash="k9n1Jg">You and I are now among those generations given the privilege to know and to live the law of the tithe. The blessings that flow from obedience to that law are both temporal and spiritual.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1d5e.jpg" alt="Elder Ronald E. Poelman" pid="8inCAH77fkirhMB7wq4YHQ" hash="HlaN0Q" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p1" pid="1OZ2joTvFUuRSZNjRak0Lw" hash="LBKUKQ">America was deep in the economic depression of the 1930s. I was one of several small children in our family, and our father had been unemployed for many months. There was no government assistance for the unemployed, and the Church welfare program was not yet in operation. Our needs were many. Some might have said we were destitute. Though I was only a child, I felt the anxiety and concern of my parents.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p2" pid="YjU89gdW4E6mxHusdtSvew" hash="zlpfjg">Each morning we knelt together as a family, and each one in turn led our prayer. One memorable morning it was Mother’s turn. She described some of our immediate needs, and then she thanked our Heavenly Father for the privilege of living the law of tithing. I immediately experienced a feeling of comfort and assurance. Living the law of the tithe was a privilege and would bring blessings. I did not doubt it because my mother knew it. Those feelings have remained and intensified throughout my life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p3" pid="Dh6jh3JVEUSSf1dIOfY_Fg" hash="tVjvZg">The first time I paid tithing, the amount was five cents. With my father, I went to the office of the bishop, who solemnly accepted my five pennies and wrote out the receipt. Then he stood and, coming from behind his desk, sat next to me. With his hand on my shoulder, he gave me the small but significant slip of paper and said, “Ronald, you have made a good beginning, and if you continue as you have begun, you can be a perfect tithe payer.” The idea of being perfect at anything seemed well beyond my ability. I was trying hard just to be a good boy. But with those words, the bishop inspired me to strive for perfection in that one basic aspect of the gospel. The blessings, both temporal and spiritual, have been abundant.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p4" pid="RJm9imHaI0-a-U02SRwppQ" hash="G4qORA">During the intervening years, my testimony of tithe paying as a privilege has been reconfirmed frequently. Obedience to that law, among others, has enabled me to be ordained to the holy priesthood, to be endowed in the house of the Lord, to serve a full-time mission, and to be sealed to family members for time and eternity. In addition, I have been privileged to return to the temple repeatedly to serve others and to be instructed regarding things of eternal importance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p5" pid="xjatv2EfPk27e9foC6FiXQ" hash="PLUAaw">The sacred significance of the law of tithing was confirmed by the Savior Himself following His resurrection and during His ministry to the people in what is now known as the Americas.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p6" pid="ylnzG_OKb0eiLN-IujAEyg" hash="fehqfQ">The Book of Mormon records that the Savior taught the Nephites from the scriptures they had, but spoke of other scriptures that they did not have, commanding them to write the words which the Father had given to Malachi, including these words:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p7" pid="6rlq9QY610Gt-8-tvwSbtg" hash="uBiPUw">“Will a man rob God? Yet ye have robbed me. But ye say: Wherein have we robbed thee? In tithes and offerings. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p8" pid="ZmiLZQFaC0my9jItVV1CpA" hash="K0-lKQ">“Bring ye all the tithes into the storehouse, that there may be meat in my house; and prove me now herewith, saith the Lord of Hosts, if I will not open you the windows of heaven, and pour you out a blessing that there shall not be room enough to receive it” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/24.8,10" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 24:8, 10</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p9" pid="s8pt5WVOYkm5UvS_nKWx7w" hash="dRkl8Q">The Savior further emphasized the importance of this commandment to us when He said to the Nephites, “These scriptures, which ye had not with you, the Father commanded that I should give unto you; for it was wisdom in him that they should be given unto future generations” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/26.2" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 26:2</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p10" pid="JTwtzocrbEG5DuE4X_eRNQ" hash="E_62jg">You and I are now among those generations given the privilege to know and to live the law of the tithe. The blessings that flow from obedience to that law are both temporal and spiritual, as many among us can testify.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p11" pid="D3Nc49Mc6ka5THL1gdHMMQ" hash="5gnXaw">In these latter days, the Lord has said, “Behold, now it is called today until the coming of the Son of Man, and verily it is a day of sacrifice, and a day for the tithing of my people” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/64.23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 64:23</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p12" pid="9RGXnozDvUagWcZZixpZMQ" hash="6NyhXw">May tithing be regarded as a sacrifice? Yes, particularly if we understand the meaning of the two Latin words from which the English word <span class="emphasis">sacrifice</span> is derived. These two words, <span class="emphasis">sacer</span> and <span class="emphasis">facere,</span> taken together mean “to make sacred.” That which we return to the Lord as tithing is indeed made sacred, and the obedient are edified.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p13" pid="6IHZCG7RdUu4Hv4GG69HZw" hash="KD6Cdg">Much earlier, the Lord emphasized the sacredness of tithing to Moses in these words, recorded in the book of Leviticus: “And all the tithe of the land … is the Lord’s: it is holy unto the Lord” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/lev/27.30" class="scriptureRef">Lev. 27:30</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p14" pid="m6EsAtdMu0WE2JxFhIDOog" hash="V8NZ_g">As a young married couple, my wife and I were expecting the birth of our first child. I was studying law at the university and working nights in a gasoline station. We had very little money. We had furnished our small basement apartment with some used furniture and many wooden boxes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p15" pid="R9PAKSoE0k6YCN8CMgjp_w" hash="oM6q1Q">As the time of the birth approached, we had assembled everything we would need, except we had no bed for the baby and no money to buy one.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p16" pid="RocbCA6X20Gn8X0gqYM7xQ" hash="Qbyhyw">It was our practice at that time to pay our tithing each month on fast Sunday. As that day approached, we discussed the possibility of postponing the paying of our tithing so that we could make an initial payment on a baby bed. In the spirit of the fast, and after praying, we decided to pay the tithing and trust our Heavenly Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p17" pid="ZbDiIHjKQk2DWNKhVdKMgQ" hash="rIK3zw">A few days later, I was walking in the business district of the city and unexpectedly met my former mission president, who asked if I was in school or working at a job. I replied that I was doing both.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p18" pid="zC1TBBajl0uxUB_354vd0Q" hash="g6FAnw">Was I married? “Yes!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p19" pid="uDV296f_vUiAObWngX4q9Q" hash="p8vgEQ">Did we have children? “No, but our first child will be born in just a few weeks.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p20" pid="PMsbTLG99EC_7AbNjIrE6A" hash="_oO-1A">“Do you have a bed for the baby?” he asked. “No,” I replied reluctantly, startled by the direct question.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p21" pid="pGWSMpHYGU2Y9AILRU2gow" hash="sN9ybA">“Well,” he said, “I am now in the furniture business, and it would please me to have a baby bed delivered to your apartment as a gift.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p22" pid="WN_SpLqihky3kxXcF8bC4g" hash="CcxUBA">A great feeling of relief, gratitude, and testimony came over me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p23" pid="G99exJsidUieBz1f8HbzeA" hash="gG25bA">The gift filled a temporal need but is still a poignant reminder of the spiritual experience that accompanied it, confirming again that the law of tithing is a commandment with a promise.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p24" pid="J0KuHY64MECct2aVJvxWQA" hash="4boBTA">The really serious challenges in life require not so much temporal resources but the gifts of the Spirit. Among such challenges might be the sickness, suffering, or death of a loved one; a rebellious and disobedient family member; false accusations; and other severe disappointments. During such trials we need increased faith, inspiration, comfort, courage, patience, and the ability to forgive. These blessings can be poured out of the windows of heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p25" pid="9QK2BJFa1Ey9-seI9t-0sw" hash="HXW-xg">There comes to mind those good and faithful people who believed the teachings of Alma the Elder and came into the fold of God. The Book of Mormon records that they were obedient and righteous (see Mosiah 18). Notwithstanding their goodness, they suffered great afflictions at the hands of their enemies. When they poured out their hearts to God, He answered them with words of comfort, assuring them that He would visit them in their afflictions (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/24.14" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 24:14</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p26" pid="ISxbI70680u62YjI1-Ou_w" hash="1pZk3A">Then we read, “The Lord did strengthen them that they could bear up their burdens with ease, and they did submit cheerfully and with patience to all the will of the Lord” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/24.15" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 24:15</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p27" pid="K-V8zAam2UWyk82o6Yc-vw" hash="mLZXYQ">May we also be so strengthened and submissive.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p28" pid="xGO3i-anEkuKjEK--TRs2Q" hash="BPdIuQ">Even though we live the law of the tithe, we surely will experience the trials and tribulations of mortality. However, if we are right with the Lord, then, as we face adversity, we can be assured that we will be blessed with faith, strength, wisdom, and help from others—with all that is necessary not only to overcome but to learn and to grow from these experiences.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p29" pid="NLNbsaFQqka8hU00UzkkBQ" hash="D-Rawg">Our prophet-leader, President Gordon B. Hinckley, has said: “I can testify concerning the law of tithing and its blessings because I have experienced them. And every man and woman in this Church who is an honest tithe payer, is honest with the Lord, can testify of the divinity of that principle” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> July 1996, 73).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p30" pid="t5I5eY3Rd0W5qgwMVAGnOQ" hash="1dyHlQ">As one of those Church members, I add my own testimony. The blessings from living the principle of the tithe can bring peace of mind, increased faith, inspiration, and a desire to live more completely all of the commandments of our Heavenly Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege.p31" pid="JOy4tQY1aUGLK2yfFWgIJg" hash="UnPsfg">Finally, and most importantly, I testify that I know that God lives, is our Father, and loves us. Jesus of Nazareth is the Son of God and our Savior and Redeemer. Today we are led by a living prophet, Gordon B. Hinckley. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1998/04/tithing-a-privilege</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1998-general-conference/1998-04-5030-elder-ronald-e-poelman-64k-eng.mp3" length="5359657" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 1998 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
