<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Ronald A. Rasband</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Ronald A. Rasband.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Ronald%20A.%20Rasband.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Ronald A. Rasband.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2000 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>One by One</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2000/10/one-by-one?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Embrace the Savior’s warm invitation to come unto Him, one by one, and be perfected in Him.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/one-by-one" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10028166_000_015" doc-version="2" hash="SSZLEQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/one-by-one.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="rLuIZAnEc0irarb6PDb-Jg" hash="u38_Cw">One by One</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="cF9MAwJCyU2unbPK7RcHZw" hash="HkziJA">Ronald A. Rasband</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="xgwpIe3w4k6OVKCi_S0oGg" hash="mdoCcg">Embrace the Savior’s warm invitation to come unto Him, one by one, and be perfected in Him.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/one-by-one.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-ac7.jpg" alt="Elder Ronald A. Rasband" pid="rDPQoePLOUKv40G-HID1Qw" hash="WcT5Xg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/one-by-one.p1" pid="0pw2cnWuTE2sgqV2vy_efg" hash="gTd7Dw">My dear brothers and sisters, I feel it a great privilege and honor to stand here at this pulpit today. I pray for the blessing of the Holy Spirit, that what I say may add to the spiritual feelings we all experience at conference time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/one-by-one.p2" pid="BkJ5RFxO5kOeSMEOqTfNkg" hash="u7RJkQ">I would be very ungrateful if I did not take this opportunity to thank the Lord in all sincerity for my calling as a Seventy. I would also like to thank our dear prophet, President Hinckley, and his fellow leaders of the Church for their confidence in me. I pledge to them and all of you my best efforts in the years of service that lie before me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/one-by-one.p3" pid="czCaTC3fGk-Mf20NAtWRsw" hash="Vmo43w">Through many hours of reflection, I have been drawn back to my pioneer ancestors in deep appreciation. All eight of my great-grandparents came into the Church as early converts. Six of the eight immigrated to the United States from Europe, where I am now serving. I feel a deep sense of love and connection to the European Saints and commit myself to do all that I possibly can to strengthen the Church and build up the kingdom of God there or wherever I may be assigned.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/one-by-one.p4" pid="PSOrVB-XgkqZ_ahcnYJ3ZQ" hash="DaFcqQ">I express my love and gratitude to my dear eternal companion and choice family for their devoted support and love. I wish to convey my love to our friends and dear missionaries whom we recently served with in the New York New York North Mission. One of the great blessings of my life is that of treasured friends and close associates that I have had the privilege to know and learn from.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/one-by-one.p5" pid="gnXoUqQeIUSWFBtcsw6Y2g" hash="aE8rqA">Throughout my life, I have come to know through my own experiences that Heavenly Father hears and answers our personal prayers. I know that Jesus is the living Christ and that He knows each of us individually, or as the scriptures express it, “one by one.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/one-by-one.p6" pid="SUgFYu03r0-MaTb2kNYKJw" hash="xpLPcg">This sacred assurance is taught compassionately by the Savior Himself in His appearance to the people of Nephi. We read of this in 3 Nephi, chapter 11, verse 15:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/one-by-one.p7" pid="3Tcy9R2jREm0LorR3RsodQ" hash="bRtOEQ">“And it came to pass that the multitude went forth, and thrust their hands into his side, and did feel the prints of the nails in his hands and in his feet; and this they did do, going forth <span class="emphasis">one by one</span> until they had all gone forth” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.15" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:15</a>; emphasis added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/one-by-one.p8" pid="QkA1SIfYbE-hpxQo3-PcXQ" hash="Q-4L0g">To further illustrate the “one by one” nature of our Savior’s ministry, we read in 3 Nephi, chapter 17, verse 9:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/one-by-one.p9" pid="6gjdV43Vdke8GoF4U6rtUg" hash="fzPpCg">“And it came to pass that when he had thus spoken, all the multitude, with one accord, did go forth with their sick and their afflicted, and their lame, and with their blind, and with their dumb, and with all them that were afflicted in any manner; and he did heal them <span class="emphasis">every one</span> as they were brought forth unto him” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/17.9" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 17:9</a>; emphasis added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/one-by-one.p10" pid="mETFti6XP0ijr1oA0lBh3w" hash="fFglTA">We then read of the special blessing given to the precious children in verse 21: “And when he had said these words, he wept, and the multitude bare record of it, and he took their little children, <span class="emphasis">one by one,</span> and blessed them, and prayed unto the Father for them” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/17.21" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 17:21</a>; emphasis added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/one-by-one.p11" pid="s9kg5Q6pXUivjJl06UaA6w" hash="ouGXgg">This was not a small gathering. In verse 25 [<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/17.25" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 17:25</a>] we read: “And they were in number about two thousand and five hundred souls; and they did consist of men, women, and children.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/one-by-one.p12" pid="ul7Y89dnaUq9W8vZmwA-vA" hash="qufy2A">Certainly, there is a very profound and tender personal message here. Jesus Christ ministers to, and loves us all, one by one.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/one-by-one.p13" pid="7AyYFg5EuUy8TmK1IE5-0g" hash="RqCqIA">As we reflect on our Savior’s way of loving, we sustain you dedicated stake and ward leaders, men and women of great faith. We gratefully recognize the many efforts of those of you working with the youth. And we express great appreciation to our caring Primary leaders and teachers for your Christlike service. We consider each of your one-by-one ministries and say thank you and please, please continue. Perhaps never in the history of mankind do we need to be serving on a one-by-one basis more than we do now.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/one-by-one.p14" pid="8F2S_AwOg0qjiHB4XxZt2Q" hash="pSM6bA">During the final months of our mission last year, we experienced an event that taught once again this profound principle that each of us is known and loved by God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/one-by-one.p15" pid="BH6mfevLU06jz41AnNLj1w" hash="buri6Q">Elder Neal A. Maxwell was coming to New York City for some Church business, and we were informed that he would also like to have a mission conference. We were so pleased to have this opportunity to hear from one of the Lord’s chosen servants. I was asked to select one of our missionaries to provide the opening prayer for the meeting. I might have randomly picked one of the missionaries to pray, but felt to ponder and prayerfully select one whom the Lord would have me ask. In going through the missionary roster, a name boldly stood out to me: Elder Joseph Appiah of Accra, Ghana. He was the one I felt the Lord wanted to pray at the meeting.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/one-by-one.p16" pid="kotJsxLOQEWfFHofcuOi9w" hash="onipzg">Prior to the mission conference, I was having a regularly scheduled interview with Elder Appiah and told him of the prompting that I had received for him to pray. With amazement and humility in his eyes, he began to weep deeply. Somewhat surprised by his reaction, I started to tell him that it was all right and he wouldn’t have to pray, when he informed me he would love to offer the prayer, that his emotion was caused by the love he has for Elder Maxwell. He told me that this Apostle is very special to the Saints in Ghana and to his own family. Elder Maxwell had called his father to be the district president in Accra and had sealed his mother and father in the Salt Lake Temple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/one-by-one.p17" pid="6pYRPxKFUESswQAJZuO8AQ" hash="PoeD4A">Now, I didn’t know any of what I just related about this missionary or his family, but the Lord did and inspired a mission president on behalf of <span class="emphasis">one</span> missionary to provide a lifelong memory and testimony-building experience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/one-by-one.p18" pid="LfWSq7asTUydGIXtF6qoTQ" hash="3oo3pA">At the meeting, Elder Appiah offered a wonderful prayer and made a humble contribution to a meeting where Elder Maxwell taught the missionaries of the attributes of Jesus Christ. All who were there will never forget the feelings of love they experienced for their Savior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/one-by-one.p19" pid="McBXWbMYw0yHe1gW1nBUsg" hash="5eijUQ">I have a testimony in my heart, brothers and sisters, that God, our Heavenly Father, and Jesus Christ know and love us individually. I’m not sure I fully understand how, I just know and have experienced that They do. I urge all of us in our own ministries, to our families and to our fellowman, to embrace the Savior’s warm invitation to come unto Him, one by one, and be perfected in Him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/10/one-by-one.p20" pid="d2yza5art0WxIKwQLVD1cg" hash="rX19_g">I share this witness and hope, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2000/10/one-by-one</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2000-general-conference/2000-10-2050-elder-ronald-a-rasband-64k-eng.mp3" length="3563630" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2000 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Rising Generation</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Our rising generation is worthy of our best efforts to support and strengthen them in their journey to adulthood.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00006561_000_018" doc-version="3" hash="glVuNQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="wZ1LlmA11USgk0IL_MNmMQ" hash="6snD6Q">Our Rising Generation</h1><p class="authorName" uuid="f8ca7541-3651-4467-bad3-8a96a9347299" pid="8D5_SkaStUecIViufk8PRQ" hash="HkziJA">Ronald A. Rasband</p><p class="kicker" pid="L8_VCn8Ilk6-xjyBrICOfA" hash="GCMzNQ">Our rising generation is worthy of our best efforts to support and strengthen them in their journey to adulthood.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" uuid="efdbce42-3292-4977-a2c0-287fdd900646">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation.t1" uuid="">
      <img src="en2006lp.nfo-o-b1.jpg" alt="Elder Ronald A. Rasband" uuid="b08a0f98-39a9-4f21-93c8-30fcac5841c3" pid="oK81qEIxiUG1pkBPmr3GfA" hash="WOIWeA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation.p1" uuid="06189aba-2693-47dc-8f23-4a0690f5e184" pid="ygRJyRn1sUmvM0QsMJwcEA" hash="ytK4jA">Good evening, my dear brethren of the priesthood. Tonight throughout the world we are gathered nearer to the temples of the Lord than ever before in the history of mankind. Through the loving-kindness of our Savior in directing His prophets, 122 temples are now accessible to the Lord’s covenant people to obtain their own temple blessings and perform vital ordinances for their departed ancestors. And more have been announced and are coming! We thank you, President Hinckley, for your inspired leadership in this tremendous effort.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation.p2" uuid="4af5d2a1-0256-4cab-acde-d40224c6deb2" pid="QStrh_TQk0OMXqZNrpgmKg" hash="euOW_g">In an early Book of Mormon time, the members of the Church also gathered near a temple to receive instruction from their prophet and leader. Late in his life, King Benjamin called upon fathers to bring their families together, to give them counsel and admonitions. From Mosiah we read:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation.p3" uuid="94b4d5e3-8f84-4b4d-8a17-4c64a07d4df2" pid="4U7SwKbNUUKK0qWIbqEkNA" hash="YFCasQ">“And it came to pass that when they came up to the temple, they pitched their tents round about, every man according to his family. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation.p4" uuid="d552f769-dbb3-4ba1-b3b0-05b337857927" pid="dK-1rrXZPUG3f058i4Qy5A" hash="FjLz2Q">“… Every man having his tent with the door thereof towards the temple, that thereby they might remain in their tents and hear the words which King Benjamin should speak unto them” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/2.5-6" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 2:5–6</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation.p5" uuid="c867cb76-1666-4198-a0b2-e1764f223227" pid="aAv7go8JoUeSZ6sSadsXKg" hash="-mTgxg">I love the imagery of these verses. Figuratively speaking, brethren, are the doors of our homes pitched towards the temples we so love? Do we attend as often as we can, showing our children through our example the importance of these sacred and special places?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation.p6" uuid="6abcd7d3-7393-433a-9976-682beeef7cdc" pid="2l9eFNgRiUSZXoM1bH07PA" hash="cpJO2g">As recorded in Mosiah, families received the word of the Lord through their prophet with enthusiasm and commitment. The people were so moved by King Benjamin’s teachings that they entered into a new covenant to follow the Lord Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation.p7" uuid="c9743260-257a-47e0-8eb6-79316c763f0f" pid="tJbPpTS0MkeR4IWhMbEqlQ" hash="6TB1JA">However, there is a sad epilogue to this story. We learn later in Mosiah concerning those who were but little children in the tents at the time of King Benjamin’s sermon:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation.p8" uuid="290f0a15-2a5e-43d2-a8c7-17b684864458" pid="A9avXxjEV02n0N5oa4Dkmw" hash="pBnu1g">“Now it came to pass that there were many of the rising generation that could not understand the words of king Benjamin, being little children at the time he spake unto his people; and they did not believe the tradition of their fathers” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/26.1" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 26:1</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation.p9" uuid="1f7d6c72-004c-4d10-a249-e2ce588f6a00" pid="o_LbJXxd9Ua6D_tgVxyzqQ" hash="STcP0g">What happened to that rising generation, brethren? Why didn’t the young children accept the righteous traditions of their fathers? More importantly, here we are centuries later, in a day of many temples and constant prophetic direction, and what of our rising generation? Do we have reason to be concerned? Certainly we do!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation.p10" uuid="ba1d365c-ed24-4a96-9af2-e94c125131c1" pid="DHy7mBTAe0OagTVqHmueRA" hash="zmGotA">The young men here and throughout the world, and their young women counterparts, are very special. President Hinckley has spoken of them:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation.p11" uuid="c96ce417-23d4-450f-a19b-ab26c68db7cd" pid="4_Ycfqm7AUmLhyibhIDCcg" hash="WeDBmA">“I have said many times that I believe we have the finest generation of young people that this Church has ever known. … They try to do the right thing. They are bright and able, clean and fresh, attractive and smart. … They know what the gospel is about, and they are trying to live it, looking to the Lord for His guidance and help” (“Your Greatest Challenge, Mother,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona,</span> Jan. 2001, 113; <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 2000, 97–98).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation.p12" uuid="9337aece-4684-49d1-8372-08f43837f64b" pid="SZyjbeJcb0ivhSvOOst4pg" hash="I-pKhA">All of us who are involved with these youth know the truth of President Hinckley’s words.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation.p13" uuid="b6604f89-30f3-4f95-8ef9-3352220bddc6" pid="2Syub_9deE2_NEpJG0pAAw" hash="RdGUUQ">Elder Henry B. Eyring of the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles, however, provides us with a somber warning, speaking of the youth:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation.p14" uuid="0ea10436-ce1c-4290-bb88-4cdf399501ba" pid="mtsI58M43Eytxibik7qgFw" hash="2ySoRw">“Many of them are remarkable in their spiritual maturity and in their faith. But even the best of them are sorely tested. And the testing will become more severe” (“We Must Raise Our Sights,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Sept. 2004, 14).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation.p15" uuid="8af3d601-9321-46a0-b879-b289d7467586" pid="qXrogq0NOkex_zTG4ADTBA" hash="INQnsw">This warning that “the testing will become more severe” gets my attention. Our rising generation is worthy of our best efforts to support and strengthen them in their journey to adulthood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation.p16" uuid="f2f1278c-7c09-4b3d-ac92-8f82ac7ce28c" pid="ORMZdvX-iEaThxpUbv960A" hash="JX1twQ">In these perilous times, as our youth are faced with this increased adversity, we can learn from others. In the armed forces, particularly in all the navies throughout the world, every seaman understands one phrase that is a clarion call for immediate help, no matter what he is doing or where he is on the ship. The call is “All hands on deck.” Many a battle at sea has been won or lost by the response to this call.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation.p17" uuid="e4c42402-9e8c-4db3-bbf4-813de2ccd8f7" pid="be0wbnHV30Gip1nLht1PWA" hash="MtQgQg">We—as members of the Church, leaders of youth, anxious fathers, and concerned grandfathers—all need to respond to the call for “all hands on deck” as it pertains to our youth and young single adults. We must all look for opportunities to bless the youth whether or not we are currently closely associated with them. We must continue to teach and fortify fathers and mothers in their divinely declared roles with their children in the home. We must ask ourselves constantly if that extra sporting event, that extra activity or errand outside of the home is more important than families being together at home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation.p18" uuid="b0656035-dd6d-4556-aa23-66173f8bc541" pid="Xse3XBLBWUmhzBAOWc756A" hash="d2FhnQ">Now is the time, brethren, when in every action we take, in every place we go, with every Latter-day Saint young person we meet, we need to have an increased awareness of the need for strengthening, nurturing, and being an influence for good in their lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation.p19" uuid="c14363b6-2f43-4f89-978d-cb32bc7250f3" pid="qY6mqOMiKUaOo2T6pNTM9g" hash="JHTDEg">In our own family, we have had such an experience with wonderful, watchful priesthood leaders. When I was first called to the Seventy some years ago, we were assigned to move to Solihull, England, to serve in the Area Presidency. Sister Rasband and I took our two youngest children with us on this assignment. Our daughter was a young single adult and our son a 17-year-old who liked American-style football and played it very well. We were very concerned about them. No friends, no extended family, and no American football! I wondered, “Would this exciting new experience prove to be a serious trial for our family?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation.p20" uuid="b0b77f1f-2c7d-409f-8e2a-a2a41819a2a4" pid="RtLY3U26Bkm33gUArTsPuA" hash="RN9HEA">The answer came in an early assignment I received. I had been asked to speak to the missionaries at the Missionary Training Center in Preston, England. I called President White of the center and was pleased to hear that he knew of my family situation. He suggested we include our children on our visit to Preston. Once we were there, he even invited our daughter and son to speak to the missionaries! What a thrill for them to be and feel included and share their testimonies of the Lord’s work!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation.p21" uuid="3f47ef9b-e22a-4b82-849f-592df2dec4d0" pid="KUvZSlcN30uDPjY-9YWjAg" hash="tBQecw">When finished and after tender good-byes to those missionaries, we visited the beautiful Preston England Temple, which was close to the Missionary Training Center. As we walked near the front door, there stood President and Sister Swanney, the temple president and matron. They greeted us and welcomed us into the temple with, “Elder Rasband, how would you and your family like to perform baptisms for the dead?” What a wonderful idea! We looked at each other and gratefully accepted. After performing the ordinances and while my son and I were still in the font with tears of joy in our eyes, he put his hand on my shoulder and asked, “Dad, why haven’t we ever done this before?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation.p22" uuid="1479cd87-df7f-406b-b5a3-f17da04a7de3" pid="6jggzXunXkWa3U2Z8T0crA" hash="JMH-RQ">I thought of all the football games, all the movies we had attended together, all of the good times we had shared—certainly happy memories and traditions that are so important to build.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation.p23" uuid="21e74c98-cd57-4808-93b9-afa14535d3f6" pid="-aFJEQnI6k-XnQ8jhqXVnQ" hash="dBmp3w">However, I realized we had an opportunity to add more meaningful spiritual experiences with our children like what we had experienced in Preston that day. Thanks to those caring and observant priesthood leaders, I knew then that our family was going to do fine in Europe. How grateful we are for the many priesthood and Young Women leaders who have always been watchful and loving to our children and yours.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation.p24" uuid="8e427bfe-fee9-4801-bc5d-27e044bafaa9" pid="-z6os2CXx0G6NQ6dRBMD_A" hash="AMCMzw">Looking to another Book of Mormon time: Nephi lived in a situation where some members of his family struggled with obedience, harmony, and faithfulness. He most certainly understood the necessity for attentive commitment to children of the rising generation. He said late in his life:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation.p25" uuid="d7ac1f2f-3e46-43f0-a2f6-de0e174cf4b4" pid="1pUWwmGsWk-x95kX6NF0gQ" hash="UagHZg">“And we talk of Christ, we rejoice in Christ, we preach of Christ, we prophesy of Christ, and we write according to our prophecies, that our children may know to what source they may look for a remission of their sins” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/25.26" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 25:26</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation.p26" uuid="6997d2db-9015-4810-9849-ab2ff1dd0d0e" pid="BT7K1kdXhESAMpOMByDvXQ" hash="-dh0ow">I pray that as the holders of the priesthood of God we may each of us do all things that lie in our power to teach our youth what source they may look to for a remission of their sins, even the Lord Jesus Christ. May we each respond with our most sincere efforts to “all hands on deck” as it pertains to saving our own rising generation—they are certainly worth our very best efforts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation.p27" uuid="f91f6932-ef9b-4210-bde3-a80eb636da2b" pid="gyaD4w0E7kmZTWKjbHE2Cw" hash="CwrKZg">I testify that this is the Lord’s true Church, directed by Him through our dear prophet, even Gordon B. Hinckley, whom I love and sustain. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2006/04/our-rising-generation</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2006-general-conference/2006-04-3020-elder-ronald-a-rasband-64k-eng.mp3" length="5468180" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special Experiences</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2008/04/special-experiences?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Our personal journey through life provides us with many special experiences that become building blocks of faith and testimony.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/special-experiences" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00009475_000_005" doc-version="2" hash="gUKZwA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/special-experiences.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="J_qlHlaHM06aGg7zsXSwLg" hash="Fi8JCg">Special Experiences</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Ul7dLhUc1kmEgbpnQCqP9Q" hash="ngxEPw">Elder Ronald A. Rasband</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="XZgvDr2Bq0u4p_J5Ep3pig" hash="wV3uvw">Our personal journey through life provides us with many special experiences that become building blocks of faith and testimony.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/special-experiences.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/special-experiences.p1" pid="TaUw80J0BUacyvUglthVCg" hash="n7GUuA">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="11"></span>I would like to add my testimony and witness on this special day that President Thomas S. Monson is the Lord’s prophet on the earth. I am grateful to have this privilege to speak in general conference.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/special-experiences.p2" pid="rMNYQyGXRUikcUVL4DIxTw" hash="NAyAvw">I am grateful, as you are, for the experience we have in this historic conference as we sustain, in an orderly and patterned way, our new prophet, First Presidency, and other leaders of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/special-experiences.p3" pid="dvI13Gbpr0KM7CbxTob12A" hash="gSLwAw">This kind of experience fortifies our testimonies and increases our faith in the knowledge that this is indeed the Lord’s true and living Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/special-experiences.p4" pid="7TbkWDFoMUuVykscyR4kuA" hash="HSLSeg">Our personal journey through life provides us with many special experiences that become building blocks of faith and testimony. These experiences come to us in vastly different ways and at unpredictable times. They can be powerful spiritual events or small enlightening moments. Some experiences will come as serious challenges and heavy trials that test our ability to cope with them. No matter what the experience may be, each gives us a chance for personal growth, greater wisdom, and, in many cases, service to others with more empathy and love. As the Lord stated to the Prophet Joseph Smith in a reassuring way during one of his most significant trials at Liberty Jail, “All these things shall give thee experience, and shall be for thy good” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/122.7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 122:7</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/special-experiences.p5" pid="uFHDejfzjE6HTOcDcUHncQ" hash="2ReAgA">As experiences accumulate in our lives, they add strength and support to each other. Just as the building blocks of our homes support the rest of the structure, so too do our personal life experiences become building blocks for our testimonies and add to our faith in the Lord Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/special-experiences.p6" pid="dUmvqGPMpkm6ZOOxfUQ5Fw" hash="KJooXQ">This very conference session illustrates the value of a life full of experiences. As we follow the wise counsel of our leaders and marvel at their teachings and spirit, is it any wonder that the Lord chooses His senior Apostle, after years of preparation, to become His chosen prophet?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/special-experiences.p7" pid="062gaFbldUWIOy3M_MfpZA" hash="KVOQRw">My patriarchal blessing indicates that I would be given special experiences that would strengthen my own testimony. Brothers and sisters, think of the special experiences you have been blessed with in your life that have given you conviction and joy in your heart. Remember when you first knew that Joseph Smith was God’s prophet of the Restoration? Remember when you accepted Moroni’s challenge and knew that the Book of Mormon was indeed another testament of Jesus Christ? Remember when you received an answer to fervent prayer and realized that your Heavenly Father knows and loves you personally? As you contemplate such special experiences, don’t they give you a sense of gratitude and resolve to go forward with renewed faith and determination?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/special-experiences.p8" pid="mqAvSN3QJk-OsXHGjcSAZw" hash="Zzevrw">Not long ago Sister Rasband and I had an experience we shall never forget. I was assigned to preside at two stake conferences in Peru. While there, we went to the city of Puno, high in the Andes Mountains, on Lake Titicaca. At 12,000 feet (3,660 m) above sea level, we were amazed at this simple and beautiful city, high on this Andean lake. We met with stake presidents in the area and had a wonderful youth fireside with hundreds of young people from the Puno area.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/special-experiences.p9" pid="r6cYhxlV0Ue4k4RaJn_luA" hash="mD82mQ">One morning we were invited to visit a small group of local members who lived out on the floating reed islands of Lake Titicaca. The people who live there are known as the Uros Indians of Bolivia and Peru.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/special-experiences.p10" pid="YEtkdCqFWE2iZnT9vghV_A" hash="7SSk6Q">We were told that a few Latter-day Saint families had joined together and built their own small, new floating island. With excitement, we took a boat out to the island and were greeted warmly by these wonderful members.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/special-experiences.p11" pid="BIAhqrV-MUmNDbQq4RhwsQ" hash="togItA">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="12"></span>We held their babies wrapped in the most beautiful, colorful handmade blankets. We ate the fish they caught that very day from the lake, which had been so carefully prepared and generously shared. We saw their wares and handicrafts and exchanged gifts with one another.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/special-experiences.p12" pid="MTULQ6FVSUCjcKXwlm2AhA" hash="RLecow">As we visited, we learned that their children paddled by canoe 45 minutes to and from Puno for seminary and school each day. We were also pleased that these members knew the scriptures well, understood them, and loved them. Eagerly they showed us their current temple recommends, having been endowed and sealed in the Cochabamba Bolivia Temple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/special-experiences.p13" pid="LDr_p5yPBkOS-vn0_F462Q" hash="IITgGA">Before we were to leave, one of the mothers asked if we would kneel with them and have a family prayer. I remember well kneeling on the spongy reeds with these faithful Saints. As we knelt, she asked if I would say the prayer and, using the Melchizedek Priesthood, dedicate their new island and home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/special-experiences.p14" pid="LMNn8CT4AkiUcsYX4Q5yvw" hash="slcXKg">I was deeply humbled that, there on the floating islands of Lake Titicaca, these faithful Latter-day Saint families would ask me to pray for the little island of Apu Inti and ask the Lord to bless the homes and families of the Lujanos and Jallahuis.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/special-experiences.p15" pid="vdXXcOjrz0O2UOz9pVuEgA" hash="00dxcA">As I consider this special experience that the Lord blessed us with, I know a new building block has been added to my house of faith. I often think of that experience in Puno as another reminder of the fulfillment of my own patriarchal blessing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/special-experiences.p16" pid="Fst7PZi3DESM0Q19fCFvdw" hash="dNcEJA">From the preface of the Doctrine and Covenants, written in 1831, foretelling the expansion of the Lord’s work in our day, the Lord revealed:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/special-experiences.p17" pid="6vNo04b5WkiM1A8Y9PW-mg" hash="vr1F5w">“But that every man might speak in the name of God the Lord, even the Savior of the world;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/special-experiences.p18" pid="bgOx_zuQLUS8lCQwgd06Qg" hash="hKygLw">“That faith also might increase in the earth;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/special-experiences.p19" pid="PEUSISaalE6ZVlq9Lf_GFg" hash="NnJ61Q">“That mine everlasting covenant might be established;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/special-experiences.p20" pid="cBh4njW3Fk2a6xJF3Y3yrw" hash="sGh6vg">“That the fulness of my gospel might be proclaimed by the weak and the simple unto the ends of the world” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.20-23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:20–23</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/special-experiences.p21" pid="IjYK74aM20ikGKgs2Hx5Jg" hash="hI6skQ">Brothers and sisters, the weak and the simple members of the Church, like you and me, are taking the gospel to the ends of the earth, to Puno, Peru, and other far-off places. Faith is increasing among God’s covenant people, and I believe it is through having a personal treasury of such valued experiences that an increase of faith can happen for each of us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/special-experiences.p22" pid="Pubb73xzAkOQiL0OLZ0ZbQ" hash="zMaaiQ">President Monson said: “[The Lord] commands. And to those who obey Him, whether they be wise or simple, He will reveal Himself in the toils, the conflicts, the sufferings which they shall pass through in His fellowship, and … they shall learn in their <span class="emphasis">own experience</span> Who He is” (in “The Way of the Master,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Jan. 2003, 7; quoting Albert Schweitzer, <span class="emphasis">The Quest of the Historical Jesus</span> [1948], 401; emphasis added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/special-experiences.p23" pid="B0wyoRkADkyiwiBzfduqww" hash="lLFKCA">In these days of worldly intrusions into our lives, when trials and difficulties may seem to engulf us, let us remember our own special spiritual experiences. These building blocks of faith will bring us conviction and reassurance of a caring, loving Father in Heaven, of our Lord and Savior, Jesus Christ, and of Their restored true and living Church. I so testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2008/04/special-experiences</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2008-general-conference/2008-04-1030-elder-ronald-a-rasband-64k-eng.mp3" length="3822748" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2008 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Divine Call of a Missionary</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The Lord needs every able young man to prepare and recommit, starting tonight, to be worthy of a call from the prophet of God to serve a mission.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50021388_000_023" doc-version="2" hash="r85g-w">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="PS-fc63CxEiu6zQOU8nG2Q" hash="znOyZQ">The Divine Call of a Missionary</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="20aFSe4jL0CKvv2lGua7dw" hash="HkziJA">Ronald A. Rasband</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="mgSVMGtKMUKOdPpA451dNw" hash="HDKVGA">The Lord needs every able young man to prepare and recommit, starting tonight, to be worthy of a call from the prophet of God to serve a mission.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p1" pid="XvxGYNs6hEe2onJYQcExkw" hash="xjcwgg">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="51"></span>Good evening, my dear brethren of the priesthood. Tonight I would like to speak about missionary service. I direct my comments to the vast army of young men who hold the Aaronic Priesthood who are gathered throughout the entire world and to their fathers, grandfathers, and priesthood leaders who watch over them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p2" pid="mOSf9q0SSke2CY38g4K0HA" hash="-MtKOQ">Missionary work is a subject very close to my heart, as it is to every member of the eight Quorums of the Seventy, whom the Lord has appointed to go “before his face into every city and place, whither he himself would come.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> Missionary work is the lifeblood of the Church and the lifesaving blessing to all who accept its message.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p3" pid="13U_liPAAUe7guSM95wpcQ" hash="qsknaA">When the Master ministered among men, He called fishermen at Galilee to leave their nets and follow Him, declaring, “I will make you fishers of men.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> The Lord extended those calls to humble men so that through them others would hear the truths of His gospel and come unto Him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p4" pid="QQ7ofHL_PEeCJOPwRgbYiw" hash="6NmcNQ">In June of 1837, the Prophet Joseph Smith called Heber C. Kimball, an Apostle, to go on a mission to England. Elder Kimball’s call came as the two sat in the Kirtland Temple and Joseph spoke with divine authority: “Brother Heber, the Spirit of the Lord has whispered to me, ‘Let my servant Heber go to England and proclaim my gospel and open the door of salvation to that nation.’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p5" pid="3L2bRr0X7EGlqsEToa38Rg" hash="7NXvfg">That whispering of the Spirit is an example of how the call comes to servants of the Lord to send missionaries to their fields of labor.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p6" pid="cS0ykal5hUuCHsYTDilKKQ" hash="S8BPHQ">Today missionaries go forth two by two as appointed by the Lord, carrying that same message, with the same divine call to serve from the prophet of God. Our prophet, President Thomas S. Monson, has said of those called to serve: “The missionary opportunity of a lifetime is yours. The blessings of eternity await you. Yours is the privilege to be not spectators but participants on the stage of priesthood service.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p7" pid="atR4QC8INkeHYRMGhHP4Ug" hash="VUi7YQ">The stage is yours, my dear Aaronic Priesthood boys. Are you ready and willing to play your part? The Lord needs every able young man to prepare and recommit, starting tonight, to be worthy of a call from the prophet of God to serve a mission.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p8" pid="y57OsiYWakawDhVtoGkfkA" hash="EnmsKg">I remember fondly our entire family’s great joy when two of our children received their calls to serve as full-time missionaries. Excitement and anticipation filled our hearts as they each opened their special letter from the prophet of God. Our daughter Jenessa was called to the Michigan Detroit Mission, and our son, Christian, was called to the Russia Moscow South <span class="pageBreak" page-number="52"></span>Mission. What humbling and thrilling experiences, all at the same time!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p9" pid="KmC3LKXFgkaw8_lWKyslWQ" hash="92AF4w">As Sister Rasband and I had the privilege of presiding over the New York New York North Mission several years ago, I marveled as the missionaries arrived in New York City.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p10" pid="kEcaAXNczkK38kDTLNmM9w" hash="mOR3vA">As I interviewed them on their first day in the mission, I had a profound sense of gratitude for each missionary. I felt that their call to our mission was divinely designed for them and for me as their mission president.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p11" pid="zkmonHiAR0qCu8WUOxOKug" hash="6C2VmA">After finishing our mission assignment, I was called by President Gordon B. Hinckley to serve as a Seventy in the Church. Part of my early training as a new General Authority included an opportunity to sit with members of the Twelve as they assigned missionaries to serve in one of the 300-plus missions of this great Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p12" pid="4R8HBeLeH0ebu3ObuNL5NA" hash="1g839g">With the encouragement and permission of President Henry B. Eyring, I would like to relate to you an experience, very special to me, which I had with him several years ago when he was a member of the Quorum of the Twelve. Each Apostle holds the keys of the kingdom and exercises them at the direction and assignment of the President of the Church. Elder Eyring was assigning missionaries to their fields of labor, and as part of my training, I was invited to observe.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p13" pid="YzFaAW6WHkq764QAfTUOPg" hash="kRdVEg">I joined Elder Eyring early one morning in a room where several large computer screens had been prepared for the session. There was also a staff member from the Missionary Department who had been assigned to assist us that day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p14" pid="GlQUyKy4206z7T7GMHyNaw" hash="qsm3Hg">First, we knelt together in prayer. I remember Elder Eyring using very sincere words, asking the Lord to bless him to know “perfectly” where the missionaries should be assigned. The word “perfectly” said much about the faith that Elder Eyring exhibited that day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p15" pid="uuesS2dqZEilXGqO9-Cbig" hash="N-Xe-A">As the process began, a picture of the missionary to be assigned would come up on one of the computer screens. As each picture appeared, to me it was as if the missionary were in the room with us. Elder Eyring would then greet the missionary with his kind and endearing voice: “Good morning, Elder Reier or Sister Yang. How are you today?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p16" pid="dndqCrq46kC83sajYKFjEw" hash="Vyqg7w">He told me that in his own mind he liked to think of where the missionaries would conclude their mission. This would aid him to know where they were to be assigned. Elder Eyring would then study the comments from the bishops and stake presidents, medical notes, and other issues relating to each missionary.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p17" pid="ZPUGMjq4MUG4diWtlN0MCQ" hash="uods0w">He then referred to another screen which displayed areas and missions across the world. Finally, as he was prompted by the Spirit, he would assign the missionary to his or her field of labor.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p18" pid="MpwBayp_8Ue_mVvESn0hSA" hash="mIsDHQ">From others of the Twelve, I have learned that this general method is typical each week as Apostles of the Lord assign scores of missionaries to serve throughout the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p19" pid="-uNDhEphFUyS0uIVJZP1ew" hash="VI8Vxg">Having served as a missionary in my own country in the Eastern States Mission a number of years ago, I was deeply moved by this experience. Also, having served as a mission president, I was grateful for a further witness in my heart that the missionaries I had received in New York City were sent to me by revelation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p20" pid="E-G2dZNSZEqzJmN_IgS5bg" hash="9EF3mg">After assigning a few missionaries, Elder Eyring turned to me as he pondered one particular missionary and said, “So, Brother Rasband, where do you think this missionary should go?” I was startled! I quietly suggested to Elder Eyring that I did not know and that I did not know I could know! He looked at me directly and simply said, “Brother Rasband, pay closer attention and you too can know!” With that, I pulled my chair a little closer to Elder Eyring and the computer screen, and I did pay much closer attention!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p21" pid="Qb6suuxF8EmhAXMYE-GWNg" hash="BCx8MA">A couple of other times as the process moved along, Elder Eyring would turn to me and say, “Well, Brother Rasband, where do you feel this missionary should go?” I would name a particular mission, and Elder Eyring would look at me thoughtfully and say, “No, that’s not it!” He would then continue to assign the missionaries where he had felt prompted.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p22" pid="mQPOnreLYEa6KQRw06NZLQ" hash="fE6WQg">As we were nearing the completion <span class="pageBreak" page-number="53"></span>of that assignment meeting, a picture of a certain missionary appeared on the screen. I had the strongest prompting, the strongest of the morning, that the missionary we had before us was to be assigned to Japan. I did not know that Elder Eyring was going to ask me on this one, but amazingly he did. I rather tentatively and humbly said to him, “Japan?” Elder Eyring responded immediately, “Yes, let’s go there.” And up on the computer screen the missions of Japan appeared. I instantly knew that the missionary was to go to the Japan Sapporo Mission.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p23" pid="r1FpFGnbr02Z8Ykq1ltrvQ" hash="e-xmyw">Elder Eyring did not ask me the exact name of the mission, but he did assign that missionary to the Japan Sapporo Mission.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p24" pid="lnDDNQNZXUimCXAjtPZuwA" hash="XZBlGg">Privately in my heart I was deeply touched and sincerely grateful to the Lord for allowing me to experience the prompting to know where that missionary should go.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p25" pid="DHSJWro9n0ywunzVIPvMDQ" hash="FFWBqQ">At the end of the meeting Elder Eyring bore his witness to me of the love of the Savior, which He has for each missionary assigned to go out into the world and preach the restored gospel. He said that it is by the great love of the Savior that His servants know where these wonderful young men and women, senior missionaries, and senior couple missionaries are to serve. I had a further witness that morning that every missionary called in this Church, and assigned or reassigned to a particular mission, is called by revelation from the Lord God Almighty through one of these, His servants.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p26" pid="Zl9kYmyo9UK5uHzqED3Sbg" hash="3Sadpw">I conclude with the Lord’s words to the Whitmer brothers, who had a profound role in the early days of the Restoration. They were witnesses to the gold plates, and their signed testimonies are included at the front of every copy of the Book of Mormon. They were among the first band of missionaries called by a prophet of God in 1829 to preach the gospel of the Lord Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p27" pid="-ABOfOQm30q0NFX0TT_BTA" hash="BXixHg">In the preface to section 14 of the Doctrine and Covenants, it states, “Three of the Whitmer sons, each having received a testimony as to the genuineness of the work, became deeply concerned over the matter of their individual duty.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p28" pid="cmZHrRxZgU2T_rQHeYwmNg" hash="N0Cqmw">To John and Peter Whitmer Jr. the Lord said this: “For many times you have desired of me to know that which would be of the most worth unto you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p29" pid="fxemY0-w1EGb5cohH5CFug" hash="00nX8Q">I suppose many of you young men have asked yourselves that same question. Here is the Lord’s answer: “And now, behold, I say unto you, that the thing which will be of the most worth unto you will be to declare repentance unto this people, that you may bring souls unto me, that you may rest with them in the kingdom of my Father.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary.p30" pid="KYG9U_hI6kCVPxbEOMlxRw" hash="WDE1bA">At this time in your life, a mission call from the Lord, my young friends, is the most important work that you can do. Prepare now, live righteously, learn from your family and Church leaders, and come join with us in building the kingdom of God on earth—accept your divine appointment in “so great a cause.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> This is my humble prayer in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2010/04/the-divine-call-of-a-missionary</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2010-general-conference/2010-04-3020-elder-ronald-a-rasband-64k-eng.mp3" length="5632026" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2010 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special Lessons</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons?lang=eng</link>
      <description>It is my hope and prayer that we will continue to bear nobly our burdens and to reach out to those among us who are suffering.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10485_000_43rasba" doc-version="2" hash="1HniwA"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="cIflOJSOdka5aqprc2gw1A" hash="eP4pjw">Special Lessons</h1><p class="authorName" pid="nU6io1O4jEy8i8LG15lc3A" hash="-SpCUQ">By Elder Ronald A. Rasband</p><p class="kicker" pid="8OmCu9GsDkqsyw4ujq2nRQ" hash="M_vkfw">It is my hope and prayer that we will continue to bear nobly our burdens and to reach out to those among us who are suffering.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p5" pid="_EZN-sAZNE2t-auKxhxmUA" hash="4Z3yrQ">
      <span class="pageBreak" page-number="80"></span>For the past 20 months, our family has been blessed with the privilege of having a very special baby.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p6" pid="ygQJaOe59EGYE_s43ayWbw" hash="tLdd4A">Little Paxton, our grandson, was born with a very rare chromosomal deletion, a genetic disorder that distinguishes him, literally, as one in hundreds of millions. For our daughter and her husband, an uncharted, life-changing journey began when Paxton was born. This experience has become a crucible for learning special lessons tied to the eternities.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p7" pid="xydEth29yUyG5hplqZ0Z_w" hash="H3kN8A">Dear Elder Russell M. Nelson, who just spoke to us, taught:</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p8" pid="IKBg_rv4UE6bMG0iBzQCuQ" hash="atulCg">“For reasons usually unknown, some people are born with physical limitations. Specific parts of the body may be abnormal. Regulatory systems may be out of balance. And all of our bodies are subject to disease and death. Nevertheless, the gift of a physical body is priceless. …</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p9" pid="IjZ3yocM4UWjfUDGnRe2XQ" hash="GcPn_A">“A perfect body is not required to achieve a divine destiny. In fact, some of the sweetest spirits are housed in frail frames. …</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p10" pid="tMpGHRf4hEu5kkFSij5GaQ" hash="BkIMyQ">“Eventually the time will come when each ‘spirit and … body shall be reunited again in … perfect form; both limb and joint shall be restored to its proper frame’ (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/11.43" class="scriptureRef">Alma 11:43</a>). Then, thanks to the Atonement of Jesus Christ, we can become perfected in Him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p11" pid="u3TWIMQaF0i54z7491jVlQ" hash="4hyAww">To all of you who have challenges, concerns, disappointments, or heartaches with a dear one, know this: with infinite love and everlasting compassion, God our Heavenly Father loves your afflicted one, and He loves you!</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p12" pid="Uo7yYNVxPkm-rAB29nV5Dw" hash="uKTQ2g">Some might ask when faced with such suffering, how could Almighty God let this happen? And then that seemingly inevitable question, why did this happen to me? Why must we experience disease and events that disable or call precious family members home early or extend their years in pain? Why the heartaches?</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p13" pid="27YsOpUmxUyVOKUDXQ4tng" hash="94h2mQ">At these moments we can turn to the great plan of happiness authored by our Heavenly Father. That plan, when presented in the pre-earth life, prompted us all to shout for joy.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> Put simply, this life is training for eternal exaltation, and that process means tests and trials. It has always been so, and no one is spared.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p14" pid="1Gf8WTVYPEGac2YYWJAUDQ" hash="ObCwwA">Trusting in God’s will is central to our mortality. With faith in Him, we draw upon the power of Christ’s Atonement at those times when questions abound and answers are few.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p15" pid="zlJoiU224kmc3_bPHdsrWQ" hash="2s3pFA">After His Resurrection, when visiting the Americas, our Savior, Jesus <span class="pageBreak" page-number="81"></span>Christ, reached out to all with this invitation:</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p16" pid="nIuLZqLZU0aA1jXNGOn1GA" hash="xalAzQ">“Have ye any that are sick among you? Bring them hither. Have ye any that are lame, or blind, or halt, or maimed, or leprous, or that are withered, or that are deaf, or that are afflicted in any manner? Bring them hither and I will heal them, for I have compassion upon you; my bowels are filled with mercy. …</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p17" pid="T4xgR9G040OZeNjouwqJ9Q" hash="GRbC7A">“And it came to pass that when he had thus spoken, all the multitude, with one accord, did go forth with their sick and their afflicted, and their lame, and with their blind, and with their dumb, and with all them that were afflicted in any manner; and he did heal them every one as they were brought forth unto him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p18" pid="gOcYCgY2c0GRSj9tL7Lm5w" hash="PnjcAw">Great strength can be found in the words “all the multitude … did go forth”—<span class="emphasis">all,</span> brothers and sisters. We <span class="emphasis">all</span> face challenges. And then the phrase: “that were afflicted in any manner.” All of us can identify, can’t we?</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p19" pid="06c3Vgqh-E-cq5UmPk4MOw" hash="kSlxmA">Shortly after precious Paxton was born, we knew Heavenly Father would bless us and teach us special lessons. As his father and I put our fingers on his tiny head in the first of many priesthood blessings, the words came into my mind from the ninth chapter of John: “that the works of God should be made manifest in him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p20" pid="dr05uZxyC0i1nZG227GbbQ" hash="bOoHTg">God’s works are definitely being made manifest through Paxton.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p21" pid="sryBxi25eUuxXTTj5Y6neQ" hash="rpfnyA">We are learning patience, faith, and gratitude through the balm of service, endless hours of intense emotions, tears of empathy, and the prayers and expressions of love for dear ones in need, especially Paxton and his parents.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p22" pid="Pih7jhsonkiz6Yj3kLbt0Q" hash="ahrr6Q">President James E. Faust, my boyhood stake president, said: “I have a great appreciation for those loving parents who stoically bear and overcome their anguish and heartbreak for a child who was born with or who has developed a serious mental or physical infirmity. This anguish often continues every day, without relief, during the lifetime of the parent or the child. Not infrequently, parents are required to give superhuman nurturing care that never ceases, day or night. Many a mother’s arms and heart have ached years on end, giving comfort and relieving the suffering of her special child.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p23" pid="xszQx5h9qkGMJ2QG75T5vw" hash="uruTnQ">As described in Mosiah, we have witnessed the Savior’s pure love given to Paxton’s family, which love is available to all: “And now it came to pass that the burdens which were laid upon Alma and his brethren were made light; yea, the Lord did strengthen them that they could bear up their burdens with ease, and they did submit cheerfully and with patience to all the will of the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p24" pid="GL-NVgBGwESvFIbXbzx2nA" hash="4grDQg">One night early in Paxton’s life, we were in the neonatal intensive care unit of the wonderful Primary Children’s Medical Center in Salt Lake City, Utah, marveling at the dedicated, undivided attention given by the doctors, nurses, and caregivers. I asked my daughter how we would ever pay for this and ventured a guess at what the cost would be. A doctor standing <span class="pageBreak" page-number="82"></span>nearby suggested that I was “way low” and that little Paxton’s care would cost substantially more than I had estimated. We learned that much of the expense for care given in this hospital is covered by the generous gifts of time and monetary contributions of others. His words humbled me as I thought of the worth of this tiny little soul to those who were so carefully watching over him.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p25" pid="6D6s8GA5tkKH03nrDql8RA" hash="jtJf4w">I was reminded of a familiar missionary scripture that took on new meaning: “Remember the worth of souls is great in the sight of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p26" pid="_KzuOFXLt0-wnA1HdWc0pA" hash="aEnAMA">I wept as I pondered the limitless love our Heavenly Father and His Beloved Son, Jesus Christ, have for each one of us, while learning in a powerful way what the worth of a soul is, both physically and spiritually, to God.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p27" pid="2dfpJy-thkq4n23arXljZQ" hash="mcWx0Q">Paxton’s family has learned they are surrounded by countless heavenly and earthly ministering angels. Some have quietly slipped in when needed and silently slipped out. Others have been at the door with food, doing the laundry, picking up the siblings, calling with encouragement, and especially praying for Paxton. Thus another special lesson learned: If you come upon a person who is drowning, would you ask if they need help—or would it be better to just jump in and save them from the deepening waters? The offer, while well meaning and often given, “Let me know if I can help” is really no help at all.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p28" pid="Sc7GOMoB8kiyK2Kk10YkBg" hash="nqYgkw">We continue to learn the important value of being aware of and interested in the lives of those around us, learning not only the importance of giving help but also the overwhelming joy that comes from helping others.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p29" pid="kD9SqVZZr0Cbr2yetR0R6w" hash="xUz85A">Dear President Thomas S. Monson, who is such a magnificent example of lifting the downtrodden, said: “God bless all who endeavor to be their brother’s keeper, who give to ameliorate suffering, who strive with all that is good within them to make a better world. Have you noticed that such individuals have a brighter smile? Their footsteps are more certain. They have an aura about them of contentment and satisfaction … for one cannot participate in helping others without experiencing a rich blessing himself.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p30" pid="ea8OZU805k2VzyY8RHcxRg" hash="fp0b2g">Though we will face trials, adversities, disabilities, heartaches, and all manner of afflictions, our caring, loving Savior will always be there for us. He has promised:</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p31" pid="-5RJ0pBp00y1gVesLiC9VQ" hash="68LReA">“I will not leave you comfortless: I will come to you. …</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p32" pid="kiDQNf6Gmk6lDYtVtwY4PQ" hash="U99bQw">“My peace I give unto you: not as the world giveth, give I unto you. Let not your heart be troubled, neither let it be afraid.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p33" pid="QCwISzQCp0uOiQnmmiVjrQ" hash="Zg135Q">How grateful we are to our Father in Heaven for our champion Paxton. Through him the Lord has manifest His works and continues to teach us these valuable, sacred, and special lessons.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p34" pid="CssGRSAnF0638U-uCBFb5w" hash="k8Cqkw">I would like to close with the words from a beloved hymn:</p>
    <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.f1">
      <div class="stanza">
        <p class="line" pid="0JQ14uitzk2PtnrWcK51yA" hash="4NMmPA">We are all enlisted till the conflict is o’er;</p>
        <p class="line" pid="UOU4Iiji7kiPLjBd9rQ2Jg" hash="lkKm7Q">Happy are we! Happy are we!</p>
        <p class="line" pid="vb0qsWqpG0arK4zitdj1nA" hash="yJlxlQ">Soldiers in the army, there’s a bright crown in store;</p>
        <p class="line" pid="kKLWHxVXLUyhOIZHjI7SQQ" hash="qUgPuQ">We shall win and wear it by and by.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      </div>
    </div>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons.p39" pid="RTTy_HFJnUyEO5n70sRxKA" hash="VRh3Uw">Brothers and sisters, it is my hope and prayer that we will continue to bear nobly our burdens and to reach out to those among us who are suffering and in need of being lifted and encouraged. May we each thank God for His blessings and renew our commitment to our Father in Heaven of humble service to His children. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2012/04/special-lessons</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2012-general-conference/2012-04-4030-elder-ronald-a-rasband-64k-eng.mp3" length="5472090" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Joyful Burden of Discipleship</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Ronald A. Rasband teaches that we can receive joy by serving each other and bearing one other's burdens as disciples of the Lord. </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10985_000_13rasband" doc-version="3" hash="6YAmfw">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="-h5p4olMo0OQSQdt4qBCjw" hash="aKlukw">The Joyful Burden of Discipleship</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p" pid="n6wGGWIYsEujy63FkW55Lg" hash="-SpCUQ">By Elder Ronald A. Rasband</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p" pid="vq9q4mar7ka_yuAE217wug" hash="hptprg">Of the Presidency of the Seventy</p>
		</div>
		<img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/leaders/ronald-a-rasband.jpg" altText="Elder Ronald A. Rasband" pid="uvfPgjQBVE-s7pYzbebTTg" hash="VwifIA" />
		<p class="kicker" pid="yNpQp0rAbUulFrk6BgZWGA" hash="umwwvQ">To sustain our leaders is a privilege; it comes coupled with a personal responsibility to share their burden and to be disciples of the Lord.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="PQ3_hmkkek6s8m2z0Np7nQ" hash="-SpCUQ1">By Elder Ronald A. Rasband</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock" pid="wSts_tGH7kqd8mjZEeI77Q" hash="-7todA">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p5" pid="MShOldteYkmCIIFpCXpVYA" hash="wCnn7Q">On May 20 of last year a massive tornado pummeled the suburbs of Oklahoma City, in the heartland of America, carving a trail more than a mile (1.6 km) wide and 17 miles (27 km) long. This storm, an onslaught of devastating tornadoes, altered the landscape and the lives of the people in its path.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p6" pid="xpPri_Tmv0qAS5fg27a2eQ" hash="HFAUbA">Just a week after the massive storm struck, I was assigned to visit the area where homes and belongings were strewn across the flattened, ravaged neighborhoods.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p7" pid="ldEAo1P16UqjBYG8MRcJBQ" hash="fg196g">Before I left, I spoke with our beloved prophet, President Thomas S. Monson, who relishes such errands for the Lord. With respect borne not only of his office but also of his goodness, I asked, “What do you want me to do? What do you want me to say?”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p8" pid="ZCdURHR02Emwtxk5vF5JQg" hash="23p-nQ">He tenderly took my hand, as he would have done with each one of the victims and each of those helping with the devastation had he been there, and said:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p9" pid="hLJuug8txk6dQ2J6Mv2UIQ" hash="m4MXXg">“First, tell them I love them.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p10" pid="HnRaJLPWVEmX73WHFBBCQw" hash="lFOyzg">“Second, tell them I am praying for them.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p11" pid="PjPnWzuUb0iiQpSxJBhkHg" hash="_DGRog">“Third, please thank all those who are helping.”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p12" pid="lzDyp5aqX0yMtT7PJOjmOg" hash="D2jM0Q">As a member of the Presidency of the Seventy, I could feel the weight on my shoulders in the words the Lord spoke unto Moses:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p13" pid="WIYCRe5QW02oipj8TQ-wig" hash="bNhqRw">“Gather unto me seventy men of the elders of Israel, whom thou knowest to be the elders of the people, and officers over them; …</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p14" pid="T0ZQnoZrRk6CABR4fbruog" hash="pRp6Jw">“And I will come down and talk with thee there: and I will take of the spirit which is upon thee [Moses], and will put it upon them; and they shall bear the burden of the people with thee, that thou bear it not thyself alone.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p15" pid="KY9ftyoZqku-3OZ9P_J_Jg" hash="hNw-_Q">These are words from ancient times, yet the Lord’s ways have not changed.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p16" pid="HplNpLuYe0G4HL2DDySncg" hash="x8J-BQ">Currently in the Church, the Lord has called 317 Seventies, serving in 8 quorums, to assist the Twelve Apostles in carrying the burden placed on the First Presidency. I joyfully feel that responsibility in the depths of my very soul, as do my fellow Brethren. However, we are not the only ones assisting in this glorious work. As members of the Church worldwide, <span class="pageBreak" page-number="10"></span>we all have the wonderful opportunity of blessing the lives of others.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p17" pid="Cih_rrcp8028jFdkwCIq7Q" hash="Fv46TA">I had learned from our dear prophet what the storm-tossed people needed—love, prayers, and appreciation for helping hands.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p18" pid="8tQg5VITHEiF6JwS3LKz3A" hash="37ALHw">This afternoon each of us will raise our right arm to the square and sustain the First Presidency and Quorum of the Twelve Apostles as prophets, seers, and revelators of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. This is not a mere formality, nor is it reserved for those called to general service. To sustain our leaders is a privilege; it comes coupled with a personal responsibility to share their burden and to be disciples of the Lord Jesus Christ.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p19" pid="MxRXxUJih0i3v64dFeZIOw" hash="BYI_mg">President Monson has said:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p20" pid="Syf0I8jso0C3JmiIQe_jlw" hash="SmBFUw">“We are surrounded by those in need of our attention, our encouragement, our support, our comfort, our kindness—be they family members, friends, acquaintances, or strangers. We are the Lord’s hands here upon the earth, with the mandate to serve and to lift His children. He is dependent upon each of us. …</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p21" pid="OHA3oVqCwEOs1zUwI3fChQ" hash="keYPrg">“‘… Inasmuch as ye have done it unto one of the least of these … , ye have done it unto me’ [Matthew 25:40].”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p22" pid="1BGUHqjxIUydb2BrUaLbzw" hash="JoWhrw">Will we respond with love when an opportunity is before us to make a visit or a phone call, write a note, or spend a day meeting the needs of someone else? Or will we be like the young man who attested to following all of God’s commandments:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p23" pid="kmgWY4ByxUOj6o7iXBrGJg" hash="zTu_-g">“All these things have I kept from my youth up: what lack I yet?</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p24" pid="oftfawSNP0uL13w3LEXJ5A" hash="pZ8Lhw">“Jesus said unto him, If thou wilt be perfect, go and sell that thou hast, and give to the poor, and thou shalt have treasure in heaven: and come and follow me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p25" pid="jdV5-9MWskuLIbtLOCQVag" hash="Dz-yNQ">The young man was being called to a greater service at the side of the Lord to do the work of the kingdom of God on earth, yet he turned away, “for he had great possessions.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p26" pid="nHU1g19GXUmisNM1YMbrWA" hash="NHtg7Q">What of our earthly possessions? We can see what a tornado can do with them in just minutes. It is so important for each of us to strive to lay up our spiritual treasures in heaven—using our time, talents, and agency in service to God.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p27" pid="ktG4uhduvEm3TWPjUz43xA" hash="zVKUSQ">Jesus Christ continues to extend the call “Come and follow me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> He walked His homeland with His followers in a selfless manner. He continues to walk with us, stand by us, and lead us. To follow His perfect example is to recognize and honor the Savior, who has borne all of our burdens through His sacred and saving Atonement, the ultimate act of service. What He asks of each one of us is to be able and willing to take up the joyful “burden” of discipleship.</p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p28" pid="bPAsECS_z0W9abN6aPOuuw" hash="u5zxpw">While in Oklahoma, I had the opportunity to meet with a few of the families devastated by the mighty twisters. As I visited with the Sorrels family, I was particularly touched by the experience of their daughter, Tori, then a fifth grader at Plaza Towers Elementary School. She and her mother are here with us today.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p29" pid="ls29g72C6UCl11FQzk-hUQ" hash="h2L_1A">Tori and a handful of her friends huddled in a restroom for shelter as the tornado roared through the school. Listen as I read, in Tori’s own words, the account of that day:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p30" pid="4ZNEqvX8GUioLeE535w2mg" hash="yEuUQQ">“I heard something hit the roof. I thought it was just hailing. The sound got louder and louder. I said a prayer that Heavenly Father would protect us all and keep us safe. All of a sudden we heard a loud vacuum sound, and the roof disappeared right above our <span class="pageBreak" page-number="11"></span>heads. There was lots of wind and debris flying around and hitting every part of my body. It was darker outside and it looked like the sky was black, but it wasn’t—it was the inside of the tornado. I just closed my eyes, hoping and praying that it would be over soon.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p31" pid="ytpyGxw7l0SOLJ1wqsGeIw" hash="50tjfg">“All of a sudden it got quiet.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p32" pid="7g4OsSY6R0K2JdZ8C1NByA" hash="kjJGgw">“When I opened my eyes, I saw a stop sign right in front of my eyes! It was almost touching my nose.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span>
			</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p33" pid="1xbIP3Gmj0GDO0Y7wWU2GQ" hash="v_tnTw">Tori, her mother, three of her siblings, and numerous friends who were also in the school with her miraculously survived that tornado; seven of their schoolmates did not.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p34" pid="bLdycIqaKkGi4TOUYqLzOw" hash="-dICjQ">That weekend the priesthood brethren gave many blessings to members who had suffered in the storm. I was humbled to give Tori a blessing. As I laid my hands on her head, a favorite scripture came to mind: “I will go before your face. I will be on your right hand and on your left, and my Spirit shall be in your hearts, and mine angels round about you, to bear you up.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span>
			</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p35" pid="QzvIlM43U0qOCd3ro1Q-ZA" hash="L-n37g">I counseled Tori to remember the day when a servant of the Lord laid his hands on her head and pronounced that she had been protected by angels in the storm.</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p36" pid="RbLn5etYzUukuZLsXDdIig" hash="AIPVxA">Reaching out to rescue one another, under any condition, is an eternal measure of love. This is the service I witnessed in Oklahoma that week.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p37" pid="eL9q1G6shkWKMBmTxMnW0w" hash="nw9YDA">Often we are given the opportunity to help others in their time of need. As members of the Church, we each have the sacred responsibility “to bear one another’s burdens, that they may be light,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> “to mourn with those that mourn,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> and to “lift up the hands which hang down, and strengthen the feeble knees.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p38" pid="rpiDbShHP0S1TAVa8dSDqQ" hash="N1D_mQ">Brothers and sisters, how grateful the Lord is for each and every one of you, for the countless hours and acts of service, whether large or small, you so generously and graciously give each day.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p39" pid="0b-PoglTgEumfSGUK_A4rw" hash="iZMiYQ">King Benjamin taught in the Book of Mormon, “When ye are in the service of your fellow beings ye are only in the service of your God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p40" pid="Wk11yMGK40Wpnth-ttXsZg" hash="oegVfQ">Focusing on serving our brothers and sisters can guide us to make divine decisions in our daily lives and prepares us to value and love what the Lord loves. In so doing, we witness by our very lives that we are His disciples. When we are engaged in His work, we feel His Spirit with us. We grow in testimony, faith, trust, and love.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p41" pid="Yu-Hd7Nan0mt_t-_SFvzPA" hash="CPwQhQ">I know that my Redeemer lives, even Jesus Christ, and that He speaks to and through His prophet, dear President Thomas S. Monson, in this, our day.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship.p42" pid="L85AZn8rcUGKFzQXYDCigQ" hash="KHKPpg">May we all find the joy that comes from the sacred service of bearing one another’s burdens, even those simple and small, is my prayer in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2014/04/the-joyful-burden-of-discipleship</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2014-general-conference/2014-04-1030-elder-ronald-a-rasband-64k-eng.mp3" length="5367642" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2014 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Stand All Amazed</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2015/10/i-stand-all-amazed?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder Rasband expresses gratitude for and testifies of the Savior’s love and Atonement, and he encourages Latter-day Saints to reach out to others with love.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/i-stand-all-amazed" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_13768_000_51rasband" doc-version="3" hash="ZAecjQ">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/i-stand-all-amazed.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="2M5bnPJZekqyW-t-Etk2_A" hash="Jc0lRQ">I Stand All Amazed</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/i-stand-all-amazed.p2" pid="IqcGCWNNcECWlxW0GS-OlQ" hash="-SpCUQ">By Elder Ronald A. Rasband</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/i-stand-all-amazed.p3" pid="wRD3Oky4PEaxepSATBnzRQ" hash="F9R90A">Of the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles</p>
		<a href="gl://image/?pid=WqAOrAio5EmehTy6XW3PwA"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" alt="Elder Ronald A. Rasband" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255570/66c9b855786143009e0b963732d1d0c1/100x125.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x62="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255570/66c9b855786143009e0b963732d1d0c1/50x62.jpg" data-src-100x125="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255570/66c9b855786143009e0b963732d1d0c1/100x125.jpg" data-src-200x250="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255570/66c9b855786143009e0b963732d1d0c1/200x250.jpg" data-src-320x401="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255570/66c9b855786143009e0b963732d1d0c1/320x401.jpg" data-src-460x576="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255570/66c9b855786143009e0b963732d1d0c1/460x576.jpg" data-src-640x802="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255570/66c9b855786143009e0b963732d1d0c1/640x802.jpg" data-src-1024x1283="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255570/66c9b855786143009e0b963732d1d0c1/1024x1283.jpg" data-src-2048x2567="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255570/66c9b855786143009e0b963732d1d0c1/2048x2567.jpg" data-src-3569x4475="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255570/66c9b855786143009e0b963732d1d0c1/3569x4475.jpg" pid="WqAOrAio5EmehTy6XW3PwA" hash="oXks4A"></img></a></div>
		<p class="kicker" pid="fDiSuW0SNEq4lr3C7V4WeA" hash="ff8o0g">My testimony of Jesus Christ has been built from many special experiences in which I have come to know His great love for each one of us.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="fYaXBaFUrEqxoZaQOrVmpA" hash="HkziJA">Ronald A. Rasband</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/i-stand-all-amazed.p5" pid="oWxZIpgOjUGsOzk_cFaf2Q" hash="DRugMg">My dear brothers and sisters throughout the world, I’m very grateful to the First Presidency for inviting me to share my humble testimony this Sabbath day. The words of a favorite Latter-day Saint hymn describe my current feelings:</p>
		<div class="poetry">
			<div class="stanza">
				<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/i-stand-all-amazed.p6" pid="EyLRNtV-U0aCu4CaMD18dA" hash="pb3qZA">I stand all amazed at the love Jesus offers me,</p>
				<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/i-stand-all-amazed.p7" pid="EbwwoP_unE2f5fd-Te6kTQ" hash="rqz_dA">Confused at the grace that so fully he proffers me. …</p>
				<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/i-stand-all-amazed.p8" pid="jbqo_R43w0OUU82AMZ3-mg" hash="tfnivw">I marvel that he would descend from his throne divine</p>
				<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/i-stand-all-amazed.p9" pid="nmINIxV7eEWjzyKeZtFI4A" hash="OUScoQ">To rescue a soul so rebellious and proud as mine,</p>
				<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/i-stand-all-amazed.p10" pid="Jl2Tle-InUiSKXqb7iWldQ" hash="Xmsj2A">That he should extend his great love unto such as I,</p>
				<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/i-stand-all-amazed.p11" pid="l3M3nPMDJkGREsxKjaTglQ" hash="Sx-kxQ">Sufﬁcient to own, to redeem, and to justify. …</p>
				<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/i-stand-all-amazed.p12" pid="-bsOBcWBHkCIsQfYV8Juug" hash="E6KubQ">Oh, it is wonderful, wonderful to me!<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
			</div>
		</div>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/i-stand-all-amazed.p13" pid="Nz84jzChcUqbH7I8OR0TQg" hash="oRIstw">A few days ago I had the great privilege to meet with the First Presidency and receive this call from our dear prophet, President Thomas S. Monson. I want to witness to all of you of the strength and love President Monson had as he said to me, “This call comes from the Lord Jesus Christ.”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/i-stand-all-amazed.p14" pid="3IFAhWqqW0Sng_OLSfEHLQ" hash="UEU_VQ">I am overwhelmed and shaken to my very core to consider the import and significance of those words so tenderly spoken by our loving prophet. President Monson, President Eyring, President Uchtdorf, I love you and will serve the Lord and you with all of my heart, might, mind, and strength.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/i-stand-all-amazed.p15" pid="Ltm23Cz5TUKq6vrMIkU-Sg" hash="NJntsA">Oh, how I have loved President Boyd K. Packer and Elders L. Tom Perry and Richard G. Scott. I dearly miss them. I am blessed to have been trained and taught at the feet of these dear Brethren. Not in the smallest part am I able to walk in their shoes, yet I am honored to stand tall on their shoulders and carry on in the Lord’s ministry.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/i-stand-all-amazed.p16" pid="sSYc2CqNFkW2MnDURHGJ0w" hash="CBb3Hg">When I think of those who have helped make me who I am, I think ﬁrst of my sweet and selfless eternal companion, Melanie. Through the years, she has helped mold me like potter’s clay into a more polished disciple of Jesus Christ. Her love and support, and that of our 5 children, their spouses, and our 24 grandchildren, sustain me. To my dear family, I love you.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/i-stand-all-amazed.p17" pid="FKZSpdbudkyh6ULcGlBDqA" hash="nRGPlg">Like Nephi of old, I was born of goodly parents in the gospel and they of goodly parents back six generations. My earliest ancestors who joined the Church were from England and Denmark. These early pioneers gave their all to the gospel of Jesus Christ and leave a legacy for their posterity to follow. I am so grateful for a multigenerational Latter-day Saint family, and I know this is a worthy goal for all of us to strive for.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/i-stand-all-amazed.p18" pid="95ydc96YJ0WYf-M-9sI2Qg" hash="w8YiUQ">Many others have contributed to preparing my life for this new call. They include my childhood friends and family, early leaders, teachers, and lifelong mentors. I must include those from my early mission to the eastern states and our beloved missionaries from the New York New York North Mission. For the many who have inﬂuenced and shaped my life, I am most grateful.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/i-stand-all-amazed.p19" pid="Bc_XJEZJY0arhmA4NnSjTw" hash="OxRiaw">I have cherished serving with my Brethren of the Seventy. For 15 years I have been in one of the greatest quorums and loving brotherhoods of the Church. Thank you, my dear fellow servants. Now I look forward to belonging to a new quorum. President Russell M. Nelson, my love is deep for you and each member of the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/i-stand-all-amazed.p20" pid="mCsMA3B-dkiRNfPpk65MwQ" hash="IIFz8A">Sister Rasband and I have been blessed to visit members during many assignments in congregations and missions around the world. We love the Latter-day Saints everywhere! Your faith has increased our faith; your testimonies have added to our testimony.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/i-stand-all-amazed.p21" pid="8wqsTpRRx0K8f5FrkKUkkg" hash="iD7Jog">Now, if I could leave one small message with you today, it would be this: the Lord has said, “Love one another; as I have loved you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> I’m conﬁdent that there is no choice, sin, or mistake that you or anyone else can make that will change His love for you or for them. That does not mean He excuses or condones sinful conduct—I’m sure He does not—but it does mean we are to reach out to our fellowman in love to invite, persuade, serve, and rescue. Jesus Christ looked past people’s ethnicity, rank, and circumstances in order to teach them this profound truth.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/i-stand-all-amazed.p22" pid="ebG5diuswE6cRUgwZkgDaA" hash="Dkt_FQ">I have been asked many times when I received my testimony.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/i-stand-all-amazed.p23" pid="MH6TLiecWEaxUE6CY9H2lQ" hash="ogCCUQ">I can’t remember not believing in Heavenly Father and Jesus Christ. I have loved Them since I learned of Them at the knees of my angel mother, reading scripture and gospel stories. That early belief has now grown into a knowledge and a witness of a loving Heavenly Father, who hears and answers our prayers. My testimony of Jesus Christ has been built from many special experiences in which I have come to know His great love for each one of us.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/i-stand-all-amazed.p24" pid="XL53CermmEmXt7p-n7TaGg" hash="G6Os7A">I’m grateful for our Savior’s Atonement and wish like Alma to shout it with the trump of God.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> I know that Joseph Smith is God’s prophet of the Restoration and that the Book of Mormon is the word of God. And I know that President Thomas S. Monson is God’s true servant and prophet on the earth today.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/i-stand-all-amazed.p25" pid="sLBA0IC1rkuD0qkJjTEHkA" hash="pmBI6w">As we follow our prophet, I pray that we may have charity in our hearts toward others and that we will become a living witness and indeed “stand all amazed at the love Jesus offers [us].” Oh, may it be “wonderful, wonderful to [you and to] me.” In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2015/10/i-stand-all-amazed</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2015-general-conference/2015-10-4020-elder-ronald-a-rasband-64k-eng.mp3" length="3362457" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Standing with the Leaders of the Church</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church?lang=eng</link>
      <description>&lt;div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_13285_000_34rasband" doc-version="3" hash="R3p25A"&gt;
	
	&lt;div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.head1"&gt;
		&lt;h1 class="title" pid="hhS311ZU30GbrVLci9mgdQ" hash="FcgLkA"&gt;Standing with the Leaders of the Church&lt;/h1&gt;
		&lt;div class="byline"&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p2" pid="znNOWsJXqU-sLTdae1OlFA" hash="-SpCUQ1"&gt;By Elder Ronald A. Rasband&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p3" pid="Bw8qzv3XcEywj54IMZH8nA" hash="F9R90A"&gt;Of the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=9yTxLvdX7UOl3mjVEWI7DA"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" altText="Elder Ronald A. Rasband" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1628372/79ecbd089eaa46868e515c8f581efeb5/100x125.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x62="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1628372/79ecbd089eaa46868e515c8f581efeb5/50x62.jpg" data-src-100x125="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1628372/79ecbd089eaa46868e515c8f581efeb5/100x125.jpg" data-src-200x250="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1628372/79ecbd089eaa46868e515c8f581efeb5/200x250.jpg" data-src-320x401="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1628372/79ecbd089eaa46868e515c8f581efeb5/320x401.jpg" data-src-460x576="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1628372/79ecbd089eaa46868e515c8f581efeb5/460x576.jpg" data-src-640x802="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1628372/79ecbd089eaa46868e515c8f581efeb5/640x802.jpg" data-src-1024x1283="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1628372/79ecbd089eaa46868e515c8f581efeb5/1024x1283.jpg" data-src-2048x2567="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1628372/79ecbd089eaa46868e515c8f581efeb5/2048x2567.jpg" data-src-3569x4475="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1628372/79ecbd089eaa46868e515c8f581efeb5/3569x4475.jpg" webURL="ronald-rasband-apostle-portrait_1628372.jpg" pid="9yTxLvdX7UOl3mjVEWI7DA" hash="AAAAAA"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;p class="kicker" pid="tP8BDUa_YUqso3iqu655Ow" hash="A8PG4Q"&gt;Are you standing with the leaders of the Church in a darkening world so that you might spread the Light of Christ?&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="authorName" pid="VCO0jy_62UCMKfhtEvLGNw" hash="-SpCUQ"&gt;By Elder Ronald A. Rasband&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class="bodyBlock"&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p5" pid="IKOJlXTEck2QM0OWEGk_9w" hash="Vq53Wg"&gt;We extend a warm welcome to the newly called General Authorities, Area Seventies, and the wonderful new Primary general presidency. And with deepest appreciation, we thank those who have been released. We love you, each one.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p6" pid="bHBuScauKUe-eWRyXfNmTQ" hash="37Jxvg"&gt;My dear brothers and sisters, we have just participated in a most blessed experience as we have raised our hands to sustain prophets, seers, and revelators and other leaders and general officers called of God in these very days. I have never taken lightly or casually the opportunity of sustaining and being guided by the Lord’s servants. And being just months into my own new calling as a member of the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles, I am humbled by your sustaining vote and confidence. I treasure your willingness to stand with me and with all of these great leaders.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p7" pid="2IOA_E8vDUKx4oXyA1w_eA" hash="n5NeNQ"&gt;Soon after I was sustained last October, I traveled to Pakistan on an assignment and, while there, met the magnificent and dedicated Saints in that country. They are few in number but large in spirit. Shortly after returning home, I received the following note from Brother Shakeel Arshad, a dear member I had met on my visit: “Thank you, Elder Rasband, for coming to Pakistan. I want to tell you that we … Church members … sustain you and love you. [We are] so lucky that you were here and we heard from you. It was just a golden day in my family’s life that we met an Apostle.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p8" pid="Cx6SyOFowEulMzoobh41XQ" hash="2x6p0A"&gt;Meeting Saints like Brother Arshad was an overwhelming and humbling experience and, using his words, “a golden day” for me as well.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p9" pid="wFTklawOK0SWzJVVWwW-PA" hash="--BO9w"&gt;In January, Church leaders participated in a Face to Face broadcast with youth and their leaders and parents from around the world. The broadcast was streamed live over the Internet to many locations in 146 countries; some locations had large audiences in chapels, and others were a single home with one youth tuning in. In total, many hundreds of thousands joined in.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=fGv4XGddSEWMb4rSdt6cEQ"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709228/7ffb2cc21561436fb69c1ff7db4403f1/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709228/7ffb2cc21561436fb69c1ff7db4403f1/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709228/7ffb2cc21561436fb69c1ff7db4403f1/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709228/7ffb2cc21561436fb69c1ff7db4403f1/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709228/7ffb2cc21561436fb69c1ff7db4403f1/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709228/7ffb2cc21561436fb69c1ff7db4403f1/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709228/7ffb2cc21561436fb69c1ff7db4403f1/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709228/7ffb2cc21561436fb69c1ff7db4403f1/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709228/7ffb2cc21561436fb69c1ff7db4403f1/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709228/7ffb2cc21561436fb69c1ff7db4403f1/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Face to Face with Elder Rasband, Sister Oscarson, and Brother Owen" pid="fGv4XGddSEWMb4rSdt6cEQ" hash="ep8OpA"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p10" pid="b6v6RK5AVUK4rVP-1a5Wdg" hash="NRqt2Q"&gt;In connecting with our vast audience, Sister Bonnie Oscarson, Young Women general president; Brother Stephen W. Owen, Young Men general president; and I—supported by our youth hosts, musicians, and others—answered questions from our youth.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=ZNI3CjhmUUmoV-e49cVQtg"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709229/02c4252718aa4a32b0ae984f95dbe171/100x140.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x70="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709229/02c4252718aa4a32b0ae984f95dbe171/50x70.jpg" data-src-100x140="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709229/02c4252718aa4a32b0ae984f95dbe171/100x140.jpg" data-src-200x281="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709229/02c4252718aa4a32b0ae984f95dbe171/200x281.jpg" data-src-320x450="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709229/02c4252718aa4a32b0ae984f95dbe171/320x450.jpg" data-src-460x647="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709229/02c4252718aa4a32b0ae984f95dbe171/460x647.jpg" data-src-640x900="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709229/02c4252718aa4a32b0ae984f95dbe171/640x900.jpg" data-src-1024x1441="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709229/02c4252718aa4a32b0ae984f95dbe171/1024x1441.jpg" data-src-1279x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709229/02c4252718aa4a32b0ae984f95dbe171/1279x1800.jpg" altText="2016 Mutual theme" pid="ZNI3CjhmUUmoV-e49cVQtg" hash="kyQhrw"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p11" pid="aoRLm6ZwD0CS91u1XonOMg" hash="DzhsvQ"&gt;Our purpose was to introduce the Mutual theme for 2016, “Press Forward with a Steadfastness in Christ,” from 2 Nephi, which reads: “Wherefore, ye must press forward with a steadfastness in Christ, having a perfect brightness of hope, and a love of God and of all men. Wherefore, if ye shall press forward, feasting upon the word of Christ, and endure to the end, behold, thus saith the Father: Ye shall have eternal life.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p12" pid="QB9QdXCUlE2tiTkUKO2P1g" hash="qVJH0w"&gt;By reading many hundreds of our youth’s questions, what did we learn? We learned that our youth love the Lord, sustain their leaders, and desire to have their questions answered! Questions are an indication of a further desire to learn, to add to those truths already in place in our testimonies, and to be better prepared to “press forward with a steadfastness in Christ.”&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p13" pid="656_PfNZd0-WNczgYtqL4w" hash="XJfrVA"&gt;The Restoration of the gospel began with a youth, Joseph Smith, asking a question. Many of the Savior’s teachings in His ministry began with a question. Remember His question to Peter: “Whom say ye that I am?”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt; And Peter’s response: “Thou art the Christ, the Son of the living God.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4"&gt;4&lt;/span&gt; We need to help each other find Heavenly Father’s answers through the guidance of the Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p14" pid="KhQ1nQWeJUux79wl1Ky3Bw" hash="2rIzkw"&gt;At that broadcast, I said to the youth:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p15" pid="3s9Yub6d-0yPklvXXA-8rw" hash="YqgxWA"&gt;“The leaders of this Church are no strangers to your issues, to your concerns, and to your challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p16" pid="S1Xb_URmIUWNDT2Y-XPP_A" hash="8Qo2NQ"&gt;“We have children. We have grandchildren. We are often meeting with youth all over the world. And we’re praying for you, we’re talking about you in the most sacred places, and we love you.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p17" pid="EnKC1wCBu0-K5zbRk34cWg" hash="30tyaQ"&gt;I would like to share one of the many, many responses we received from that event.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p18" pid="J0B7IGHd5EyPX7H-0MXOHA" hash="pTJ_Uw"&gt;Lisa, from Grande Prairie, Alberta, Canada, wrote: “This Face to Face event was wonderful. What a strength to my testimony and convictions of the gospel. We are so blessed to have inspired leaders who have been called to serve in so many different capacities.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6"&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p19" pid="z3d-BqADGkC2gxs5xl3HrQ" hash="MWrzjA"&gt;Liz, from Pleasant Grove, Utah, wrote on an earlier post: “I am grateful for my personal faith and the opportunity to sustain a prophet of God and the men and women who serve with him.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7"&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p20" pid="re-J-oeUkEiwVlNSIsxm8g" hash="y__5aQ"&gt;We have sustained leaders today who, by divine inspiration, have been called to teach and guide us and who are calling out to us to beware of the dangers we face each day—from casual Sabbath-day observance, to threats to the family, to assaults on religious freedom, and even to disputing latter-day revelation. Brothers and sisters, are we listening to their counsel?&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p21" pid="Sl4gWsfQbUWirv8PdI9Vpw" hash="nXtgDg"&gt;Many times in conferences, sacrament meetings, and Primary we have sung the tender words, “Lead me, guide me, walk beside me.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8"&gt;8&lt;/span&gt; What do those words mean to you? Who comes to mind when you think of them? Have you felt the influence of righteous leaders, those disciples of Jesus Christ who have in the past and continue today to touch your life, who walk the Lord’s path with you? They may be close at home. They may be in your local congregations or speaking from the pulpit at general conference. These disciples share with us the blessing of having a testimony of the Lord Jesus Christ, the leader of this Church, the leader of our very souls, who has promised, “Be of good cheer, and do not fear, for I the Lord am with you, and will stand by you.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9"&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p22" pid="3OTur-exwUGvlkSdJU3PHQ" hash="8pk7DQ"&gt;I remember President Thomas S. Monson sharing the story of being invited to his stake president Paul C. Child’s home to prepare for advancement to the Melchizedek Priesthood. What a special blessing for President Child, who did not know at the time that he was teaching a young Aaronic Priesthood boy who would one day become the prophet of God.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p23" pid="-ozR5yFxBUmzfbq-wrE_bA" hash="PIIXpA"&gt;I have had my own learning moments from our dear prophet, President Monson. There is no question in my mind or in my heart that he is the Lord’s prophet on the earth; I have been a humbled recipient as he has received revelation and acted upon it. He has been teaching us to reach out, to protect each other, to rescue one another. So it was taught at the Waters of Mormon. Those “desirous … to be called his people” were willing “to bear one another’s burdens,” “to mourn with those that mourn,” and “to stand as witnesses of God.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11"&gt;11&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p24" pid="T2-kEKmxekSh2r8XxQwe5Q" hash="Fm18kQ"&gt;I stand today as a witness of God the Eternal Father and His Son, Jesus Christ. I know our Savior lives and loves us and directs His servants, you and me, to fulfill His mighty purposes on this earth.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12"&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p25" pid="uq2fJsc6hUmjmqMWTugYSQ" hash="C1aqTQ"&gt;As we press forward, choosing to follow the counsel and the warnings of our leaders, we choose to follow the Lord while the world is going in another direction. We choose to hold fast to the iron rod, to be Latter-day Saints, to be on the Lord’s errand, and to be filled “with exceedingly great joy.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13"&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p26" pid="dcpuaE6XmE6wi7NQXqPgIw" hash="TPnsdg"&gt;The growing question of today is clear: are you standing with the leaders of the Church in a darkening world so that you might spread the Light of Christ?&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p27" pid="v__l3hn9mkCgxSmOQpU-5Q" hash="kgvasg"&gt;Relationships with leaders are so important and significant. No matter what age leaders may be, how close or far away, or when they may have touched our lives, their influence reflects the words of the American poet Edwin Markham, who said this:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;div class="poetry"&gt;
			&lt;div class="stanza"&gt;
				&lt;p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p28" pid="P6RokfA-fUGBA7nzge1Syg" hash="0gPc_w"&gt;There is a destiny that makes us brothers:&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p29" pid="7pkY7kaLU0OXJ_5tQ6LYxQ" hash="W2H5mw"&gt;[No one] goes his way alone:&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p30" pid="fbqMhoWIZ0WNKP0f7QYmcA" hash="ZfGwoQ"&gt;All that we send into the lives of others&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p31" pid="FmtFe7y7k0KsNwa4-m7fxw" hash="9SLR0g"&gt;Comes back into our own.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14"&gt;14&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p32" pid="C59EOunWzkutVNbmxsTAwA" hash="dx3b1w"&gt;Shakeel Arshad, my friend in Pakistan, sent his support to me, his brother and friend. So have many of you. When we reach out to lift one another, we prove those powerful words: “[No one] goes his way alone.”&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p33" pid="o_--Yaf2M0uboDV6xzcKRw" hash="CbSsJA"&gt;Most of all, we need our Savior, our Lord, Jesus Christ. One of the accounts from scripture that has always spiritually moved me is when Jesus Christ walked out on the water to meet His disciples who were traveling in a ship on the Sea of Galilee. These were leaders newly called, like many of us on the stand today. The account is recorded in Matthew:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p34" pid="cg_mF3SlGUyBbwyYSm21Bg" hash="nuXAMg"&gt;“But the ship was now in the midst of the sea, tossed with [the] waves: for the wind was contrary.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p35" pid="yeI5oyASqECuVLN4jR2XgA" hash="wj1xYA"&gt;“And in the fourth watch of the night Jesus went unto them, walking on the sea.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p36" pid="PDNmM8FZ2kKDTRZR72FDdw" hash="PXsDjQ"&gt;“And when the disciples saw him walking on the sea, they were troubled, … and they cried out for fear.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p37" pid="-FgGjMZwPk2MPdjp2chMYg" hash="Zd8kSw"&gt;“But straightway Jesus spake unto them, saying, Be of good cheer; it is I; be not afraid.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15"&gt;15&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p38" pid="7R8uirzcz0qkBJ0jeufBvA" hash="NWmw2g"&gt;Peter heard that wonderful call of encouragement from the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p39" pid="dgUg3nfE0EC-sdYV0tz4AA" hash="4B_y_w"&gt;“And Peter answered him and said, Lord, if it be thou, bid me come unto thee on the water.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p40" pid="hiHXtuSr1UqFAQ0n7-8xYQ" hash="mkmCSQ"&gt;“And [Jesus] said, Come.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16"&gt;16&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p41" pid="M5GhVQiSI0W4-gDwABOSag" hash="ak0avQ"&gt;Pretty bold. Peter was a fisherman, and he knew about the hazards of the sea. However, he was committed to following Jesus—night or day, on a ship or on dry land.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p42" pid="WxD4fQ939E2QYpbH8uRpbg" hash="oF7tRw"&gt;I can imagine that Peter leaped over the side of the boat, not waiting for a second invitation, and began to walk on the water. Indeed, the scripture says, “He walked on the water, to go to Jesus.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17"&gt;17&lt;/span&gt; As the wind increased in strength and force and as the waves swirled about his feet, Peter became “afraid; and beginning to sink, he cried [out], saying, Lord, save me.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p43" pid="yx-qT0_TFEqOLjEYsTf09w" hash="SZG3uw"&gt;“And immediately Jesus stretched forth his hand, and caught him.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18"&gt;18&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p44" pid="Sc_2Q_cjrUiQm7ifJg2Hug" hash="2FXqJg"&gt;Such a powerful lesson. The Lord was there for him, just as He is there for you and for me. He reached out His hand and drew Peter to Him and to safety.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p45" pid="3smmOsRfNUSDA_L7dcj7GA" hash="STAQ6A"&gt;I have needed the Savior and the rescue of His hand so many times. I need Him now as never before, as does each of you. I have felt confident at times leaping over the side of the boat, figuratively speaking, into unfamiliar places, only to realize that I could not do it alone.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p46" pid="_foV8R-XYUO8hd6eoSeBYQ" hash="EqNVgA"&gt;As we discussed during Face to Face, the Lord often reaches out to us through our families and leaders, inviting us to come unto Him—just like He reached out to save Peter.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p47" pid="mtRZzxlBt0aHl0E8uhlsGA" hash="iK4u0Q"&gt;You too will have your many moments to respond to frequent invitations to “come unto Christ.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19"&gt;19&lt;/span&gt; Isn’t that what this mortal life is all about? The call may be to come rescue a family member; come serve a mission; come back to church; come to the holy temple; and, as we have recently heard from our wonderful youth in the Face to Face event, come, please help me answer my question. In due time, each one of us will hear the call “Come home.”&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p48" pid="qIOjTICBB0aZsuCItTdiQg" hash="588H_g"&gt;I pray that we will reach out—reach out and take the Savior’s hand that He is extending to us, often through His divinely called leaders and our family members—and listen for His call to come.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church.p49" pid="oxe1ehIi8UGpPmYAJyc4Pw" hash="Um4uPg"&gt;I know that Jesus Christ lives; I love Him, and I know with all my heart that He loves each of us. He is our great Exemplar and the divine leader of all of our Father’s children. Of this I bear my solemn witness in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2016/04/standing-with-the-leaders-of-the-church</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2016-general-conference/2016-04-2040-ronald-a-rasband-64k-eng.mp3" length="6703100" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lest Thou Forget</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder Rasband speaks to those who seek to fortify their faith, reminding them of God’s love and encouraging them to remember and record spiritual experiences.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD60001311_000_64rasband" doc-version="1" hash="7DGrpw">
		
		<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.head1">
			<h1 class="title" pid="Jq-RvIABB0mbG9gxB8mdyg" hash="mgCSHw">Lest Thou Forget</h1>
			<div class="byline">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p2" pid="_YNgyqYm7USIj-RQEcSqAA" hash="-SpCUQ1">By Elder Ronald A. Rasband</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p3" pid="qZrpBfYdS0-KeOQXgaheZg" hash="F9R90A">Of the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles</p>
			</div>
			<p class="kicker" pid="fKXmNcR08E2WKcGqiih2Lg" hash="UyRuIw">I encourage you to recall, especially in times of crisis, when you felt the Spirit and your testimony was strong; remember the spiritual foundations you have built.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="15NaEU1uXUqgu-EJcr-psg" hash="-SpCUQ">By Elder Ronald A. Rasband</p></div>
		<div class="bodyBlock">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p5" pid="Rl1DzcY-Bkq4iScsS7OWvA" hash="fF8dnw">Good afternoon, dear brothers and sisters. How blessed we have been during this conference. My first year as a member of the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles has been most humbling. It has been a year of stretching, growth, and earnest, ever-present petitions to my Father in Heaven. I have felt the sustaining prayers of family, friends, and Church members all around the globe. Thank you for your thoughts and prayers.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p6" pid="Na2J5GtGIkOOtPHThjn1QQ" hash="tiIT4A">I have also had the privilege of meeting with cherished friends, some from years past and many I have met recently. It was after a meeting with a dear friend that I have known and loved for many years that I felt impressed to prepare my remarks today.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p7" pid="fcb0Mw203kWSP9gPW4GNAw" hash="RG35IQ">When we met, my friend confided that he had been struggling. He felt he was experiencing, to use his words, a “crisis of faith” and sought my counsel. I felt grateful that he would share his feelings and concerns with me.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p8" pid="MlhkK-oz40eL0cCExytWyg" hash="tclnUg">He expressed a great longing for what he had once felt spiritually and what he now thought he was losing. As he spoke, I listened carefully and prayed earnestly to know what the Lord would have me say.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p9" pid="n8P-MaFZ5UC-NYybfoTpgw" hash="oa1UEQ">My friend, like perhaps some of you, asked the question so poignantly phrased in the Primary song: “Heavenly Father, are you really there?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> For those of you who may be asking this same question, I would like to share with you the counsel I would offer to my friend and hope that each of you may find your faith strengthened and your resolve renewed to be a committed disciple of Jesus Christ.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p10" pid="wpiO-nYgB0-rfFk1Jv1zCA" hash="j9UsrA">I begin by reminding you that you are a son or daughter of a loving Father in Heaven and that His love remains constant. I know that such reassuring feelings of love are difficult to recall when you are in the midst of personal struggles or trials, disappointments, or broken dreams.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p11" pid="aq91aEB1zUa52N7Qrk1BCA" hash="DuS5Fw">Jesus Christ knows about fierce struggles and trials. He gave His life for us. His final hours were brutal, beyond anything we can even comprehend, but His sacrifice for each one of us was the ultimate expression of His pure love.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p12" pid="d2WH5LI8F0SMnwFRA-Xw9A" hash="DxJAQQ">No mistake, sin, or choice will change God’s love for us. That does not mean sinful conduct is condoned, nor does it remove our obligation to repent when sins are committed. But <span class="emphasis">do not forget,</span> Heavenly Father knows and loves each of you, and He is always ready to help.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p13" pid="NNO7r2Oy7UG9o7nkUb9i6w" hash="qwR0HA">As I pondered my friend’s situation, my mind reflected on the great wisdom found in the Book of Mormon: “And now, my sons, remember, remember that it is upon the rock of our Redeemer, who is Christ, the Son of God, that ye must build your foundation; that when the devil shall send forth his mighty winds, yea, his shafts in the whirlwind, yea, when all his hail and his mighty storm shall beat upon you, it shall have no power over you to drag you down to the gulf of misery and endless wo, because of the rock upon which ye are built, which is a sure foundation, a foundation whereon if men build they cannot fall.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p14" pid="qfXdqXXIuU-onLxxY9-OIw" hash="Hc1CUw">I testify that “the gulf of misery and endless wo” is a place no one wants to be. And my friend was feeling that he was on the edge.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p15" pid="Uaf7mcJI0U-LDv6fuKE6rQ" hash="1SqEpA">When I have counseled individuals such as my friend, I have explored their decisions made over the years which led them to forget sacred experiences, to weaken, and to doubt. I encouraged them, as I encourage you now, to recall, especially in times of crisis, when you felt the Spirit and your testimony was strong; remember the spiritual foundations you have built. I promise that if you will do this, avoiding things that do not build and strengthen your testimony or that mock your beliefs, those precious times when your testimony prospered will return again to your memory through humble prayer and fasting. I assure you that you will once again feel the safety and warmth of the gospel of Jesus Christ.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p16" pid="53X-YFeupkqbXrnvgi9XGg" hash="dETATQ">Each of us must first strengthen ourselves spiritually and then strengthen those around us. Ponder the scriptures regularly, and remember the thoughts and feelings you experience as you read them. Seek other sources of truth as well, but heed this caution from the scriptures: “But to be learned is good <span class="emphasis">if</span> they hearken unto the counsels of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Attend Church meetings, especially sacrament meeting, and partake of the sacrament and renew covenants, including the promise to always remember the Savior, that His Spirit may ever be with you.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p17" pid="77UKxFbDyk-kTASrotkxIw" hash="ypqgaA">No matter what mistakes we have made or how imperfect we feel we are, we can always bless and lift others. Reaching out to them in Christlike service can help us feel the love of God deep within our hearts.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p18" pid="gUCJZ5DhHUilPqz6UiBX_w" hash="khfJgg">It is important to remember the powerful counsel found in Deuteronomy: “Keep thy soul diligently, <span class="emphasis">lest thou forget </span>the things which thine eyes have seen, and lest they depart from thy heart all the days of thy life: but teach them thy sons, and thy sons’ sons.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p19" pid="DVDYKL4YwkuoP6Jrvy6U9w" hash="F9RAvQ">Generations are affected by the choices we make. Share your testimony with your family; encourage them to remember how they felt when they recognized the Spirit in their lives and to record those feelings in journals and personal histories so that their own words may, when needed, bring to their remembrance how good the Lord has been to them.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p20" pid="WxYbe_OsbkqZ2GqC0C15EQ" hash="rhoK7g">You will recall that Nephi and his brothers returned to Jerusalem to obtain the brass plates that contained the recorded history of their people, in part so that they would not forget their past.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p21" pid="hwpg0mf5ikW9slAqOHo6FA" hash="NJEIhQ">Also, in the Book of Mormon, Helaman named his sons after their “first fathers” so they would not forget the goodness of the Lord:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p22" pid="4Tp3puktDE2MNpBuCyL7Xg" hash="TlK3CA">“Behold, my sons, I desire that ye should remember to keep the commandments of God. … Behold, I have given unto you the names of our first parents who came out of the land of Jerusalem; and this I have done that when you remember your names ye may remember them; and when ye remember them ye may remember their works; and when ye remember their works ye may know how that it is said, and also written, that they were good.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p23" pid="qK5fX_lX2kmswwNRtFVW3g" hash="CFTZtQ">“Therefore, my sons, I would that ye should do that which is good, that it may be said of you, and also written, even as it has been said and written of them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p24" pid="ZLY3ukZyGUqGU8BHlfXizg" hash="tfsHMQ">Many today have the same tradition of naming their children after scriptural heroes or faithful ancestors as a way of encouraging them not to forget their heritage.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p25" pid="G__Hy5INn0SnqDBZVvtXlA" hash="iiYF3Q">When I was born, I was given the name of Ronald A. Rasband. My last name honors my father’s ancestral line. The middle initial <span class="emphasis">A</span> was given to me to remind me to honor my mother’s Danish Anderson ancestry.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p26" pid="p7Nv27pMGkiaGVvusfo9xA" hash="DEm5PQ">My great-great-grandfather Jens Anderson was from Denmark. And in 1861 the Lord led two Mormon missionaries to the Jens and Ane Cathrine Anderson home, where the missionaries introduced them and their 16-year-old son, Andrew, to the restored gospel. Thus began a legacy of faith of which my family and I are the beneficiaries. The Andersons read the Book of Mormon and were baptized a short time later. The following year, the Anderson family heeded the call of a prophet to cross the Atlantic to join the Saints in North America.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p27" pid="g-1iU0A-WU2X0sdNmwszNQ" hash="kC_92w">Sadly, Jens died on the ocean voyage, but his wife and son continued to the Salt Lake Valley, arriving on September 3, 1862. Despite their hardships and their heartaches, their faith never wavered, and neither has the faith of many of their descendants.</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=J8002iEf1UyUH72A9pD9Nw"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1814986/f40519ce5db34e4982658c49fe6c9ce5/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1814986/f40519ce5db34e4982658c49fe6c9ce5/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1814986/f40519ce5db34e4982658c49fe6c9ce5/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1814986/f40519ce5db34e4982658c49fe6c9ce5/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1814986/f40519ce5db34e4982658c49fe6c9ce5/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1814986/f40519ce5db34e4982658c49fe6c9ce5/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1814986/f40519ce5db34e4982658c49fe6c9ce5/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1814986/f40519ce5db34e4982658c49fe6c9ce5/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1814986/f40519ce5db34e4982658c49fe6c9ce5/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1814986/f40519ce5db34e4982658c49fe6c9ce5/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Painting in Elder Rasband’s office" pid="J8002iEf1UyUH72A9pD9Nw" hash="Ss2s0A"></img></a>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p28" pid="cByHuP8D70qp6Ev2tvf5Dg" hash="bI90YA">In my office hangs a painting<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> that captures so beautifully a symbolic reminder of that first meeting between my ancestors and those dedicated early missionaries. I am determined not to forget my heritage, and because of my name I will forever remember their legacy of faithfulness and sacrifice.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p29" pid="vZDVKliwf0GD1-EA2qoLcQ" hash="y-nhFQ">Never forget, question, or ignore personal, sacred spiritual experiences. The adversary’s design is to distract us from spiritual witnesses, while the Lord’s desire is to enlighten and engage us in His work.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p30" pid="oRfiX7YYHUai5ynU5W9log" hash="vMkZBg">Let me share a personal example of this truth. I distinctly recall a time when I received a prompting in answer to mighty prayer. The answer was clear and powerful. However, I failed to act immediately on the prompting, and after a period of time I began to wonder if what I had felt had been real. Some of you may have fallen for that deception of the adversary as well.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p31" pid="Zelz0wfIdUKUaNen1-V-sw" hash="M0g_Ng">Several days later, I awoke with these powerful verses of scripture in my mind:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p32" pid="0VQnlgfCOUqWc0_vtlCzgQ" hash="4qVL9g">“Verily, verily, I say unto you, if you desire a further witness, cast your mind upon the night that you cried unto me in your heart. …</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p33" pid="Ozajz-sVFUKOnEuaH7GU7w" hash="t4RqIw">“Did I not speak peace to your mind concerning the matter? What greater witness can you have than from God?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p34" pid="49_zA0RUIkC1qQnPvqTAcA" hash="48YmYg">It was as if the Lord was saying, “Now, Ronald, I already told you what you needed to do. Now do it!” How grateful I was for that loving correction and direction! I was immediately comforted by the prompting and was able to move forward, knowing in my heart that my prayer had been answered.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p35" pid="Q1-68fv8xE6XrxRSz-1O6w" hash="Phrkvg">I share this experience, dear brothers and sisters, to demonstrate how quickly our minds can forget and how spiritual experiences guide us. I have learned to cherish such moments “lest I forget.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p36" pid="HIndSjrvPEeoCtHnCBoYKg" hash="7AzJVA">To my friend, and to all who wish to bolster their faith, I give you this promise: as you faithfully live the gospel of Jesus Christ and abide by its teachings, your testimony will be protected and it will grow. Keep the covenants you have made, regardless of the actions of those around you. Be diligent parents, brothers and sisters, grandparents, aunts, uncles, and friends who strengthen loved ones with personal testimony and who share spiritual experiences. Remain faithful and steadfast, even if storms of doubt invade your lives through the actions of others. Seek that which will edify and fortify you spiritually. Avoid counterfeit offerings of so-called “truths” which are so pervasive, and remember to record your feelings of “love, joy, peace, longsuffering, gentleness, goodness, faith, meekness, [and] temperance.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p37" pid="gWSiqpxZ8EW2cJDNCT1NrA" hash="Mfvagg">In the midst of life’s greatest storms, <span class="emphasis">do not forget</span> your divine heritage as a son or daughter of God or your eternal destiny to one day return to live with Him, which will surpass anything the world has to offer. Remember the tender and sweet words of Alma: “Behold, I say unto you, my brethren, if ye have experienced a change of heart, and if ye have felt to sing the song of redeeming love, I would ask, can ye feel so now?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p38" pid="pzI0bFYLoUSZ6STxOIkCJw" hash="m4niNw">To all who feel the need to have their faith fortified, I plead with you, <span class="emphasis">do not forget!</span> Please do not forget.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p39" pid="4-0lITM0q0uK5BDV7EYbTQ" hash="F-gnpg">I bear witness that Joseph Smith was a prophet of God. I know he saw and talked with God the Father and His Son, Jesus Christ, just as he recorded in his own words. How grateful I am that he <span class="emphasis">did not forget</span> to write of that experience, that we may all know of his testimony.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget.p40" pid="p7k-B7lDPEap8ukZIwpz8Q" hash="jAk1fA">I bear my solemn witness of the Lord Jesus Christ. He lives; I know He lives and stands at the head of this Church. These things I know for myself, independent of any other voice or witness, and I pray that you and I will <span class="emphasis">never forget </span>sacred eternal truths—first and foremost that we are sons and daughters of living and loving Heavenly Parents, who desire only our eternal happiness. Of these truths I testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
		
	</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2016/10/lest-thou-forget</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2016-general-conference/2016-10-5040-ronald-a-rasband-64k-eng.mp3" length="7623993" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let the Holy Spirit Guide</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder Rasband teaches that the Holy Ghost inspires, testifies, teaches, and prompts us.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD60003501_000_54rasband" doc-version="1" hash="OSVByA">
		
		<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.head1">
			<h1 class="title" pid="7qAuMXjz9kWKYn9zcGCbYA" hash="5zJEJA1">Let the Holy Spirit Guide</h1>
			<div class="byline">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p2" pid="DGNo2Et5j0eDzpoROU1nUg" hash="-SpCUQ1">By Elder Ronald A. Rasband</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p3" pid="TPmK6G-De0mC8uzKNks2Tw" hash="F9R90A">Of the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles</p>
			</div>
			<p class="kicker" pid="J6u9cV0dTkecbkeTYFcm1w" hash="6-S3sg">By divine assignment, the Holy Ghost inspires, testifies, teaches, and prompts us to walk in the light of the Lord.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="crvcDjqktUiAOBhiuTCQ7Q" hash="-SpCUQ">By Elder Ronald A. Rasband</p></div>
		<div class="bodyBlock">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p5" pid="pa0bWwOBL0StUe1nN5V4VA" hash="GC1epQ">Brothers and sisters, I, like all of you, recognize we are seeing the hastening of the Lord’s work through President Thomas S. Monson and his message this morning. President Monson, we love you, sustain you, and ever pray for you, “our prophet dear.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p6" pid="mCHiUr9BTkC-JA3Gm9etxA" hash="5_TK7A">We have felt an outpouring of the Spirit this weekend. Whether you are here in this great hall or watching from homes or gathered in meetinghouses in distant parts of the world, you have had the opportunity to feel the Spirit of the Lord. That Spirit confirms to your hearts and minds the truths taught at this conference.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p7" pid="MliEyz1J2kGYsolpTght2A" hash="4q41sQ">Consider the words of this familiar hymn:</p>
			<div class="poetry">
				<div class="stanza">
					<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p8" pid="dRunLkiY4U69s8_UomwZ9g" hash="5zJEJA">Let the Holy Spirit guide;</p>
					<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p9" pid="5-rJXM78U0e-wJ4GB2MbCw" hash="Qu03dg">Let him teach us what is true.</p>
					<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p10" pid="H3ZXiLTB4E-J9uZohl8SYQ" hash="gK7QLw">He will testify of Christ,</p>
					<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p11" pid="Kuk69CVREU--gNeoQ9RB7w" hash="IUhMCA">Light our minds with heaven’s view.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
				</div>
			</div>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p12" pid="XxNGwMuIMUm_5iKHw0YfPA" hash="J4WCzw">From latter-day revelation we know that the Godhead is comprised of three distinct and separate beings: our Father in Heaven; His Only Begotten Son, Jesus Christ; and the Holy Ghost. We know that “the Father has a body of flesh and bones as tangible as man’s; the Son also; but the Holy Ghost has not a body of flesh and bones, but is a personage of Spirit. Were it not so, the Holy Ghost could not dwell in us.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p13" pid="muUyOgavZ0GwZ6ZS-tbSjg" hash="Wv1rqw">My message today focuses on the importance of the Holy Ghost in our lives. Our Father in Heaven knew that in mortality we would face challenges, tribulation, and turmoil; He knew we would wrestle with questions, disappointments, temptations, and weaknesses. To give us mortal strength and divine guidance, He provided the Holy Spirit, another name for the Holy Ghost.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p14" pid="RlWaweInMk-xDpohPzvJfg" hash="u8l2tg">The Holy Ghost binds us to the Lord. By divine assignment, He inspires, testifies, teaches, and prompts us to walk in the light of the Lord. We have the sacred responsibility to learn to recognize His influence in our lives and respond.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p15" pid="rfJCDEVQYUCxPA0inmgMjg" hash="Zbz92w">Remember the Lord’s promise: “I will impart unto you of my Spirit, which shall enlighten your mind, which shall fill your soul with joy.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> I love that assurance. Joy that fills our souls brings with it an eternal perspective in contrast to day-to-day living. That joy comes as peace amidst hardship or heartache. It provides comfort and courage, unfolds the truths of the gospel, and expands our love for the Lord and all God’s children. Although the need for such blessings is so great, in many ways the world has forgotten and forsaken them.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p16" pid="h4Q0zaecBkeGTJxPnRfxJw" hash="sG3kUA">Each week as we partake of the holy sacrament, we make a covenant to “always remember him,” the Lord Jesus Christ, and His atoning sacrifice. When we keep this sacred covenant, the promise is given that we “may always have his Spirit to be with [us].”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p17" pid="Ndbmt8FO4EyqB7ljqRTxwA" hash="aALYHg">How do we do that?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p18" pid="e6Viz8Vg6ke3MkLrRhQYTw" hash="1FraEg"><span class="strong">First,</span> we strive to live worthy of the Spirit.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p19" pid="O3TP275D3U-HYRGQ9nIZ_A" hash="J1T9MA">The Holy Ghost accompanies those who are “strict to remember the Lord their God from day to day.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> As the Lord counseled, we must “lay aside the things of this world, and seek for the things of a better,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> for “the Spirit of the Lord doth not dwell in unholy temples.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> We must always try to obey God’s laws, study the scriptures, pray, attend the temple, and live true to the <a href="/scriptures/pgp/a-of-f/1.13" class="scriptureRef">thirteenth article of faith</a>, “being honest, true, chaste, benevolent, virtuous, and … doing good to all men.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p20" pid="2ya9yX-kvkq6wNB_kK7glw" hash="z5SwLA"><span class="strong">Second,</span> we must be willing to receive the Spirit.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p21" pid="b_1PtA12d0mMWI6eOrtZQg" hash="2lcCWQ">The Lord has promised, “I will tell you in your mind and in your heart, by the Holy Ghost, which shall come upon you and which shall dwell in your heart.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> I began to understand this as a young missionary in Scotch Plains, New Jersey. One hot July morning my companion and I felt prompted to look up a Temple Square referral. We knocked on the door of the Elwood Schaffer home. Mrs. Schaffer politely turned us away.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p22" pid="5trXRbuwFEmjVRNo4ZY_8g" hash="StqVDA">As she began to shut the door, I felt to do something I had never done before and have never done since! I stuck my foot in the door, and I asked, “Is there anyone else who might be interested in our message?” Her 16-year-old daughter, Marti, did have an interest and had fervently prayed for guidance just the day before. Marti met with us, and in time her mother participated in the discussions. Both of them joined the Church.</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=VsJ8wEe0PE6QrJsBpd_tCQ"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1912037/649b47c2c4214a8a8a90e2dbf655fc09/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1912037/649b47c2c4214a8a8a90e2dbf655fc09/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1912037/649b47c2c4214a8a8a90e2dbf655fc09/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1912037/649b47c2c4214a8a8a90e2dbf655fc09/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1912037/649b47c2c4214a8a8a90e2dbf655fc09/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1912037/649b47c2c4214a8a8a90e2dbf655fc09/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1912037/649b47c2c4214a8a8a90e2dbf655fc09/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1912037/649b47c2c4214a8a8a90e2dbf655fc09/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1912037/649b47c2c4214a8a8a90e2dbf655fc09/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1912037/649b47c2c4214a8a8a90e2dbf655fc09/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Elder Rasband as a missionary" pid="VsJ8wEe0PE6QrJsBpd_tCQ" hash="AAAAAA1"></img></a>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p23" pid="5p7IBBKWe02bXeZv9AUwvA" hash="hYDUEw">Resulting from Marti’s baptism, 136 people, including many of her own family, have been baptized and made gospel covenants. How grateful I am that I listened to the Spirit and stuck my foot in the door on that hot July day. Marti and a number of her dear family members are here today.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p24" pid="m5XnvjcBg0KWeDe5Y7bRZg" hash="mgj11A"><span class="strong">Third,</span> we must recognize the Spirit when it comes.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p25" pid="CszPAJ45RECIvJOb0uCupg" hash="TmztqA">My experience has been that the Spirit most often communicates as a feeling. You feel it in words that are familiar to you, that make sense to you, that prompt you. Consider the response of the Nephites as they listened to the Lord pray for them: “And the multitude did hear and do bear record; and their hearts were open and they did understand in their hearts the words which he prayed.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> They felt in their hearts the words of His prayer. The voice of the Holy Spirit is still and small.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p26" pid="dngSAj5p8kegw8ZvavE4HQ" hash="8vZ4JQ">In the Old Testament, Elijah contended with the priests of Baal. The priests expected the “voice” of Baal to come down as thunder and light their sacrifice with fire. But there was no voice, and there was no fire.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p27" pid="qhz4rvmuJkmExGJiBb2b9A" hash="bjuVSg">On a later occasion, Elijah prayed. “And, behold, the Lord passed by, and a great and strong wind rent the mountains, and brake in pieces the rocks before the Lord; but the Lord was not in the wind: and after the wind an earthquake; but the Lord was not in the earthquake:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p28" pid="KIDwEigom0a20mEyPXh3wA" hash="HGz2nw">“And after the earthquake a fire; but the Lord was not in the fire: and after the fire a still small voice.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p29" pid="FjoRtgGZYU2hFKnA-eBxgg" hash="U_lu7A">Do you know that voice?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p30" pid="I8MpfhCk8UK57IVvpuiKMw" hash="El0LiA">President Monson has taught, “As we pursue the journey of life, let us learn the language of the Spirit.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> The Spirit speaks words that we feel. These feelings are gentle, a nudge to act, to do something, to say something, to respond in a certain way. If we are casual or complacent in our worship, drawn off and desensitized by worldly pursuits, we find ourselves diminished in our ability to feel. Nephi said to Laman and Lemuel, “Ye have heard his voice from time to time; and he hath spoken unto you in a still small voice, but ye were past feeling, that ye could not feel [the] words.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p31" pid="_tYjAoggIkeatxtH_CwXiA" hash="Wv2hjw">Last June, I was on an assignment to South America. We were on a tight 10-day schedule visiting Colombia, Peru, and Ecuador. An enormous earthquake had killed hundreds, injured tens of thousands, damaged and destroyed homes and communities in the Ecuadorian cities of Portoviejo and Manta. I felt prompted to add to our schedule a visit to members living in those cities. With damage to the roads, we weren’t sure we could get there. In fact, we had been told we could not get there, but the prompting would not go away. Consequently, we were blessed and were able to visit both cities.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p32" pid="yGZk9IZjM02nx6RoAAMzSQ" hash="Net_cw">With such short notice, I expected that only a few local priesthood leaders would attend the hastily organized gatherings. However, we arrived at each stake center to find the chapels filled all the way back to the stage. Some who attended were the stalwarts of the region, the pioneers who had held fast to the Church, encouraging others to join them in worship and to feel the Spirit in their lives. Sitting on the front rows were the members who had lost loved ones and neighbors in the earthquake. I felt prompted to bestow an apostolic blessing upon all who were in attendance, one of my very first given. Though I was standing at the front of that room, it was as if my hands were on each of their heads, and I felt the words of the Lord pouring forth.</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=6dPvwqV1AUCh4I9_Mk6K2A"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1912039/08eb16a8e861463d9372a620afbcf57c/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1912039/08eb16a8e861463d9372a620afbcf57c/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1912039/08eb16a8e861463d9372a620afbcf57c/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1912039/08eb16a8e861463d9372a620afbcf57c/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1912039/08eb16a8e861463d9372a620afbcf57c/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1912039/08eb16a8e861463d9372a620afbcf57c/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1912039/08eb16a8e861463d9372a620afbcf57c/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1912039/08eb16a8e861463d9372a620afbcf57c/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1912039/08eb16a8e861463d9372a620afbcf57c/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1912039/08eb16a8e861463d9372a620afbcf57c/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Elder and Sister Rasband in South America" pid="6dPvwqV1AUCh4I9_Mk6K2A" hash="AAAAAA"></img></a>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p33" pid="gaFlaB3crECRnO3kNjH97A" hash="kAiJSg">It didn’t end there. I felt prompted to speak to them just as Jesus Christ had done when visiting the people in the Americas. “He took their little children … and blessed them, and prayed unto the Father for them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> We were in Ecuador, we were about our Father’s business, and these were His children.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p34" pid="YZNKCDAszkyBhXfqeHZl7Q" hash="73p2VA"><span class="strong">Fourth</span>, we must act on the <span class="emphasis">first</span> prompting.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p35" pid="WVm78En7tUGjnQ0JcuR23w" hash="BjAmZA">Remember the words of Nephi. “I was led by the Spirit, not knowing beforehand the things which I should do. Nevertheless,” he said, “I went forth.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p36" pid="SUJbGW9O6k-yf0qUnD2v5Q" hash="wEWUkw">And so must we. We must be confident in our first promptings. Sometimes we rationalize; we wonder if we are feeling a spiritual impression or if it is just our own thoughts. When we begin to second-guess, even third-guess, our feelings—and we all have—we are dismissing the Spirit; we are questioning divine counsel. The Prophet Joseph Smith taught that if you will listen to the first promptings, you will get it right nine times out of ten.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p37" pid="21fk7gwfU029bk2v31bpmg" hash="WyI2cA">Now a caution: don’t expect fireworks because you responded to the Holy Ghost. Remember, you are about the work of the still, small voice.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p38" pid="h0tHp5L-30yW3LO_06X6jA" hash="HaUXGA">While serving as a mission president in New York City, I was with some of our missionaries in a restaurant in the Bronx. A young family came in and sat near us. They appeared golden for the gospel. I watched our missionaries as they continued to visit with me, then noticed as the family concluded their meal and slipped out the door. Then I said, “Elders, there’s a lesson here today. You saw a lovely family come into this restaurant. What should we have done?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p39" pid="iwkVzZSmdEeDy8Ana6KedA" hash="iLEdKQ">One of the elders spoke up quickly: “I thought about getting up and going over to talk to them. I felt the nudge, but I didn’t respond.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p40" pid="B79KF0WItUakNoud0grNGA" hash="Hh9VNQ">“Elders,” I said, “we must always act on our first prompting. That nudge you felt was the Holy Ghost!”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p41" pid="DwR71oCbNkqLiV-WOw4Pkw" hash="xqCoiQ">First promptings are pure inspiration from heaven. When they confirm or testify to us, we need to recognize them for what they are and never let them slip past. So often, it is the Spirit inspiring us to reach out to someone in need, family and friends in particular. “Thus … the still small voice, which whispereth through and pierceth all things,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> points us to opportunities to teach the gospel, to bear testimony of the Restoration and Jesus Christ, to offer support and concern, and to rescue one of God’s precious children.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p42" pid="F--sUeR36kWN4YKupfz_LA" hash="23ywMQ">Think of it as being what is called a first responder. In most communities the first responders to a tragedy, disaster, or calamity are firefighters, police officers, paramedics. They arrive with lights flashing, and may I add, we are so incredibly grateful for them. The Lord’s way is less obvious but requires just as immediate a response. The Lord knows the needs of all His children—and He knows who is prepared to help. If we let the Lord know in our morning prayers that we are ready, He will call on us to respond. If we respond, He will call on us time and time again and we will find ourselves on what President Monson calls “the Lord’s errand.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> We will become spiritual first responders bringing help from on high.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p43" pid="6drJKtXsh0Cp2N5fo4sAdw" hash="Rns0dg">If we pay attention to the promptings that come to us, we will grow in the spirit of revelation and receive more and more Spirit-driven insight and direction. The Lord has said, “Put your trust in that Spirit which leadeth to do good.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide.p44" pid="0zpL5o1HJU-WVIQqZmL6Cg" hash="4vb2Eg">May we take seriously the Lord’s call to “be of good cheer, for I will lead you along.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> He leads us by the Holy Ghost. May we live close to the Spirit, acting quickly upon our first promptings, knowing they come from God. I bear witness of the power of the Holy Ghost to guide us, guard us, and ever be with us, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
		
	</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2017/04/let-the-holy-spirit-guide</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2017-general-conference/2017-04-4040-ronald-a-rasband-64k-eng.mp3" length="7495332" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
