<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Rosemary M. Wixom</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Rosemary M. Wixom.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Rosemary%20M.%20Wixom.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Rosemary M. Wixom.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2010 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Stay on the Path</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2010/10/stay-on-the-path?lang=eng</link>
      <description>As we hold on to our children and follow the Savior’s lead, we will all return to our heavenly home and be safe in our Heavenly Father’s arms.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/stay-on-the-path" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50021411_000_1030" doc-version="2" hash="cxaGiw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/stay-on-the-path.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="6G27oO1gVE-j9Ptd52adAQ" hash="ang95w">Stay on the Path</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="iPqbodNDukWgjVXS_xfp6Q" hash="8qQ1Bg">Rosemary M. Wixom</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="p4l1dJWgOkqOsbqCTNrutg" hash="A2SI9Q">As we hold on to our children and follow the Savior’s lead, we will all return to our heavenly home and be safe in our Heavenly Father’s arms.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/stay-on-the-path.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/stay-on-the-path.p1" pid="H9hrfWrSYEC0b-U9WuXR0A" hash="ayYDbA">I recently observed the birth of tiny Kate Elizabeth. After she entered this world and was placed into her mother’s arms, Kate reached out and caught hold of her mother’s finger. It was as if little Kate were saying, “If I hold on, will you help me stay on the path back to my Heavenly Father?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/stay-on-the-path.p2" pid="OxrVpXX0IEK2nU-YOMjggA" hash="WA35AA">At age seven, Joseph Smith contracted typhoid fever, and an infection settled in his leg. Dr. Nathan Smith was pioneering a procedure by which the infected leg could be saved. Without anesthesia, Dr. Smith would need to cut Joseph’s leg and actually remove portions of the infected bone. Joseph declined brandy to endure the pain and refused to be tied down but said, “I will have my father sit on the bed and hold me in his arms, and then I will do whatever is necessary.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/stay-on-the-path.p3" pid="q7SDPN8JgECYN-M5pSc6vA" hash="G-gnBA">For children all over the world, we say: “Take my hand. Hold on tight. We will stay on the path together back to our Heavenly Father.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/stay-on-the-path.p4" pid="e0YiHM9dCEeWNxtErNgFig" hash="KO3Xrg">Parents, grandparents, neighbors, friends, Primary leaders—each of us can reach out to hold on to the children. We can stop, kneel down, and look into their eyes and feel of their innate desire to follow the Savior. Take hold of their hands. Walk with them. It is our chance to anchor them on the path of faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/stay-on-the-path.p5" pid="B1-c7MIKx0S3RkfyFbza9A" hash="YifH2Q">No child needs to walk the path alone so long as we speak freely to our children of the plan of salvation. Understanding the plan will help them hold to the truths that they are children of God and He has a plan for them, that they lived with Him in the premortal existence, that they shouted for joy to come to this earth, and that through the Savior’s help, we all can return to our Heavenly Father’s presence. If they understand the plan and who they are, they will not fear.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/stay-on-the-path.p6" pid="DA4F3526NkiPbSo-L8HgQQ" hash="bNB3sQ">In <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/24" class="scriptureRef">Alma 24</a> we read, “He loveth our souls [and] he loveth our children; therefore, … the plan of salvation might be made known unto us as well as unto future generations.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/stay-on-the-path.p7" pid="Y7SNjWYrYE61yYSpvYlV7Q" hash="on_Ktg">We begin to make the plan known to our children when we hold tight to the iron rod ourselves.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/stay-on-the-path.p8" pid="zf6lusmvz0WF5DUpBNBVuw" hash="0ObpAQ">When we are holding tight to the iron rod, we are in a position to place our hands over theirs and walk the strait and narrow path together. Our example is magnified in their eyes. They will follow our cadence when they feel secure in our actions. We do not need to be perfect—just honest and sincere. Children want to feel as one with us. When a parent says, “We can do it! We can read the scriptures daily as a family,” the children will follow!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/stay-on-the-path.p9" pid="Vig6meN70Eu0z-buzltO5A" hash="RoSHag">One such family with four young children writes: “We decided to start small because of our children’s short attention spans. Our oldest child was not yet reading, but she could repeat our words, so we began reading the Book of Mormon, just three verses each night. My husband and I would read one verse each, and then Sydney would repeat a verse. We progressed to four verses and then five verses as the boys began to repeat their own verses. Yes, it was tedious, but we kept going. We tried to focus on consistency instead of speed. It took us three-and-a-half years to finish the Book of Mormon. It was a great feeling of accomplishment!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/stay-on-the-path.p10" pid="aW4fkWYpaU2pZ8csALi9pQ" hash="zaBXnw">The mother continues: “Daily family scripture reading is a habit in our family now. Our children are comfortable with scriptural language, and my husband and I take opportunity to bear testimony of truths. Most important, the Spirit has increased in our home.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/stay-on-the-path.p11" pid="PcqTuX4JBkOrjKCvrX5pFQ" hash="tlF7lg">Do you take from this family’s experience what I do? When our intent is to hold tight to the word of God, our reading of the scriptures can be just one verse at a time. It’s never too late to begin. You can start now.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/stay-on-the-path.p12" pid="XP_hLFlB6EedYrazW4ttyA" hash="RoQ7iQ">The world will teach our children if we do not, and children are capable of learning all the world will teach them at a very young age. What we want them to know five years from now needs to be part of our conversation with them today. Teach them in every circumstance; let every dilemma, every consequence, every trial that they may face provide an opportunity to teach them how to hold on to gospel truths.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/stay-on-the-path.p13" pid="MIeZ2LkdUEG45fP1GNZR0Q" hash="1ftpUQ">Shannon, a young mother, did not expect that she would teach her children the power of prayer when they piled into their van to drive to their home just 40 minutes away. There was no storm when they left their grandmother’s home, but as they began to drive through the canyon, the light snow turned into a blizzard. The van began sliding on the surface of the road. Soon visibility was near zero. The two youngest children could sense the stress of the situation and began to cry. Shannon said to the older children, Heidi and Thomas, ages 8 and 6, “You need to pray. We need Heavenly Father’s help to get home safely. Pray that we will not get stuck and that we will not slide off the road.” Her hands shook as she steered the car, yet she could hear the whisper of little prayers repeatedly coming from the backseat: “Heavenly Father, please help us get home safely; please help us so we will not slide off the road.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/stay-on-the-path.p14" pid="iaJfAAlBakmUdpGnresYvA" hash="_B-7aA">In time the prayers calmed the two little ones, and they stopped their crying just as they learned that a road closure prevented them from driving any farther. Cautiously, they turned around and found a motel for the night. Once in the motel, they knelt down and thanked Heavenly Father for their safety. That night a mother taught her children the power of holding true to prayer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/stay-on-the-path.p15" pid="_YlS8sSOHkuQpXmgMeAhng" hash="PTdsRw">What trials will our children face? Like Joseph Smith, our children can find the courage to “do whatever is necessary.” When we are intentional about holding them and teaching them of Heavenly Father’s plan through prayer and scriptures, they will come to know <span class="emphasis">where</span> they came from, <span class="emphasis">why</span> they are here, and <span class="emphasis">where</span> they are going.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/stay-on-the-path.p16" pid="k7xxSBPfn0-c5g7SXwimog" hash="IvIHXg">Last spring my husband and I attended a soccer game of our four-year-old grandson. You could feel the excitement on the field as the players ran in every direction chasing the soccer ball. When the final whistle blew, the players were unaware of who won or who lost. They had simply played the game. The coaches directed the players to shake hands with the opposing team members. Then I observed something quite remarkable. The coach called for a victory tunnel. All the parents, grandparents, and any spectators who had come to observe the game stood up and formed two lines facing each other, and by raising their arms they formed an arch. The children squealed as they ran through the cheering adults and down the path formed by the spectators. Soon the children from the opposing team joined the fun as all the players—the winners and the losers—were cheered on by the adults as they ran the path of the victory tunnel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/stay-on-the-path.p17" pid="n7G9-ebFdU-35gKlQ--qZw" hash="Ci_YSw">In my mind’s eye, I had another picture. I had the feeling I was seeing children living the plan, the plan Heavenly Father has created for each individual child. They were running the strait and narrow path through the arms of the spectators who love them, each one feeling the joy of being on the path.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2010/10/stay-on-the-path.p18" pid="eELS8KswLUKJfFHzKW4U5A" hash="1HX-PA">Jacob said, “O how great the plan of our God!”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> The Savior has “marked the path and led the way.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> I testify that as we hold on to our children and follow the Savior’s lead, we will all return to our heavenly home and be safe in our Heavenly Father’s arms. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2010/10/stay-on-the-path</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2010-general-conference/2010-10-1030-rosemary-m-wixom-64k-eng.mp3" length="4744767" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2010 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Words We Speak</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak?lang=eng</link>
      <description>How we speak to our children and the words we use can encourage and uplift them and strengthen their faith.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10785_000_43wixom" doc-version="2" hash="5ph0zQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="mxodFrtjQ0Gd40rm4xT6eg" hash="yM4Wtw">The Words We Speak</h1><p class="authorName" pid="s4NTGMn6mEC1wEn7KLbeOQ" hash="aSgalg">By Rosemary M. Wixom</p><p class="kicker" pid="-zGiTdni9Eat6TE-W5D7zQ" hash="VRtOVA">How we speak to our children and the words we use can encourage and uplift them and strengthen their faith.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" pid="m6HT4LZZz0aT0w-Mf1Yhfg" hash="ACV4bg">
				<span class="story">
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.p5" pid="m7hTw9C6UE2tmIkPAhW7bA" hash="LqdSaA"><span class="pageBreak" page-number="81"></span>A young father recently learned of the passing of his extraordinary second-grade teacher. In memory of her, he wrote: “Of all the feelings and experiences I remember, the feeling most prevalent in my mind is ‘comfort.’ She may have taught me spelling, grammar, and math, but far more importantly she taught me to love being a child. In her classroom, it was OK to spell a word wrong here and there; ‘We’ll work on it,’ she’d say. It was OK to spill or tear or smudge; ‘We’ll fix it and we’ll clean it up,’ she would respond. It was OK to try, OK to stretch, OK to dream, and OK to enjoy those pleasures that come from the insignificant things that only children find exciting.”</p>
				</span>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.p6" pid="j6HVpmwQOE6s82Z47S8nCg" hash="24_LGw">One of the greatest influences a person can have in this world is to influence a child. Children’s beliefs and self-worth are shaped early in their lives. Everyone within the sound of my voice has the power to increase a child’s confidence in himself or herself and to increase a child’s faith in Heavenly Father and Jesus Christ through the words they speak.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.p7" pid="WBXS8GxH-UisHZdE65RPbA" hash="DpxFmg">In Helaman chapter 5 we read, “And now, my sons, remember, remember that it is upon the rock of our Redeemer, who is Christ, the Son of God, that ye must build your foundation.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.p8" pid="PkoMw3VS_Um8_6jNn8jUeg" hash="8OTCsA">These were the <span class="emphasis">words</span> Helaman taught his sons. And we read on: “And they did remember his <span class="emphasis">words;</span> and … they went forth … to teach the word of God among all the people.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.p9" pid="0qF_t4RWYkOtB7oId5u8nQ" hash="n9kMgw">Even though Helaman’s sons were persecuted and put in prison, those words they had heard never failed them. They were protected and encircled about with a pillar of fire. Then came a voice, saying to their captors:</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.p10" pid="sVtlk1bi8kWkb-OzWRO7MQ" hash="rBhSBQ">“Repent ye, and seek no more to destroy my servants. …</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.p11" pid="uCCoSP5qx0-3DrQ6-G17NQ" hash="5o4gkw">“… It was not a voice of thunder, neither was it a voice of a great tumultuous noise, but behold, it was a still voice of perfect mildness, as if it had been a whisper, and it did pierce even to the very soul.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.p12" pid="6ExSKisD9EqEJtjYzSPJng" hash="G_FbUg">We can learn from that voice from heaven. It was not loud, scolding, or demeaning; it was a still voice of perfect mildness, giving firm direction while giving hope.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.p13" pid="ZrHQyEyDSUq5F4YVhhTSbw" hash="RndHIw">How we speak to our children and the words we use can encourage and uplift them and strengthen their faith to stay on the path back to Heavenly Father. They come to this earth ready to listen.</p>
				<span class="story">
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.p14" pid="GqTfKyXtV0WijD5PyGWxQQ" hash="YiSYEA">An example of a child listening happened in a fabric store. The store was crowded with shoppers when it became obvious to everyone that a mother was panicked because she had lost her young son. At first, she was calling his name. “Connor,” she would say as she briskly walked around the store. As time passed, her voice got louder and more frantic. Soon the store security officers were notified, and everyone in the store was involved in looking for the child. Several minutes passed with no success of finding him. Connor’s mother, understandably, was becoming more <span class="pageBreak" page-number="82"></span>frantic by the minute and was rapidly yelling his name over and over again.</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.p15" pid="eMyi6_Jje0igKU_Nc5mhiw" hash="F6tUkQ">One patron, after saying a silent prayer, had the thought that Connor may be frightened as he listened to his mother scream his name. She mentioned this to another woman involved in the search, and they quickly made a plan. Together they began to walk between the tables of fabric, quietly repeating the words “Connor, if you can hear my voice, say, ‘Here I am.’” As they walked slowly toward the back of the store repeating that phrase, sure enough, they heard a timid, soft voice say, “Here I am.” Connor was hiding between the bolts of fabric under a table. It was a voice of perfect mildness that encouraged Connor to respond.</p>
				</span>
				<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.t1">
					<h2 class="title" pid="Ft3f7ZcT1ku9HWkALVqApQ" hash="iLpV0w">Pray to Know a Child’s Needs</h2>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.p17" pid="OUX0GM1CVEKku1suGF57mg" hash="WKKv_A">To speak to a child’s heart, we must know a child’s needs. If we pray to know those needs, the very words we say may have the power to reach into their hearts. Our efforts are magnified when we seek the direction of the Holy Ghost. The Lord said:</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.p18" pid="oig1VZeDdEC-htvGx7QuYg" hash="RgO7Jg">“Speak the thoughts that I shall put into your hearts, …</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.p19" pid="xaibRuX_I0-1gpFx0oGlTA" hash="b9Zy-g">“For it shall be given you in the very hour, yea, in the very moment, what ye shall say.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
				</div>
				<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.t2" pid="6zxs0nHvfEuomP-qped5_A" hash="04Kaww">
					<h2 class="title" pid="H8QPJhcbMkSRl6CjoBZzPg" hash="SJC3xg">Disconnect and Listen with Love</h2>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.p21" pid="-WrveDAcYEimCS7PvKQwng" hash="LPA1LA">Unfortunately, the distractions of this world prevent many children from hearing encouraging words that could shape their view of themselves.</p>
					<span class="story">
						<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.p22" pid="RzuggSy9ZE-Y3O_-SczBTQ" hash="37Uduw">Dr. Neal Halfon, a physician who directs the UCLA Center for Healthier Children, Families, and Communities, refers to “parental benign neglect.” One example involved an 18-month-old and his parents:</p>
						<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.p23" pid="FtAZT2ZmtUONfK4RjQO_JA" hash="HLwJQg">“‘Their son seemed happy, active and engaged, clearly enjoying time and pizza with his parents. … At the end of dinner, Mom got up to run an errand, handing over care to Dad.’</p>
						<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.p24" pid="GWHMFhQtsU-1UMpBz1aaWA" hash="-RfkHQ">“Dad … started reading phone messages while the toddler struggled to get his attention by throwing bits of pizza crust. Then the dad re-engaged, facing his child and playing with him. Soon, though, he substituted watching a video on his phone with the toddler until his wife returned.</p>
						<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.p25" pid="raCCq2etLEO0tGTH0RmPIg" hash="4_24QQ">“… [Dr.] Halfon observed a dimming of the child’s internal light, a lessening of the connection between parent and child.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
					</span>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.p26" pid="23-ucV05hU2r5VWH3gD1JQ" hash="rqA5qA">The answer to our prayer of how to meet our children’s needs may be to more often technologically disconnect. Precious moments of opportunity to interact and converse with our children dissolve when we are occupied with distractions. Why not choose a time each day to disconnect from technology and reconnect with each other? Simply turn everything off. When you do this, your home may seem quiet at first; you may even feel at a loss as to what to do or say. Then, as you give full attention to your children, a conversation will begin, and you can enjoy listening to each other.</p>
				</div>
				<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.t3" pid="DxEOdogPn0uAP74nNVg7gw" hash="-UcJNQ">
					<h2 class="title" pid="KdIHmr6HGkSyOV-veqBbgQ" hash="IkUq8w">Write to Persuade Our Children</h2>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.p28" pid="Z5U1c3Z2Hk-UmblQK4b69w" hash="-FyNrQ">We can also influence our children through the words we write to them. Nephi writes, “We labor diligently to write, to persuade our children … to believe in Christ, and to be reconciled to God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
					<span class="story">
						<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.p29" pid="jCXg6IlKoUyexDg5OeU65w" hash="9G5Wpw">President Thomas S. Monson shared the experience of Jay Hess, an airman who was shot down over North Vietnam in the 1960s: “For two years his family had no idea whether he was dead or alive. His captors in Hanoi eventually allowed him to write home but limited his message to less than 25 words.” President Monson asks: “What would you and I say to our families if we were in the same situation—not having seen them for over two years and not knowing if we would ever see them again? Wanting to provide something his family could recognize as having come from him and also wanting to give them valuable counsel, Brother <span class="pageBreak" page-number="83"></span>Hess wrote [the following words]: ‘These things are important: temple marriage, mission, college. Press on, set goals, write history, take pictures twice a year.’”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
					</span>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.p30" pid="8zgRX3MvpkCHiDaCmT_NIg" hash="JfLTvg">What words would you write to your children if you had 25 words or less?</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.p31" pid="NchVPl0fTE-_97TMqAxnfg" hash="dprchw">The young father I spoke about earlier, who wrote about his memories of his second-grade teacher, is now raising a beautiful baby daughter. He feels the heavenly trust that has been placed in him. As she grows up, what will be her future? What will he say that will sink deep into her heart? What words will encourage her, lift her, and help her to stay on the path? Will it make a difference if he takes time to whisper, “You are a child of God”? Will she remember someday that her father often said the words, “I love everything about you”?</p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.p32" pid="GQc6DiDi7kit9_jWQ4mxlQ" hash="w_Z89w">Isn’t that what our Heavenly Father was saying to His Son and to all of us when He said, “This is my beloved Son” and then added, “in whom I am well pleased”?<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
					<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak.p33" pid="jxpcs0OjTUeStsBjPAkaaQ" hash="ZHSqFA">May the words we speak and write to our children reflect the love our Heavenly Father has for His Son, Jesus Christ, and for us. And then may we pause to listen, for a child is most capable of speaking great and marvelous things in return. I say this in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
				</div>
			</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2013/04/the-words-we-speak</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2013-general-conference/2013-04-4030-rosemary-m-wixom-64k-eng.mp3" length="4979014" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2013 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Covenants Protects Us, Prepares Us, and Empowers Us</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Rosemary M. Wixom encourages girls and women of all ages to make and keep sacred covenants in order to return to Heavenly Father's presence.
		</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10985_000_61wixom" doc-version="4" hash="sbqFrQ">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="SVlfIvw8WU-B9DCQeMIy8g" hash="lR5g5A">Keeping Covenants Protects Us, Prepares Us, and Empowers Us</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us.p" pid="d1TbQSHglUO0ZBPz8oYd9Q" hash="aSgalg">By Rosemary M. Wixom</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us.p" pid="xfjpqnjYIE-tk42kzx6P3A" hash="amFNAg">Primary General President</p>
		</div>
		<img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/leaders/rosemary-m-wixom.jpg" altText="Rosemary M. Wixom" pid="WeVEtv6wKUaSsOwfl2EP_Q" hash="lg617Q" />
		<p class="kicker" pid="9na6_gW8I0CSGpFwvRHMCA" hash="I6rGjA">We are covenant-making women of all ages walking the path of mortality back to His presence.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="m6tI4eY6pkq01a9rpbo1eA" hash="aSgalg1">By Rosemary M. Wixom</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock" pid="FwnN2cw5D0qle-hVAwBc2A" hash="oUoHUw">
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us.p5" pid="ohUs7Ua8ZkqK7p4S4KqnGw" hash="igQK_w">
				<span class="pageBreak" page-number="116"></span>Oh, sisters, we love you. While visiting Mexico recently, I had a glimpse of the sisterhood we are all feeling tonight. Imagine this scene: We had just finished Primary on Sunday morning, and the children, teachers, and I were spilling out into the crowded hallway. Just then the door to the Young Women class opened, and I saw the young women and their leaders. We all reached out for a hug. With the children holding onto my skirt and the women close around me, I wanted to express the feelings I felt at that very moment.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us.p6" pid="mz0YCM0szEqLfRUuFOomHw" hash="RE-C1A">I do not speak Spanish, so only English words came into my mind. I looked into all of their faces and said, “We are daughters of our Heavenly Father, who loves us, and we love Him.” Everyone immediately joined in, in Spanish. There we were in a crowded hallway, reciting together the Young Women theme as we said, “We will stand as witnesses of God at all times and in all things, and in all places.”</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us.p7" pid="OZBFyrFpMkCtTOC_8adGig" hash="r1k2Yw">Tonight we gather together all over the world as His disciples, with a desire to defend and sustain the kingdom of God. We are daughters of our Heavenly Father. We are covenant-making women of all ages walking the path of mortality back to His presence. Keeping covenants protects us, prepares us, and empowers us.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us.p8" pid="94g5t9PCYk6GouaSEPp23A" hash="ODzy3g">There are girls among us tonight who are Primary age. Some of you have recently taken that first step on the path to eternal life with the ordinance of baptism.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us.p9" pid="A5HXWhsLuUifyN79dtFHSQ" hash="1h3WUw">Look around you. The future is bright as you see women who have also made covenants and are ready to show you the way along the path ahead.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us.p10" pid="ab2vcOX-YUSFMzeRBO5PWQ" hash="RjrawQ">If you are 8, 9, 10, or 11 years old, whether in the Conference Center, in your home, or in a meetinghouse around the world, would you please stand up? Welcome to the general women’s meeting. Now, please stay standing because we want to invite you tonight to participate. I am going to hum a Primary song. And as soon as you recognize the tune, will you begin singing with me? Now, you must sing out so all can hear.</p>
		<div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us.f1">
			<div class="stanza">
				<p class="line" pid="sfnkVZ8Cb0i40Q2tEbCexA" hash="NZTYMw">Teach me to walk in the light of his love;</p>
				<p class="line" pid="MP69EhuTEkizQfI857dIbA" hash="JX6Tfw">Teach me to pray to my Father above;</p>
				<p class="line" pid="zgFNVYXsPUCpqi4CowAJTA" hash="aPUjeA">Teach me to know of the things that are right;</p>
				<p class="line" pid="cHMSy0QfI06USfKfil7FJw" hash="fUzeEw">Teach me, teach me to walk in the light.</p>
			</div>
		</div>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us.p15" pid="ATDMPwSoCUyhD3Nwy61SvQ" hash="bS_AGA">
			<span class="pageBreak" page-number="117"></span>Stay standing, girls, while everyone 12 and older now sings the second verse.</p>
		<div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us.f2">
			<div class="stanza">
				<p class="line" pid="dJ1kuNpItUW1Cpy4vzzAlQ" hash="lnKoGA">Come, little child, and together we’ll learn</p>
				<p class="line" pid="bABahN52tEaEKG9W9vO46Q" hash="vvNnYQ">Of his commandments, that we may return</p>
				<p class="line" pid="FVsMKoiHNU24tffiNUwliw" hash="FEI-RA">Home to his presence, to live in his sight—</p>
				<p class="line" pid="1gbDGuirs0Kozg_2KhfKxg" hash="YK0msA">Always, always to walk in the light.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span>
				</p>
			</div>
		</div>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us.p20" pid="n2ERJx-CuU6ucHBCtfSk6w" hash="3nyv3w">That was beautiful. You may sit down. Thank you.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us.p21" pid="3XLIJvabaUyn7RHX2JDlAA" hash="K8G4Ng">As women of all ages, we walk in <span class="emphasis">His</span> light. Our journey on the path is personal and well lit with the Savior’s love.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us.p22" pid="UhasXXFQgkmrMI9_qmXarQ" hash="JEa6lQ">We enter the gate to the path of eternal life with the ordinance and covenant of baptism, and then we receive the gift of the Holy Ghost. Elder Robert D. Hales asks us, “Do [we] understand and do [our] children understand that when [we] are baptized [we] are changed forever?”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us.p23" pid="_qnuyOnyK0OK66-BDYWvqw" hash="HF_WPA">He also explained that “when we understand our baptismal covenant and the gift of the Holy Ghost, it will change our lives and will establish our total allegiance to the kingdom of God. When temptations come our way, if we will listen, the Holy Ghost will remind us that we have promised to remember our Savior and obey the commandments of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us.p24" pid="K6AVbElc6kOhdsZ65dHfww" hash="eHpk4Q">Each week as we partake of the emblems of the sacrament, we renew our baptismal covenant. Elder David A. Bednar said: “As we stand in the waters of baptism, we look to the temple. As we partake of the sacrament, we look to the temple. We pledge to always remember the Savior and to keep His commandments as preparation to participate in the sacred ordinances of the temple.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us.p25" pid="g-Xzc04K00iGM7Fw8Jc1Ag" hash="2jlDNg">Temple ordinances lead to the greatest blessings available through the Atonement of Jesus Christ. They are those ordinances necessary for our exaltation in the celestial kingdom. As we strive to keep our covenants, our feelings of inadequacy and imperfection begin to fade, while the ordinances and the covenants of the temple come alive. Everyone is welcome to walk that path to eternal life.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us.p26" pid="fL5FbtvCIESrh9IU2ndYZQ" hash="GPD7vg">I am in awe at the strength of the girls, young women, and women I have met around the world whose feet are firmly planted on this path. Let me share some examples of covenant girls and women I have met.</p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us.p27" pid="9-dq7n02vUOQzVVjwaSOog" hash="mevsEg">Luana was 11 years old when I visited her family in Buenos Aires, Argentina. Because of a traumatic event in her childhood, Luana could not speak. She had not spoken for years. She sat silently as we all conversed. I kept hoping for even a whisper from her. She looked at me intently as if uttering words were not necessary for me to know her heart. After a prayer, we stood up to leave, and Luana handed me a drawing. She had drawn Jesus Christ in the Garden of Gethsemane. I then recognized her witness loud and clear. Luana had made a covenant at baptism to stand as a witness of God “at all times and in all things, and in all places.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> She understood the Atonement of Jesus Christ, as witnessed through her drawing. Had she come to know that, through the strengthening and enabling power of the Atonement, she could be healed and speak again? Since that day three years ago, Luana has progressed in her effort to speak. She is now participating in Young Women with her friends. Faithful to the covenant she made at baptism, she continues to share her witness of the Savior.</p>
		</span>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us.p28" pid="G5vkX4PQukSThGJzas_IfA" hash="McCKIw">Youth all over the world are drawn to temples. In Lima, Peru, I met a father and three of his daughters outside the entrance of the temple. I saw the light in their faces. Two of the daughters were severely disabled and sitting in wheelchairs. The third <span class="pageBreak" page-number="118"></span>daughter, while attending to her sisters’ needs, explained she had two more sisters at home. They too were in wheelchairs. They were unable to travel the 14 hours to the temple. The temple meant so much to this father and his daughters that four of them had come to the temple that day—two of them simply to observe the one who could be baptized for the dead and perform that sacred ordinance. Like Nephi, they “[delighted] in the covenants of the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span>
			</p>
		</span>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us.p29" pid="Jc20DNmzvESPbQWdvgzkXA" hash="Cx7zTw">A single woman I know values the weekly ordinance of the sacrament and its sacred promise “that [she] may always have his Spirit to be with [her].”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> That constant companionship is a promise that softens the waves of her loneliness. It gives her strength to immerse herself in developing her talents and a desire to serve the Lord. She has discovered great joy in adoring all the children in her life, and when she seeks serene peace, you will find her in the temple.</p>
		</span>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us.p30" pid="Nb4zZjmxukOyvUBJE8t7Yw" hash="84IHkQ">Lastly, an elderly woman in her 90s has watched her children and grandchildren grow up and her great-grandchildren come into the world. Like many of us, she has had a life filled with sorrows, afflictions, and incomprehensible joy. She confesses that if she were rewriting her life story, she would not choose to include some of the chapters that have been written. Yet, with a smile, she says, “I just must live a little longer and see how it all turns out!” She continues to hold fast to the covenants on the path.</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us.p31" pid="GK25O_Wi_0eQyDLaisT4QA" hash="pgf5vA">Nephi taught:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us.p32" pid="76vILkD4FkuQYnEZ-Hh9Yg" hash="m2U4Yw">“After ye have gotten into this strait and narrow path, I would ask if all is done? Behold, I say unto you, Nay. …</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us.p33" pid="vaZrGCar4UqZDU8Pcq3cmQ" hash="EUlB_A">“Wherefore, ye must press forward with a steadfastness in Christ, having a perfect brightness of hope, and a love of God and of all men. Wherefore, if ye shall press forward, feasting upon the word of Christ, and endure to the end, behold, thus saith the Father: Ye shall have eternal life.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us.p34" pid="yq_oQA_heUmniqQCr98_UA" hash="1ZA7nQ">Each one of us is on that path. Tonight we sang about walking the path in the light. As individuals, we are strong. Together with God, we are unstoppable.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us.p35" pid="mz1SACNTrUKXEdRPyr5WHA" hash="bxnp6g">The Lord said to Emma Smith, “Lift up thy heart and rejoice, and cleave unto the covenants which thou hast made.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span>
		</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us.p36" pid="sj0tbATbXEKnyGJMGDGabQ" hash="kkFNww">We do rejoice that through keeping our covenants, we may feel the love of our Heavenly Father and our Savior, Jesus Christ. I testify that They live. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2014/04/keeping-covenants-protects-us-prepares-us-and-empowers-us</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-womens-meeting/march-2014-general-womens-meeting/2014-03-0010-rosemary-m-wixom-64k-eng.mp3" length="5400540" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2014 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Returning to Faith</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Rosemary M. Wixom shares the story of a woman who returned from doubt to faith and of the family members and friends who lovingly supported her.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_12565_000_42wixom" doc-version="6" hash="YMIHtg">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="9wi-Fp8v9USb72LiaYufHQ" hash="2laGcA">Returning to Faith</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith.p2" pid="PX3WX6bHBU-gB1xZmfxWXw" hash="aSgalg">By Rosemary M. Wixom</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith.p3" pid="XlpfVUlLy0q_GCeN9ibBvw" hash="amFNAg">Primary General President</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=lh8kv0_cC0ykUvQf2bTUVg"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" type="jpg" uri="rosemary-m-wixom-10.jpg" translate="no" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255597/82d804b236304681931f5f8eb5c49ead/100x138.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x69="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255597/82d804b236304681931f5f8eb5c49ead/50x69.jpg" data-src-100x138="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255597/82d804b236304681931f5f8eb5c49ead/100x138.jpg" data-src-200x276="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255597/82d804b236304681931f5f8eb5c49ead/200x276.jpg" data-src-320x441="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255597/82d804b236304681931f5f8eb5c49ead/320x441.jpg" data-src-460x635="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255597/82d804b236304681931f5f8eb5c49ead/460x635.jpg" data-src-640x883="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255597/82d804b236304681931f5f8eb5c49ead/640x883.jpg" data-src-1024x1413="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255597/82d804b236304681931f5f8eb5c49ead/1024x1413.jpg" data-src-2048x2827="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255597/82d804b236304681931f5f8eb5c49ead/2048x2827.jpg" data-src-3643x5030="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255597/82d804b236304681931f5f8eb5c49ead/3643x5030.jpg" pid="lh8kv0_cC0ykUvQf2bTUVg" hash="3gdm_A"></img></a>
		</div>
		<p class="kicker" pid="Yo-qzDh4Bk2OXPL286mLQA" hash="JFGuKw">Every one of us can strengthen our faith in Jesus Christ on our individual journey and find joy.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="gjTvbSgmGk-3fn8RDd3IAA" hash="aSgalg1">By Rosemary M. Wixom</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock" pid="AnoA7rgSqkqgn6IbGlxiAA" hash="zE6Haw">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith.p5" pid="uTje2JgsoEqloRp0Ysjwyw" hash="ZFTCtg">On this Easter morning, President Monson, we are so grateful to hear the voice of our living prophet. We value your words, including your counsel “Find joy in the journey”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> and “The future is as bright as your faith.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith.p6" pid="dzHSZLeLEEGiI36-VY3-zA" hash="UvuW4w">This year Primary children are sharing the joy and the brightness of their faith in Jesus Christ when they sing the song “I Know That My Savior Loves Me.” They sing the truth “I know He lives! ... My heart I give to Him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Like Primary children, every one of us can strengthen our faith in Jesus Christ on our individual journey and find joy.</p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith.p7" pid="AC_hhE3XFkiAHESilM0Lpw" hash="i5G-hQ">In a recent Sunday Relief Society meeting, I listened to a young mother share part of her journey of conversion. She had grown up in the Church, with parents who taught her the gospel. She attended Primary, Young Women, and seminary. She loved to learn and discover truths. Her constant quest was to know <span class="emphasis">why.</span> Elder Russell M. Nelson has said, “The Lord can only teach an inquiring mind.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> And this young woman was teachable.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith.p8" pid="uAZGKwKAHEeTat_sko_Q5w" hash="CZ9bQw">After high school she attended a university, was sealed in the temple to a returned missionary, and was blessed with beautiful children.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith.p9" pid="YBjsEXY0dEG99QCnB40a2w" hash="zg0U6g">With the spirit of inquiry, this mother continued to ask questions. But as the questions grew harder, so did the answers. And sometimes there were no answers—or no answers that brought peace. Eventually, as she sought to find answers, more and more questions arose, and she began to question some of the very foundations of her faith.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith.p10" pid="LDXydrUIC0CUJnxd9dpvsg" hash="cMo9GQ">During this confusing time, some of those around her said, “Just lean on my faith.” But she thought, “I can’t. You don’t understand; you’re not grappling with these issues.” She explained, “I was willing to extend courtesy to those without doubts if they would extend courtesy to me.” And many did.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith.p11" pid="cGQPK4mJT0CMlKUIb3wUZw" hash="AIroaQ">She said, “My parents knew my heart and allowed me space. They chose to love me while I was trying to figure it out for myself.” Likewise, this young mother’s bishop often met with her and spoke of his confidence in her.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith.p12" pid="2k2BplaJukSJAhoHbjMzYA" hash="AEOa_A">Ward members also did not hesitate to give love, and she felt included. Her ward was not a place to put on a perfect face; it was a place of nurture.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith.p13" pid="BJeEitlDJ0WJQ8nwol8qJQ" hash="D9RzfA">“It was interesting,” she remembers. “During this time I felt a real connection to my grandparents who had died. They were pulling for me and urging me to keep trying. I felt they were saying, ‘Focus on what you know.’”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith.p14" pid="BglRcVP81k-ydIP5mX-ddQ" hash="x6V35Q">In spite of her substantial support system, she became less active. She said, “I did not separate myself from the Church because of bad behavior, spiritual apathy, looking for an excuse not to live the commandments, or searching for an easy out. I felt I needed the answer to the question ‘What do I really believe?’”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith.p15" pid="l3LfflqzEkaguLGg8EMt-Q" hash="McX4zw">About this time she read a book of the writings of Mother Teresa, who had shared similar feelings. In a 1953 letter, Mother Teresa wrote: “Please pray specially for me that I may not spoil His work and that Our Lord may show Himself—for there is such terrible darkness within me, as if everything was dead. It has been like this more or less from the time I started ‘the work.’ Ask Our Lord to give me courage.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith.p16" pid="0Br_xGFnGkyYX8_elekyQg" hash="RkW5Gg">Archbishop Périer responded: “God guides you, dear Mother; you are not so much in the dark as you think. The path to be followed may not always be clear at once. Pray for light; do not decide too quickly, listen to what others have to say, consider their reasons. You will always find something to help you. … Guided by faith, by prayer, and by reason with a right intention, you have enough.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith.p17" pid="eVkjPfQ2JUaOPUynXePvZA" hash="nmia3Q">My friend thought if Mother Teresa could live her religion without all the answers and without a feeling of clarity in all things, maybe she could too. She could take one simple step forward in faith—and then another. She could focus on the truths she did believe and let those truths fill her mind and heart.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith.p18" pid="VFH8EEzhxkywoBII56wosA" hash="kb8Btg">As she reflected back, she said, “My testimony had become like a pile of ashes. It had all burned down. All that remained was Jesus Christ.” She continued, “But He does not leave you when you have questions. When anyone tries to keep the commandments, the door is wide open. Prayer and scripture study became incredibly important.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith.p19" pid="FqrOBvd6HEiyIiJcKg8sYw" hash="OElCqA">Her first step to rebuild her faith was to start with basic gospel truths. She bought a Primary songbook and began reading the words of the songs. They were treasures to her. She prayed for faith to lift the heaviness she felt.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith.p20" pid="4SP7VGXvmUu9UsXvSnKUHg" hash="xbHjow">She learned that when she came up against a statement that caused her to doubt, she “could stop, look at the whole picture, and make the gospel personal.” She said, “I would ask, ‘Is this the right path for me and my family?’ Sometimes I would ask myself, ‘What do I want for my children?’ I realized I want them to have temple marriages. That’s when belief came back to my heart.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith.p21" pid="lVofXhbqrEGhECbMswBRSQ" hash="qVptQQ">Elder Jeffrey R. Holland has said, “Humility, faith, and the influence of the Holy Spirit [will] always be elements of <span class="emphasis">every</span> quest for truth.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith.p22" pid="ZvbA1aCMg0-uRbQXrIyl1w" hash="bQgFlA">Though she had questions about how the Book of Mormon came to be, she could not deny the truths she knew in the Book of Mormon. She had focused on studying the New Testament to better understand the Savior. “But eventually,” she said, “I found myself back in the Book of Mormon because I loved what I felt when reading about Jesus Christ and His Atonement.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith.p23" pid="iKUGiVrpqE2jO0d5NmX3YA" hash="5OgS-A">She concluded, “You have to have your own spiritual experiences with the truths in that book,” and she was having them. She explained, “I read in Mosiah and felt completely directed: ‘Believe in God; believe that he is, and that he created all things … ; believe that he has all wisdom, and all power, both in heaven and in earth; believe that man doth not comprehend all the things which the Lord can comprehend.’<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span>”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith.p24" pid="pQk1t3b0ykKpkFiauz68tA" hash="sRRbgg">About this time a call came to serve as Primary pianist. “It was safe,” she said. “I wanted to have my children in Primary, and now I could be with them. And I wasn’t ready to teach yet.” As she served, she continued to feel from those around her the invitation “Come; we want you, whatever stage you are at, and we will meet you there. Give us whatever you have to offer.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith.p25" pid="3ebnng9ahkqTrsumr2DUjw" hash="BANz-Q">Playing the Primary songs, she often thought to herself, “Here are truths I love. I can still bear testimony. I will just say those things that I know and trust. It may not be a perfect offering of knowledge, but it will be my offering. What I focus on expands inside of me. It is beautiful to get back to the essence of the gospel and feel clarity.”</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith.p26" pid="y_VIvSTvSUC99ZWvRiF2Kg" hash="jsoExQ">On that Sunday morning, as I listened to this young sister share the story of her journey, I was reminded that “it is upon the rock of our Redeemer” that we all must build our foundation.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> I was also reminded of the counsel of Elder Jeffrey R. Holland: “Hold fast to what you already know and stand strong until additional knowledge comes.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith.p27" pid="hHx_x1hMi0yBgfpu67X6nQ" hash="1EAa7g">During her lesson, I came to know more fervently that answers to our sincere questions come when we earnestly seek and when we live the commandments. I was reminded that our faith can reach beyond the limits of current reason.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith.p28" pid="en_MX-IuMUajkn1DQCRCbA" hash="TDlnOg">And, oh, how I want to be like those who surrounded this young mother, loving and supporting her. As President Dieter F. Uchtdorf said: “We are all pilgrims seeking God’s light as we journey on the path of discipleship. We do not condemn others for the amount of light they may or may not have; rather, we nourish and encourage all light until it grows clear, bright, and true.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith.p29" pid="9C7N2DdHzEevk9eRbUGoag" hash="FQSU-Q">When the Primary children sing “A Child’s Prayer,” they ask: “Heavenly Father, are you really there? And do you hear and answer every child’s prayer?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith.p30" pid="JMSUnXP96Ui8a-dJ1bZXLQ" hash="nARsaw">We too may wonder, “Is Heavenly Father really there?” only to rejoice—as my friend did—when the answers come in quiet, simple assurances. I testify that those simple assurances come as His will becomes ours. I testify that truth is on the earth today and His gospel is found in The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2015/04/returning-to-faith</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2015-general-conference/2015-04-4020-rosemary-m-wixom-64k-eng.mp3" length="4894626" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discovering the Divinity Within</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Sister Wixom teaches that we each came to earth with a divine nature. Understanding and developing our divine nature helps us know why we are here on earth; it also helps us know that Heavenly Father loves us. The divine nature within each of us moti</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_13768_000_11wixom" doc-version="4" hash="ZqIIkQ">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="wCpI31rxD0WOJoifMkPzbQ" hash="Y8rCLA">Discovering the Divinity Within</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p2" pid="yUlMcPVQJ0-J5gU6GxjQUg" hash="aSgalg">By Rosemary M. Wixom</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p3" pid="gRk6YILewky600qKjRyYBA" hash="amFNAg">Primary General President</p>
		<a href="gl://image/?pid=PlsKEPLX4EmAVhKtlGrl6Q"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" alt="Rosemary M. Wixom" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255597/82d804b236304681931f5f8eb5c49ead/100x138.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x69="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255597/82d804b236304681931f5f8eb5c49ead/50x69.jpg" data-src-100x138="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255597/82d804b236304681931f5f8eb5c49ead/100x138.jpg" data-src-200x276="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255597/82d804b236304681931f5f8eb5c49ead/200x276.jpg" data-src-320x441="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255597/82d804b236304681931f5f8eb5c49ead/320x441.jpg" data-src-460x635="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255597/82d804b236304681931f5f8eb5c49ead/460x635.jpg" data-src-640x883="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255597/82d804b236304681931f5f8eb5c49ead/640x883.jpg" data-src-1024x1413="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255597/82d804b236304681931f5f8eb5c49ead/1024x1413.jpg" data-src-2048x2827="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255597/82d804b236304681931f5f8eb5c49ead/2048x2827.jpg" data-src-3643x5030="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255597/82d804b236304681931f5f8eb5c49ead/3643x5030.jpg" pid="PlsKEPLX4EmAVhKtlGrl6Q" hash="eKkAZQ"></img></a></div>
		<p class="kicker" pid="SaqcZJnL0kKINUfHc4F9VA" hash="cIxj4A1">We come to this earth to nurture and discover the seeds of divine nature that are within us.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="s2-k3u2G5UOksM0nA222IA" hash="8qQ1Bg">Rosemary M. Wixom</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p5" pid="JUWWp30MYUKlcNp4908YLQ" hash="lQm8PA">Sisters, we love you! I testify that life is a gift. God has a plan for each one of us, and our individual purpose began long before we came to this earth.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p6" pid="_hT9Y3OIP0CDDd4TGOwodQ" hash="yfyZSA">Lately I have come to recognize the miracle of a baby’s birth into mortality as part of the Lord’s plan. Each one of us developed physically within our mother’s womb while relying for many months on her body to sustain ours. Eventually, however, the process of birth—dramatic for both mother and child—separated us.</p>
		<a href="gl://image/?pid=ouKgTCXPP0qRapKLNJtv5g"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572804/f9ffec010c0b4243b93c066aaec13be9/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572804/f9ffec010c0b4243b93c066aaec13be9/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572804/f9ffec010c0b4243b93c066aaec13be9/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572804/f9ffec010c0b4243b93c066aaec13be9/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572804/f9ffec010c0b4243b93c066aaec13be9/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572804/f9ffec010c0b4243b93c066aaec13be9/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572804/f9ffec010c0b4243b93c066aaec13be9/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572804/f9ffec010c0b4243b93c066aaec13be9/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572804/f9ffec010c0b4243b93c066aaec13be9/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572804/f9ffec010c0b4243b93c066aaec13be9/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Newborn" pid="ouKgTCXPP0qRapKLNJtv5g" hash="MI6p3w"></img></a>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p7" pid="GRFGJnjRLESSDTWZPCQsaQ" hash="OkN2lQ">As a baby emerges into this world, the change of temperature and light and the sudden release of pressure on the chest induce the baby to take its first gasping breath. Those little lungs suddenly fill with air for the first time, the organs spring into action, and the baby begins to breathe. As the umbilical cord is clamped, that lifeline between mother and baby is forever severed, and the baby’s life on earth begins.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p8" pid="JlpBvwM5CE-3bpQYt5K5UA" hash="oBmNOQ">Job said, “The Spirit of God hath made me, and the breath of the Almighty hath given me life.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p9" pid="7Y5GWDoWKEej5zqLwHNLkQ" hash="TIQcUw">We come into this world “trailing clouds of glory.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> “The Family: A Proclamation to the World” teaches that each one of us “is a beloved spirit son or daughter of heavenly parents” and “each has a divine nature and destiny.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Heavenly Father generously shares a portion of His divinity within us. That divine nature comes as a gift from Him with a love that only a parent can feel.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p10" pid="WNX2OdfbUEatbulFgI9eEg" hash="cIxj4A">We come to this earth to nurture and discover the seeds of divine nature that are within us.</p>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.t1">
			<h2 pid="-OucYcRQZEqeFLHTeOmfOQ" hash="0aUIxQ">We Know Why</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p12" pid="yHaDmS3qMESOvjFLLKQyjA" hash="Z86Weg">Elaine Cannon, a former Young Women general president, said, “There are two important days in a woman’s life: The day she is born and the day she finds out why.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p13" pid="ikxb6lg3PkSKh_xw50pCOQ" hash="D7HZZg">We know why. We have come to this earth to help build His kingdom and to prepare for the Second Coming of His Son, Jesus Christ. With every breath we take, we strive to follow Him. The divine nature within each one of us is refined and magnified by the effort we make to draw nearer to our Father and His Son.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p14" pid="UGTsEeXxkE-L02UB2v5Njw" hash="rD-X5w">Our divine nature has nothing to do with our personal accomplishments, the status we achieve, the number of marathons we run, or our popularity and self-esteem. Our divine nature comes from God. It was established in an existence that preceded our birth and will continue on into eternity.</p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.t2">
			<h2 pid="G5T8PC0qeEWxCKTNzWBC_A" hash="_ZbQgQ">We Are Loved</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p16" pid="b3kubjtdeEm-CUXRQt2WnQ" hash="VLcJTQ">We identify with our divine nature as we feel and give the love of our Father in Heaven. We have the agency to nurture it, let it flourish, and help it grow. Peter said we are given “precious promises” that we “might be partakers of the divine nature.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> As we understand who we are—daughters of God—we begin to feel those precious promises.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p17" pid="owPr1Oj9xEmcBGwx8PK7DQ" hash="5_wMIQ">Looking out through a window, not just into a mirror, allows us to see ourselves as His. We naturally turn to Him in prayer, and we are eager to read His words and to do His will. We are able to take our validation vertically from Him, not horizontally from the world around us or from those on Facebook or Instagram.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p18" pid="oQzeBYeeyUK09JwPBaFUlQ" hash="bI0F1w">If you ever question that spark of divinity within you, kneel in prayer and ask Heavenly Father, “Am I really Thy daughter, and dost Thou love me?” Elder M. Russell Ballard said, “One of the sweetest messages the Spirit will relay is how the Lord feels about you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p19" pid="IkGcEFUtLkqBhJ1bKcd4-w" hash="t4w1bA">We are His. Paul said, “The Spirit itself beareth witness with our spirit, that we are the children of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> Often the first Primary song we learn is “I Am a Child of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> Now it is time to take that beloved phrase “I am a child of God” and add the words “Therefore, what?” We might even ask questions such as these: “What will I do to live my life as a child of God?” “How can I develop the divine nature that is within me?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p20" pid="bqVQ6I1ZkkmsTZi8WuGiDQ" hash="In28lw">President Dieter F. Uchtdorf said, “God sent you here to prepare for a future greater than anything you can imagine.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> That future, a day at a time, comes alive when you do more than just exist; it comes alive when you live your life to fill the measure of your creation. This invites the Lord into your life, and you begin to let His will become yours.</p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.t3">
			<h2 pid="vyk6_7SQOUqJac8flU-4ug" hash="KHfzLw">We Learn Because of Our Divine Nature</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p22" pid="bvGjJUnkV021wGkhayuBYw" hash="ip-rcw">Divine nature breathes into us the desire to know these eternal truths for ourselves.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p23" pid="81vRlXcTq06NBwRwHgbmfQ" hash="O7shHA">A young woman named Amy recently taught me this lesson when she wrote: “It is hard being a teenager these days. The path is getting narrower. Satan is really trying. It is either right or wrong; there is no in-between.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p24" pid="c7o5MqyCXk2g_T3KMDlaQg" hash="BDnB5w">She continued: “Good friends are sometimes hard to find. Even when you think you have best friends who will never leave, that could change for any reason. That is why I am so glad that I have family, Heavenly Father, Jesus Christ, and the Holy Ghost, who can be my companions whenever things with friends go wrong.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p25" pid="6csRG-kgQ0eHYXJpe679UQ" hash="esCW1g">Amy went on to say: “One night I was troubled. I told my sister I didn’t know what to do.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p26" pid="9FGR4nE_5k-uN_1cOl8LNw" hash="RhSG8A">Later that night her sister sent her a text and quoted Elder Jeffrey R. Holland when he said: “Don’t give up. … Don’t you quit. You keep walking. You keep trying. There is help and happiness ahead. … It will be all right in the end. Trust God and believe in good things to come.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p27" pid="8Y1aG3jdoUCicrODAnsEww" hash="FdSgwg">Amy explained: “I remembered reading that and just praying that I would feel love from God if He really was there for me.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p28" pid="Fb07A-3OcU6lnrqImimPHQ" hash="u4SKig">She said: “As soon as I asked and believed that He was there, I felt the most amazing, happy, warm feeling. Words can’t describe it. I knew He was there and that He loved me.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p29" pid="kuaRTCV940KRCBpwP65B0g" hash="t7zRTA">Because you are His child, He knows who you can become. He knows your fears and your dreams. He relishes your potential. He waits for you to come to Him in prayer. Because you are His child, you not only need Him, but He also needs you. Those sitting around you right now in this meeting need you. The world needs you, and your divine nature allows you to be His trusted disciple to all His children. Once we begin to see the divinity in ourselves, we can see it in others.</p>
		</div>
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.t4">
			<h2 pid="DhfcaXehb0qeuBRvB2E9Zw" hash="rfU8lw">We Serve Because of Our Divine Nature</h2>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p31" pid="IRz3GxGZckKL6RXy3eQQ5A" hash="TC84Bw">Divine nature breathes into us the desire to serve others.</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=LbpD4GKC0EOFIxFu9suCKA"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572864/294740e77e64478f8a25a4f39b7d2f92/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572864/294740e77e64478f8a25a4f39b7d2f92/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572864/294740e77e64478f8a25a4f39b7d2f92/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572864/294740e77e64478f8a25a4f39b7d2f92/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572864/294740e77e64478f8a25a4f39b7d2f92/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572864/294740e77e64478f8a25a4f39b7d2f92/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572864/294740e77e64478f8a25a4f39b7d2f92/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572864/294740e77e64478f8a25a4f39b7d2f92/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572864/294740e77e64478f8a25a4f39b7d2f92/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1572864/294740e77e64478f8a25a4f39b7d2f92/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Mother and child during Ethiopian famine" pid="LbpD4GKC0EOFIxFu9suCKA" hash="OdJyUw"></img></a>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p32" pid="BIx8YpGm8ESr9-TP00lzWg" hash="siwcoA">Recently, Sharon Eubank, the director of Humanitarian Services and LDS Charities, told of an experience shared by Elder Glenn L. Pace. There was widespread drought and extreme famine in Ethiopia in the mid-1980s. To provide relief, feeding stations with water and food were created for those who could get to them. An old man who was starving was walking a long distance to get to a feeding station. He was passing a village when he heard the cry of a baby. He searched until he found the baby sitting on the ground next to his dead mother. Picking up the baby, the man continued to walk 25 miles (40 km) to the feeding station. When he arrived, his first words were not “I’m hungry” or “Help me.” They were “What can be done for this baby?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p33" pid="JEuUculRSkmVSZIipN7aqQ" hash="7Nk9-Q">The divine nature within us ignites our desire to reach out to others and prompts us to act. Heavenly Father and Jesus Christ can help us find the strength to do so. Could the Lord be asking us, “What can be done for this daughter, this brother, this father, or this friend?”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p34" pid="MWvsQgfEtkKAM1Yp7ED5ww" hash="UoDcng">It is through the whisperings of the Spirit that the divine nature of a doubter, after gasping for breath, finds the peace to breathe again.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p35" pid="qOKzmkXGRkaQv3Xi9yx8pw" hash="5c65zA">When the prophet speaks, his words resonate with our divine nature and give us strength to follow.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p36" pid="zaUPZW4hRkCAUxI0wkZl0A" hash="5VL9tg">Partaking of the sacrament each week breathes hope into the divinity within us, and we remember our Savior, Jesus Christ.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within.p37" pid="LbU0wpx8pkiBpI-OUOC_4g" hash="ZBiTRQ">I promise that as you seek to discover the depth of the divine nature that lies within you, you will begin to further magnify your precious gift. Let it guide you to become His daughter, walking the path back to Him—where we will be “restored to that God who gave [us] breath.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2015/10/discovering-the-divinity-within</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2015-general-conference/2015-09-0010-rosemary-m-wixom-64k-eng.mp3" length="5408824" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2015 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
