<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Royden G. Derrick</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Royden G. Derrick.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Royden%20G.%20Derrick.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Royden G. Derrick.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 1977 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>The Beatitudes and Our Perfection</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection?lang=eng</link>
      <description>On a beautiful, clear day, early in the spring of 1820, a fourteen-year-old boy knelt in a grove of trees and poured out his thoughts and feelings to God. What followed made his experience the most important event that had transpired in nearly 1,800 </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection" dup-mag="false" dup-conf="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03083_000_027" doc-version="3" hash="2QSHOQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="67N15qwARUmyMZOnsJoA7g" hash="avA9uQ">The Beatitudes and Our Perfection</h1><p class="authorName" pid="blRKPoVP506UUBcMxiHOQw" hash="fJ9QkA">Royden G. Derrick</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26a2.jpg" alt="Elder Royden G. Derrick" pid="xGqZ27_47k-Floq4HBwJxA" hash="IA4zgQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p1" pid="6ymn-cbfM0Wcy4YRiMdnhw" hash="9Qd3zw">On a beautiful, clear day, early in the spring of 1820, a fourteen-year-old boy knelt in a grove of trees and poured out his thoughts and feelings to God. What followed made his experience the most important event that had transpired in nearly 1,800 years. God the Father and his Son, Jesus Christ, appeared to him in person—face to face.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p2" pid="52SIwYhcmUatswhegT4dMQ" hash="YM_kcg">Subsequently, through this young man, whose name was Joseph Smith, God restored his church and the fulness of his gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p3" pid="aHxnr4_g10CCXHheJu70jQ" hash="OWlxOw">This restoration is what made that experience so important. I bear witness in the name of Jesus Christ that this is true. I know that he talked with God and that there was such a restoration because the Holy Spirit has borne witness of it to me. I say it without the slightest hesitation. I have a sure conviction that it happened.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p4" pid="LIo7046EpEmIJBhW2ItkfQ" hash="mS8hxw">It is important that members of the Church know that each General Authority has that sure knowledge, for the Savior, referring to individual revelation, said to Peter, “And upon this rock [meaning the rock of individual revelation] I will build my church.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/16.18" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 16:18</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p5" pid="4NeipJg5PEKLLQW-Dwq6Zg" hash="7nmLSA">Serving the Lord is not an individual matter. It is a family affair. Every wife should support her husband in his Church responsibilities; every husband should support his wife in hers; every child his parent; every parent his children; every brother his sister; and every sister her brother.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p6" pid="5FEi82SpdUuSMwQbPixavA" hash="Ovk5og">This builds the eternal family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p7" pid="A7by-XatzES6rTp5IPKZnQ" hash="KUEPIg">I am grateful to my sweetheart, who has been a good companion, an outstanding mother, a dedicated wife, and a remarkable missionary companion. I am grateful to her parents, who have reared a righteous family; to our children, who have joined with us over the years in serving the Lord; to our families, who have been so loyal and supportive; and to my wonderful parents and brother, who, from their heavenly abode, I am confident, are aware of my recent calling to be an especial witness of the Savior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p8" pid="64pgCWu6yE-0J-vSK4CqMg" hash="LY8JoA">Missionary service is rewarding.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p9" pid="MT3c-lwz7ESNIhWtAcn80w" hash="syy6jA">Sister Derrick and I spent three satisfying years in northern England in missionary work. We had been home only forty-eight hours when the call came to return as soon as possible and preside over a new mission being established in the Republic of Ireland. What a glorious experience it has been.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p10" pid="BHjc1IPtwEChqCcMyNnEpg" hash="8VuAMQ">In Ireland, where social pressures are unusually strong, a father with tears running down his cheeks said, “They call me a fool—my family calls me a fool—my friends call me a fool; but I’ll take their abuse any and every day of the year in loyalty to my Savior who has led me to the true Church.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p11" pid="mwgBFhoCFEO2R-ZfLFTgMg" hash="fFCPaA">Still another, who had been particularly skeptical, on the night of his baptism said, “It’s true—but not only is it true, it is the whole truth and nothing but the truth.” So declare we to the world regarding this message of the Restoration.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p12" pid="HFOnf4oz-0yDDoiwwrSdRg" hash="1a88Cg">The more experience I gain in teaching the restored gospel of Jesus Christ, the more I am impressed with the concept of the <span class="emphasis">Beatitudes</span> shared by a friend years ago which deserves a more broad exposure. Each of the Beatitudes represents a specific step in our orderly progression towards perfection, and teaches us how to qualify ourselves for exaltation, for the Bible concludes the chapter on the Beatitudes with the words, “Be ye therefore perfect, even as your Father which is in heaven is perfect.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.48" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:48</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p13" pid="7aCb-SENykOuLNRHb25eIA" hash="NY-5ww">The Savior began his sermon saying, <span class="emphasis">“Blessed are the poor in spirit: for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.” </span>(<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.3" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:3</a>; italics added.) When the Savior gave the same sermon to the people of ancient America, he said, “Blessed are the poor in spirit who come unto me, for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/12.3" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 12:3</a>.) “Who come unto me”—that clarifies the meaning.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p14" pid="3bSuw8423UmgcfwZXZ9Gbg" hash="qJ_hGA">When I was a boy, a herd of horses ran wild on Ensign Flats just north of the Utah State Capitol building. In the summertime we would occasionally sit on the mountainside with binoculars and watch the herd as they roamed and grazed on the flat below. For the most part the horses appeared to be a mangy lot, but there was one that had a grace, a dignity, and a spirit that qualified him to lead the herd. We tried on several occasions to put a rope on this stallion. One day we succeeded, but we soon found that we had on the end of the rope a bundle of fury that we couldn’t manage. As hard as we tried, we couldn’t ride him. After several attempts we gave up and turned him loose. He was of no value to us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p15" pid="L0eMdZZn3UmIpTAtJi3KCA" hash="oxnLpw">I was reading recently that when professionals train Arabian horses they work with them for several months. At the conclusion of the training period they are placed in a corral without food or water. After several days both food and water are placed some distance away, but within sight. The gate is then opened and the horses run to satisfy their appetites.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p16" pid="D4uBkQ8Nq062p7G-vqSN1A" hash="dylHlQ">Just before they reach the food and water, the trainer blows a whistle. Those that respond to the trainer’s whistle are singled out as the most valued. They are submissive to the master’s call.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p17" pid="_DuxE9yzik26dLGzYxvWpQ" hash="IC7CZw">Under a mandate from the Lord we have 25,000 young men who are sifting the people of the world to find those that are submissive to Him and to the whisperings of the Holy Spirit. We are finding an increasing number throughout the nations of the world who respond, but the vast majority prefer to satisfy their own appetites and to do things their own way instead of the Lord’s way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p18" pid="5KI3X6ni10emuFQ8xBRvdg" hash="ARfRYA">When we love the Lord we will submit ourselves to <span class="emphasis">his</span> plan and serve him with all of our heart, might, mind, and strength. This is the <span class="emphasis">first</span> step. We must take it in order to qualify for exaltation. The miracle of change begins when we come forth with a contrite spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p19" pid="A8PveGi0-EmVJ4FkCjcWmA" hash="UASuEg">The Savior then said, <span class="emphasis">“Blessed are they that mourn: for they shall be comforted.” </span>(<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.4" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:4</a>; italics added.) This is the <span class="emphasis">second step.</span> It is an essential one. The apostle Paul spoke of a godly sorrow for our sins when he said, “For godly sorrow worketh repentance to salvation.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-cor/7.10" class="scriptureRef">2 Cor. 7:10</a>.) It is necessary to repent of our sins if we are to be forgiven and if the atonement of Jesus Christ is to be effective in our lives. Oh! how joyous it is to work with a person as he goes through the process of repentance, enters the water of baptism, and comes into the kingdom of God. There develops a bond of love and unity with those who have gone through this purifying process that the world does not understand.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p20" pid="sOiMRH-HUEmbtxFSaVAz3w" hash="YBk3dQ">The Savior next said, <span class="emphasis">“Blessed are the meek: for they shall inherit the earth.” </span>(<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.5" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:5</a>; italics added.) To be meek is to be teachable. Those who are willing to listen can learn much. Those who are unwilling to listen deny themselves great blessings. You needn’t worry about being deceived, for the prophet Moroni wrote, “By the power of the Holy Ghost you may know the truth of all things.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.5" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 10:5</a>.) You have the receiving set within you to distinguish false doctrine from true doctrine. Follow the steps outlined by the Savior in the Beatitudes and your receiving set will become finely tuned. Then pray to God in sincerity for an answer and your receiving set will work. This is God’s way for us to discern the truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p21" pid="gIriGsTgj0S08GI2JT8zFQ" hash="iO5X7g">The Savior further said, <span class="emphasis">“Blessed are they which do hunger and thirst after righteousness: for they shall be filled.” </span>(; italics added.) The Book of Mormon account reads, “For they shall be filled with the Holy Ghost.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/12.6" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 12:6</a>.) This is important. The Holy Ghost is the great teacher and teaches us the truth of all things. God has documented his plan of salvation—a plan for <span class="emphasis">our</span> salvation. It is found in the holy scriptures and the Lord has commanded us to “search the scriptures.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/5.39" class="scriptureRef">John 5:39</a>.) The plan is not complicated, but it is comprehensive. It is so comprehensive that we never stop learning, yet it is beautifully simple. The Lord has promised us all that if we follow his program we will learn “line upon line, precept upon precept” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/98.12" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 98:12</a>), until the perfect day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p22" pid="jWaobGJQGUaiqtuktswoUw" hash="fXOhJA">This promise is to every man. We should develop an insatiable appetite for knowledge pertaining to our salvation, for the Savior said, “And this is life eternal, that they might know thee the only true God, and Jesus Christ, whom thou hast sent.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/17.3" class="scriptureRef">John 17:3</a>.) There is no more important, exciting, and exhilarating subject than to learn about him who created the worlds and the plan he has prepared for us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p23" pid="auSZ9gXwgEqdC-aQhEwSRA" hash="v3O7AQ">As we begin to follow the teachings of the Savior, our thoughts and our hearts turn to others. The Savior continued, <span class="emphasis">“Blessed are the merciful: for they shall obtain mercy.”</span> (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.7" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:7</a>; italics added.) Happiness is a by-product of helping others. No man ever finds happiness by thinking of himself. True happiness comes when we lose ourselves in the service of others—when we are merciful to our fellowmen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p24" pid="mHjagI4pckSA0N2dRQBN-A" hash="nf7oXw">Being merciful to others leads to purity of heart, for the Savior said, <span class="emphasis">“Blessed are the pure in heart: for they shall see God.” </span>(<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.8" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:8</a>; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p25" pid="Fd65flZpdkevrqxH3mIYcw" hash="-uf1JA">The by-product of a pure heart is inner peace. The Lord next said, <span class="emphasis">“Blessed are the peacemakers: for they</span><span class="emphasis">shall be called the children of God.”</span> (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.9" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:9</a>; italics added.) When a man obtains inner peace he wants peace in his family. He wants peace in his community. He wants peace in the nation. And he wants peace in the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p26" pid="ab9t_QShE0-pChLVC4JQJA" hash="Kd-_vA">Sister Derrick and I recently drove from Dublin to Limerick, Ireland. Along the way were signs painted on walls and bus stop enclosures: “Brits out—Peace in.” That is not the way nor the road to peace. Peace comes from within the individual. Establish peace in the hearts and minds of the citizens of a country and you’ll have peace in the nation. We declare to the world that living the principles of the gospel of Jesus Christ as restored through the Prophet Joseph Smith will bring peace to the hearts of men and in turn will bring peace to the nations of the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p27" pid="gWRHSw1p0Ua5WQkFpMdcQg" hash="P4wUyg">Teaching the doctrine of the Savior was never done without opposition. The Lord says of those who are willing to withstand social pressures and criticism and continue to serve him: “<span class="emphasis">Blessed are they which are persecuted for righteousness’ sake: for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p28" pid="fzGplLx7hkmP8lVIEGYoqg" hash="JEcTeg">
        <span class="emphasis">“Blessed are ye, when men shall revile you, and persecute you, and shall say all manner of evil against you falsely, for my sake.</span>
      </p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p29" pid="CIS2rb-hpUuEvCZNUzhloQ" hash="XsGIww">
        <span class="emphasis">“Rejoice, and be exceeding glad: for great is your reward in heaven: for so persecuted they the prophets which were before you.”</span> (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.10-12" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:10–12</a>; italics added.) And thus the Savior described the miracle of change that comes into one’s life when he accepts the gospel of Jesus Christ, which is a beautiful, miraculous, and soul-satisfying gift from God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p30" pid="IT7BPswjZUKB3D9oA06H2Q" hash="GDqang">The Savior concluded the Beatitudes by saying of those who conform their lives to these teachings, “Ye are the salt of the earth. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p31" pid="BFAPmBa820-36PgHUEKFHw" hash="2ySmew">“Ye are the light of the world. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p32" pid="xJfZxP_sKUOe-0bcxioJjQ" hash="vp9xlQ">“Let your light so shine before men, that they may see your good works, and glorify your Father which is in heaven.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.13-14,16" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:13–14, 16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p33" pid="zQYeMjmwEEGk9bZJ1ZDEbw" hash="xbwXCw">The prophet Nephi, referring to the Savior, said, “He inviteth them all to come unto him and partake of his goodness; and he denieth none that come unto him.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/26.33" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 26:33</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection.p34" pid="L_lvnrKTqUychnU_Jnw5Kw" hash="_rl6Hg">To all men everywhere we reiterate that invitation to come unto the Savior the way he has outlined, partake of his goodness, “and enjoy the words of eternal life in this world, and eternal life in the world to come, even immortal glory” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/6.59" class="scriptureRef">Moses 6:59</a>), “which gift is the greatest of all the gifts of God” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/14.7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 14:7</a>). In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1977/04/the-beatitudes-and-our-perfection</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1977-general-conference/1977-04-4030-elder-royden-g-derrick-64k-eng.mp3" length="6727829" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 1977 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Heritage of Royal Families</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Those who believe in the Bible should not find it difficult to accept the experience related by the Prophet Joseph Smith concerning the visit of an ancient American prophet, Moroni. It happened on the evening of 21 September 1823, in Manchester, New </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03109_000_013" doc-version="2" hash="HDJs2A"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="JscS6eCEs0ux8eZY2Ogm1A" hash="cXTsIQ">The Heritage of Royal Families</h1><p class="authorName" guid="f68d93a7-7965-447b-87ee-0c88052eb590" pid="JjIJZ4p75k6_7MZbcuGFgw" hash="fJ9QkA">Royden G. Derrick</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="ac3c5fcd-b511-4e63-9a21-e31e21079f23">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26a2.jpg" alt="Elder Royden G. Derrick" guid="fabd4051-b5b3-4af7-99c8-5b270a1e6ac9" pid="GgOcZOekPkCnR8Tayx6EQA" hash="IA4zgQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="pUbB56Oo4k-Yj8r9xdJsjg" hash="bNh2_Q">Those who believe in the Bible should not find it difficult to accept the experience related by the Prophet Joseph Smith concerning the visit of an ancient American prophet, Moroni. It happened on the evening of 21 September 1823, in Manchester, New York. Joseph Smith related:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="4OfDIoVZ9Ueoh1JfaX4S_A" hash="OMrmuQ">“While I was thus in the act of calling upon God, I discovered a light appearing in my room, which continued to increase until the room was lighter than at noonday, when immediately a personage appeared at my bedside, standing in the air, for his feet did not touch the floor.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="6BNhe5f5vk6D44PehCaXFQ" hash="54XcpQ">“He had on a loose robe of most exquisite whiteness. … His hands were naked, and his arms also, a little above the wrist; so, also, were his feet naked, as were his legs, a little above the ankles. His head and neck were also bare. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="PN6Fvknh70WrF1V9GvrRlg" hash="nGvQ8Q">“Not only was his robe exceedingly white, but his whole person was glorious beyond description, and his countenance [was] truly like lightning. The room was exceedingly light, but not so very bright as immediately around his person. When I first looked upon him, I was afraid; but the fear soon left me.” [<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.30-32" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:30–32</a>]</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="iHtoU7coGUWKF1e5uDA7iA" hash="Wzybjg">In the conversation that ensued, Moroni instructed Joseph Smith regarding valuable records he had deposited in the earth fourteen centuries before. Among other things, he quoted from the book of Malachi, with some deviation as follows:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="3TAI-hOuS0aMjUg4enXr-g" hash="Yh471Q">“Behold, I will reveal unto you the Priesthood, by the hand of Elijah the prophet, before the coming of the great and dreadful day of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="2gSmFOqFb0WfG-o5Ohoozw" hash="sgO5pw">“… And he shall plant in the hearts of the children the promises made to the fathers, and the hearts of the children shall turn to their fathers. If it were not so, the whole earth would be utterly wasted at his coming.” [<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.38-39" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:38–39</a>]</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="Yx7jgH1HQE6o6pTxiYyiXA" hash="q6gW7g">How could the gravity of this important message be more dramatically emphasized? We should not dismiss it lightly. It places upon our shoulders a sacred responsibility.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="lRa-0oyMuk2bQ-Gl6y29cQ" hash="Y3vLSQ">On 3 April 1836, Joseph Smith and Oliver Cowdery had a most glorious manifestation in the Kirtland Temple. The resurrected Christ appeared before them. Joseph Smith’s description of the Savior on that occasion is one of the most precious of our scriptures (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/110.2-3" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 110:2–3</a>). Then Moses appeared and committed to them the keys of the gathering of Israel; then Elias, who committed the dispensation of the gospel; and finally, the prophet Elijah, who announced:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="zcn6OHXc60CDetdLyME9Ew" hash="9k5UGQ">“The time has fully come, which was spoken of by the mouth of Malachi—testifying that he [Elijah] should be sent, before the great and dreadful day of the Lord come—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="_yWOkIwqqEe0M-cV2GhE0g" hash="leKHCA">“To turn the hearts of the fathers to the children, and the children to the fathers, lest the whole earth be smitten with a curse” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/110.14-15" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 110:14–15</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="ZHqC881Kq0yRPG702JwAVA" hash="ZYgheQ">What glorious experiences these must have been as those of ancient days appeared and committed the keys necessary to accomplish the work of salvation in these latter days.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="XgV3W_kQgU-sqe2RPl467A" hash="-aOpQA">From that day to this, the Saints, whenever circumstances permitted, and even when they didn’t, have built temples, searched out their ancestors, prepared a genealogical record, and performed the necessary saving ordinances for their own salvation and that of their progenitors. This is the turning of the hearts of the children to the fathers, about which both Elijah and Malachi spoke.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="-HI6TxcRr0e-0igYyybeyw" hash="gpDCZA">We have been given the responsibility by the Lord to do this work for all those who have passed on. Laws of privacy are such that we presently do temple work only for those who died beyond ninety-five years ago, except at the initiation of family members.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="Fja4X-AFpEeCTmerPjuFVw" hash="SdUA1A">We estimate that there are available written records existing of the names and vital statistics of about 6 billion persons who died before <small>A.D.</small> 1900. Nearly all of those names are for people who lived between <small>A.D.</small> 1200 and 1900. Of these, we have microfilmed the records of about 1 billion and have completed the temple work for about 57 million. We estimate that there are 2.5 billion records of individuals available to acquire at this time, and another 2.5 billion that we anticipate will become available as the doors to other nations open to us. We are currently microfilming and storing in our vault 100 million additional names each year. Considering the value and perishability of these records, this is a great service not only to the Church but to the entire world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="piTRYsPXAUKkSU7SBqsnAw" hash="WdUbQA">For many years we relied mainly upon family and individual genealogical research for obtaining names for proxy temple work. Beyond a few close generations, gathering names by family genealogical research is slow and inefficient. For example, in a recent presentation, Elder J. Thomas Fyans estimated that he has as many as 348 third cousins who have the same second-great-grandfather (see <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1978, p. 28). If each were to be searching for information on that same person, there would be untold duplication of effort.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="eLxlxZsmakKbM1DXt7wVTQ" hash="PD6cEA">We commend you, and all of those who have gone before, who have so diligently researched your ancestry. Your effort, your faith, and your diligence have established a solid foundation for this work to proceed. You have earned the reputation for the city in which our Church is headquartered as being the genealogical center of the world. This reputation you have built has opened doors for the work to expand that may have otherwise remained closed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="vQKtQgthRkqxdy0Hxrk-_w" hash="3gUorQ">It is unlikely that we can accomplish the temple work that must be done if we continue to rely upon individual research alone. In recent years we have moved into the computer age. New technology is progressing rapidly. The time has come for us to take advantage of this remarkable mechanism which the Lord has made available to us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="UjBE0CROVU-PbWI0s6AL3w" hash="jLwuDg">Last year we announced the name extraction program. Stakes have set up units to extract names for use in the temples from microfilm furnished from our storage vaults. The progress has been gratifying. We are optimistic that improving technology will result in a further reduction of unit cost and effort to enable us to accomplish even more.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="Ijqa7TPWz0Cp4Z7Lrpe7gg" hash="G42p6Q">Members have inquired as to what their role is <span class="emphasis">now</span> in fulfilling this charge given to us by the Lord through his prophets. Our answer is—</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.f1"><ol class="number" guid="224c7b5e-4077-44f0-952d-05781233a4ee"><li guid="0be66a95-18f0-42df-8373-356ee3b69af5" pid="Qc9hFKqGNkq9vWDmDntzXQ" hash="ZTPY2A">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p guid="b83faaf6-97a6-48a8-a57a-9a5f9b3593a3" pid="9S0NSgro2Um-HzQoVF6_QA" hash="AQ2GYA">Complete your four-generation family group records and pedigree chart. Compare your records with those of your brothers and sisters to confirm accuracy. Then, just one of you forward one set of sheets, listing all brothers and sisters on the first line, to the Genealogical Department commencing 1 July 1979, and concluding 1 July 1981.</p>
        </li><li guid="448d93ac-53bc-4997-b44a-6ed7772a1d49" pid="URCD0Gb05USRy9nIhNQDJQ" hash="yv78bw">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p guid="47efe5b1-da54-4c70-8646-cb307dcd58f8" pid="gZdKudnaLU6T0_Ln51fXOw" hash="nwyHMA">Perform temple ordinances regularly.</p>
        </li><li guid="ab61d81f-493e-4753-8fb1-0a92d6b738bc" pid="kvMHJuqzd0ycD5mXsmq84w" hash="KPHoOA">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p guid="61c14aab-5682-4978-8f38-3a9ff4c98fa8" pid="2ZMmD2QeaU6-JNqQQv5AOg" hash="j8BpcA">Participate in your stake name extraction program when invited to do so.</p>
          <p guid="50907fe8-e24d-4687-a067-530b74fc00cb" pid="0XpecmFS0USROyhMsVf76A" hash="dbT5wA">Now, there is one more to which we must give more attention than we have in the past:</p>
        </li><li guid="d7e0d39d-c5ea-4aa1-a24e-912bebd7988f" pid="fxvKLOueVESxAGjDLoOTzQ" hash="1aT7TA">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p guid="015a338d-9696-4834-9470-3ea469984f92" pid="7YX88UG02kKS3dD_aEdrpA" hash="H_w9bg">Write personal and family histories.</p>
        </li></ol></div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="9nuueaBVBka4IiFBRxBzxw" hash="ZW8b8A">The televising of the film series “Roots,” and more recently “Roots II,” has stirred an interest in personal and family histories that the experts believe is here to stay. One of the major television networks recently expressed this belief and with our cooperation has filmed a documentary on this subject. In 1980, our World Conference on Records will be oriented toward the writing of personal and family histories. This will give members of the Church and others the opportunity of learning how it can be done from experts the world over.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="s8g3WePsOUqZwdKaxtyc_w" hash="iPBikQ">Have you ever dreamed of belonging to a royal family? A royal family has the authority to be such—received from one who has a right to bestow such an honor. You likely have a person holding such a dignified honor right in your own home. The Apostle Peter, addressing the Saints of his day, said, “Ye are a chosen generation, a royal priesthood, an holy nation, a peculiar people” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-pet/2.9" class="scriptureRef">1 Pet. 2:9</a>). Don’t you have this same royal priesthood in your home?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="FR2glEmwHEObhdrqPYW0pg" hash="oC7OyA">A royal family is a family whose members are honest, true, chaste, benevolent, virtuous, temperate, patient, charitable, humble, diligent, well read, and law-abiding. The Lord has cautioned, “But I have commanded you to bring up your children in light and truth” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/93.40" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 93:40</a>). He also instructed us, “And they shall … teach their children to pray, and to walk uprightly before the Lord” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.28" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:28</a>). He further said, “Seek ye out of the best books words of wisdom; seek learning, even by study and also by faith” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.118" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:118</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="0QqXbsulvEmkPB60DoVGSg" hash="dbwKmg">A royal family is a family of well-disciplined parents and children who control their appetites. The Lord promises those who do so, “And all saints who remember to keep and do these sayings, walking in obedience to the commandments, … shall find wisdom and great treasures of knowledge, even hidden treasures” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/89.18-19" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 89:18–19</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="AlUWR83lvUupaIIQqaUndg" hash="nGECPw">A royal family is a family that is exemplary. They set a pattern for other families to follow. The Savior said, speaking to his faithful followers:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="3M-wQ9rlgka5xtfM7DG_Zw" hash="UUOWCg">“Ye are the light of the world. A city that is set on an hill cannot be hid.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="Y-lsvT91P0y7KH7A5ZLjEQ" hash="r1g2lQ">“Neither do men light a candle, and put it under a bushel, but on a candlestick; and it giveth light unto all that are in the house.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="Urs5KXgjj0m6lei-47lZWQ" hash="5DPUGQ">“Let your light so shine before men, that they may see your good works, and glorify your Father which is in heaven.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.14-16" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:14–16</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="6oxms0oVdUejqsH9zKCmvQ" hash="i4kGKA">A royal family is a family that has a heritage. Many of our Church families have a pioneer heritage. There are many other kinds of heritages inherited by other families of the Church of which they can be duly proud. In our society a heritage is best perpetuated by a family history. Family histories should be kept up to date by succeeding generations. In addition, each member of the family should keep a daily journal, and from that he can prepare a personal history. President Kimball kept a personal journal, and from that was written a personal history that has made a valuable contribution to the literature of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="_1_HIv4TZU2fsu-vVmLO5Q" hash="_b5IUg">A personal history becomes a family treasure that enables children to emulate the virtues and personal characteristics of their forebears. Their forefathers become the David, the Samson, the Moses, and the Abraham of their lineage. Writing family and personal histories is becoming the popular thing to do. More and more people throughout the world are becoming interested in this exciting pastime to them, but sacred responsibility to us. The hearts of the children are indeed turning to the fathers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families.p" pid="zCUyxHVm1UWjhAyxablDGQ" hash="z1m4Hg">A royal family is not necessarily confined to the political kingdoms ruling the nations of the world. You too can belong to a royal family. If you have not already done those things that will make it so, start today, so that coming generations in your family will be faithful to those principles which characterize royalty in the kingdom of God. The self-discipline you exercise will enrich your life and the lives of your family members. That you may build this enrichment into your family to be perpetuated for generations to come, that we, indeed, may be a chosen people, a royal priesthood—yes, a royal family in the kingdom of God—so that the world will not be wasted at his coming, I pray. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div><div class="resources">
    <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26a2.jpg" alt="Elder Royden G. Derrick" guid="fabd4051-b5b3-4af7-99c8-5b270a1e6ac9" pid="SbN5ZOQcHUuc4t_kK1UCGQ" hash="IA4zgQ1" />
    <unknown name="digitalAssets" guid="">
      <unknown name="assetGroup" guid="">
        <unknown name="path" guid="fabd4051-b5b3-4af7-99c8-5b270a1e6ac9"></unknown>
      </unknown>
    </unknown>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1979/04/the-heritage-of-royal-families</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1979-general-conference/1979-04-2060-elder-royden-g-derrick-64k-eng.mp3" length="13132581" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 1979 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moral Values and Rewards</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The history of the people of ancient America, recorded in the Book of Mormon, teaches that civilizations are built on moral foundations; that when people are morally strong, they do well; that when they are morally weak, they suffer. It teaches us th</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03135_000_029" doc-version="2" hash="IuWQbA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="fC8HKB14VUqsCj0qAYFxGg" hash="cIy5xQ">Moral Values and Rewards</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="9s7QbZwhiECgj8oFSQVNEg" hash="fJ9QkA">Royden G. Derrick</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26a2.jpg" alt="Elder Royden G. Derrick" pid="Pf3nk4Luq0Co10_oRIDicg" hash="IA4zgQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p1" pid="uJyr0uDwA0KiJnGsAotKOQ" hash="ARAGwQ">The history of the people of ancient America, recorded in the Book of Mormon, teaches that civilizations are built on moral foundations; that when people are morally strong, they do well; that when they are morally weak, they suffer. It teaches us that freedom cannot outlive morality and that freedom is not free—it must be earned.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p2" pid="aDBvsGSl40qop6n_Z9XfPw" hash="FMyVLQ">It teaches that people change again and again, but that mandates from God never change. They remain the same because the fundamental principles of good behavior are everlasting and never change. The Lord has given us direction through the scriptures as to how we should behave to enrich our lives, to bring peace to our souls, to strengthen our families, and to uplift the dignity of men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p3" pid="PQhu83VO90uUUtnhFlw9mg" hash="4E7Afg">The Lord said, “Wherefore, hear my voice and follow me, and you shall be a free people.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/38.22" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 38:22</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p4" pid="d32SEFXb0UyXmvwGVPe3Ng" hash="w3zc8w">During his ministry he said, “Know the truth, and the truth shall make you free.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/8.32" class="scriptureRef">John 8:32</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p5" pid="xT1glxWS2EWmmz2aqDhPCA" hash="QOrKfA">The Psalmist wrote, “Blessed is the nation whose God is the Lord.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/33.12" class="scriptureRef">Ps. 33:12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p6" pid="hOr5mMwr9U6sh8i4JJXtBA" hash="RfVfyw">From Ecclesiastes, “Fear God, and keep his commandments: for this is the whole duty of man.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/eccl/12.13" class="scriptureRef">Eccl. 12:13</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p7" pid="lLkxFIWsiUWkt4xjE9jgNw" hash="wFWALA">The Savior said, “For whatsoever ye sow, that shall ye also reap.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/6.33" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 6:33</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p8" pid="YYlvmP9HLkOmoXdETUKk7Q" hash="Gk64uQ">And from latter-day scripture we learn, “There is a law, irrevocably decreed in heaven before the foundations of this world, upon which all blessings are predicated—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p9" pid="r8aRtulMwk27CAuatp5-VA" hash="bhRL8g">“And when we obtain any blessing from God, it is by obedience to that law upon which it is predicated.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/130.20-21" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 130:20–21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p10" pid="mEGWYhdf5E2M_i9nA3GnaA" hash="MbOvYg">The basic unit of society is the family. Our moral values are established in our family relations. The responsibility for teaching moral principles rests with the home. But not every home offers the love and guidance necessary to responsible parenthood. In an ideal society, the home should accept the responsibility for teaching moral values.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p11" pid="T0ZS1Syth06IU1jcUGWxpQ" hash="3TYOHA">The Lord said, “But I have commanded you to bring up your children in light and truth.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/93.40" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 93:40</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p12" pid="EuvZpGZ4SUWvpr6H6NZYlA" hash="Tw8XOA">And again, “And they shall also teach their children to pray, and to walk uprightly before the Lord.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.28" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:28</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p13" pid="wTr_odvomUG5YC041btbeg" hash="X-EvUw">The teachers in church and in school should be allies of the parents in teaching children appropriate values that will guide them throughout their lives. The home should be a laboratory of learning, where these values, and more sensitive ones too, are inculcated into the lives of family members through daily experiences. Then the three work in harmony to fulfill parental responsibility.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p14" pid="JEaZZuZ6Dkypn_ZCj-59OA" hash="Ki5YAw">Unfortunately, today many societies in the world do not place sufficient importance upon the home and the family. In a recent edition of <span class="emphasis">U.S. News and World Report,</span> an article was published quoting statistics that show an alarming decay among the families of America. Problems that cause such serious erosion are centered around moral issues and selfishness. Strong families result when family members serve one another. When we concentrate on our own comfort and on satisfying our own appetites, the family and the society are adversely affected.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p15" pid="5b3pbaetKkOuFgEnl4s6SA" hash="BMUXiA">We spend our time doing many things, some of which have influence on this life only, and others, on both here and beyond. Building a family is an eternal objective. The benefits of family unity can extend beyond our mortal existence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p16" pid="vIbXQdM0vkKoq6wRaV1EbQ" hash="csldfg">Several weeks ago, while en route to Monterrey, Mexico, I sat next to an attractive Mexican of Lamanite extraction. During our conversation I learned that he had eight children. He was obviously proud to be their father. I encouraged him to talk about them. Then I asked, “How long do you plan to be with them?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p17" pid="bfvt_QKF-ku2wAQ2lxVyfQ" hash="Ibzavg">“As long as I live.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p18" pid="ZE_j9yWvBEmUf5GNMndfFw" hash="3ZHecg">“And then what?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p19" pid="cqaF7ty_3ked_jSg6zpxAQ" hash="HCezlA">“I’ll lie down and turn to dust.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p20" pid="qDztvalFP0iXfalgY4Vdmg" hash="CToxeA">From the Bible, we read the words of the Savior to his Apostles just prior to his crucifixion: “In my Father’s house are many mansions: if it were not so, I would have told you. I go to prepare a place for you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p21" pid="vHCsY3k80Ui8vE4pJv5Y6g" hash="0YLyxA">“And if I go and prepare a place for you, I will come again, and receive you unto myself; that where I am, there ye may be also.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.2-3" class="scriptureRef">John 14:2–3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p22" pid="r6w8XBylSEStAeFvG0RCOQ" hash="RDgK9A">I asked him what Jesus meant by that. He pondered the question, and then he was ready to listen. I explained about the spirit world and the Resurrection and asked, “Do you <span class="emphasis">really</span> love your children?” He was emphatic.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p23" pid="w9_4eTS2fE606AEUwiHnQw" hash="psmVMw">“How would you like to be with your wife and children in the next life?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p24" pid="kB9nAz21CEOJrfp_mv2Obg" hash="TJtcSA">“There is nothing I would rather have.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p25" pid="CGTa4774sEyBDgeseVNWoQ" hash="sZ9weA">I explained that he could have them. We talked about the Book of Mormon—that it was a history of his progenitors, that it contained the narration of the visit of Jesus Christ to America, and that it was a key to having an eternal family. I had him write his name and address on a card and promised to have a Book of Mormon in Spanish delivered to his home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p26" pid="OxabNryWak-dMZiY8syRuQ" hash="afO4Ag">When I arrived in Monterrey, I gave the referral to the missionaries. Last week I received a letter reporting on their visit to the family. They wrote: “The following Sunday, after the conference, we went to Roberto’s home. His wife came to the fence, and supposing we were preachers of religion she told us it would not be possible to see her husband, that he was very busy. But after talking and showing the card you gave us, he quickly came out with open arms to greet us. We entered his home and knelt down with the family in prayer. He has eight beautiful children. The Spirit of the Lord was present.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p27" pid="wuAU_OalP06GmSdHaMUH9Q" hash="hKYGjA">“He gratefully accepted our offer to return to teach them the plan of salvation. He received the Book of Mormon and promised to read the words of the book from cover to cover.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p28" pid="6dvVgwF2NEes2SQvlc0tjw" hash="VA-WyQ">How could any thinking person who loves his family not want such a precious gift—to be with his wife and his family in this life and the next, and then to include parents and other progenitors (going back) and grandchildren and their continuing posterity (going forward) in an eternal family relationship.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p29" pid="_EG630kWR0GrANfz5hImng" hash="fK6vlQ">The scriptures say, “All covenants, contracts, bonds, obligations, oaths, vows, performances, connections, associations, or expectations, that are not made and entered into and sealed by the Holy Spirit of promise, … by revelation and commandment through the medium of mine anointed, whom I have appointed on the earth to hold this power … are of no efficacy, virtue, or force in and after the resurrection from the dead; for all contracts that are not made unto this end have an end when men are dead.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/132.7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 132:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p30" pid="wXDlBbBol0i3yMJ_gYSaoQ" hash="l4GcTw">I testify that the authority from God to seal by the Holy Spirit of Promise for time and all eternity is vested in our prophet, Spencer W. Kimball. He has properly delegated that authority today so that this sacred work of sealing families for time and all eternity goes forward daily in the holy temples of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p31" pid="nSNKXaYhDEaedfB8TKrMTg" hash="DTMZ1w">How I wish that my friends who are not in the Church would listen to this important message—that you can be with your families forever. All you have to do to qualify is to keep the commandments of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p32" pid="X2bnmJ487kar80IPVQi_og" hash="v89I3A">The scriptures tell us, “And the spirit and the body are the soul of man.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.15" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:15</a>.) When a man dies, his body goes to the grave and his spirit goes to a place of waiting. We call that place paradise.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p33" pid="FembeutBuEGTp1fJkKpGBQ" hash="o5zKkA">President Joseph F. Smith was privileged to look into the spirit world back to the time of the advent of the Savior into that great world of the spirits of the dead about the time of the Crucifixion: “And I saw the hosts of the dead, both small and great,” he wrote.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p34" pid="lD2yjCm7802Kgx9ApD5K6g" hash="4F35Og">“And there were gathered together in one place an innumerable company of the spirits of the just, who had been faithful in the testimony of Jesus while they lived in mortality. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p35" pid="PjG4im1iQE6ZAa3I5bvY5w" hash="B7Sjrw">“All these had departed the mortal life, firm in the hope of a glorious resurrection, through the grace of God the Father and his Only Begotten Son, Jesus Christ. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p36" pid="Iqhd4bftMUe8JzM1VQrcRA" hash="hYA4Aw">“While this vast multitude waited and conversed, rejoicing in the hour of their deliverance from the chains of death, the Son of God appeared, declaring liberty to the captives who had been faithful. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p37" pid="YWJc5kk4LUK7_Tunv6P-Lg" hash="xwN8HQ">“But unto the wicked he did not go, and among the ungodly and the unrepentant who had defiled themselves while in the flesh, his voice was not raised. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p38" pid="S5x8TbIKKUmHu5zneYtTSw" hash="SxqP-w">“But behold, from among the righteous, he organized his forces and appointed messengers, clothed with power and authority, and commissioned them to go forth and carry the light of the gospel to them that were in darkness, even to all the spirits of men; and thus was the gospel preached to the dead.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p39" pid="RYsJ9JzF80qPSzknkXoo2g" hash="LpprpQ">“And the chosen messengers went forth to declare the acceptable day of the Lord and proclaim liberty to the captives who were bound, even unto all who would repent of their sins and receive the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p40" pid="nW89jaEIiUu9t8qdd_ZiBg" hash="zSrWPA">“Thus was the gospel preached to those who had died in their sins, without a knowledge of the truth, or in transgression, having rejected the prophets.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/138.11-12,14,18,20,30-32" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 138:11–12, 14, 18, 20, 30–32</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p41" pid="d56fdRQuQUmqVWhiTVgQqw" hash="Gzx1MQ">Today, too, there are spirits awaiting their day of deliverance and resurrection. “Faithful elders of this dispensation, when they depart from mortal life, continue their labors in the preaching of the gospel of repentance and redemption, through the sacrifice of the Only Begotten Son of God, among those who are in darkness and under the bondage of sin in the great world of the spirits of the dead.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p42" pid="723JdboxgEKKf30-lG3Mlw" hash="K1G_WQ">“The dead who repent will be redeemed, through obedience to the ordinances of the house of God,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p43" pid="xzhW1HNW9k6iJknBT9LbYA" hash="U6qIEg">“And after they have paid the penalty of their transgressions, and are washed clean, shall receive a reward according to their works, for they are heirs of salvation.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/138.57-59" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 138:57–59</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p44" pid="8sUrMlE3EUm0cPlE4xiBPQ" hash="Gbpn5Q">One of the major missions of the Church is to uniquely identify these individuals who have died and perform the necessary saving ordinances in their behalf, for they cannot do it for themselves. Once these ordinances are performed, if the individual accepts the gospel in the great world of spirits, then this work will be effective.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p45" pid="kmqX2uGsDUGKYEBSXcVBnA" hash="M7Oicg">One of the ordinances performed in the temples of the Lord is the sealing of wives to husbands and the sealing of children to parents for the living and by proxy for the dead, thus uniting families for the eternities according to their willingness to conform to gospel principles.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards.p46" pid="X-RUBrbTaUSgoE-XcsmVEA" hash="-pVWOQ">And so, when members of a society serve the Lord according to the commandments he has given them, and uphold proper moral values, they receive very special rewards both in this life and in the life to come. This is not man’s program; it is the Lord’s program of salvation, which exalts and brings freedom, in every sense of the word, to those who will hear his voice and follow him, to which I testify in the name of him who gave his life that these things might be, even the Lord, Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1981/04/moral-values-and-rewards</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1981-general-conference/1981-04-5020-elder-royden-g-derrick-64k-eng.mp3" length="6939263" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 1981 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Valiance in the Drama of Life</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life?lang=eng</link>
      <description>William Shakespeare was insightful when he wrote: “All the world’s a stage, and all the men and women merely players.” ( act 2, sc. 7, line 139.) Let me set the stage for a drama that is not fiction, but is reality. The drama is founded upon certain </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03161_000_012" doc-version="2" hash="GiUc1g">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="RPEltZeMVkuPs9Jv-Tzpew" hash="06FxaA">Valiance in the Drama of Life</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Q7GKsoAytEav2cnS_3zHUw" hash="fJ9QkA">Royden G. Derrick</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26a2.jpg" alt="Elder Royden G. Derrick" pid="BcUy2r1xEUS37Q8OZzI8Hw" hash="IA4zgQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p1" pid="pzATGqJKK0Gk7I3nRmhAiQ" hash="vMcIxg">William Shakespeare was insightful when he wrote: “All the world’s a stage, and all the men and women merely players.” (<span class="emphasis">As You Like It,</span> act 2, sc. 7, line 139.) Let me set the stage for a drama that is not fiction, but is reality. The drama is founded upon certain facts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p2" pid="16x46df_0Eihr_iAigFNaQ" hash="jiv7lg">It is a fact that God lives. It is a fact that Jesus Christ was and is a divine being. It is a fact that the Father and the Son appeared to Joseph Smith in the Sacred Grove. It is a fact that Joseph Smith was a prophet of God. It is a fact that God revealed his will through his prophets in biblical days, and that he does so today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p3" pid="VAwiNG02S0--gmiCLCuB_w" hash="lBt4FA">The script for this drama was written before the world began. The script writer has revealed clues about future scenes to individuals who have shared them with all who would listen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p4" pid="xoMqDgWO5E6aFowMKi6igg" hash="QJFpPw">For example, twenty-six hundred years ago, one of the important characters in the drama was shown some scenes of “what shall be in the latter days.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/dan/2.28" class="scriptureRef">Dan. 2:28</a>.) Daniel the prophet was shown the interpretation of King Nebuchadnezzar’s dream, from which he related, “And in the days of these kings,” referring to the latter-day scenes, “shall the God of heaven set up a kingdom, which shall never be destroyed: and the kingdom shall not be left to other people, but it shall break in pieces and consume all these kingdoms, and it shall stand for ever.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/dan/2.44" class="scriptureRef">Dan. 2:44</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p5" pid="sLqTHZ9ZQ0Ou7_dbsJu-OQ" hash="ClcMkg">The scenes relating to these clues are now on stage, front-center.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p6" pid="U34ZDSJaO0S_Z8A1ZUbWuQ" hash="wVS1Zg">At fourteen and one-half years of age, Joseph Smith went into the woods and prayed to our Heavenly Father, wanting to know which church of all the churches was true. There appeared before him God the Father and his Son Jesus Christ. The Father said, <span class="emphasis">“This is My Beloved Son. Hear Him!”</span> (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.17" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:17</a>.) Then Jesus Christ told that fourteen-year-old boy that the true church of God was not on the earth, and that he had been selected to be an instrument in the hands of God in restoring the church of Jesus Christ and the true principles of Jesus Christ. In the scenes following, “the God of heaven set up a kingdom” about which Daniel the prophet said, “[it] shall never be destroyed.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p7" pid="up3jTdXwCEG1v7zF5qNiwg" hash="WYGOzw">Joseph Smith permitted manuscript pages of the translation of the Book of Mormon to fall into the hands of others, and they were lost. This was displeasing to the Lord, who said to him, “The works, and the designs, and the purposes of God cannot be frustrated, neither can they come to naught.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/3.1" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 3:1</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p8" pid="CVvq644kMkqjWTzbDOLXDQ" hash="QSu2hg">“Remember … that it is not the work of God that is frustrated, but the work of men.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/3.3" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 3:3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p9" pid="XZuSlPYbIkCXI0p6I_WMqg" hash="KwlVLg">“Behold, thou art Joseph, and thou wast chosen to do the work of the Lord, but because of transgression, if thou art not aware thou wilt fall.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/3.9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 3:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p10" pid="0tYPmvqPHE-atjhDO4rg_w" hash="nwnmfQ">Had Joseph not measured up, the Lord would have made a change in the cast by appointing another to take his place. But he did measure up, as attested by further revelations from God which commended him for his faithfulness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p11" pid="luRbz3F25UKrRSJSnydtpw" hash="9D1Htw">The Lord said that this kingdom, which would be established in the latter days, “shall never be destroyed.” We needn’t question whether this church that God has set up is going to fail. It will not! For God has so decreed!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p12" pid="vBZ9NumSI0q7DwseiwBCRw" hash="sppUew">Daniel further prophesied that “the kingdom shall not be left to other people.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/dan/2.44" class="scriptureRef">Dan. 2:44</a>.) We cannot join any ecumenical movement, for if we do so, we will be required to compromise principles. We cannot do that, for the Lord has established the principles upon which his church is built, and we have no right to change them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p13" pid="W6l-qKBzIUq9Rub2JFqX-g" hash="oNWvcg">Eighteen months after the Church was organized, and following heavenly visitations during which the authority to act in the name of God was given to Joseph Smith, the Lord declared that “The keys of the kingdom of God are committed unto man on the earth,” and that the kingdom “shall roll forth, until it has filled the whole earth.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/65.2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 65:2</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p14" pid="RASi8PF60EKXP651NY_GCA" hash="S09rig">Clues to other scenes in the drama have been given to other prophets such as Isaiah, Jeremiah, Ezekiel, and John the Revelator, as well as others from biblical history; and Nephi, Alma, Helaman, Mormon, Moroni, and others from Book of Mormon history.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p15" pid="h_Ih_xGSjUuLx2GrAOUH3Q" hash="FwKhnQ">The star of the cast is Jesus Christ, the Savior of mankind. Many events in his life were the fulfillment of scenes previously shown to former-day prophets. Tomorrow, we commemorate the most important scene of all—the resurrection of Jesus Christ, who suffered and died to atone for the sins of men and women.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p16" pid="OAxxagYjV0GBTUGdE9Ht0Q" hash="BnBEPQ">The number of people in the cast is unlimited. “If ye have desires to serve God,” the Lord said, “ye are called to the work.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/4.3" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 4:3</a>.) To pass the screen test, one must repent, be baptized, and keep God’s commandments. Anyone is welcome to participate, for the prophet Nephi said, “He inviteth them all to come unto him and partake of his goodness; and he denieth none that come unto him, black and white, bond and free, male and female; and he remembereth the heathen; and all are alike unto God, both Jew and Gentile.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/26.33" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 26:33</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p17" pid="JWEbxHs_4UeyrL9SJCTN7A" hash="PDse0w">The acceptance of the gospel of Jesus Christ is affected by attitude. William James, a famous author and psychologist, wrote, “The greatest discovery of my age is that men can change their circumstances by changing the attitude of their minds.” (Richard L. Evans, <span class="emphasis">Richard Evans’ Quote Book</span> [Salt Lake City: Publishers Press, 1971], p. 161.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p18" pid="fF-iIXiRck2oy_3VdkVv5g" hash="l0B55w">In the book of Proverbs we read, “For as he thinketh in his heart, so is he.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/23.7" class="scriptureRef">Prov. 23:7</a>.) Henry David Thoreau sustained that concept when he said that a man becomes what he thinks about all day long. (See <span class="emphasis">Familiar Quotations,</span> ed. John Bartlett, 14th ed., Boston: Little, Brown and Co., 1968, p. 682.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p19" pid="K2VbtpteLk-lsZRL0T35pA" hash="rcAR3w">We have our agency. It is the decision of each of us as to the character we play in this drama—as to what kind of person we are or will become.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p20" pid="kxC_Oc5Ff0evMYway2itIw" hash="X2AoYA">When President David O. McKay was a young missionary in Scotland, he was homesick, discouraged, and low in spirit. As he walked down the street with his companion, he noticed an inscription chiseled in a stone lintel of an unfinished building which read, “Whate’er Thou Art, Act Well Thy Part.” From that moment, he began to act the part of a good missionary and became a great one. This was a learning experience that helped him in numerous important callings he received later in life. (See <span class="emphasis">Cherished Experiences from the Writings of President David O. McKay,</span> comp. Clare Middlemiss, Salt Lake City: Deseret Book, 1955, p. 174.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p21" pid="8T4ntp2RFEW8SX9chyn91Q" hash="1K6r6Q">If we want to be a person of integrity, we act as if we have integrity and we will be a person of integrity. If we want to be a person of charity and love, we act as if we have that characteristic and we will be that person.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p22" pid="9mXdS4hGbUS6qWY6a2CC9A" hash="uo8NZA">The Savior alluded to this principle when he asked, “What manner of men ought ye to be?” Then he answered his own question, “Even as I am.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/27.27" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 27:27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p23" pid="TPGHGuKWJkWcgSIQ6v2cBg" hash="w1R6aQ">We should strive to become like him by acting as he would act.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p24" pid="0g_5n5nog0-IqHJDYM-HqA" hash="yOQnZA">God does not select the type of life we live. We make that selection by what we think. If you want to play the part, just act the part. What role are you playing now? Are you a valiant supporter? Are you a half-hearted member lacking conviction? Are you a bystander? Or are you one who fights against the Church of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p25" pid="5-FhCnR69EWJFZFc38UcIA" hash="EsFRow">There is a reward for valiancy in this drama of life. The Savior said, “And … you shall have eternal life, which gift is the greatest of all the gifts of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/14.7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 14:7</a>.) It is difficult to conceive of eternal life being a place of joy and happiness without those we love in this life. Based upon our valiance, our future life will include our wife or husband, our children, our parents—yes, our posterity as well as our progenitors.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p26" pid="oXBCybXql0yFJuJtoqC51w" hash="zlfv-w">What can I do for my children to help them qualify for eternal life? Several years ago, the Missionary Department made a professional survey to determine what happens to returned missionaries. The survey included those missionaries who had returned from one to ten years previous and was claimed to be accurate within 3 percent. It disclosed that their faithfulness was most exemplary and praiseworthy. It was a revealing report that was much more favorable than one could expect.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p27" pid="ozkhltzY4kejH-wd5t2DnA" hash="cYHxDQ">A few weeks ago, I visited a stake consisting of young families. I asked the priesthood leaders how many of them had filled a mission. I was surprised when every man raised his hand. The next week I visited a more mature stake which was one of the outstanding stakes of the Church, and asked the same question. Every man in the meeting, but two, raised his hand.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p28" pid="13FbDWebTECjqSpnFh5Pjw" hash="t5afSQ">The conclusion? Not that every man has to be a returned missionary to be a priesthood leader, but that those who fulfill an honorable mission develop an understanding of the gospel and a self-discipline that results in dedication and commitment to what they know to be true.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p29" pid="tKr0CJj1AkS2P5U-NDihhg" hash="GYodNg">We should organize our family plans to result in a mission for each of our sons, and temple marriage for each of our sons and daughters. Planning missions for our sons might begin at birth when we start their own missionary savings program which will assist significantly in their being financially, morally, physically, and mentally prepared when they reach mission age. However, we should, above all else, teach our children “to pray, and to walk uprightly before the Lord.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/68.28" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 68:28</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p30" pid="Lo0lZieBg0KLtw04Zi2yVQ" hash="yYUwkg">What can I do for my progenitors to help them qualify for eternal life? I can help my parents and grandparents to understand the gospel, to be baptized, and to receive these saving ordinances in the temple of God. I can make certain that my deceased parents, grandparents, great-grandparents, and as far as I can go in my genealogical research, have received in person or vicariously the temple saving ordinances necessary for them to gain eternal life. By doing these things for our posterity and for our progenitors, a forever family can be established, resulting in a dynasty of righteous lives that will bring joy and happiness “in this world, and eternal life in the world to come, even immortal glory.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/6.59" class="scriptureRef">Moses 6:59</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life.p31" pid="p6ryeJcJfkaF7TeSapa-2A" hash="6798AQ">The final scene of this great drama is near at hand. The kingdom of God is going forth preparatory to the second coming of Christ when the curtain will fall and the Savior will say to each of the valiant, “Well done, thou good and faithful servant: thou hast been faithful over a few things, I will make thee ruler over many things: enter thou into the joy of thy lord.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/25.21" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 25:21</a>.) And thus the kingdom of God will continue forever through the eternities to come. As the prophet Daniel said, “And it shall stand for ever” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/dan/2.44" class="scriptureRef">Dan. 2:44</a>), with you and I having received judgment and reward according to the role to which we have been faithful in this life—to which I testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1983/04/valiance-in-the-drama-of-life</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1983-general-conference/1983-04-2040-elder-royden-g-derrick-64k-eng.mp3" length="6469728" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 1983 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“By Their Fruits Ye Shall Know Them”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Our revered leader of years past, President David O. McKay, often said, “The mission of the Gospel of Jesus Christ [is] to make evil-minded men good and to make good men better.” ( Oct. 1961, p. 469.)</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03180_000_024" doc-version="2" hash="2Rowlg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="qIo8YcouAEWLGm0n3HRGYA" hash="hKmG7g">“By Their Fruits Ye Shall Know Them”</h1><p class="authorName" guid="f68d93a7-7965-447b-87ee-0c88052eb590" pid="uESh_-EMNEWO4juE5KSAkw" hash="fJ9QkA">Royden G. Derrick</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="a65a9c55-588d-4a6e-b3ee-232188f6b0e8">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26a2.jpg" alt="Elder Royden G. Derrick" guid="e87305c7-d243-4ce6-a8db-9c078880ffb5" pid="070w8TlfdE-mmR2TG27Axw" hash="IA4zgQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="A0tXk-W4yUq8nbVBDr3VHA" hash="_6yEtQ">Our revered leader of years past, President David O. McKay, often said, “The mission of the Gospel of Jesus Christ [is] to make evil-minded men good and to make good men better.” (<span class="emphasis">Millennial Star,</span> Oct. 1961, p. 469.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="Ub_Cerq5rEuy2UCvN2XSNQ" hash="UUV34w">The Lord said to the people of ancient America, “And whatsoever thing persuadeth men to do good is of me; for good cometh of none save it be of me. I am the same that leadeth men to all good.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/4.12" class="scriptureRef">Ether 4:12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="MbvL6EkwrEGiJJ-DrusXtg" hash="q0aMNw">To be good, one must seek after truth, for truth is the ingredient which, when inculcated into our lives, changes us for good. “Truth is knowledge of things as they are, and as they were, and as they are to come.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/93.24" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 93:24</a>.) “Truth abideth and hath no end.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.66" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:66</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="l0Nh-uxDgEiryjcX4AiMfg" hash="FZG2_A">Intelligence is the ability to use knowledge properly. The Lord has said, “The glory of God is intelligence, or, in other words, light and truth.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/93.36" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 93:36</a>.) The light of which this scripture speaks is the Light of Christ, for Jesus further said, “I am the true light that lighteth every man that cometh into the world.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/93.2" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 93:2</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="0GjW0ZXNbU20b0OzsTAlUg" hash="ThdVJQ">One of my earliest recollections happened when I was about four years of age. Several blocks from our home was a little wooden grocery store. In the front of the store windows the proprietor had built a ledge about four inches wide, where at this time of the year he placed big juicy apples to attract those passing by. As I walked by the front of the store, I saw those beautiful red apples, and my mouth began to water. Without realizing what I was doing, I took one and continued walking up the street.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="R2PXoP_DvEqF9RHprVzDbA" hash="P0p75w">When I got a short distance away, I looked at what I had in my hand and suddenly realized I had stolen an apple. I began to run but made the mistake of running the wrong way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="wkA2WaKIH0i-dg7gPivLcg" hash="--gXdA">On the downhill side of our front porch, there was latticework between the porch level and the ground level. A small door enabled us to store gardening tools under the porch and also gave us access to a convenient place to hide.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="Xmc25ssvIUynYfp2a9fkeA" hash="01IY9g">I ran all the way home, crawled under the porch, and sat there all afternoon shivering with fear—and eating the apple. I knew that I had done wrong, and I knew that my Heavenly Father knew that I had done wrong.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="YrmeJowce02uu3yPrZ6yIQ" hash="_B8cdQ">I have often reflected upon how I suffered from a remorse of conscience at such an early age. The Light of Christ, which lights every man that comes into the world, was evident that day, which in later years caused me to ponder about how the Light of Christ can influence our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="iormdpFpAU-nWoO0bJEaJQ" hash="wSxGsQ">Envision yourself standing on the banks of the River Jordan on a particular day nearly two thousand years ago and observing two men standing in the water. John the Baptist, clothed with camel’s hair and with a girdle of skin about his loins, is baptizing Jesus; and Jesus, dressed in the garb of the day, is coming up out of the water. The heavens open and a marvelous thing occurs. The Holy Ghost descends in the form of a dove and alights upon him. And a voice from heaven is heard saying, “This is my beloved Son, in whom I am well pleased.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/3.17" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 3:17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="Aw9ki_kkOEyOiMcrdbLVgQ" hash="2t2Vew">Envision yourself some time later in the temple in Jerusalem. The weather is hot outside; but inside, the thick stone walls give relief to a group gathered in discussion. It is Jesus talking to the scribes and the Pharisees:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="Ard-NvdP_EypO8G5OtZXUA" hash="EwakKQ">“I am the light of the world: he that followeth me shall not walk in darkness, but shall have the light of life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="Lcht1ictO02X5KUfSTLfLA" hash="zaO-9Q">“The Pharisees therefore said unto him, Thou bearest record of thyself; thy record is not true.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="CJwifdLgL0-L7l3P37tnxw" hash="plF4jQ">“Jesus answered and said unto them, Though I bear record of myself, yet my record is true: for I know whence I came, and whither I go; but ye cannot tell whence I come, and whither I go. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="cDBnBkJqmEG3YZZWk2LSKQ" hash="rbTTyg">“It is also written in your law, that the testimony of two men is true.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="9MwlwdYgLEq_w_XFss-GBA" hash="hVtlww">“I am one that bear witness of myself, and the Father that sent me beareth witness of me.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/8.12-14,17-18" class="scriptureRef">John 8:12–14, 17–18</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="8LrgdMkz7kKtP7zOWADdHg" hash="0B8h6Q">The testimony of the Father and the testimony of Jesus were not for the people of their day alone, but for men down through the ages. It was documented then—for us today—and is just as true today as it was two thousand years ago. The truths of the gospel of Jesus Christ have been restored to the earth through the Prophet Joseph Smith and are available to each of us for study.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="GBXYf7rK2kmSilkbr6KLBA" hash="t8P3FQ">In my limited experience in the fields of religion and education, it has been my observation that it takes as much intelligence for one to assimilate the principles of the gospel as it does for one to understand the complicated formulas of science. An understanding of the gospel is a quest and must be pursued through study, thought, and prayer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="FpQlfiU62Uukdnl0qn6TCQ" hash="fXyWpQ">Brigham Young taught: “All true wisdom that mankind have they have received from God, whether they know it or not. There is no ingenious mind that has ever invented anything beneficial to the human family but what he obtained it from that One Source. … There is only one source from whence men obtain wisdom, and that is God, the fountain of all wisdom; and though men may claim to make their discoveries by their own wisdom, by meditation and reflection, they are indebted to our Father in Heaven for all.” (<span class="emphasis">Journal of Discourses,</span> 13:148.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="dF9K_Aft1E2HawAARyoIIA" hash="eynmQg">To those who pursue and apply gospel principles, the Lord says, “And if your eye be single to my glory, your whole bodies shall be filled with light, and there shall be no darkness in you; and that body which is filled with light comprehendeth all things.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.67" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:67</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="stYanDE_JkyZB2JtVdQpSw" hash="AppdjQ">President Joseph F. Smith said: “[The] knowledge of truth, combined with proper regard for it, and its faithful observance, constitutes true education. The mere stuffing of the mind with a knowledge of facts is not education. The mind must not only possess a knowledge of truth, but the soul must revere it, cherish it, love it as a priceless gem; and this human life must be guided and shaped by it in order to fulfil its destiny.” (<span class="emphasis">Gospel Doctrine,</span> … ed., Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1939, p. 269.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="160Vq7ghlESVlLyjzwsTKA" hash="ajczEg">Of what value is truth unless it is assimilated into the minds and hearts of men? “Truth is the rock foundation of every great character,” wrote William George Jordan. “It is loyalty to the right as we see it; it is courageous living of our lives in harmony with our ideals.” (<span class="emphasis">The Power of Truth,</span> Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1943, p. 3.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="pOeuDUWSRUScRZcsA38DBg" hash="grZtKg">The Lord says:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="me65A-o_A0GRkMBYOpJYSQ" hash="ILyZQQ">“Whatever principle of intelligence we attain unto in this life, it will rise with us in the resurrection.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="jM29NBi1E0m4TVasbylDmA" hash="hDs01g">“And if a person gains more knowledge and intelligence in this life through his diligence and obedience than another, he will have so much the advantage in the world to come.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/130.18-19" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 130:18–19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="ViCyPk7zeEm9L2PPCkw4bQ" hash="hxiZng">He further said, “It is impossible for a man to be saved in ignorance.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/131.6" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 131:6</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="MKGZ6_EJ5Emdb6hdJu1fvg" hash="ykRc_g">Brigham Young asked the question, “When shall we cease to learn?” And then he answered his own question with the words, “Never, never.” (<span class="emphasis">Journal of Discourses,</span> 3:203.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="DQWwR3pIxkOnuCm-0Sx1xw" hash="nx4s4Q">We should not overlook the fact that some truths have little or nothing to do with our eternal salvation, while others are essential to it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="3FgOD33iEkSZGNOWNAmx_w" hash="S2dZIA">When one is loyal to the truth, we say he is a person of integrity. When one is loyal to the truth under intense opposition, we say he is a person of <span class="emphasis">great</span> integrity. Integrity is a quality or state of being of sound moral principle. Integrity is uprightness, honesty, and sincerity—yes, all that and even more.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="LzW8lCluxUCU9D4kNsfHVg" hash="Kb5oAw">Following the First Vision, the Prophet Joseph Smith was persecuted unmercifully for the rest of his life and died as a martyr at thirty-eight years of age; yet he never wavered in declaring what he knew to be the truth. He knew that if he denied what he had said, the persecution would cease; yet he stood firm. He recorded:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="lgjs6VaFO0i4FaF1qMSP3A" hash="0Rxq1Q">“I … [saw] a light, and in the midst of that light I saw two Personages, and they did in reality speak to me; and though I was hated and persecuted for saying that I had seen a vision, yet it was true; and while they were persecuting me, reviling me, and speaking all manner of evil against me falsely for so saying, I was led to say in my heart: Why persecute me for telling the truth? I have actually seen a vision; and who am I that I can withstand God, or why does the world think to make me deny what I have actually seen? For I had seen a vision; I knew it, and I knew that God knew it, and I could not deny it, neither dared I do it; at least I knew that by so doing I would offend God, and come under condemnation.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.25" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:25</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="kp2_hO7wokCtB3Ss2-hofA" hash="wKgNkA">To so react requires great integrity and also builds great integrity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="wqF2h7ki606beeJ1L5l9RA" hash="xFidIw">We revere Abraham Lincoln because of his commitment to a principle in which he strongly believed. And though the opposition was severe, the pathway filled with stumbling blocks, and the future dark and uncertain, he tenaciously held to what he believed to be right, prevailed in the cause, and eventually won the undying gratitude of a nation that was destined to become great. We have other such patriots in other lands throughout the world who are heralded as men of great integrity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="gZHXq_GkJE-sUOo_Ec5Blw" hash="1UuQig">Samuel Johnson made an interesting observation when he wrote: “Integrity without knowledge is weak and useless. … Knowledge without integrity is dangerous and dreadful.” (<span class="emphasis">Rasselas,</span> ch. 41.) Leaders in schools of elementary, secondary, and higher education know that the true success of their system is measured by the man it forms. Such is also true of families, politics, governments, and religion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="kHf_XbB5LEyXu85u1RxCAA" hash="B_hsZA">Many live by the motto that the end justifies the means. There are those who gain their possessions by deceit, bribery, and dishonest practices, then seek legitimacy by contributing freely to a righteous cause. Integrity cannot be compromised.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="35HL9DBMbUW2wCPq7MFzgw" hash="0-gsGw">Integrity is sustained by forethought and commitment. It was written of Helaman’s stripling warriors, “Yea, and they did obey and observe to perform every word of command with exactness.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/57.21" class="scriptureRef">Alma 57:21</a>.) They were fully committed to what they would do when they got into the heat of battle. Their efforts won them the crown of integrity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="ZDTZ-BOstUyk9GDqKyCFWg" hash="ZNUdFQ">Let us review our own lives to determine how each of us measures up in our own quest for integrity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="JDQRufTJskmLX67Opf-CfA" hash="qjm2hw">As an employee, are you committed to give at least forty hours work for forty hours pay?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="gaiQCmeoJkCET6PQMv4R4A" hash="zC1B2w">Do you work enthusiastically in your job and use your best efforts to strengthen the company for which you work?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="CvezjarS0ESKlZ5PRNsp5A" hash="1xYWaQ">Do you, as an administrator, study your challenges thoroughly and anticipate the results before you submit your recommendations?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="F6p_Dp0KwEOBBUDPa3_z4g" hash="rulp_w">Do you jump to conclusions without taking the time to know the facts before you make your decision?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="cVakSHkT3EijJJU4ZQ2h0w" hash="ccU3Lw">Do you properly sustain those working under your jurisdiction?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="waqRMcsTU0y0uTFRNt6wpw" hash="odoe3A">Do you sincerely sustain those to whom you are responsible?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="weL84omgJU6TZ3QVFjxjpw" hash="6Y4aKQ">Do you young men and young women stand loyal, in the face of opposition, to those moral principles you have been taught in the home?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="d1k9CC6QpkeU15VDnltv1w" hash="sv9NRA">Do you, as a wife and mother, strive earnestly to create an atmosphere of love and harmony in the home?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="VMfui9Z0R0WBbPuWuavsZw" hash="HYR3tQ">Do you fathers and mothers seriously strive to inculcate values of integrity, morality, charity, and good manners in your children?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="YFIysF0R_0aja3UatkXvYQ" hash="4ihBJA">Are you completely honest with yourself and others?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="nB69WdiKhEqvZDqdik8usw" hash="1lKFNw">Are you obedient to Him who gave you life?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="WZnBHp29rUKm8F3P1RN18A" hash="dDpcAw">The Lord said to the people in his day, and to us too: “By their fruits ye shall know them.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/7.20" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 7:20</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="8Q1FWcKSf0-sbEsC0ki-Lw" hash="7jAV3w">“For a good tree bringeth not forth corrupt fruit; neither doth a corrupt tree bring forth good fruit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="9hGHZi0LKUqRABfNOS1XFg" hash="DTAhaw">“… Every tree is known by his own fruit.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/6.43-44" class="scriptureRef">Luke 6:43–44</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="RvBFmEqXRUC6MWBy88u8yw" hash="x9OBWw">May I suggest a formula for bringing forth good fruit and helping one to gain eternal salvation? (1) have faith in the Lord Jesus Christ and in yourself, (2) study eternal truths, (3) ponder and pray for understanding, (4) strive to incorporate principles of truth into daily living, (5) exercise integrity in all that you do, and (6) strive to do everything you do to a standard of excellence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them.p" pid="kXMEM--_TkaBnM66K2QpWw" hash="MKzVCw">Let us diligently strive to understand the wonderful things of God. The jewels of the gospel of Jesus Christ are within our reach. But we must seek—ask and strive for—and live the principles of truth. When we do so, we will become better men and better women and contribute to a better community, a better nation, and a better world, for which I pray in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div><div class="resources">
    <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26a2.jpg" alt="Elder Royden G. Derrick" guid="e87305c7-d243-4ce6-a8db-9c078880ffb5" pid="22BEQRlpaUmx92a9d3QXZQ" hash="IA4zgQ1" />
    <unknown name="digitalAssets" guid="">
      <unknown name="assetGroup" guid="">
        <unknown name="path" guid="e87305c7-d243-4ce6-a8db-9c078880ffb5"></unknown>
      </unknown>
    </unknown>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1984/10/by-their-fruits-ye-shall-know-them</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1984-general-conference/1984-10-4030-elder-royden-g-derrick-64k-eng.mp3" length="7417492" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 1984 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Way to Perfection</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection?lang=eng</link>
      <description>In October of 1833, the Prophet Joseph Smith received a revelation in which the Lord said, “I will raise up unto myself a pure people, that will serve me in righteousness.” (.) The Lord was speaking of our pioneer forefathers, and also of the Saints </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03239_000_030" doc-version="2" hash="keqblw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="_rlS852nb0OTLrLGh6vqkQ" hash="_dueew">The Way to Perfection</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="0Sm87mBnM0modLolUNGFbg" hash="fJ9QkA">Royden G. Derrick</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26a2.jpg" alt="Elder Royden G. Derrick" pid="pNVu8g8v1Ui0rtdRozPaug" hash="IA4zgQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p1" pid="PC6TPmxz606tmyX-VbuxjQ" hash="ZZj8dw">In October of 1833, the Prophet Joseph Smith received a revelation in which the Lord said, “I will raise up unto myself a pure people, that will serve me in righteousness.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/100.16" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 100:16</a>.) The Lord was speaking of our pioneer forefathers, and also of the Saints of this day. In view of that implied responsibility, I would like to discuss with you today the way to perfection, which not only applies to this life but to the next one as well.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p2" pid="CHHEWjqZxUWiXmhVK7Iv0w" hash="3YUCow">A fortnight ago I received an interesting letter from a member of the Church who grew up in a country located high in the Himalaya Mountains of southern Asia. He wrote: “I was brought up in a royal, aristocratic, Hindu priest family. I was taught to work but not to hope for a reward. I thought, Why should I work if there is no reward? Am I following the right way? I was offended with polytheistic and pantheistic philosophy. I wanted to know the <span class="emphasis">real</span> truth and the [<span class="emphasis">right</span>] way.” He told how he had found the truth and the only right way through the Mormon missionaries in Seoul, Korea. He bore a powerful testimony of the divinity of Jesus Christ that brought tears to my eyes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p3" pid="cxuqRVmzDk6c8eBk2F-7-Q" hash="bB00yQ">I was intrigued by his statement concerning the need for a reward. The Lord has promised us resurrection and immortality, but these are not a reward. According to Webster’s dictionary, a reward is “something that is given for some service or attainment.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p4" pid="uRH9x7Nc-0iiNOpjbsLxFQ" hash="VRXiVw">Resurrection is the reuniting of the body and the spirit. As Jesus was resurrected, eventually every person who was ever born into this world will be resurrected, whether he wants to be or not. When a person is resurrected, he receives immortality, which is to live forever in the resurrected state. Likewise, every person who was ever born into this world will receive immortality regardless of his or her behavior in this life. Thus, <span class="emphasis">resurrection</span> and <span class="emphasis">immortality</span> are synonymous. They are not a reward—they are a gift—for we have rendered no service nor attained any accomplishment to warrant these as a reward. The gift is from the Savior; it comes through His atoning sacrifice.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p5" pid="7PKVr30zQEud_moz3mUccQ" hash="lUbByw">The scriptures teach us that there <span class="emphasis">is</span> promise beyond—that there <span class="emphasis">is</span> a reward for service rendered and for attainment. The reward is exaltation in the celestial kingdom of God. Exaltation is the highest of three degrees of glory in the celestial kingdom. The celestial kingdom is the highest of three kingdoms in the realm of immortality. Exaltation is earned by accepting Jesus Christ and His divine sonship and following His precepts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p6" pid="yTBOUeoy9Euul41dQHPCEQ" hash="ePos-Q">Jesus showed us the way. Its simplicity is encompassed in His Beatitudes, which have echoed down through the centuries of time and will yet echo through the millenniums of time: “Blessed are the poor in spirit: for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.3" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:3</a>.) In repeating the Sermon on the Mount to the people in ancient America, He said it differently: “Blessed are the poor in spirit <span class="emphasis">who come unto me,</span> for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/12.3" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 12:3</a>; italics added.) This addition, “who come unto me,” enables one to better understand the meaning of this verse. The Lord said he is angered with the inhabitants of the earth, for “they seek not the Lord to establish his righteousness, but every man walketh in his own way, and after the image of his own god.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.16" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:16</a>.) The Beatitudes are steps we can take to come to Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p7" pid="ydSLcoDaQ0uyz8C_sSzs4w" hash="eypVeA">
        <span class="emphasis">Step 1.</span> To come unto Christ, one’s first step is to come forth with a broken heart and a contrite spirit that results in overcoming unrighteous pride and becoming submissive to His will.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p8" pid="s30RDq_NzEGUOOYdFQJY3w" hash="G1vrgw">
        <span class="emphasis">Step 2.</span> “Blessed are they that mourn: for they shall be comforted.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.4" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:4</a>.) The Apostle Paul spoke of a godly sorrow for our sins that is essential to our spiritual progress.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p9" pid="aMfdekFveUi-6BziKgUr4A" hash="P6IwGQ">
        <span class="emphasis">Step 3.</span> “Blessed are the meek: for they shall inherit the earth.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.5" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:5</a>.) The dictionary defines <span class="emphasis">meek</span> as “enduring injury with patience and without resentment.” This is an important virtue that one must develop in preparation for entrance into the celestial kingdom, which kingdom the earth will become when it is celestialized.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p10" pid="grJ4OFzXCUOohelNICB6fw" hash="1wLPLQ">
        <span class="emphasis">Step 4.</span> “Blessed are they which do hunger and thirst after righteousness: for they shall be filled.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.6" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:6</a>.) The scripture from ancient America adds, “shall be filled with the Holy Ghost.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/12.6" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 12:6</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p11" pid="itYUHUskI06YKJ0oTyc6vw" hash="b5OvOg">A young man approached Socrates and asked him to be his tutor and to teach him what he knew. Socrates took the young man to the seaside and out into the water. Then he pushed his head under the water for almost too long. The young man struggled, came up gasping for air, and demanded the meaning of such an unwarranted action. The great Socrates responded, “When you want to learn as badly as you want a breath of air, only then can I teach you what you want to know.” To understand the gospel of Jesus Christ, one must first have a strong desire to learn and a willingness to study.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p12" pid="YfzfYwhDzkCqjVQnFBM2Yg" hash="A6vCkg">
        <span class="emphasis">Step 5.</span> “Blessed are the merciful: for they shall obtain mercy.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.7" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:7</a>.) Webster’s dictionary defines <span class="emphasis">mercy</span> as “compassion or forbearance shown to an offender.” Such is the by-product of gospel living.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p13" pid="bDhaCGHT10q9Tz_KX8UMKw" hash="HYzDhA">
        <span class="emphasis">Step 6.</span> When one extends mercy to others, he develops purity of heart. The Savior said, “Blessed are the pure in heart: for they shall see God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.8" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:8</a>.) The dictionary has twenty-two different definitions for the word <span class="emphasis">see,</span> one of which is “to understand.” When one develops purity of heart, he will come to understand God. As one develops an understanding of God, he comes to know Him. The Savior said, addressing the Father, “And this is life eternal, that they might know thee the only true God, and Jesus Christ, whom thou hast sent.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/17.3" class="scriptureRef">John 17:3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p14" pid="51-kKSO5GkWWCsHPCeKnog" hash="XpxqEg">
        <span class="emphasis">Step 7.</span> Once one has gained purity of heart, he receives peace in his mind and peace in his heart. The Savior continued, “Blessed are the peacemakers: for they shall be called the children of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.9" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:9</a>.) Having gained inner peace, we have put on the full armor of God. Now we can more easily withstand persecution, which leads to—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p15" pid="IdRQJzdYcUOX5TAV5D87_Q" hash="rk221Q">
        <span class="emphasis">Step 8.</span> “Blessed are they which are persecuted for righteousness’ sake: for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p16" pid="zRKjSTXb00eyPrbCRhOjjA" hash="JEcTeg">“Blessed are ye, when men shall revile you, and persecute you, and shall say all manner of evil against you falsely, for my sake.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p17" pid="E9FE_QxASkaD6I65XvT0YA" hash="9_Sqfw">“Rejoice, and be exceeding glad: for great is your reward in heaven: for so persecuted they the prophets which were before you.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.10-12" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:10–12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p18" pid="AvXwNdRSqku_jFKMpp9ixg" hash="XHal3g">The Savior concluded His sermon by encouraging us to become perfect, as our Heavenly Father is perfect. While these steps follow one another in a natural sequence, we should always be striving to perfect ourselves in each of these virtues. We should always help others as they strive to improve. Disparagement of others should not exist within our ranks, for each of us is struggling to move forward. A helping hand should be extended to lift one another over the shoals along the rocky shore near which our ship must sail.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p19" pid="GfYA3h5HiUKfioGbw--EaA" hash="_WVmlQ">In our state of imperfection, sin often occurs. The Lord has told us that if we truly repent, He will forgive us. Repentance involves recognition of our imperfections, remorse for having strayed, restitution where appropriate, and resolve that the transgression will never be repeated.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p20" pid="gs7wQxr79EWmqGlfn7VIKw" hash="-TXBxw">It is important that we partake of the sacrament regularly. When we do so, in sincere repentance, our baptismal covenants are renewed, the Lord forgives us, and we start anew. It is truly a marvelous and a merciful process, one which enables us to grow and progress.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p21" pid="30rsIVJ98EeimjFEMxJ-7g" hash="8AK_ZQ">When we partake of the sacrament, we witness unto God that we are willing to take upon ourselves the name of Jesus Christ. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.77" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:77</a>.) What does that mean?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p22" pid="jgjMzi3AFEGYkiOEzdQLYA" hash="LcimBQ">The Savior said to Peter, “Come follow me.” (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/4.19" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 4:19</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/1.17" class="scriptureRef">Mark 1:17</a>.) Peter walked in His footsteps for three years. He went where Jesus went. He did what Jesus instructed him to do. Then the Savior said to Peter and to His other Apostles also:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p23" pid="pMyW9SrnTUabMqI9XI3euQ" hash="4HjEVA">“In my Father’s house are many mansions: if it were not so, I would have told you. I go to prepare a place for you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p24" pid="JzgVTKKhMkq_qHQFes870A" hash="0YLyxA">“And if I go and prepare a place for you, I will come again, and receive you unto myself; that where I am, there ye may be also.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.2-3" class="scriptureRef">John 14:2–3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p25" pid="FbedkiUA0Eu9_acpVYSOSQ" hash="Txi0Gw">And where did Jesus go? He went to His Father. But before He went to His Father, He went someplace else. He went to Gethsemane. We are not required to go through His trials, but we are required to be <span class="emphasis">willing</span> to go through them. To prove that we are willing to do so, we must go through our own trials and remain faithful.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p26" pid="a7Dcznc85Ui1UINlc7U0cA" hash="ahKHWA">The Lord said, “My people must be tried in all things, that they may be prepared to receive the glory that I have for them, even the glory of Zion; and he that will not bear chastisement is not worthy of my kingdom.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/136.31" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 136:31</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p27" pid="mH5qH3RhNEWWITHe0432qQ" hash="2AiQ_w">At the conclusion of the Sermon on the Mount in the Holy Land, the Savior said, “Be ye therefore perfect, even as your Father which is in Heaven is perfect.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.48" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:48</a>.) But when the Savior repeated the Sermon on the Mount to the people of ancient America, He said, “Therefore I would that ye should be perfect <span class="emphasis">even as I,</span> or your Father who is in heaven is perfect.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/12.48" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 12:48</a>; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p28" pid="fa-Hef-IPUW0cwuWWsMW_Q" hash="g2q6jw">Something important occurred between the time He taught this sermon to the people in the Holy Land and when He taught it to the people of ancient America. In the meantime, He went through His Gethsemane, where He drank the bitter cup and did not shrink. We too should strive for perfection, bear up under our problems and our sorrows, remain faithful to the end, and not shrink.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p29" pid="Bc7fzAZ2e0S7BMIFI9c9qg" hash="P4izbw">My friend from the Himalayas will have his trials and tribulations as he returns to his homeland to share this important message with his people: that Jesus Christ is our Redeemer and our Savior and our Exemplar who will direct them along the right path that leads to exaltation; that there <span class="emphasis">is</span> a reward, but it <span class="emphasis">must be earned;</span> and that the reward is glorious beyond description. He tasted of that reward when he asked the Lord, “Is it true?” and the Holy Spirit bore witness to him that truly it is.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection.p30" pid="sgA41KlH50CqvtwS2_LNvw" hash="eMHDhQ">I testify that this restored gospel which we espouse is indeed the real truth and the <span class="emphasis">right</span> way to a glorious and eternal reward. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1989/04/the-way-to-perfection</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1989-general-conference/1989-04-5040-elder-royden-g-derrick-64k-eng.mp3" length="6329298" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 1989 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
