<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Rulon G. Craven</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Rulon G. Craven.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Rulon%20G.%20Craven.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Rulon G. Craven.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Apr 1991 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 1991 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Prophets</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1991/04/prophets?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My brothers and sisters, while I served thirteen and one-half years as secretary to the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles, my testimony was strengthened concerning living prophets. The Lord said through the Prophet Joseph Smith: “The Twelve Apostles [are</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/prophets" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_91905_000_014" doc-version="2" hash="JKB3KA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/prophets.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="qh5fo2a1WkGvAj5jxFiREg" hash="A7-WEg">Prophets</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Gu4XQ3mGY0yFUMOURi_7dQ" hash="KtFU_A">Rulon G. Craven</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/prophets.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1fa4.jpg" alt="Elder Rulon G. Craven" pid="x5PQ2APZG0Omaut_SaoYUg" hash="a0jcLg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/prophets.p1" pid="I_X-AnFiwUue0QGtIMUsHg" hash="ypeO2g">My brothers and sisters, while I served thirteen and one-half years as secretary to the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles, my testimony was strengthened concerning living prophets. The Lord said through the Prophet Joseph Smith: “The Twelve Apostles [are called to be] special witnesses of the name of Christ in all the world.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/107.23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 107:23</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/prophets.p2" pid="1Ynt1i9FNUWDSzdS0R5ynw" hash="MceLww">Prophets have a special gift of the Spirit, a prophetic gift. During the time I served as secretary to the Twelve, I observed these men whom our Father in Heaven has called as special witnesses of his Son Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/prophets.p3" pid="-UTPWwlfjUq2w6gCPNKqxQ" hash="7J77Cg">The Thursday morning meetings in the upper room of the temple were always a special experience for me. My heart was often filled with emotion as I listened to the members of the Twelve pray to their Father in Heaven, remembering these are the Twelve Apostles, chosen by our Father in Heaven and sustained by the Saints as prophets, seers, and revelators.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/prophets.p4" pid="dUSIeQy_4UinxlKfZ6_kMw" hash="9xiA_Q">As President Hunter would lead the Twelve through the agenda, I was continually reminded of section 107, verse 27, of the Doctrine and Covenants, which reads, “And every decision made by either of these quorums must be by the unanimous voice of the same; that is, every member in each quorum must be agreed to its decisions, in order to make their decisions of the same power or validity one with the other.” [<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/107.27" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 107:27</a>]</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/prophets.p5" pid="gCI_1caYAkWzjmhv_VYvqg" hash="L5mHLQ">The members of the Twelve strive to live according to the promptings of the Spirit. They speak their mind. However, they are also good listeners and speak when moved upon by the Holy Spirit. Their posture in quorum meetings is to listen and sense the directing power of the Spirit, which always leads to a unity of decision. I marveled as I watched the directing power of the Spirit touch the minds and hearts of the members of the Twelve, influencing the decision-making process.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/prophets.p6" pid="bbduPD2TG06ud4oVf2RBzg" hash="QpvRAA">Decisions made by the Council of the First Presidency and the Council of the Twelve are directed by the Spirit because they strive continually to abide by the counsel of the Lord found in section 107, verse 30, of the Doctrine and Covenants, which reads: “The decisions of these quorums, or either of them, are to be made in all righteousness, in holiness, and lowliness of heart, meekness and long suffering, and in faith, and virtue, and knowledge, temperance, patience, godliness, brotherly kindness and charity;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/prophets.p7" pid="CyrLuwO2f0Gn16b6vDwnqg" hash="c-zBoA">“Because the promise is, if these things abound in them they shall not be unfruitful in the knowledge of the Lord.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/107.30-31" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 107:30–31</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/prophets.p8" pid="H2AwwfCkVkKGWbMqUNTFSw" hash="JJLEgw">The members of the First Presidency, the Quorum of the Twelve, the Seventy, and the Presiding Bishopric are truly men who are striving to be pure in heart. A spirit of righteousness, love, and unity abounds in their quorum meetings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/prophets.p9" pid="9YjKreg5MkSKQdC4zj5law" hash="cLgn0A">The Twelve love President Hunter, and President Howard W. Hunter loves the Twelve. President Hunter’s gentle, persuasive leadership invites the Spirit of the Lord into all of their meetings. I hope President Hunter will forgive me for relating an experience which portrayed to me the great love the Twelve have for each other, which love brings the Holy Spirit into their quorum meetings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/prophets.p10" pid="sqqSHSGooEWntXkwfesiUw" hash="6eFZqw">Many will remember a number of years ago President Hunter was informed that he would not walk again. However, his faith and determination were greater than that message. Daily, without fanfare and the knowledge of others, he went through some very strenuous physical therapy exercises with determination, faith, and the vision that he would walk again. During those difficult months, his Brethren of the Twelve were praying for him daily in their quorum meetings and in their private prayers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/prophets.p11" pid="o_i-19gqVUSH4GI4oxGgug" hash="33MuDA">Months later, on a Thursday morning, I went to President Hunter’s office to discuss an agenda item for the temple meeting that morning. I found he left early and was informed that he was walking to the temple. I questioned that information and then hurried to catch up with him. When I caught up with him, he was walking with the help of a walker. We walked together to the elevator and then up to the fourth floor. We went down the hall to the upper room of the temple. When their president walked into that room, the Twelve stood and began to clap their hands. They tenderly watched him walk over to his chair and let his body down into the chair. Then with magnificent love, honor, and tenderness, each of the Twelve went up to him and extended to him an affectionate touch, kiss on the forehead, and a hug, showing their great love and admiration for him. They all sat down, and President Hunter thanked them and said, “I was not supposed to walk again, but with the Lord’s help and my determination and, most important, the faith of my Brethren of the Twelve, I am walking again.” President Howard W. Hunter is an example of maintaining faith and determination in the face of adversity. The Twelve are examples of maintaining faith and prayer in behalf of those who are experiencing adversity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/prophets.p12" pid="44tsyt3wYUKEcjvsOuFxiw" hash="Gi5lcQ">My brothers and sisters, I share these personal experiences with you because I was there. I have a humble desire to strengthen your faith in the First Presidency and the Quorum of the Twelve, whom we sustain as prophets, seers, and revelators.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/prophets.p13" pid="cqoxc0zhrUeYq_HmUAeaCA" hash="4NXlVA">These men, from my close observation, live close to the Lord. I have witnessed the power of the Holy Spirit touch their hearts and minds and give expression to their words. I have marveled at the unity of purpose of the First Presidency and the Twelve in serving the Lord. Christ and his prophets are one. I continually observed the love and sustaining power extended by his two counselors and the Twelve to our prophet leader, President Ezra Taft Benson. My witness from personal observation is that you can have unwavering faith in the united counsel of the First Presidency and the Quorum of the Twelve. They will lead you in the path of righteousness, happiness, and inner peace.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/prophets.p14" pid="8MbUHHLmp0esRTleYjtu8A" hash="-RF7Bw">My wife, Donna, and our children have made it a practice to read, listen to, and follow the counsel of the prophets. We have always been abundantly blessed in our homes, in our occupations, and in our personal lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/prophets.p15" pid="N5Mv-0DxRk-CWiiscWgooA" hash="4PMQjw">My brothers and sisters, there will yet be perilous and challenging times ahead. I admonish the Saints to look to the prophets, study their words. Teach their words in your family home evenings. Sustain them in private and in public; pray for them in your private and family prayers. And in turn, enjoy in your lives that inner peace that surpasseth understanding.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/04/prophets.p16" pid="B4a2n3jzOUi-S3HGRLNXRw" hash="Ah82aw">I leave you my special witness of the reality of our Father in Heaven, that Jesus is the Christ, the Savior of all who will come unto him, and that his chosen prophets do walk the earth today. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1991/04/prophets</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1991-general-conference/1991-04-2040-elder-rulon-g-craven-64k-eng.mp3" length="4455605" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 1991 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temptation</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1996/04/temptation?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My brothers and sisters, it has been a wonderful experience to work with the Saints who love their Heavenly Father and love one another. We have witnessed their valiancy and their challenges as they face the trials of life.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/temptation" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_96905_000_030" doc-version="2" hash="gp3YRQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/temptation.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="LcN8r--mMUyCwdaXwO-v5w" hash="zzzdkw">Temptation</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="3XBaFo1ujkWHUgTaNFgFHA" hash="KtFU_A">Rulon G. Craven</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/temptation.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1fa4.jpg" alt="Elder Rulon G. Craven" pid="ui3bADMqDkS1CieVQ2abtw" hash="a0jcLg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/temptation.p1" pid="DzXU1U5PZU2Y2FLvABNNFw" hash="k-LqpA">My brothers and sisters, it has been a wonderful experience to work with the Saints who love their Heavenly Father and love one another. We have witnessed their valiancy and their challenges as they face the trials of life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/temptation.p2" pid="gbAv66OdfEODO7ist9oKEw" hash="o2t9eQ">During the past years I have at times been asked by the Brethren to meet with repentant members of the Church and interview them for the restoration of their temple blessings. This has always been a spiritually moving experience to restore the blessings of those wonderful people who have repented. I have asked some of them the question, “What happened in your life that caused you to temporarily lose your membership in the Church?” With tear-filled eyes they answered: “I didn’t obey the basic principles of the gospel: prayer, attending church regularly, serving in the Church, and studying the gospel. I then gave in to temptations and lost the guidance of the Holy Spirit.” It is always a special experience for me to meet these repentant souls and to feel with them the miracle of forgiveness and the joy of being reunited with the Saints and the Holy Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/temptation.p3" pid="xiMj89BGV0iKwQCInzUIOg" hash="EZFAcg">Temptation is a necessary part of our earthly experience. The Lord through the Prophet Joseph Smith explains the reason why we are tempted: “It must needs be that the devil should tempt the children of men, or they could not be agents unto themselves; for if they never should have bitter they could not know the sweet” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/29.39" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 29:39</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/temptation.p4" pid="F2NYseW8Ok2FKJ12NTrgWQ" hash="xkRAAQ">In the Book of Mormon, Nephi explains the consequences of yielding to temptation: “The temptations of the devil … blindeth the eyes, and hardeneth the hearts of the children of men, and leadeth them away into broad roads, that they perish and are lost” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/12.17" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 12:17</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/temptation.p5" pid="nItUDEY14ESiVSKIlcVoNw" hash="golBsA">To blind the eyes is <span class="emphasis">not</span> to see or acknowledge the consequences of our actions. To harden the heart is to <span class="emphasis">ignore</span> or not be willing to accept counsel. To be led into the broad roads is to give in to worldly enticements and lose the influence of the Holy Spirit in our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/temptation.p6" pid="9MUOK06kqUWLEmIj2wlyQw" hash="FvqRpQ">Brigham Young stated: “Many think that the Devil has rule and power over both body and spirit. Now, I want to tell you that he does not hold any power over man, only so far as the body overcomes the spirit that is in a man, through yielding to the spirit of evil. … The spirit is influenced by the body, and the body by the spirit” (<span class="emphasis">Discourses of Brigham Young,</span> sel. John A. Widtsoe [1941], 69–70).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/temptation.p7" pid="3pB8pPqtr0iLn4bYkhM7OQ" hash="7bYFLQ">Temptation is like a magnetic force which holds a metal object in its power. It loses its magnetic force and power when you turn away from it. So we must turn away from temptation; then it will lose its power.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/temptation.p8" pid="hZTgcY_2R0ufTr-nesYdBg" hash="ir0TOg">Our mind, throughout the day, is continually active. We choose the avenues of thought that our mind travels. Allowing worldly thoughts to enter your mind can lead to unrighteous acts. As we travel the highways of life, our physical senses are continually bombarded with billboards, posters, magazines, videos, movies, etc., that entice and tempt the mind and, if allowed, create mental pictures that are not becoming to a Latter-day Saint.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/temptation.p9" pid="ApIhlQp_kEqFqNTKmRn-Lg" hash="uEqrNg">When evil thoughts arise—Stop! Think! Control your mind! Visualize a large EXIT sign in your mind’s eye. Immediately change your thoughts. Get off of that avenue of thinking.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/temptation.p10" pid="TK7Pm2-IlEyASynZKQ6ikQ" hash="a-FC1g">When unrighteous feelings and desires well up inside of you, the Holy Ghost will prompt NO. Listen to the Holy Spirit. Stop! Think! Visualize a WRONG WAY sign in your mind. Immediately change or erase those thoughts leading to wrong unrighteous feelings and evil fantasies that can become addictive to mind and body.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/temptation.p11" pid="etWjfacAhkSQleYpm-NojQ" hash="9OpdKQ">When tempted to choose an unrighteous act, or entertain unrighteous thoughts, look down the road ahead and contemplate the inevitable consequences of that act. Stop! Think! Visualize a STOP sign in your mind. Put on your mental brakes. Immediately change your thinking to something different and something uplifting.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/temptation.p12" pid="tRgipoacnUe4QmLzQWRdlA" hash="bE7rpw">To overcome temptation you and I must control our thoughts. <span class="emphasis">Exit</span> from your mind bad thoughts. Avoid the <span class="emphasis">wrong way</span> of unrighteous thoughts. <span class="emphasis">Stop</span> thoughts that lead to behavior unbecoming to a Latter-day Saint. You do not have to yield to temptation! Discipline what you allow your eyes to see, your ears to hear, your mouth to speak, and your hands to touch.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/temptation.p13" pid="k6StqXYin02f8_ThmsZzHQ" hash="_diZhA">Yielding to temptation can lead to the addiction of both body and spirit. Addiction can be overpowering and lead to enslavement, and enslavement leads to loss of freedom and inner peace.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/temptation.p14" pid="TiB6KyfANk6RIWjuH3_DLg" hash="ma54jA">When persons allow themselves to succumb to temptation, they are acting against counsel: the counsel of the Holy Ghost, the counsel of our prophet leaders, the counsel of sound doctrine, the counsel of covenants, and often the counsel of those who love them most. They then separate themselves from the friendship and love of others and the guidance of the Holy Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/temptation.p15" pid="SKWnXpCys0eKiYFUm6M-Tw" hash="6k6Qhg">Temptation can be a compassionate way of warning us of possible dangers. It acts like a caution sign. It warns us of possible danger ahead. Temptation can alert the mind to turn away from an improper thought or act.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/temptation.p16" pid="nk2a9HRDj0Wb1z4ePslCCg" hash="jo9oHw">As eternal beings living this earthly experience, we will not be free from temptation. Temptation implies an inner struggle to do that which is right. The person who thinks continually in a sensual and carnal manner cannot undergo inner spiritual development. His or her sensual thinking prevents spiritual growth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/temptation.p17" pid="EWH0KSdauUmeT4wU1XMdrg" hash="kKo8ZQ">Elder George Q. Cannon said: “Unless they [individuals] were exposed to temptation they never could know themselves, their own powers, their own weaknesses nor the power of God. If Satan had no power to tempt mankind, they would be in a state where they could neither know good nor evil; they could not know happiness nor misery. All their powers would lie dormant, for there would be nothing to arouse them. They would be destitute of that experience which prepares men to become like God, their Eternal Father” (<span class="emphasis">Gospel Truth,</span> sel. Jerreld L. Newquist, 2 vols. in 1 [1987], 109).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/temptation.p18" pid="UMB7vdzuQUW38-MieeGn7w" hash="DjYAqQ">Through obedience to gospel principles, the enticements of the world lessen in our lives. With each right choice we make, we spiritually empower ourselves. The accumulation of right choices builds inner spiritual strength and divine character. We should expect temptation, for without temptations there would be little education and little character improvement.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/temptation.p19" pid="_Tl4c32OfEmas-kQP4vrIg" hash="K4CToA">It is a frightening realization that the powers of evil will increase in the world. This brings us to the question, What can we do? Is there a way to escape from the powers of evil? Yes, there is.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/temptation.p20" pid="s7a6Wxil7UeP9R0-rTsnzQ" hash="TxnAIw">Members of the Church can overcome temptation by (1) obedience to the guiding principles and doctrines of the gospel of Jesus Christ, (2) following the counsel of our prophets and leaders, and (3) living in such a way that our lives are constantly influenced by the power of the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/temptation.p21" pid="BIS2zihwRUaEKYM1Sxpqmw" hash="EDfVqg">Train your mind to obey gospel principles and covenants. Stay on the highway of daily personal and family prayer, the avenue of studying the scriptures and the teachings of the prophets, the road of serving in the Church, and be willing to get off the wrong road daily and on the right road leading to eternal life. Your greatest protection against temptation is an active and vibrant testimony of the gospel of Jesus Christ, which binds us to our Heavenly Father. Our greatest example of overcoming temptation is the Savior: “He suffered temptations but gave no heed unto them” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.22" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:22</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1996/04/temptation.p22" pid="GTYT3yYzq0CgPJKK34t6hQ" hash="qdvdSw">My brothers and sisters, I know this work is true. I know prophets travel the earth today. I know that Jesus is the Christ and that God does live in the heavens. As we draw near to our Heavenly Father in obedience and righteousness, He will draw near to us. He will bless us, perfect us, and protect us. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1996/04/temptation</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1996-general-conference/1996-04-5040-elder-rulon-g-craven-64k-eng.mp3" length="5236079" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 1996 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
