<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Russell C. Taylor</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Russell C. Taylor.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Russell%20C.%20Taylor.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Russell C. Taylor.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 1984 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>The Joy of Service</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1984/10/the-joy-of-service?lang=eng</link>
      <description>On this momentous occasion, my first time at this pulpit, I stand humbly and prayerfully. May I share from the testimony of the heart and from the fire of application and experience the personal joy of service in God’s kingdom.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-joy-of-service" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03180_000_010" doc-version="2" hash="8mqgVw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-joy-of-service.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="_csSn_sSqkKGvP7r-Tonuw" hash="v2QxGA">The Joy of Service</h1><p class="authorName" guid="8104c1aa-00e4-4de3-9c9f-09af24919936" pid="NmEWgML4XkyBtbZgKrAiYw" hash="rsajNg">Russell C. Taylor</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="a571e574-b123-4727-9062-217453109299">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-joy-of-service.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-269e.jpg" alt="Elder Russell C. Taylor" guid="c4b6042e-25a3-4ff9-a557-77c7188a89f8" pid="pbNK7K3BVUyTOAIyBu6FtQ" hash="1L2a5Q" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-joy-of-service.p" pid="XU95HMbgKEGEIdH7uO2R5w" hash="aEdckQ">On this momentous occasion, my first time at this pulpit, I stand humbly and prayerfully. May I share from the testimony of the heart and from the fire of application and experience the personal joy of service in God’s kingdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-joy-of-service.p" pid="7UWzjUQMt0mKgPiVRzkN5Q" hash="GGDMgQ">I can say unashamedly, I rejoice in the service of God. My experience teaches that the highest goodness attainable is a life of unselfish service to mankind. The Master said, “He that is greatest among you shall be your servant.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/23.11" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 23:11</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-joy-of-service.p" pid="7wzPPF2CLkeYpu6dvEUkPw" hash="Q8qftQ">It has been wisely said, “Service is the rent we pay for our own room on earth.” We should know that the rent is due on a daily basis and know that the receipt is never stamped “paid in full,” because the rent, service in God’s kingdom, is again due today and due tomorrow.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-joy-of-service.p" pid="_pxUdVVNqkmoN5V1HZPeiA" hash="AWpP-g">Some mistakenly think that a commitment to service comes <span class="emphasis">after</span> a great spiritual experience. This is like the man who is cold, standing before the stove, and saying, “Give me heat, and <span class="emphasis">then</span> I will put in some wood.” The joy and blessings of service <span class="emphasis">follow</span> the rendering of service. The missionary who renders eighteen months of faithful missionary service <span class="emphasis">then</span> has a lifetime to think about it, while perfecting a life of service to others. Some would want and expect the windows of heaven to open<span class="emphasis"> before</span> they pay their tithing, even though the prophet Malachi so plainly teaches:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-joy-of-service.p" pid="obvcPJuAwUKVqnZ9zoWRbg" hash="tsIucA">“Bring ye all the tithes into the storehouse … and <span class="emphasis">prove</span> me <span class="emphasis">now</span> … saith the Lord of hosts, if I will not open <span class="emphasis">you</span> the windows of heaven, and pour you out a blessing, that there shall not be room enough to receive it.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/mal/3.10" class="scriptureRef">Mal. 3:10</a>; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-joy-of-service.p" pid="Qs1rSnxdUUy2mu3Bzdl71w" hash="v0LH9A">There comes a time in the life of all people when they must <span class="emphasis">certify</span> with their actions what they believe. Jesus said of his own life, “The Son of man came not to be ministered unto, but to minister.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/20.28" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 20:28</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-joy-of-service.p" pid="5eOANzhJjkyBZlIu6IcbqA" hash="xGOCUg">Elder Bruce R. McConkie has so eloquently taught us that service is essential to salvation. I have been impressed with the <span class="emphasis">urgency</span> of doing. Knowing is not enough; we must apply. Being willing is not enough; we must do. Progress is not created by contented people. It is up to us, you and me, to be uncomfortable in complacency, to refrain from being spectators, and to be players in the game of life. The Lord has chosen His people to perform a mighty work. Our home teaching, our visiting teaching should be more than <span class="emphasis">going;</span> it should be <span class="emphasis">doing</span> with Christian love. It can be done; you can each do your portion of the work because you desire it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-joy-of-service.p" pid="bz64iZwCf0CfI1D0EFIbgw" hash="GPui0Q">Fathers and mothers, with your strength of example you will influence your sons and daughters for eternity with examples of loving, uncomplaining service far more convincingly by <span class="emphasis">doing</span> than only by saying. Show your children a life of love for them by a life of love and service to the Church and to our Father’s children in spiritual need.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-joy-of-service.p" pid="6cyzMAICGEyWdk2CSDSJ4w" hash="VQIQ5g">I recall King Benjamin’s instruction to parents as they were counseled in teaching their children:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-joy-of-service.p" pid="sAL7H98RoUe_BbffnO4p-g" hash="F5kFrw">“But ye will teach them to walk in the ways of truth and soberness; ye will teach them to love one another, and to serve one another.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/4.15" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 4:15</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-joy-of-service.p" pid="Ql63lDOTYEOakTXRmPaL6A" hash="kZFljA">As wisely stated, “Until a man learns to think, he is not an educated man, no matter how many degrees he has.” I would also add that a thinking man will want to serve. The greater your service, the closer your access to God. One who serves and sacrifices goes to bed at night with peace of mind.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-joy-of-service.p" pid="5SANL6K_Y0KFwQkZG961mw" hash="R7w4Kw">I think of a dear sister who has crippling arthritis in her hands but faithfully each week, upon entering the genealogical name extraction center in Denver, finds the joints of her fingers limber enough to type the names with efficiency and rapidity—the blessings of unselfish service.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-joy-of-service.p" pid="PJ99p0GBnkqrINzDiUF6yw" hash="sqSaOw">Jesus washed the feet of his disciples, feet that were hot, sweaty, and soiled with dust and dirt. He washed not their hands or face; he washed their feet. He who is the greatest shall be the least—he it is who learns to serve. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/50.26" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 50:26</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-joy-of-service.p" pid="PF-HM_yUjki8jKcAYZ7TtA" hash="DIQhbw">Within days of arriving in Europe, Sister Taylor and I, still living out of suitcases in a small hotel room in Germany, were scheduled to attend a mission presidents’ seminar in Amsterdam, Holland. As we drove to and from the seminar, as arranged by the Regional Representative, we set out to meet our leaders in western Europe. We drove an hour each way into a small village to bless a leader and his family. We went to their homes. In each home we met a lovely wife and handsome children. We ate at their tables, slept as invited, and in each case knelt in prayer and blessed their homes, their families, their callings, and the area for successful missionary service. I now know our leaders there. I felt a genuine love for them, and I felt the same response from them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-joy-of-service.p" pid="IZRsmvoWhk-uNHHwRvDhUg" hash="w-bcfw">You have those feelings of approaching in some small degree the indescribable joy of the celestial glory. He that loses his life shall save it. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/17.33" class="scriptureRef">Luke 17:33</a>.) My well of spirituality has indeed been deepened.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-joy-of-service.p" pid="TuJk83MfU0S0TiaiBZNxVA" hash="tdIXBA">I invite those yet to be members of the Church to come off the back rows as spectators and become participants in the Lord’s restored Church through baptism and the gift of the Holy Ghost, that they might also lose their lives in service and thereby save it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/10/the-joy-of-service.p" pid="At8vTCe7_kCStHQuvX2U8w" hash="aH_EhA">Through the years my heart has been changed and softened through service. As the least of the Brethren, I invite all to lengthen and strengthen their service in God’s kingdom. I bear witness to the divinity of this work. I also bear witness that this Church is led by inspired leaders, whom I sustain with all of my soul, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div><div class="resources">
    <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-269e.jpg" alt="Elder Russell C. Taylor" guid="c4b6042e-25a3-4ff9-a557-77c7188a89f8" pid="XSun6c3reU2TCOnKr-tulg" hash="1L2a5Q1" />
    <unknown name="digitalAssets" guid="">
      <unknown name="assetGroup" guid="">
        <unknown name="path" guid="c4b6042e-25a3-4ff9-a557-77c7188a89f8"></unknown>
      </unknown>
    </unknown>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1984/10/the-joy-of-service</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1984-general-conference/1984-10-2020-elder-russell-c-taylor-64k-eng.mp3" length="3822031" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 1984 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making Points for Righteousness</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness?lang=eng</link>
      <description>As the first member of the First Quorum of the Seventy sustained into the Second Quorum of the Seventy in this dispensation, I echo support and sustain this historic action and would want all to know I feel it an honor to serve in this or any capacit</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03239_000_019" doc-version="2" hash="tHYH2A">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="nWPIKw0dGEaEnPlt7LGUoA" hash="JLUpGA">Making Points for Righteousness</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="lTIlThMvy0andOwz7VF48Q" hash="rsajNg">Russell C. Taylor</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-269e.jpg" alt="Elder Russell C. Taylor" pid="Cja1G9752UCD7kAkfiOraw" hash="1L2a5Q" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p1" pid="P-0mn6pahEyLq-xIyJpzYg" hash="OM1rvA">As the first member of the First Quorum of the Seventy sustained into the Second Quorum of the Seventy in this dispensation, I echo support and sustain this historic action and would want all to know I feel it an honor to serve in this or any capacity in the kingdom of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p2" pid="kdd03KAIDkWDDXPUhsTj_g" hash="-KUGZA">My message tonight is directed to the young men of the Aaronic Priesthood. I will admit before all of you: get me to a good football or basketball game, and I’m a happy man. I have four favorite teams. Three of them are professional, and one is a college team—the Jazz, the Nuggets, the Broncos, and the Cougars. When they win, my wife has a hard time keeping me in my seat. When one of these teams loses, I’m not very friendly (and with some of these teams, I’ve had a lot of practice being unfriendly this year). But, after a night’s sleep, I find it doesn’t really matter—not really.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p3" pid="Mq71fCjI8EKPilWZTtXhlg" hash="b2p39Q">But when a young man loses in his preparation for life, that really matters—because that has lasting consequences.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p4" pid="Mh34wz-Ld0ip-hPZohpKvw" hash="w0U3vA">Playing ball is a great deal like life. You want to do your best, to be committed, to be a team player. You want to follow the rules so you don’t foul out. You want to make points.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p5" pid="mJmmFbPtUkeiSjI-bshDTw" hash="3uviTQ">The rules in real life are different from those in a game. Our rules are the commandments of God. You make points when you serve your mission, draw close to the Lord, live the Word of Wisdom, stay morally clean, and live a life of service and Church activity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p6" pid="Uw9xWxTDH0id4jFyoaE41Q" hash="YuLkIA">How many points are you making in your life? Are you winning?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p7" pid="CwgOVpwLek-nD0QSRWdLMg" hash="VRxQXw">When you make a basket in a basketball game or kick a goal in soccer, there’s a great feeling of accomplishment and excitement. The same thing happens when you make gospel points. You feel good about yourself. You also feel closer to the Lord. You feel the excitement of knowing you’re doing what God wants you to do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p8" pid="K2CF47TWqkaEjSnPycw7pg" hash="Pj_XdA">You’re in a different league when you’re shooting for gospel points. It’s a celestial league. You’re one of the Lord’s own sons, and he’s depending on you to do your very best. There are forces of good and forces of evil in the world. You represent the Lord as a force for good. You have come to earth at this time for a special purpose. He has a mission for you to accomplish, a <span class="emphasis">lifetime</span> mission.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p9" pid="YmiLntjLd0KOLg_010_4pA" hash="izciMw">You’re probably going to have a tough opponent to overcome. Sometimes the media, friends, or other influences will try to pull you away from what is right. Choose to stand with the Lord. Join with the valiant prophet Joshua, who declared, “Choose you this day whom ye will serve; … but as for me and my house, we will serve the Lord.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/josh/24.15" class="scriptureRef">Josh. 24:15</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p10" pid="ve13-Vms206Fp-R0Qgc0yw" hash="jPPQhQ">To win this most important game of all, you need to make <span class="emphasis">five points.</span> Let me be your coach for a few minutes. We will talk about plays and assignments—making points for righteousness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p11" pid="tuY4LbpB7kCNKrQaoe_Pag" hash="AzsCtA">The first point to be made is to <span class="emphasis">serve your mission.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p12" pid="VY8AZwolZkqb3tBsEZ7QZw" hash="Lywb2Q">Be determined to serve a mission. Prepare well for it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p13" pid="X339Bu53R0eLTer2tC4UJA" hash="be9Ilw">The prophet has asked each young man to serve a mission. That usually involves sacrifice. Ofttimes it means you give up something good for something better. It may mean postponing schooling or an athletic scholarship. It means saving money—for a mission instead of a car.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p14" pid="f9U7p_NA70qyXa4TXlwKfA" hash="omJ7Kg">It also means sacrificing the things of the world. The prophet Moroni tells us, “Come unto Christ, and be perfected in him, and <span class="emphasis">deny yourselves of all ungodliness.</span>” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.32" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 10:32</a>; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p15" pid="XUECw86CYkKwBppzq4LD_Q" hash="W6mAcA">The hymn tells us, “Sacrifice brings forth the blessings of heaven.” (<span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> 1985, no. 27.) Do you know that sacrifice purifies our spirits and brings us closer to the Lord?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p16" pid="pWmAZXOfeEeuDsqRpTqbBA" hash="fouFUw">Serving your mission is more than being called and sharing the gospel with your brothers and sisters for two years. That <span class="emphasis">is</span> important, but your mission is also doing what the Lord wants you to do throughout <span class="emphasis">all</span> your life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p17" pid="y1pNKCrJ9UWYwzivQLAJVw" hash="8G2Fdw">A mission can change the quality of your life in ways that you can barely imagine. You will find out what that is only as you serve the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p18" pid="Uk52YBTW9U-mBOQI_naIDQ" hash="B4t-NA">Serve your mission. Make a point for righteousness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p19" pid="FyBs9QoVtUaEN2caDgyB-w" hash="t6Y1gw">The second point to be made is to <span class="emphasis">draw close to the Lord.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p20" pid="tBmPQT9jgkKTSEBlOThFLQ" hash="B2UjtA">How do you make that point? You make it by taking appropriate time to <span class="emphasis">read the scriptures daily,</span> having earnest prayer, and fasting. These practices will help your testimony grow.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p21" pid="sqFJ1X9bB0yLjyce01PazA" hash="R2Olvg">A seminary student said, “I used to think the scriptures were boring—until I started to read them.” At a recent stake conference, a beautiful young woman said in her testimony, “If you think the scriptures are boring, then you are boring.” They discovered that the scriptures provide answers to the problems they may face—with friends, at home, or at school. Gospel principles apply to any time period—Old Testament times or today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p22" pid="deTqq11dnUuTZ2pqWrfJyA" hash="illz7w">The Lord will speak to you through the words of the scriptures. Draw close to the Lord through the scriptures.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p23" pid="6Ctk243ekEik7AqN__344g" hash="qqnpMQ">Take a <span class="emphasis">time-out</span> to <span class="emphasis">pray each morning and night</span> and as often in between as needed. That’s one of the wonderful gifts the Lord has given you—he’s accessible by prayer any time, any place. He’s always there for you. Tell him your goals, your troubles. Give him thanks for your blessings. Ask him to teach you how you can help do his work. He hears your prayers. He cares about you. He wants you to succeed in living the gospel. Draw close to the Lord through prayer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p24" pid="ezX6kMog1kqwT34CoTXWfA" hash="wh8cwg">
        <span class="emphasis">Fast</span> the first Sunday of each month and also when you need special help from the Lord. Make it a true fast. Fasting is more than abstaining from food. It is more than helping the needy through fast offerings, important as that is. It is a spiritual law as well, just as is the law of tithing or the Word of Wisdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p25" pid="FjLbJZ6jpEe-N1kyYwEyqw" hash="Dbzy6g">In a sincere fast, we are given an open invitation by the Lord to draw close to him, to open our hearts to him, to feel his Spirit and pure love. It’s a time to recommit to obeying his commandments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p26" pid="TrzfIY6xQ0e1LTIh-oaepQ" hash="2thacg">You’ll find there are points to make as you draw close to the Lord through scripture study, prayer, and fasting. Your testimony will grow. While many young men today are starving spiritually, you can grow spiritually.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p27" pid="hgV4CbO1CkCIbvlc16JVmA" hash="lq3chA">The third point: this is a tough two-pointer; the defense is all over you. <span class="emphasis">Live the Word of Wisdom.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p28" pid="iFRVZSoiIUKVEaK9bpqi5w" hash="syWyig">Choose not to use drugs or alcohol <span class="emphasis">before</span> you’re tempted. They are destructive to your physical, mental, and spiritual well-being. Using them is wrong. They can destroy you. With drugs there is a high—but, oh, the risk; for you come down harder and lower after each experience. You can truly end up in the depths of hell. Young men, may you know <span class="emphasis">now</span> that drugs dull your conscience so that you discern less clearly between good and evil.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p29" pid="2t9A1aKPi0SlO8PnFcHaHA" hash="OfJpdA">President David O. McKay said, “Sin can stun the conscience as a blow on the head can stun the physical senses.” (<span class="emphasis">Gospel Ideals,</span> Salt Lake City: Improvement Era, 1953, p. 146.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p30" pid="yqZy_9i2y0eXY8tw_2RgCA" hash="c2sbzg">In the Word of Wisdom, the Lord tells us, “In consequence of evils and designs which do and will exist in the hearts of conspiring men in the last days, I have warned you, and forewarn you, by giving unto you this word of wisdom by revelation.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/89.4" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 89:4</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p31" pid="z2xbgwMeUkm88EbJzpWHYg" hash="DlhyFQ">Conspiring, evil men want to make money by selling drugs, alcohol, and tobacco. They don’t care how much death and pain come as a result. Beware of these merchants of death. Say no to those mind- and body-destroying drugs and chemicals that are ravaging the youth throughout the world. Why indulge when you know they destroy and promise nothing but sorrow? Young men, the ball is in your hands. Make that important goal for righteousness. Live the Word of Wisdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p32" pid="hOMSrlLn10CvLZ2FaYUwEg" hash="Y9B-Uw">Point number four: This is a three-point basket that could win the game. <span class="emphasis">Stay morally clean.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p33" pid="LHIkFiUvdUmG8BLJF3EFXA" hash="9uXLxw">Your mission call, your mission in life, and who and where you marry will be influenced by whether you lead a pure and chaste life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p34" pid="BL4WqHm1FU6N0Vmq6SvPfw" hash="haCEDg">Alma taught his son Shiblon the importance of being morally clean. He said, “See that ye bridle all your passions, that ye may be filled with love.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/38.12" class="scriptureRef">Alma 38:12</a>.) That is an interesting paradox—true love comes when you bridle your passions, when you use self-control.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p35" pid="0KpkUul_kEGYOOgi69spAQ" hash="REGecA">You should avoid anything that causes you to lose control of yourself or to lose concern for the welfare of another person.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p36" pid="kXoHoZoaJE2TJ-SyjJ7xJg" hash="L59o2Q">Sharing affection can be a very positive, pleasing experience and was given to us by the Lord to strengthen the bonds between men and women. It is part of the force that leads us to marriage. The feelings generated can be very strong, but if you don’t control them, they’ll control you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p37" pid="OU4t3ybv1UKb33CK9xhNYw" hash="MaDkDQ">To be prepared for your life’s mission, you must purify your thoughts and feelings. <span class="emphasis">You</span> have the power to decide, deliberately and intentionally, what images you entertain in your mind and what emotions you feel in your heart.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p38" pid="fB960K7zNE-pNN1yqjA-vg" hash="l8NPTw">Movies and television often portray premarital sex as an appropriate expression of love between a man and a woman. This is a lie. Sex outside of marriage becomes an expression of selfishness, lack of self-control, and lack of concern for the other person. These actions will bring you unhappiness and are condemned by God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p39" pid="VMnIu-qVJkyI8kMw94PoLA" hash="0Wn_eA">Protect the chastity of young women as you would protect your own life. We hold you priesthood bearers responsible, first and foremost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p40" pid="CVRJd4uEFEadC8Nw3fQljw" hash="R5y0aw">Live a morally clean life. Make that winning point for righteousness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p41" pid="4itEgOxkAku7ytlnEI69tw" hash="GFr-_A">Point number five is to <span class="emphasis">live a life of service and Church activity.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p42" pid="2MISFPRxV0Oey6PQBoWndQ" hash="n7VLjA">Be committed to activity in the Church and balance this with service. Service opens windows in your life instead of just mirrors that always reflect yourself.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p43" pid="_vIFFLAmYUKKJ2nefZAHsg" hash="M4v_Mw">Do more than just attend your meetings—get involved in living and enjoying the gospel. Be a loyal and supportive member of your Aaronic Priesthood quorum and prepare well for the day when you will hold the Melchizedek Priesthood, the priesthood after the order of the Son of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p44" pid="ZldXh4aGo0ur3Ya0ZR6TFQ" hash="MNqCEQ">Of deepest concern in all of your activities is whether you have private prayer, whether you read the scriptures daily as the prophet, President Benson, has asked you to do, and whether you agree with your parents and leaders about important spiritual matters. These are the kinds of things that really determine whether or not you have a testimony and the spiritual stamina to finish the game of life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p45" pid="X6ezRFjOaEGP2i8oifg1bw" hash="lbC0yQ">Now, my young friends, there will be other points you can make for righteousness, too; but I ask you, can you make these five points? Do you have the determination to do your best, to live by the rules, to strengthen your courage and testimony? I know you can. But please, wake up! You are the youth of the noble birthright.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p46" pid="k2-PoDgie0qaCU2Ziw7xUw" hash="bPmqgg">There may be some among you who have fouled out. You’ve broken the rules, gotten offsides, moved before the snap, fumbled the ball. The ball—the gospel—is in your hands. Know that a loving Heavenly Father understands your weaknesses and wants you back on his team. Talk to your bishop. He will help you come back. You are needed and loved.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p47" pid="ZU8L9tgaT0-7HfLpUyivTw" hash="TzerGQ">Now, young men, I speak as your friend, not as your judge. Practice these five points in your life. Write them down. Put them where you can see them daily. Check your progress frequently. There are points to win and blessings to obtain.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness.p48" pid="G_WDhAIiTUCcdILy8deN2g" hash="5MBOVA">You priesthood leaders and fathers, you are the home-field coaches. Review these points with these, your sons. Discuss them in depth. Help these young men work on them. Making these points will help lead them to joy and happiness and exaltation. Of this I testify, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1989/04/making-points-for-righteousness</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1989-general-conference/1989-04-3030-elder-russell-c-taylor-64k-eng.mp3" length="6704539" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 1989 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
