<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Russell T. Osguthorpe</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Russell T. Osguthorpe.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Russell%20T.%20Osguthorpe.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Russell T. Osguthorpe.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2009 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Helps Save Lives</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2009/10/teaching-helps-save-lives?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We teach key doctrine, invite learners to do the work God has for them, and then promise that blessings will surely come.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/teaching-helps-save-lives" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50019113_000_007" doc-version="2" hash="hk11zg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/teaching-helps-save-lives.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="k53sfKmxukC00OTH7wXd_A" hash="2tVwHA">Teaching Helps Save Lives</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="a_-uhUMkJE-fekxTKAWJDA" hash="1I_dsg">Russell T. Osguthorpe</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="7Xm3B4BitE2NsSBf8pu6Lg" hash="gl1zaA">We teach key doctrine, invite learners to do the work God has for them, and then promise that blessings will surely come.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/teaching-helps-save-lives.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/teaching-helps-save-lives.p1" pid="pUcXvd5Hx0WzFoUxBkLMKQ" hash="t4lh-A">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="15"></span>One day while serving as a mission president, I was talking on the phone to our oldest son. He was on his way to the hospital where he worked as a physician. When he arrived at the hospital, he said, “Nice talking to you, Dad, but now I’ve got to get out of my car and go save some lives.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/teaching-helps-save-lives.p2" pid="B4Q7srhG8UyPX7iNCyxYig" hash="eI5k8A">Our son treats children with life-threatening illnesses. When he is able to diagnose a disease properly and give the right treatment, he can save a child’s life. I told our missionaries that their work is also to help save lives—the spiritual lives of those they teach.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/teaching-helps-save-lives.p3" pid="XfctR_nXNECexMt5HeNWlg" hash="kYRyqw">President Joseph F. Smith said: “When [we receive] the truth [we] will be saved by it. [We] will not be saved merely because someone taught it to [us], but because [we] received and acted upon it” (in Conference Report, Apr. 1902, 86; see also <span class="emphasis">Teaching, No Greater Call</span> [1999], 49; <a href="/scriptures/nt/1-tim/4.16" class="scriptureRef">1 Timothy 4:16</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/teaching-helps-save-lives.p4" pid="VJoDf4FLzUOwvRotHd1Lxw" hash="It6gRA">Our son saves lives by sharing his knowledge of medicine; missionaries and teachers in the Church help save lives by sharing their knowledge of the gospel. When missionaries and teachers draw upon the Spirit, they teach the appropriate principle, invite their learners to live that principle, and bear witness of the promised blessings that will certainly follow. Elder David A. Bednar shared these three simple elements of effective teaching in a recent training meeting: (1) key doctrine, (2) invitation to action, and (3) promised blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/teaching-helps-save-lives.p5" pid="OwFFuSxy0kKARMcOPIREVQ" hash="3EqOtw">The guide <span class="emphasis">Preach My Gospel </span>helps missionaries teach key doctrine, invite those they teach to take action, and receive promised blessings. The guide <span class="emphasis">Teaching, No Greater Call </span>helps parents and teachers do the same. It is to gospel teaching what <span class="emphasis">Preach My Gospel </span>is to missionary work. We use them to prepare to teach, and then we draw upon the Spirit as we teach.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/teaching-helps-save-lives.p6" pid="9oXSMMzqq0ilfWUEqOLApg" hash="Cz7egA">President Thomas S. Monson tells of a Sunday School teacher from his youth, Lucy Gertsch. One Sunday, partway through a lesson about selfless service, Sister Gertsch invited her students to give their class party fund to the family of one of their classmates whose mother had passed away. President Monson said that in giving that invitation to action, Sister Gertsch had “closed the manual and opened our eyes and our ears and our hearts to the glory of God” (“Examples of Great Teachers” [worldwide leadership training meeting, Feb. 10, 2007], <span class="emphasis">Liahona,</span> June 2007, 76; <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> June 2007, 108). Sister Gertsch had clearly used the manual to prepare her lesson, but when inspiration came, she closed the manual and invited her students to live the gospel principle she was teaching.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/teaching-helps-save-lives.p7" pid="3jTUyAP78kuaifBOKlxrpw" hash="hTAq4A">As President Monson has taught: “The goal of gospel teaching … is not to ‘pour information’ into the minds of class members. … <span class="emphasis">The aim is to inspire the individual to think about, feel about, and then do something about living gospel principles</span>” (in Conference Report, Oct. 1970, 107).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/teaching-helps-save-lives.p8" pid="_-hOrtd8REG5va5oYfRVww" hash="lOobFQ">When Moroni appeared to the Prophet Joseph, he not only taught him key doctrines of the Restoration, but he also told him that “God had a work for [him] to do” and promised him that his name would be known throughout the world (see <a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.33" class="scriptureRef">Joseph Smith—History 1:33</a>). All parents and gospel teachers are messengers from God. Not all of us teach future prophets, as did Sister Gertsch and Moroni, but we are all teaching future leaders of the Church. So we teach key doctrine, invite learners to do the work God has for them, and then promise that blessings will surely come.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/teaching-helps-save-lives.p9" pid="UZ6KiXDzu0is9yPuhnp1Vw" hash="5NoWHA">I remember as a young boy feeling carefree as I walked to the church for a Primary meeting. When I arrived, I was surprised to see all of the parents there for a special program. Then it hit me. I had a part in this program, and I had forgotten to memorize my lines. When my turn came to say my part, I stood in front of my chair, but <span class="pageBreak" page-number="16"></span>not one word came from my mouth. I could remember nothing. So I just stood there and then finally sat down and stared at the floor.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/teaching-helps-save-lives.p10" pid="bnNCt1vThUuWO8hqQrBpLw" hash="WYBkYg">After that experience, I made a firm resolve never to speak in any Church meeting again. And I held to that resolve for some time. Then one Sunday, Sister Lydia Stillman, a Primary leader, knelt down at my side and asked me to give a short talk the following week. I said, “I don’t give talks.” She responded, “I know, but you can give this one because I’ll help you.” I continued to resist, but she expressed so much confidence in me that her invitation was hard to refuse. I gave the talk.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/teaching-helps-save-lives.p11" pid="O3V9gt8rF0O2AV_jJ4NcJQ" hash="XX9eJQ">That good woman was a messenger from God, who had a work for me to do. She taught me that when a call comes, you accept it, no matter how inadequate you might feel. As Moroni did with Joseph, she made certain that I was prepared when the time came to give that talk. That inspired teacher helped save my life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/teaching-helps-save-lives.p12" pid="lArFpG0-xEW3MheGb8pxww" hash="wBvCBg">When I was in my teens, a recently returned missionary named Brother Peterson taught our Sunday School class. Every week he would draw a large arrow from the lower left-hand corner of the blackboard pointing to the upper right-hand corner. Then he would write at the top of the blackboard, “Aim High.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/teaching-helps-save-lives.p13" pid="UfVfxROLzEKOwJidvC1n_A" hash="JUTnaw">Whatever doctrine he was teaching, he would ask us to stretch ourselves, to reach a little higher than we thought was possible. The arrow and those two words, <span class="emphasis">aim high, </span>were a constant invitation throughout the lesson. Brother Peterson made me want to serve a good mission, to do better in school, to set my sights higher for my career.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/teaching-helps-save-lives.p14" pid="ul4DHLkm0EOBYKggeU8idg" hash="tstK_A">Brother Peterson had a work for us to do. His goal was to help us “think about, feel about, and then do something about living gospel principles.” His teaching helped save my life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/teaching-helps-save-lives.p15" pid="Ukz8LvU-7US3XKTS_De-RQ" hash="WgY8Lw">At the age of 19, I was called to serve a mission in Tahiti, where I had to learn two foreign languages—French and Tahitian. Early in my mission, I became very discouraged at my lack of progress in either language. Every time I tried to speak French, people responded in Tahitian. When I tried to speak Tahitian, they answered in French. I was on the verge of giving up.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/teaching-helps-save-lives.p16" pid="YxRkp4adX0O0MeKZvrQW-Q" hash="mCvF0w">Then one day, as I was walking past the laundry room at the mission home, I heard a voice calling me. I turned around and saw a gray-haired Tahitian woman standing in the doorway motioning for me to come back. Her name was Tuputeata Moo. She spoke only Tahitian. And I spoke only English. I missed much of what she was trying to tell me, but I did understand that she wanted me to return to the laundry room every day so she could help me learn Tahitian.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/teaching-helps-save-lives.p17" pid="X1xcuYo2I0KQEmzOfGsMaQ" hash="L0E8yQ">I stopped by daily to practice with her while she ironed clothes. At first I wondered if our meetings would be of any help, but gradually I began to understand her. Each time we met, she communicated to me her complete confidence that I could learn both languages.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/teaching-helps-save-lives.p18" pid="RZ84sFDw5Eaze2th-mT_wg" hash="38YLRg">Sister Moo helped me learn Tahitian. But she helped me learn much more than that. She was really teaching me the first principle of the gospel—faith in the Lord Jesus Christ. She taught me that if I relied on the Lord, He would help me do something I thought was impossible. She not only helped save my mission—she helped save my life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/teaching-helps-save-lives.p19" pid="dTmeP_ttM0mvOD4bbO3TCQ" hash="xmFzuA">Sister Stillman, Brother Peterson, and Sister Moo taught “by persuasion, by long-suffering, by gentleness and meekness, and by love unfeigned; by kindness, and pure knowledge, which shall greatly enlarge the soul” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.41-42" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:41–42</a>). They taught with virtue <span class="pageBreak" page-number="17"></span>garnishing their thoughts, and because of that, the Holy Ghost was their constant companion (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.45-46" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:45–46</a>).</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/teaching-helps-save-lives.f2">
	<p pid="IUS0KAhVeUCp1YBH7HECJg" hash="6orYBw">These great teachers have inspired me to ask questions about my own teaching:</p>
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="-b4_fZfjnEuzBOZRhjGaPQ" hash="WyMQtA">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="9C3jnKlAUkiF-DMWVNDJdQ" hash="4kNJZw">As a teacher, do I view myself as a messenger from God?</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="OVHncB76iE-nnpfG1TT2-A" hash="MC8PoQ">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="ihWW9NPFJk20gVPsuayFsA" hash="bTLfQg">Do I prepare and then teach in ways that can help save lives?</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="eGTqz1GAhkOlQq09qtfJCA" hash="4vzkHQ">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="dJFtVuvOTEqVRBhj5ewZVQ" hash="B0lZLA">Do I focus on a key doctrine of the Restoration?</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="aEeRU-lJzUyrw4O9dTm_yg" hash="hMlthw">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p pid="Hhqzn9lgb0qDTA7uuwzAWg" hash="3mtBYw">Can those I teach feel the love I have for them and for my Heavenly Father and the Savior?</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="RGAERhxm-0-wpDDwOnpdLA" hash="_k9UaA">
          <span class="label">5.</span>
          <p pid="N9MoSsv6r0qG-rDWKAmIAA" hash="tHpfpA">When inspiration comes, do I close the manual and open their eyes and their ears and their hearts to the glory of God?</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="xAKoArAClUmxHYIMOKaiFw" hash="N86lZg">
          <span class="label">6.</span>
          <p pid="Gsi-PekRD0uPJhlyz5Ns4A" hash="FEjN1g">Do I invite them to do the work that God has for them to do?</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="W8M5uAnqX0epjB9pnrRACQ" hash="4ukXJg">
          <span class="label">7.</span>
          <p pid="GOGJxOuKdkewoPpguzm_TA" hash="A14f5w">Do I express so much confidence in them that they find the invitation hard to refuse?</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="b3FWC0rPJU2yyUiU9rm94g" hash="i8U7Aw">
          <span class="label">8.</span>
          <p pid="7pX2wVbXBE-K2fJoT6JNzw" hash="UBv_iw">Do I help them recognize promised blessings that come from living the doctrine I am teaching?</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/teaching-helps-save-lives.p20" pid="Wv9I9aj-H0aamUBgpScYGg" hash="5fMUSw">Learning and teaching are not optional activities in the kingdom of God. They are the very means by which the gospel has been restored to the earth and by which we will gain eternal life. They provide the pathway to personal testimony. No one can be “saved in ignorance” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/131.6" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 131:6</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/teaching-helps-save-lives.p21" pid="Tag_J34dEUacYN0YDRLQcg" hash="Lx0Ilw">I know that God lives. I testify that Jesus is the Christ. I bear witness that the Prophet Joseph opened this dispensation by learning truth and then teaching it. Joseph asked one question after another, received divine answers, and then taught what he had learned to God’s children. I know that President Monson is the Lord’s mouthpiece on the earth today and that he continues to learn and to teach us as Joseph did because teaching helps save lives. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2009/10/teaching-helps-save-lives</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2009-general-conference/2009-10-1050-russell-t-osguthorpe-64k-eng.mp3" length="5007744" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2009 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Step Closer to the Savior</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2012/10/one-step-closer-to-the-savior?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Conversion is the goal of all gospel learning and teaching. Conversion is not a onetime event. It is a lifelong quest to become more like the Savior.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/one-step-closer-to-the-savior" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10491_000_53osguthorpe" doc-version="2" hash="IsEoFw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/one-step-closer-to-the-savior.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="2Xt3nYKsgkCZGAiOGlb-QA" hash="RmAkrA">One Step Closer to the Savior</h1><p class="authorName" pid="Desi6ag-D0SI00xj4Ik6kw" hash="TO9iIA">By Russell T. Osguthorpe</p><p class="kicker" pid="coxNZeTAfkOdErz4A0OPTw" hash="oKasOg">Conversion is the goal of all gospel learning and teaching. Conversion is not a onetime event. It is a lifelong quest to become more like the Savior.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" pid="YRjNGL8nbkS5OE9w2bwy2w" hash="CfsVpg">
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/one-step-closer-to-the-savior.p5" pid="5mcG9w7E0UCBf2ynmPN77g" hash="a_f7bQ">
      <span class="pageBreak" page-number="96"></span>This past summer a brief article I had written appeared in the <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and <span class="emphasis">Ensign.</span> My son emailed me saying, “Dad, maybe you could tell us when you have an article coming out.” I responded, “I just wanted to see if you were reading the Church magazines.” He wrote back explaining that his 10-year-old daughter had “passed the test. She got the <span class="emphasis">Ensign</span> from the mailbox, came into the house, and read it. Then she came up to our room and showed us your article.”</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/one-step-closer-to-the-savior.p6" pid="xzjRWcrCV02xSGwitouK4Q" hash="-zrfvQ">My granddaughter read the <span class="emphasis">Ensign</span> because she wanted to learn. She acted on her own by exercising her agency. The First Presidency recently approved new learning resources for youth that will support the innate desire of young people to learn, live, and share the gospel. These new resources are now available for review online. In January we will begin using them in classrooms. (Learn more about the new learning resources for youth at <a href="http://lds.org/youth/learn"><span class="language">lds.org/youth/learn</span></a>.)</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/one-step-closer-to-the-savior.p7" pid="el5A_VYUN06p8Qr15gMwWA" hash="88mvQw">When the Savior taught, the learner’s agency was paramount. He showed us not only what to teach but also how to teach. He focused on the needs of the learner. He helped individuals discover truth for themselves.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> He always listened to their questions.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/one-step-closer-to-the-savior.p8" pid="-fiWakGV2k2GpGwcUBp3rw" hash="SD--5A">These new learning resources will help us all learn and teach in the Savior’s way in our homes and in our classrooms.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> As we do, we will be responding to His invitation to “come, follow me,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> just as Elder Robert D. Hales so beautifully taught. While these new resources were being developed, I saw leaders and teachers in the auxiliaries and seminary counsel together with parents so that they could meet the needs of their learners. I’ve seen young women in their classes, young men in their Aaronic Priesthood quorums, and youth in Sunday School learn to exercise their agency and act for themselves.</p>
    <span class="story">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/one-step-closer-to-the-savior.p9" pid="Cy8h8_rU-0qnb3W_vQ5paA" hash="-UTxPg">One youth Sunday School teacher wondered how to help two young men with autism act for themselves. When she invited class members to share what they were learning, she worried that these two young men might refuse her invitation. But they didn’t. One stood to teach what he had learned and then invited his classmate with autism to help him. When the first began to struggle, his classmate stayed with him and whispered in his ear so that he could feel successful. They were both teaching that day. They were teaching <span class="emphasis">what</span> the Savior taught, but they were also teaching <span class="emphasis">how</span> the Savior taught. When the Savior taught, He acted out of love for the one He was teaching, just as this classmate did for his friend.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
    </span>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/one-step-closer-to-the-savior.p10" pid="L5Qi_L8kT0W9TuJzjZIveg" hash="JS7AQA">When we learn and teach His word in His way, we accept His invitation to “come, follow me.” We follow Him one step at a time. With each step, we draw closer to the Savior. We change. The Lord knew that spiritual growth did not happen all at once. It comes gradually. Each time we accept His invitation and choose to follow Him, we progress along the pathway to full conversion.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/one-step-closer-to-the-savior.p11" pid="2tlty5ywJ0W5kkSQZaQkaw" hash="PQKGbA">Conversion is the goal of all gospel learning and teaching. Conversion is not a onetime event. It is a lifelong quest to become more like the Savior. Elder Dallin H. Oaks has reminded us that “to <span class="emphasis">know</span>” is not enough. “To be ‘converted’ … requires us to <span class="emphasis">do</span> and to <span class="emphasis">become.</span>”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> So learning for conversion is a continual process of knowing, doing, and becoming. Likewise, teaching for conversion requires key doctrine, invitations to action, and promised blessings.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> When we teach true doctrine, we help the learner to know. When we invite others to action, we help them to do or live the doctrine. And when the blessings come that the Lord has promised, we are changed. Like Alma, we can become new creatures.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
    <span class="story">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/one-step-closer-to-the-savior.p12" pid="X3MYnhu9KUObnmu7E8hMTw" hash="FUCo5A">The new learning resources for youth have one central goal: to help youth become converted to the gospel of Jesus Christ. I recently saw a young man in a youth Sunday School class discover truth for himself. When I noticed that he was having difficulty <span class="pageBreak" page-number="97"></span>relating the Atonement to his own life, I asked him if he had ever felt forgiveness. He responded: “Yeah, like that time I broke a guy’s nose when we were playing soccer. I felt bad about it. I wondered what I needed to do to feel better. So I went to his home and asked him to forgive me, but I knew I needed to do more, so I prayed, and then I felt that Heavenly Father forgave me too. This is what the Atonement means to me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/one-step-closer-to-the-savior.p13" pid="1iopW9xhQU-pQeBUz4qAYg" hash="lKRZXw">When he shared this experience in class that day, he read from <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/3.16" class="scriptureRef">John 3:16</a>—“For God so loved the world, that he gave his only begotten Son”—and then testified of the power of the Atonement. This doctrine was no longer an abstract concept to this young man. It became part of his life because he asked his own question and then exercised his agency to act.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
    </span>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/one-step-closer-to-the-savior.p14" pid="FOQ89VlTNEuTWGz3jZPKBw" hash="poMn2Q">This young man was becoming more converted, and so were his classmates. They focused on a key doctrine by studying the scriptures. They related those sacred words to their own life and then testified of the blessings that had come to them as a result of living the doctrine. When we teach the gospel of Jesus Christ, we focus on the scriptures and the words of modern prophets. We draw upon sacred text to help strengthen faith, build testimonies, and help everyone become fully converted. The new learning resources for youth will help all who use them to understand and live the word of God.</p>
    <span class="story">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/one-step-closer-to-the-savior.p15" pid="gItJJZyOY0i3MYMclPC0Dw" hash="U3JFOA">While teaching the Saints in Costa Rica, I held up a copy of <span class="emphasis">Teaching, No Greater Call</span> and asked, “So how many of you have a copy of this manual?” Nearly everyone raised a hand. With a smile, I said, “And I bet you’re reading it every single day.” To my surprise, a sister on the front row raised her hand, indicating that she was reading it every day. I asked her to come to the podium and explain. She responded, “I read the Book of Mormon every morning. Then I read something in <span class="emphasis">Teaching, No Greater Call</span> so I can teach my children in the very best way what I’ve just learned.”</p>
    </span>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/one-step-closer-to-the-savior.p16" pid="tpfuPdNtFE-HOEOtCTGjqA" hash="j376bw">She wanted to learn and teach His word in His way, so she studied His word in the scriptures and then studied how to teach His word so that her children could be fully converted. Her pattern of gospel learning and teaching did not happen, I believe, all at once. She made a decision to do something. And the more she did what she knew she should do, the more the Lord strengthened her to walk in His way.</p>
    <span class="story">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/one-step-closer-to-the-savior.p17" pid="aGd4UMV_R0qlGyQYQrCoXw" hash="i_T66g">Sometimes the pathway to conversion can be long and hard. My brother-in-law was less active in the Church for 50 years. Not until he was in his 60s did he begin to accept the Savior’s invitation to come back. Many helped him along the way. One home teacher sent him a postcard every month for 22 years. But he had to decide he wanted to come back. He had to exercise his agency. He had to take that first step—and then another and another. Now he and his wife have been sealed together, and he is serving in a bishopric.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/one-step-closer-to-the-savior.p18" pid="_RIVEpHXQ0G85MTXDllt-Q" hash="QXVHng">Recently we showed him the videos that have been developed to help leaders and teachers implement the new learning resources. After watching the videos, my brother-in-law <span class="pageBreak" page-number="98"></span>leaned back in his chair and said, somewhat emotionally, “Maybe if I had had that when I was young, I wouldn’t have fallen away.”</p>
    </span>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/one-step-closer-to-the-savior.p19" pid="byFP9RRE6U6WVCYa-8QCRw" hash="RK1OMg">Several weeks ago I met a young man who was struggling. I asked if he was a member of the Church. He told me that he was agnostic but that earlier in his life he had been acquainted with the Church. When I told him about my calling in the Sunday School and that I would be speaking in general conference, he said, “Hey, if you’re speaking, I’ll watch that session.” I hope he’s watching today. I know that if he’s watching, he has learned something. This Conference Center is a unique place of learning and teaching for conversion.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/one-step-closer-to-the-savior.p20" pid="hZmx4T0p1k-i0sxsQFpH6A" hash="HkXkag">When we live the principles taught by those we sustain as prophets, seers, and revelators, we learn in the Savior’s way.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> We take one step closer to Him. As this conference draws to a close, I invite everyone in the sound of my voice to take that step. Like the Nephites of old, we can return to our “homes, and ponder upon the things which … have [been] said, and ask of the Father, in [Christ’s] name, that [we] may understand.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/one-step-closer-to-the-savior.p21" pid="8nYF1OCPL0yNGGpEsWRF_A" hash="0Cwu2g">We want every young person to understand. We want them to learn, teach, and live the gospel of Jesus Christ every day. This is what the Lord wants for all of His children. Whether you are a child, a youth, or an adult, I invite you to come and follow in His footsteps. With each step we take, I testify that the Lord will strengthen us. He will help us come the rest of the way. Then when obstacles appear, we will keep going. When doubt comes, we will keep going. We will never turn back. We will never fall away.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/one-step-closer-to-the-savior.p22" pid="VI4dDtVxLUSt8HuWCT3lnA" hash="O42hEw">I testify that God the Father and His Son, Jesus Christ, live. I testify that the Savior continues to beckon us just as He did in former times to come unto Him. We can all accept His invitation. We can all learn, teach, and live His word in His way by taking one step closer to the Savior. As we do, we will become truly converted. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2012/10/one-step-closer-to-the-savior</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2012-general-conference/2012-10-5030-russell-t-osguthorpe-64k-eng.mp3" length="5260320" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
