<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Sharon G. Larsen</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Sharon G. Larsen.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Sharon%20G.%20Larsen.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Sharon G. Larsen.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Mar 1998 18:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 1998 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Young Women—Titles of Liberty</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1998/04/young-women-titles-of-liberty?lang=eng</link>
      <description>You don’t have to be Captain Moroni to make a difference. Our Father in Heaven needs you to be who you are, in your family. He planned it that way.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/young-women-titles-of-liberty" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_98905_000_040" doc-version="2" hash="nqvgbg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/young-women-titles-of-liberty.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="L-gAnTJu1k-_T681n7mRFA" hash="IcPZyg">Young Women—</h1>
    <p class="subtitle" pid="Vhtm2QepREej-qraB-kefQ" hash="exXyxg">Titles of Liberty</p>
    <p class="authorName" pid="F3iGzO5zbES-FBOtYusQSg" hash="dXOe_w">Sharon G. Larsen</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="cUuGpy8I3kmqOQN1k42Lyg" hash="531IwA">You don’t have to be Captain Moroni to make a difference. Our Father in Heaven needs you to be who you are, in your family. He planned it that way.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/young-women-titles-of-liberty.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1d6a.jpg" alt="Sharon G. Larsen" pid="77WtTHG6_E-AgYKrMitPjQ" hash="uD4NNA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/young-women-titles-of-liberty.p1" pid="nmwGou9yt02fyzb2FQ2P2w" hash="L1nrdw">The captain of the Nephite army was angry! Amalickiah, a wicked and ambitious dissenter, was seeking to destroy the homes and families and country of the righteous Nephites. Captain Moroni took his coat and tore it to make a banner. On the coat he wrote these words, “In memory of our God, our religion, and freedom, and our peace, our wives, and our children” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/46.12" class="scriptureRef">Alma 46:12</a>), and he fastened this piece of his coat on the end of a pole. He called this banner “the title of liberty.” It was hoisted upon every tower which was in all the land—a reminder to protect their families from wicked intruders.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/young-women-titles-of-liberty.p2" pid="aXizZjZY10ipvzbXlFXPMA" hash="KMLuig">Young women, you are like titles of liberty as you strive to protect your families from such intruders as selfishness, harshness, anger, and strife. Your banner stands for peace and love and service to your families.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/young-women-titles-of-liberty.p3" pid="k3X2of-eVke6KzgjX3EC1Q" hash="YgfqDw">Listen to the example of a young woman who wrote: “Right now in my family we are going through a tough time. I have been given the opportunity to fill my mother’s role. Sometimes I have to not participate in activities after school so I can care for my brother. Sometimes I have to not go out with my friends so that I can cook dinner or go grocery shopping.” Then she adds, “Because of this responsibility, I have learned a great deal about being a mother, growing up and taking responsibility, not only for myself but for others.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/young-women-titles-of-liberty.p4" pid="AlnOVdlqSEmnACsxYUfjXA" hash="SQDXvw">When you are carrying your title of liberty, your banner, you will find many ways to bless your family, to love your family, and to just pay attention.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/young-women-titles-of-liberty.p5" pid="JnnIigGWw0iDe9xr2VnxbA" hash="df25zg">For example, when our daughter Shelly was returning from her mission, I didn’t raise my coat on a pole, but I found a piece of red carpet long and narrow. When Shelly returned home, she walked onto a red carpet leading to the front door.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/young-women-titles-of-liberty.p6" pid="cU6OjOKSbkuuuR9btfbFaA" hash="c5TEXA">But you don’t need a red carpet or a torn coat. Sometimes just a note on a pillow or a smile or a hug is better than anything else you can think of to express love.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/young-women-titles-of-liberty.p7" pid="aSjQk6hlpU-DVFiYeJEOVA" hash="jzEB_w">Service expresses love.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/young-women-titles-of-liberty.p8" pid="KMxmZ6ywpE262kRGz1QJWg" hash="khlh5A">Lindsey was holding her banner high when she served her mother. She wrote: “My mom took a nap. I had cleaned the house. When she got up, she was surprised.” Now listen to what Lindsey said: “I had a good feeling inside.” How do you think her mother felt? How do you think Heavenly Father felt about what she did?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/young-women-titles-of-liberty.p9" pid="EmxBDRd7TEO7zajA-br5Cw" hash="PCYaOA">Young women, in my heart I roll out the red carpet for every one of you and give you a standing ovation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/young-women-titles-of-liberty.p10" pid="nPamUsRpHE-LKnuhqMb2Sw" hash="wCPqdw">You don’t have to be Captain Moroni to make a difference. Our Father in Heaven needs you to be who you are, in your family. He planned it that way. Your family wouldn’t be the same without you. You are very important.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/young-women-titles-of-liberty.p11" pid="nCLUXPcGDkC2pCV1wS8XCg" hash="OHKSaQ">I remember when I was about Beehive age (back when dinosaurs roamed the earth!), my older sister was leaving home to go away to school. I was crying inconsolably. As she tried to comfort me, she said, “Don’t cry, Sharon; I’ll be back.” With tear-stained face, I looked up at her and said, “Oh, I know you’ll be back, but who is going to mop the kitchen floor while you’re gone?” I think that’s called turning your heart to yourself!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/young-women-titles-of-liberty.p12" pid="wk0k0ypEl0OTR8q57Y7d7w" hash="virGIg">I soon discovered it was more than having the floor mopped that I would miss. We need each other. We need to stand by each other.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/young-women-titles-of-liberty.p13" pid="X3dOpD8mBUqOvyvnGIe3GQ" hash="NQfWGw">A few years later this same older sister turned her heart to me when I asked her if I could borrow her car to go visit my friends. She agreed but said that I needed to have it back by four o’clock. I happily took off. We were having such a good time, I could hardly believe it when I looked at the clock and it was six o’clock! When I ran into the house, my sister wasn’t there, but on the table was a beautiful chocolate cake, my favorite, with a note that said: “Don’t worry. I know you were having a good time. I managed to get a ride. I love you.” Now, that is turning your heart to your family, holding your banner high! She was worrying about my feelings when I was the one who had inconvenienced her!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/young-women-titles-of-liberty.p14" pid="A8f0zI6vsEO0X8CEh5ywVA" hash="Nn8bvQ">There is power between sisters. There is a power between brothers and sisters. There is a power between parents and children to sustain each other and, yes, even “save” each other.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/young-women-titles-of-liberty.p15" pid="8T5mEUUW1kS7foPRjPLFhw" hash="J663Ig">Consider the lifesaving power in this story. A few years ago, twin girls Brielle and Kyrie were born prematurely to the Jackson family. They were placed in separate incubators to reduce the risk of infection. Kyrie, the larger sister at two pounds three ounces, quickly began gaining weight and calmly slept. But Brielle, who weighed only two pounds at birth, could not keep up with her. Suddenly one day Brielle’s condition became critical. The nurse tried everything she could think of to stabilize Brielle. Still Brielle squirmed and fussed as her oxygen intake plummeted and her heart rate soared. Then the nurse remembered a procedure she had heard about. She said to the worried parents, “Let me just try putting Brielle in with her sister to see if that helps.” The parents consented, and the nurse slipped the squirming baby into the incubator with the bigger sister. No sooner had the door of the incubator closed than Brielle snuggled up to Kyrie and calmed right down. Within minutes Brielle’s blood-oxygen readings were the best they had been since she was born. As she dozed, Kyrie wrapped her tiny arm around her smaller sibling (see Nancy Sheehan, “A Sister’s Helping Hand,” <span class="emphasis">Reader’s Digest,</span> May 1996, 155–56).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/young-women-titles-of-liberty.p16" pid="v7kPnzcVWk2a5RlupVjvCw" hash="8_Zz3A">The doctors and nurses had tried every medical and scientific device available to help the baby and nothing worked. Nothing could do for the struggling baby what her own sister could do for her. This is what sisters can do for each other. This is what family members can do for each other.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1998/04/young-women-titles-of-liberty.p17" pid="pWI9OTGlQ0a1B3g2NqMTKQ" hash="06tlBQ">Young women, your life is the banner that can help to protect your families from wicked intruders. We call upon you to take a stand for kindness and goodness and service to those you love most—your families. I pray, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1998/04/young-women-titles-of-liberty</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/1998-general-young-women-meeting/1998-03-0030-sharon-g-larsen-64k-eng.mp3" length="7423188" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 1998 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Light in the Wilderness</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1999/04/your-light-in-the-wilderness?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Keep your eyes riveted on your goal … and walk in the straight and narrow path of the Son—the Son of God.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-light-in-the-wilderness" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_99260_000_038" doc-version="2" hash="0SPonA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-light-in-the-wilderness.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="q0gWjr7Pf0uOpPn3jTaRpA" hash="ITF-ig">Your Light in the Wilderness</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="qVnBqFA1W0Cv0KaUixokfA" hash="dXOe_w">Sharon G. Larsen</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="t9mZzt1wL0-FDJ9g9NLefA" hash="Z6BfZw">Keep your eyes riveted on your goal … and walk in the straight and narrow path of the Son—the Son of God.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-light-in-the-wilderness.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-a83.jpg" alt="Sharon G. Larsen" pid="3_q4MHYHuUuKlLsIrLBotw" hash="z6aU6Q" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-light-in-the-wilderness.p1" pid="TxDasTOBN0Ce7XPiiLoq8Q" hash="bYz3Hg">Knowing what you may or may not know, what would you think of an eight-year camping trip in the wilderness—no trips to town, no light, not even a fire? This describes the experience Father Lehi and his family had when they were told by the Lord to leave Jerusalem. I’ll bet there was some murmuring in the camp—and not a lot of volunteers! There were undoubtedly young women like you on this marathon trip.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-light-in-the-wilderness.p2" pid="A0Oly8zpY0yk3nsCiCiOXA" hash="3U9kQw">The Lord warned them not to make any fires. Then He taught them, “I will … be your light in the wilderness; and I will prepare the way before you, if … ye shall keep my commandments; … ye shall be led towards the promised land; and ye shall know that it is by me that ye are led” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/17.13" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 17:13</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-light-in-the-wilderness.p3" pid="jCZJbkqssEm5xpkKVlhmHQ" hash="nX_PGw">You all must have promised lands that you would like to go to, and you can have your own light in that wilderness that challenges young people today. This light comes all wrapped up in love, the Lord’s love for every one of His children, and especially for young people. The Lord knows that you face challenges and temptations, and He provides the light that brightens your hearts, your minds, and your spirits. He has said that His word is truth and truth is light and light is the Spirit of Jesus Christ (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.45" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:45</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-light-in-the-wilderness.p4" pid="sNmJwQpzsEu-J9uT1NOzqQ" hash="tVoNMw">Sunny is an exchange student from Korea. She is living in a strange new land with a new language and a new family. School was hard and she had no friends to eat with or talk with or go to school activities with. She said: “I felt so miserable. Then I started thinking about praying. I had not thought about praying for help to Heavenly Father and for comfort and faith in myself. Then I began to read the Book of Mormon every morning and pray before I went to school. School began to be much easier. I was so surprised that I could understand better! I felt like someone was helping me while I was studying” (letter in possession of Young Women office).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-light-in-the-wilderness.p5" pid="SuOsGfmQ0UmER9ND3SaR0A" hash="lXgwNA">You know, don’t you, that prayer turns on the light? When you make prayer a regular part of your life, you begin walking in the light, in the straight and narrow way.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-light-in-the-wilderness.p6" pid="p9m7WoND5UmJvI1fQUrMcQ" hash="qaxMAA">When I was about your age, I learned the importance of a straight and narrow path and how difficult it was to be focused and stay on it. I grew up in a very small town in the foothills of the Canadian Rockies. My dad was a farmer, and I learned to work! Every summer I drove the tractor for him, mowing and raking hay, hauling hay bales, and plowing fields. I remember when I first started to learn to plow and cultivate a field. Dad explained the importance of plowing a straight furrow or a straight line. If you went crooked, there would be spots missed in the field and the weeds would take over. He said: “If you will keep your eye focused on the fence post across the field and let that be your goal, you will plow a straight furrow. Don’t let the bumpy terrain throw you off. It’s when you start looking at the end of the tractor that the holes and bumps take you off course and you begin to go crooked.” Then he left me to do the job.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-light-in-the-wilderness.p7" pid="WYROJrkBHkGFUvECfRxVcQ" hash="SflB1g">I remembered about the fence post across the field for several rounds, then I started singing songs to make the time pass. I sang every song and hymn I knew, and those I didn’t know I made up. I was singing at the top of my lungs and having a good time when I noticed my dad walking through the field towards me. I stopped the tractor and he said, “Can you tell what has happened to the straight lines?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-light-in-the-wilderness.p8" pid="jPnSzHt61UGXvrE6riCHpw" hash="G39MSw">I said, “What do you mean?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-light-in-the-wilderness.p9" pid="Ih7mytyvAkK2JcMj5XLhEw" hash="W6Hl8g">He said: “Look at the line. Your first few rounds are straight, but evidently you quit paying attention to where you were plowing. You must have quit looking at the fence post across the field—your goal. Can you see that gradually each time you’ve gone around, you’ve just gone a little crooked until now there are big spots in the field?” He got on the tractor and drove a few rotations to straighten out the lines. As he got off to let me try again, he said, “Sharon, always pay attention to where you are going.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-light-in-the-wilderness.p10" pid="DUVbPBnOGESUVnuypMmvtA" hash="RnLJhg">When the pressures of the world seem to overwhelm us and we are tempted to give up what we want most for what we want now, it is difficult to pay attention, to look beyond the moment, beyond the end of the tractor. The holes and bumpy terrain, persuasion from friends who may seem to be having such a good time, can throw us off course. But the light that will help us stay on the straight path is like the goal across the field. If there are times we become distracted and tempted, the Lord will be there to help us straighten out our course. You can walk away from the darkness and come into the light—His light.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-light-in-the-wilderness.p11" pid="_mBorq-ZKkGJz3OgSADmkg" hash="qKaK_A">A young friend who did not understand the importance of having the light, having the Spirit, was trying to explain to me why he thought it was important to see some of the vulgar and violent movies on the market today. He said, “If you don’t see these things, you will be naive and uninformed and the world will take advantage of you.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-light-in-the-wilderness.p12" pid="d1Dv6M7GWE6RQE7iOSAhRw" hash="mhroDA">I asked my young friend, “Would you rather expose yourself to what the world has to offer to be informed and then left on your own to make decisions, or would you choose to be guided by the Lord and live your life to be filled with so much light and truth and goodness that there is no room for darkness?” You can’t be in the light and the dark at the same time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-light-in-the-wilderness.p13" pid="qLKs7K5UYEa4UHLKTkDFHw" hash="drKvMA">This light is symbolized in the Young Women torch. That torch you wear with your profile in the flame can fuel your desire to stand for truth and righteousness. It is a reminder that Christ is your light and He will show you the way through the happy times and the mists of darkness. You <span class="emphasis">never</span> need to feel alone or forsaken.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-light-in-the-wilderness.p14" pid="Ubejn59faE-trx5E0RRLfA" hash="AgvJeQ">Emily, a Laurel class president wanting to know the Lord’s will for one of her counselors, describes how this light feels. She said: “I prayed about a certain girl, and I had such a strong revelation—it’s like when your heart and mind make connection and everything is so clear. So I knew without a doubt that she was to be my counselor” (letter in possession of Young Women office). Prayer is what makes the connection with God’s power, which leads to loving and serving, sacrificing, and enlarging your own capacities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-light-in-the-wilderness.p15" pid="ZBfiqqHx1UKg1PKuu8OrOA" hash="5G42_Q">The brother of Jared in the Book of Mormon knew about this process. He had built eight barges, or ships, under the direction of the Lord, but they had no light in them. He called upon the Lord for help (and that’s our opportunity too). But the answer did not come in the way he was expecting. The Lord could have easily put light in those barges, but He wanted the light—the light of the Spirit—in the brother of Jared.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-light-in-the-wilderness.p16" pid="xFULY98BKEyIQWOgAdGNvg" hash="YXKA_g">What do you think the brother of Jared was doing from the time he realized the Lord was not going to give him a flashlight to the time he carved out 16 stones and asked the Lord to touch them and give them light? I think he must have done a great deal of what Sunny Kim and Emily did—fasting and praying and pondering and reading his scriptures and serving and loving and forgiving and just trying to be obedient so he would have the Spirit, the light, to direct him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-light-in-the-wilderness.p17" pid="3XUzMSo7z0GvKvoe_Mipyw" hash="ofevCw">While the brother of Jared was doing everything he knew to do, was working hard and using every resource available—especially faith in the Lord—he went to the Lord again with his idea, and his efforts were enough. The Lord touched those 16 stones and there was light (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/2.18-25" class="scriptureRef">Ether 2:18–25</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/3.1-6" class="scriptureRef">Ether 3:1–6</a>). There are always answers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-light-in-the-wilderness.p18" pid="6LmEmGauP0yMfnycBKPqqg" hash="d4L8QQ">Many young women are following this light, and the Lord is blessing them. Listen to the testimonies of some who let the Lord be their light:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-light-in-the-wilderness.p19" pid="Tr3ySgeft0y_reC41E2a9g" hash="dlxfPA">[Note: Several young women bore testimonies via videotape.]</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-light-in-the-wilderness.p20" pid="AA-B4CROqUeV5eHXBQNk7g" hash="3ZFiyw">Let the Lord be your light. Let Him prepare the way before you to your promised land. “There [is] … no life so dark [that] he cannot light” (Sam Cardon and Steven K. Jones, “Come unto Him,” <span class="emphasis">New Era,</span> Apr. 1995, 10). You don’t have to be a prophet like Lehi or the brother of Jared. Just be you—with a hunger and thirst for righteousness. Trust Him. Keep your eyes riveted on your goal across the field and walk in the straight and narrow path of the Son—the Son of God. I testify of the light and the Spirit that comes from Jesus Christ.</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-light-in-the-wilderness.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="3geuzf9TOUelT_bJx940Pw" hash="2jUyfg">
            <span class="emphasis">The Lord is my light, my all and in all.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="Pb12QH0r7USbf0F0bUbprg" hash="ZbsdFA">
            <span class="emphasis">There is in his sight no darkness at all.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="UUJZwS-9VkiAyiJI6FRYuQ" hash="0gySeg">
            <span class="emphasis">He is my Redeemer, my Savior, and King.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/04/your-light-in-the-wilderness.p21" pid="Z7DjRcynu0CwD-a-d61P7A" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1999/04/your-light-in-the-wilderness</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/1999-general-young-women-meeting/1999-03-0010-sharon-g-larsen-64k-eng.mp3" length="6955107" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 1999 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agency—A Blessing and a Burden</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1999/10/agency-a-blessing-and-a-burden?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Agency is the power to think, choose, and act for ourselves. It comes with endless opportunities, accompanied by responsibility and consequences.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/agency-a-blessing-and-a-burden" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_99265_000_006" doc-version="2" hash="3jJggg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/agency-a-blessing-and-a-burden.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="YpIZ5W4vGk68TbQHbrr1MQ" hash="y6Ayfw">Agency—</h1>
    <p class="subtitle" pid="Z6YFXQ5ZhEWmh7rnyEJrBA" hash="_fcvwQ">A Blessing and a Burden</p>
    <p class="authorName" pid="VffVWPOL30WXZK-h-StKyg" hash="dXOe_w">Sharon G. Larsen</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="E-5QMyvcTUW9BeZ0KlCENg" hash="MLNlaw">Agency is the power to think, choose, and act for ourselves. It comes with endless opportunities, accompanied by responsibility and consequences.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/agency-a-blessing-and-a-burden.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-a83.jpg" alt="Sharon G. Larsen" pid="kJ9SCvkTYUWQtF6OBg2RQA" hash="z6aU6Q" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/agency-a-blessing-and-a-burden.p1" pid="d2XGLi3SkES3pmJ8JCpV_w" hash="lXfq7g">As we left our Father in Heaven’s presence and entered this world, we brought with us a priceless, sacred, premortal, and eternal gift. It is this gift, the gift of agency, about which I wish to speak.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/agency-a-blessing-and-a-burden.p2" pid="B2O9UpHXEkivU0EEbAwAbQ" hash="64Yxlw">Agency is the power to think, choose, and act for ourselves. It comes with endless opportunities, accompanied by responsibility and consequences. It is a blessing and a burden. Using this gift of agency wisely is critical today because never in the world’s history have God’s children been so blessed or so blatantly confronted with so many choices.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/agency-a-blessing-and-a-burden.p3" pid="NzOAfks3lk-ZMDbw3yz7Fw" hash="MWjcQA">Life was simpler years ago in my hometown on the Canadian prairie. Our phone number was one digit—3. We had one black-and-white movie that came from the larger town of Cardston every Thursday night. Mail came Monday, Wednesday, and Friday—unless it snowed hard.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/agency-a-blessing-and-a-burden.p4" pid="nfQJ98mgc0iRLVCEZHN2zw" hash="ig5T3w">There was one main road. Three miles west was our farm, and 20 miles east on that same road was the Cardston Alberta Temple. There weren’t many other roads to choose or places to go.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/agency-a-blessing-and-a-burden.p5" pid="TMGNbbqGLUSEJEpDsKXAYw" hash="HaCpwA">Today there are infinite telephone numbers, movies of all kinds and colors, E-mail at our fingertips 24 hours a day, and many roads that relentlessly call for our judgment. Our environment is flooded with choices. But our purpose for being here on earth has never changed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/agency-a-blessing-and-a-burden.p6" pid="XKTInTCGAES-vzfwK2rwsA" hash="Slo8rw">The Lord told Abraham that He sent us to earth to see if we would do what He asked us to do (see <a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.25" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:25</a>). Choice becomes inescapable. The world’s two opposing forces seek our commitment. On the one hand, there is the reality of Satan, and on the other, the more powerful love of the Savior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/agency-a-blessing-and-a-burden.p7" pid="rEd3yPlG2kuQA83siGKAhg" hash="-9k1RA">Lehi teaches us that if there was no opposition, there would be no righteousness nor wickedness, neither good nor bad. We can’t act for ourselves if there is no choice (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.11,16" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:11, 16</a>). To become a committed follower of Christ, we must have the option to reject Him. So Satan is permitted to exercise his power, and yielding our will to God can sometimes become difficult. Yet it is in this exercise of acting for ourselves that we grow.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/agency-a-blessing-and-a-burden.p8" pid="cc78ZS2qUkKBAn76l7hFBQ" hash="t-ae2Q">C. S. Lewis said: “Only those who try to resist temptation know how strong it is. … You find out the strength of a wind by trying to walk against it, not by lying down. A man who gives in to temptation after five minutes simply does not know what it would have been like an hour later.” Lewis goes on, “Christ, because He was the only man who never yielded to temptation, is also the only man who knows to the full what temptation means” (<span class="emphasis">Mere Christianity</span> [1960], 109–10).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/agency-a-blessing-and-a-burden.p9" pid="bjU0vyf43UyXCU_DdZz-bA" hash="5xG8qg">I remember asking my parents if I could do certain things. Their response never varied: “You have been taught. You know how we feel about that, but you will have to decide for yourself.” Yet deciding for oneself dictates consequences, which are not always what we want. We want the freedom without consequences. And so, too often, we try to stand neutral, undecided, and uncommitted. It is in this atmosphere that we become vulnerable to the influence of Satan.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/agency-a-blessing-and-a-burden.p10" pid="V-_ShjEkzkiCiO4juDrQeA" hash="LAs4jw">King Ahab and his people in northern Israel tell us about neutrality and indecision. The Lord’s hand was stayed because the people would not decide whom to worship—Jehovah or Baal. Baal is another name for Satan. The Lord sent Elijah the prophet with this clear message: “How long halt ye between two opinions? if the Lord be God, follow him: but if Baal, then follow him.” The scriptures say, “The people answered him not a word” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/1-kgs/18.21" class="scriptureRef">1 Kgs. 18:21</a>). They didn’t want the responsibility of making a commitment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/agency-a-blessing-and-a-burden.p11" pid="MgjTNWF1n0SDTmX6INIp7w" hash="mWKvDw">You remember the story: Elijah challenged them to a test to see who is God. They would each pray to their god to see which would burn up the offering on the altar. When the priests called mightily to their idol, they were left unheard and unsupported.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/agency-a-blessing-and-a-burden.p12" pid="hnJ9O-J7j0ef6DgYbZiKbA" hash="nbU7WA">In stark contrast, one lone prophet of the true and living God was not only heard, he was magnified in his efforts. When Elijah petitioned his God, the fire of the Lord came down and consumed everything—the sacrifice, the wood, the stones, the dust—and it licked up the water in the trench. Following this exhibition, the people said, “The Lord, he is the God” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/1-kgs/18.39" class="scriptureRef">1 Kgs. 18:39</a>), and then the scriptures say the priests of Baal were killed. There were no unbelievers still alive in northern Israel that day! Choices would not be a dilemma if good were rewarded as quickly and spectacularly as was Elijah or if wrongdoing meant immediate death. But it is not that simple when our work is to increase our faith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/agency-a-blessing-and-a-burden.p13" pid="oQQCWw5inkioTXYnvkiqtQ" hash="luPHQQ">Our faith and commitment are tested when the world offers tempting and enticing alternatives that can turn our faces from the Lord’s kingdom. Some would like to live in that eternal city and still keep a “summer home” in Babylon. If we are not consciously and deliberately choosing the kingdom of God, we will in fact be moving backwards as the kingdom of God moves forward “boldly, nobly, and independent” (Joseph Smith, “The Wentworth Letter,” in <span class="emphasis">Encyclopedia of Mormonism,</span> ed. Daniel H. Ludlow, 5 vols. [1992], 4:1754). Choosing which way we face will determine our blessings or our burdens. The Lord invites us to cast our burdens on Him, and He will sustain us (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/55.22" class="scriptureRef">Ps. 55:22</a>), while Mormon warns, “The devil will not support his children” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/30.60" class="scriptureRef">Alma 30:60</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/agency-a-blessing-and-a-burden.p14" pid="8_2Q98gmxkmNMfoh41YDWA" hash="cJyDfQ">A young man I love with all my heart said to me: “No one can tell me what to do. I am in charge of my own life.” He has the mistaken idea that to be independent and free, he must oppose God’s will. Where, then, will his strength come?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/agency-a-blessing-and-a-burden.p15" pid="YB10pxBmR0Kc-wmn7l4Caw" hash="1h0ksA">Brother James E. Talmage says of Jesus: He “was all that a boy should be, for His development was unretarded by the dragging weight of sin; He loved and obeyed the truth and therefore was free” (<span class="emphasis">Jesus the Christ</span> [1979], 112).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/agency-a-blessing-and-a-burden.p16" pid="t_hwXdFKLU-kP8y5NT1QGw" hash="EA2EQw">Making right choices frees us and blesses us, even in choosing what may appear trivial in our lives. A friend thought the Lord was too involved in his life. He said, “I can’t take all those absolutes in the Church that tell me I must do this, I can’t do that.” My friend did not see that those absolutes are evidence of our Father’s vigilant care.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/agency-a-blessing-and-a-burden.p17" pid="3plvIGn-C0ySVbgvio-Lgg" hash="sw0cRw">Isn’t it incredible? There are six billion people on this planet, and Heavenly Father cares what I watch for entertainment, and He cares what I eat and drink. He cares how I dress and how I earn and spend my money. He cares what I do and don’t do. Heavenly Father cares about my happiness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/agency-a-blessing-and-a-burden.p18" pid="SZPiAw3GUUevH32--0fLKQ" hash="pc_fsQ">Our Father’s caring comes in so many ways, and we have only to listen and live for it. Someone said, “If [we] have not chosen the Kingdom of God [first], it will make in the end no difference what [we] have chosen instead” (William Law, 18th-century clergyman).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/agency-a-blessing-and-a-burden.p19" pid="ildqGEMykEqXrJCg4rmPhA" hash="3018cA">Because our purpose here on earth has not changed, nor will it ever, our Father steadily and regularly supplies additional gifts to make our world safe and strengthen our wise use of agency. Think about the gift of prayer—opportunities to be heard and understood. Think about the gift of the Holy Ghost, who will show us all the things that we should do (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/32.5" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 32:5</a>). Think about sacred covenants we have made, the scriptures, priesthood and patriarchal blessings. Think about the ultimate gift of the Atonement and its reminder in the sacrament that blankets us with love and hope and grace. These gifts help us use our agency wisely to return back to our heavenly home, where “eye hath not seen, nor ear heard, neither have entered into the heart of man, the things which God hath prepared for them that love him” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/2.9" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 2:9</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/agency-a-blessing-and-a-burden.p20" pid="SJ0T1Z9H3E2bh9WvbbTQsg" hash="5mBnIA">Today there are many roads, but like my hometown, there is only one main road, the strait and narrow.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/agency-a-blessing-and-a-burden.p21" pid="Gtg-zMIJtUGzFbANY-2Kig" hash="Ca-zrA">Acknowledging our tendency to wander in strange roads (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/8.32" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 8:32</a>), we plead to the Lord through this hymn:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/agency-a-blessing-and-a-burden.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="aaMt2O2_kkiApUNU-8KcDg" hash="3jTlkQ">
            <span class="emphasis">Prone to wander, Lord, I feel it,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="STLPx_q0GUOc_kBpVq8Rlg" hash="SPOWQA">
            <span class="emphasis">Prone to leave the God I love;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="8dRJD6Bl3kWLXXqxNDsUWg" hash="RTBuBg">
            <span class="emphasis">Here’s my heart, O take and seal it;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="9Y1k7tJ_cE23Y4IUqsOSBQ" hash="fkQVnQ">
            <span class="emphasis">Seal it for thy courts above.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/agency-a-blessing-and-a-burden.p22" pid="gHIPFvIpnUWximKENEDBiA" hash="Q3tgRw">I close with the prayer of Nephi speaking for you and for me: “O Lord, wilt thou not shut the gates of thy righteousness before me, that I may walk in the path of the low valley, that I may be strict in the plain road” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/4.32" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 4:32</a>), in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1999/10/agency-a-blessing-and-a-burden</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1999-general-conference/1999-10-1040-sharon-g-larsen-64k-eng.mp3" length="4754804" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 1999 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Standing with God</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god?lang=eng</link>
      <description>What does it mean to stand as a witness of God? It means we will not bow down or give in or be persuaded to do anything contrary to God’s will.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10033256_000_037" doc-version="2" hash="oDrvyw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="QTvTH3t8vEaUjYaUgj2qsA" hash="mRwrKA">Standing with God</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="TWHr2eFHLE6tb6hmoUh91A" hash="dXOe_w">Sharon G. Larsen</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="-8Z0952Gk0u1wn4QJQvt0A" hash="7J6ybw">What does it mean to stand as a witness of God? It means we will not bow down or give in or be persuaded to do anything contrary to God’s will.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-a83.jpg" alt="Sharon G. Larsen" pid="87uCbhoAK0uFQjJWTeB5Jg" hash="z6aU6Q" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god.p1" pid="mX3MxPC7PUuEIbqahYH_og" hash="sn8Exw">My very dear young sisters, you have just stood and in your own voices made a commitment to your Father in Heaven. What were you thinking about while you were saying the Young Women theme? What is the meaning for you of what you just said?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god.p2" pid="vbyFsIVDm02OOHT2RX9enQ" hash="Y02NVQ">Remember the story of three young men who had made such a commitment? They lived in Babylon, where people were not following the Lord. These young men, Shadrach, Meshach, and Abed-nego, stood as witnesses of God at the peril of their lives. Living under the rule of King Nebuchadnezzar, they were required by decree that on a certain day when the music started, all the people in the kingdom were to kneel and worship a solid gold 90-foot form of a man who represented the king. Anyone refusing would be thrown into a fiery furnace. There must have been thousands of people in Babylon that day for the festivities and to witness the dedication of this spectacular golden idol.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god.p3" pid="47yDz4vRAkWSanJzcxc8Hg" hash="fKw95Q">When the music began and the herald announced that all must kneel, everyone obeyed—everyone, that is, but those brave Hebrews. They refused to insult their God. Can you imagine the courage of these young men? No threats from the king could dissuade them. With faith in their God, they stood together and prayed as they were bound and carried to be burned. The furnace was so hot the men who threw them in died. King Nebuchadnezzar stood by to watch the death of these three infidels. Looking into the inferno, he asked his advisers, “Didn’t we throw three people into the fire?” They assured him indeed they had. Not quite believing what he saw, the puzzled king said: “But I see four men loose and walking in the middle of the fire, and [most puzzling of all] they have no hurt. The form of the fourth man is like that of the Son of God” (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/dan/3.24-25" class="scriptureRef">Dan. 3:24–25</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god.p4" pid="X2bXilFAo0uB-XpFj-3TBQ" hash="734d5g">Nebuchadnezzar then called to the Hebrews to come out of the furnace and declared them to be servants of the Most High God. He sent out another decree protecting Shadrach, Meshach, and Abed-nego (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/dan/3.26-30" class="scriptureRef">Dan. 3:26–30</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god.p5" pid="ZXZLXMxDd0WsoFzRe4HlBw" hash="kLZ4kA">What does it mean to stand as a witness of God? It means we will not bow down or give in or be persuaded to do anything contrary to God’s will. It means we will risk speaking up when our knees are shaking. It means we will listen and follow the still, small voice of the Holy Ghost.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god.p6" pid="FJZXdxK9X0Wt94Pb3y-v2g" hash="o7AbRw">Let’s look at an up-to-date version of another heroic Bible message:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god.p7" pid="Bc5rptgGrkWwoAJajwFIQw" hash="kilqMw">A certain girl went down from her locker toward the lunchroom and fell among thieves, who stripped her of her confidence and self-esteem when she overheard them making fun of her and of the way she dressed, and they walked off leaving her alone and friendless. And by chance there came down a certain girl that way dressed in fine clothes, and when she saw her, she passed by on the other side of the hall.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god.p8" pid="grvvreZ4n0CPF7knUKfeTQ" hash="ryYYdw">And likewise, a girl from the “in” crowd of popular girls, when she was at the place, came and looked on her and passed by on the other side without speaking.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god.p9" pid="u97JToqQIkiMXJwhqUnIzA" hash="GhHbQA">But a certain young woman came down the hall where she was, and when she saw her, she had compassion and went to her and bound up her wounds when she said, “Would you eat lunch with me?” (author’s adaptation of the parable of the good Samaritan; see <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.30-37" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:30–37</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god.p10" pid="pqtX-vxE4E-TmpCuZLot-w" hash="q80rTg">Looking more closely at this familiar parable, why didn’t the other girls stop to help? Are we so intent on our own problems that we do not notice or think anyone else has any? Do we judge the girl in need to be socially beneath us and worry what the popular kids would think if we stopped to help? Maybe the “dream guy” of the school is waiting to walk you to class and you couldn’t possibly keep him waiting!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god.p11" pid="yDCGq0MAVUWDWV_vkcEBuw" hash="1G2z6A">Each one who passed the girl in need had one question in her mind: <span class="emphasis">If I stop, what will happen to me?</span> The girl who did stop to help also had one question: <span class="emphasis">If I don’t stop, what will happen to her?</span> When we are confident of our Father in Heaven’s infinite love, we can reach out to others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god.p12" pid="g_q8NJ3OJUuUS8-ZFFdt7Q" hash="aMqB-Q">We can be a witness for God when we know Him, when we trust Him, and when we feel secure in His loving care. There are no new or easy ways we earn a relationship. It is the old ways, the tried-and-true-always-works ways: scripture study, prayer, and living those things you learn through your study and prayers. As you read the scriptures, you become acquainted with what your Father in Heaven wants for His children and how He continually reaches out to sustain and bless and forgive us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god.p13" pid="eRscW8eo9U-Vhrsi8KJ2PA" hash="AEPkEw">When you pray for personal guidance, your Father in Heaven knows what is in your heart, but He wants you to tell Him of your hopes and dreams and needs. Only when you speak with certainty that, indeed, you do want to be a witness will you know what you are going to do about it. Let God speak to you and let the sacrament take on deeper meaning. Hear these familiar words: “And witness unto thee, O God, the Eternal Father, that they are willing to take upon them the name of thy Son, and always remember him and keep his commandments which he has given them” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.77" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:77</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god.p14" pid="DlQNfEHzAEG85hE8Zsa8mA" hash="Py0t6w">We have received many letters from young women who are seriously trying to stand as a witness and say what He would say and do what He would do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god.p15" pid="Xxz6Es7H9UKObQnlzrSP_A" hash="5YGR7g">Cathy wrote a letter telling about a “good Samaritan” named Michelle. Cathy had been hospitalized much longer than she had expected to be. Some friends dwindled away, busy in their own lives; but Michelle came often and brought fun and cheer. She decorated the dreary hospital room with Mormonad posters, balloons, and other paraphernalia. One day when Cathy was particularly low, Michelle thought to bring her scriptures. Cathy said: “Bringing her scriptures and reading them to me made me want what she had. I wanted to love the scriptures like Michelle does. Without that act of kindness and caring from Michelle, my testimony wouldn’t be what it is today.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god.p16" pid="GqhnAhMkVE-mCrAcxlp3Bg" hash="pgdM0g">Standing as a witness means you know with certainty that you want to do what is right and let the consequence follow. To stand means you remain firm and immovable, even when (or especially when) you are the smallest or the youngest or the last one standing. You may be the means for holding up others. You have to be strong!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god.p17" pid="qxQK4D1WzEmRqNRLbCXWZg" hash="-SwKRA">In your mind, how will you be a witness? What is your plan? Abrey is the designated “pray-er” for her basketball team. Jenelle had the courage to leave a party showing vulgar movies. Marcie got rid of her immodest clothes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god.p18" pid="FVkq8vQRVkmti8LUivE_ww" hash="arfQmQ">Witnessing is showing by our behavior what we believe, and that can start in our own families. How cheerfully do we contribute to our family? How hard do we work to be successful in our studies? How faithfully do we respond to callings to serve? How willing are we to forgive someone who has hurt us?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god.p19" pid="piKMFkTvEkGRaD_nYY_yHQ" hash="bw65XA">The First Presidency and Quorum of the Twelve Apostles have boldly declared where they stand. Their testimony of the Living Christ, validated by each one of their signatures, is for all the world to see and know of their conviction.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god.p20" pid="vYgXzuNsmkOUnKLWeORLRA" hash="KrmP9Q">You too can be confident and powerful as a witness of God. Live the standards of the gospel of Jesus Christ. Do not compromise. You must not compromise.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god.p21" pid="tJXWI8potUW8RrO4x06X7g" hash="CyNKLA">Pay attention to those around you who give you courage and strength. The testimony of my parents has been a strength to me throughout my life. The first line of their last will and testament describes what they left for their children after their death: “We leave with you, our children, our testimony that God lives, that Jesus Christ, the Only Begotten in the flesh, also lives.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god.p22" pid="av7tym3UoUyr7706p-YW2w" hash="d8WqvQ">Their testimonies of faith in the Lord took up most of the first page of their will, and then one simple sentence followed: “Divide up the material things, and what you don’t want give to someone in need or take to the dump.” There wasn’t much to divide up, but the wealth of their testimonies made us rich indeed!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god.p23" pid="yZY-hfiP8EG-l-1-nbqJiA" hash="z9xxBQ">Mom and Dad gave us their most precious possession—their testimonies of the gospel of Jesus Christ, ending with these words: “May your hearts ever be open and your feelings tender toward these great truths, is our humble prayer.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god.p24" pid="Sib6AoOTVEGN5pSHGltHnQ" hash="2thPbA">The way you live your life every day, the words you say and don’t say, the people you help, the clothes you wear, your choice of entertainment will show your strength and courage. It will give you confidence to reach out.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god.p25" pid="PZUsAObXX0SUQrzn49GHcA" hash="z3JYAA">You don’t have the power to make rainbows or waterfalls, sunsets or roses, but you do have the power to bless people by your words and smiles and your sincere interest in them. Think of it—you carry within you the power to make the world better for someone each day! That is standing as a witness of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god.p26" pid="loGb-NXB80Ss10Bw8jvknQ" hash="BfUVFw">I know with all my being that there is no one in all time or eternity to take your place in the heart of your Father in Heaven. You can trust Him and depend on Him. There is nothing you have done or can do to separate you from His love (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/rom/8.35,38-39" class="scriptureRef">Rom. 8:35, 38–39</a>). He will never fail you or leave you alone. And in gratitude for His power and peace and joy, you resist the temptations and enticements of the world and humbly say, “With my Father in Heaven’s help, I will stand as a witness of Him at all times and in all things and in all places.” In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2000/04/standing-with-god</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/2000-general-young-women-meeting/2000-03-0010-sharon-g-larsen-64k-eng.mp3" length="5197735" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2000 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Celestial Guide</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide?lang=eng</link>
      <description>When you pray often and seek to know the Lord’s will like Nephi did, the Lord will show you the way.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029247_000_037" doc-version="2" hash="yJ4X-w">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="MRCGALFIsE6htNFULSQZkQ" hash="Ah2nPQ">Your Celestial Guide</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="hkHSSx3Hx0ebopuebxgqqg" hash="dXOe_w">Sharon G. Larsen</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="0uiaHs6y7Ua4Cfy8Qbgq6Q" hash="iiC6Mg">When you pray often and seek to know the Lord’s will like Nephi did, the Lord will show you the way.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-a83.jpg" alt="Sharon G. Larsen" pid="1g1bPoBy-0ah1w9_elPkwg" hash="z6aU6Q" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.p1" pid="tbarBi-Y_kmy8H8usmkNDQ" hash="aJdsxQ">At this time in your life, you have probably had the experience of trying to perform a task that seemed really difficult and beyond your ability or experience. And possibly while you were attempting this seemingly insurmountable task, there were some, maybe even friends, who tried to discourage you, embarrass you, and belittle you. Challenges are different for each of us, but the Source for help is the same. Let’s look at Nephi’s experience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.p2" pid="RP4wk4p6u02ebeVMeDgC9A" hash="ZGr8zg">He grew up in a desert. We don’t know if he had ever seen a ship before the Lord asked him to build a ship—a seemingly insurmountable task! But Nephi had faith the Lord would help him. He said the Lord showed him “from time to time” how he should build it (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/18.1" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 18:1</a>). Nephi tells us he did not build it like men build ships. He built it “after the manner” the Lord showed him (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/18.2" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 18:2</a>). Then he tells us how.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.p3" pid="dOu4ZhZgwEyMxGnQqUO2og" hash="QBvzFg">“I did pray oft unto the Lord; wherefore the Lord showed unto me great things” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/18.3" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 18:3</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.p4" pid="WtfXlET0z0iyoENrF5kGEg" hash="bmD80A">When you pray often and seek to know the Lord’s will like Nephi did, the Lord will show you the way. But you can be sure when you are trying your best to obey, you may face strong opposition from those wishing to discourage and dissuade you. Nephi’s dissenters were his own brothers. Think how hard that would be!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.p5" pid="cMKTjeOAi0SjhAIzEdXGEA" hash="foqDAA">At times you young women may feel you are having an experience like Nephi. The Lord has not asked you to build a ship, but to build your life. You don’t yet know what your completed mortal life looks like. But your Father in Heaven knows and can guide you one step at a time. He is asking you to build your life according to His guidelines because He is the One who created you and wants you ready to return back home with Him someday. Like Nephi, you too may have detractors and dissenters seeking to change your course, or at least slow down your progress.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.p6" pid="hrfxiIot3E-aAdPNJsQurQ" hash="qD2I8w">But you have access to the same system of communication that Nephi used. Long before e-mail and faxes, cell phones and satellite dishes, computers and the Internet, this communication with your Heavenly Father was in place. It predates every type of networking invention today. Its power extends through the cosmos.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.p7" pid="NAiouw_RbEO5R7tCxtgfTg" hash="1eoSig">Heavenly Father has given you the gift of the Holy Ghost to be available to help you whenever you earnestly seek Him. Like Nephi, you can know what to do to build according to the Lord’s plan for you. You will want to invite this power to help you navigate through the challenges of mortality until you are safely home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.p8" pid="vqEeWvWFS0C118VfwJ8YvQ" hash="TrWiyw">It requires no special equipment or experience, no social status or money for the Holy Ghost to guide you. The next time you renew your baptismal covenant by taking the sacrament, listen to the promise: when you always remember your Savior and keep His commandments, you will always have His Spirit to be with you (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.77,79" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:77, 79</a>). Think of that! With a gift so magnificent, why would we ever resist such guidance?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.p9" pid="DKIgkXRrWUaYmEndviJzPw" hash="zJrLGA">When our young daughter was practicing the piano, I suggested she play her piece over five more times to be prepared for her lesson.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.p10" pid="8j57C8a0ck27Oh7sNnSOFA" hash="o33sPw">She said, “No, Mom. Five is too many.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.p11" pid="1yEwOewSJ0C22R376nM63A" hash="5Qb0dw">I said, “Then you choose how many times you need.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.p12" pid="w9_b8Hi5Bkqo2-kLdi2OnQ" hash="tKR41Q">She said, “No. You choose—but don’t choose five!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.p13" pid="Bwm7s_tfoUW8nAquO5dbFw" hash="Re_kjA">Are we ever like that when the Spirit prompts us what to do and it isn’t easy or comfortable or popular? We say, “Please tell me again. I want to be obedient, but just tell me something a little easier—and more fun.” It can be dangerous trying to please ourselves.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.p14" pid="YW-Z3rmKqky8hY-WgfYm9A" hash="oinnsg">I remember when I was about your age wishing the Spirit would tell me something different. I grew up in a small town in Canada. There were 10 people in my high school graduating class, so I graduated in the top 10 of my class! One evening my sister Shirley and I were going to the same party at a friend’s house. Mom and Dad reminded us to come right home after the party. Shirley was a year younger than I and went with her group of friends, and I went with mine. After the party Shirley went directly home, a clear indication to Mom and Dad that the party was over. I was not as wise. With my group of friends we began driving around the exciting places in town—the grain elevators and the cemetery!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.p15" pid="CIwfRML0HE2DmsB6V7HK5Q" hash="WgSM6A">As time passed I got the strong feeling that I should be home. But how could I be the first one to say, “I have to go home”? So I didn’t. I stayed with my friends, laughing and pretending I was having a good time. The feeling that I should go home grew stronger and stronger. Finally I laughingly said to my friends, “If you see a blue car ahead, it’s just my dad looking for me.” No sooner had I said those words than there indeed was a blue car and my dad standing in the middle of the road (there wasn’t a lot of traffic), waving his arms for us to stop.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.p16" pid="3hAEXjFB70Clnsokoty9Og" hash="hD3IPA">Dad came around to the car door, opened it, and said quietly, “Sharon, you’d better come home with me.” I wanted to crawl under the floor mats of the car and never come out! How could my dad be so cruel and insensitive, and why didn’t my sister wait outside the house so Mom and Dad wouldn’t know when the party was over? I talked to my sister recently about this, and she said, “I did wait outside until I almost froze to death.” At the time I was sure it was everyone else’s fault that I was so humiliated in front of my friends!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.p17" pid="v7GNCsQW3kiVj1YhkW6Aag" hash="6WcVeQ">Through the lens of time and reality, I see more clearly what really happened. I was prompted and warned several times—not by a legion of angels or even one small angel, but a still, small voice. Actually, it was just a feeling I had. It was so subtle, so quiet that it could be easily brushed away and I could pretend it wasn’t really there—and my friends were!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.p18" pid="D9mreo3iSE2M3pNAxWaZsg" hash="vSOXeg">I had overstepped something that was expected of me. I had chosen to be popular with my friends instead of pleasing my parents and the Lord. But even when I deliberately chose not to obey, the Spirit was still there prompting me. You can’t do wrong and feel right. Pretending the Spirit isn’t prompting you when it is, is like putting the wrong answer down on a test when you know the right answer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.p19" pid="0jASRfJD20CoarL4xWChig" hash="f9ekQw">There may be times the Spirit finds it difficult to help you because maybe you are not asking for His help in your prayers, or maybe because you are not listening, or maybe the message can’t get through the loud music or the radio or video.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.p20" pid="wbMX-fM7BUaHGfTleMV31w" hash="_xdqwA">Kirstin said, “From personal experience, if we will listen to the Spirit, our lives will not be as complicated and full of temptation” (letter on file in the Young Women office). Laman and Lemuel refused to listen so many times that they were “past feeling” those sacred promptings (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/17.45" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 17:45</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.p21" pid="Pv5RDxuobk2z9PH9HAqZwg" hash="qqWexA">You might ask yourself, <span class="emphasis">How can I tell it’s the Holy Ghost teaching me and not my emotions or circumstances?</span> Think of a time when you know you felt the Spirit of the Lord. Maybe it was during testimony meeting at camp or you were with your family or you were reading the scriptures or praying. Maybe sometime during this meeting as you listen to the music or hear our prophet speak, you will feel that warmth in your heart. That is the Holy Ghost bearing witness to you. Remember, remember how the Spirit feels. Use that experience to help you identify the Spirit again and again.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.p22" pid="waLTvdkhLECI3Z5CxX2QHA" hash="6eeNmA">The Holy Ghost will teach you in different ways at different times. Nephi had to learn this. Learn how the Lord communicates with you. Amanda said: “I was sitting in seminary one day, listening to the ‘Plan of Salvation Speech’ that I had heard a million times before, but all of a sudden, it just clicked. I could kind of see in my mind everything and how it fit together. I could really feel the [Spirit of the] Holy Ghost with me and knew that everything in the gospel was true” (letter).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.p23" pid="P4ghEklP6EmBihe9ilGz0w" hash="J5DtPQ">Sometimes the prompting is no more than an uneasy feeling. One young woman said, “My stomach got a funny feeling and something was telling me to say no and walk away.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.p24" pid="jrkJoTbPBEuAo0nKC9Lmig" hash="N8DYTA">Carolani was having a particularly bad time. She said: “I asked in my mind, ‘What did Heavenly Father want me to do?’ I got the impression to read my patriarchal blessing, so I did. I cried tears of joy knowing I was someone who was loved and worth something” (letter).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.p25" pid="vle2bnjWjkmWTQ68V07mcw" hash="36zRfg">Young women, you are loved, and you are worth everything, even the life of your Savior. I saw evidence of this love in a small branch in British Columbia, Canada. We met in a little house for branch conference and in the basement for Young Women. The poster of the theme was on the wall. A doily and flowers were on a small table surrounded by four chairs. Attending were the branch Young Women president, the stake Young Women president, a general Young Women officer, and one young woman named Hawley. Also present were the influence and power of the Holy Ghost. I learned a lesson at that very moment—that the Lord was as concerned about one precious young woman as He is about the thousands of you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.p26" pid="zcZk1FNbrEKepbouwOxbHQ" hash="W33qNA">Heavenly Father’s top priority is His children. If it’s important to you, it’s important to Him. Whatever concern you have is His concern. Whatever you have a question about, the Lord knows the answer. Whatever sadness you are feeling, He knows how you feel and will ease the pain. He knows what it’s like to feel all alone. He will comfort you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.p27" pid="FnCNpuoc4EmIJvF5ltD8XA" hash="KoqCHQ">If Heavenly Father knew me growing up in a town so small it was rarely on any map, He knows you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide.p28" pid="RPyNSfF_3EmJCTdvLVTUBA" hash="aqA8SQ">If He knows one young woman in a faraway branch in British Columbia, He knows you—wherever you are. I have learned that truth for myself and bear that witness to you, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2001/04/your-celestial-guide</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/2001-general-young-women-meeting/2001-03-0010-sharon-g-larsen-64k-eng.mp3" length="5394547" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2001 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Fear Not: For They That Be with Us Are More”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2001/10/fear-not-for-they-that-be-with-us-are-more?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We are not alone in this sacred trust of parenting, loving, and leading. There is no greater joy. It is worth every sacrifice.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/fear-not-for-they-that-be-with-us-are-more" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029371_000_027" doc-version="2" hash="6tgi3g">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/fear-not-for-they-that-be-with-us-are-more.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="MD-uODlbyU-y083Wqg5iKQ" hash="1yAgWQ">“Fear Not:</h1>
    <p class="subtitle" pid="beJbIhilYEmt3DHIbR84HQ" hash="iHyyJQ">For They That Be with Us Are More”</p>
    <p class="authorName" pid="G16q8KPBT06C2uxALjsSmQ" hash="dXOe_w">Sharon G. Larsen</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="7HhakX94TkKj4NOoSqG7hg" hash="0b7sow">We are not alone in this sacred trust of parenting, loving, and leading. There is no greater joy. It is worth every sacrifice.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/fear-not-for-they-that-be-with-us-are-more.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-a83.jpg" alt="Sharon G. Larsen" pid="7QwcYZeA2kehAHan_31qHA" hash="z6aU6Q" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/fear-not-for-they-that-be-with-us-are-more.p1" pid="10aASnth1kmJaQPqWjaSAw" hash="SGJd4Q">As parents and leaders of youth, it might be easy to lose our faith and wring our hands with worry for them and the world they are living in.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/fear-not-for-they-that-be-with-us-are-more.p2" pid="3tWmMjKaJk2ydSN4ros5uw" hash="CsfFuQ">Our circumstances today are not without precedence or hope. When Enoch was the prophet, the heavens wept because of the wickedness of the world (see <a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/7.28-37" class="scriptureRef">Moses 7:28–37</a>). There is no doubt the heavens are weeping today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/fear-not-for-they-that-be-with-us-are-more.p3" pid="309jD-SBcU6A4qouO5VRew" hash="shB3jQ">Elisha the prophet was surrounded by the whole Syrian army determined to kill him. He reassured his worried and only companion, who was busy counting Syrian heads, that when we are on the Lord’s side, regardless of numbers or worldly power, we are in the majority. I testify that the consoling words of Elisha to his young friend are still true today: “They that be with us are more than they that be with them” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/2-kgs/6.16" class="scriptureRef">2 Kgs. 6:16</a>). The Lord will surround and protect our young people with chariots of fire, as He did for Elisha, in the form of parents, grandparents, aunts, uncles, neighbors, leaders, and friends who will vigorously love them and lead them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/fear-not-for-they-that-be-with-us-are-more.p4" pid="RdhYIBDVLUySvbdywyNUiA" hash="28Uevw">The past four years I have been immersed in the work of Young Women. As we cross the world visiting with them, we learn to some degree about their hopes and dreams and fears and disappointments. I echo President Hinckley’s words: this is “the best generation the Church has ever had” (<span class="emphasis">Church News,</span> 15 Feb. 1997, 3). As a whole, these young people are valiantly and energetically taking a stand for goodness and decency.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/fear-not-for-they-that-be-with-us-are-more.p5" pid="8clIZyxJYUKAsJvaxdRiUg" hash="7K0Jig">Strong and good as they are, our young people need our help. And help is available: The Young Women Personal Progress program, the Aaronic Priesthood Duty to God, the <span class="emphasis">Guidebook for Parents and Leaders of Youth,</span> and the revised <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth</span> will help parents and leaders be actively and directly involved in holding back the sliding scale of morality. Our youth want more than landlords. They want people who will love them and lead them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/fear-not-for-they-that-be-with-us-are-more.p6" pid="YCYULjut70K7BCekiYaPgw" hash="dIcKJQ">A vital part of that loving is listening. I know what listening really is, because I have had the blessed experience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/fear-not-for-they-that-be-with-us-are-more.p7" pid="itrUEJeem06fncSxYp8Yrg" hash="NCZAvw">I used to farm with my dad. I didn’t always enjoy it, but when lunchtime came we’d sit in the shade of the tall poplar trees, eat our lunch, and talk. My dad didn’t use this as a golden teaching moment to lay down the law and straighten out his daughter. We just talked—about anything and everything.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/fear-not-for-they-that-be-with-us-are-more.p8" pid="yQjzOtnTXEuBQGvbqtErbQ" hash="vW2Iow">This was the time I could ask questions. I felt so safe I could even ask questions that might provoke him. I remember asking him, “Why did you embarrass me in front of my friends last week when I had stayed out too late and you came and got me?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/fear-not-for-they-that-be-with-us-are-more.p9" pid="gLaoVzejwEKlvUqYhxYyaA" hash="U4Qjmw">His answer leads to another aspect of love. He wasn’t being arbitrary. There were certain standards of behavior I was expected to live. He said, “Having you out late worried me. Above all, I want you safe.” I realized his love for me was stronger than his desire for sleep or the inconvenience of getting dressed and driving down the road looking for me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/fear-not-for-they-that-be-with-us-are-more.p10" pid="mKOLKByVoECEMG8fsKoKcg" hash="2JKPrw">Whether it is a hayfield or other casual places, those times together can fill the reservoir for other times that may not be as idyllic and serene. Relationships stay intact with this kind of investment—in spite of hard doctrine and correction—or maybe because of it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/fear-not-for-they-that-be-with-us-are-more.p11" pid="XYBZ1rWTMk-ZfGPoyoNh5A" hash="oYTRmw">Love is listening when <span class="emphasis">they</span> are ready to talk—midnight, 6 <small>A.M.</small> on their way to seminary, or when you’re busy with your urgencies. Have you seen the Church spot on television showing a darkened bedroom? The door opens, and in walks a little girl with a book under her arm. She goes over to where her dad is sound asleep and asks, “Daddy, will you read me a story?” The dad doesn’t open his eyes; he just mumbles in his sleep, “Oh, honey, Daddy is so tired. Ask Mommy.” The little girl patters over to where her mother is sleeping and asks, “Mommy, can Daddy read me a story?” You see the dad’s eyes pop open, and the next picture shows all three of them together, and Dad is reading a story.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/fear-not-for-they-that-be-with-us-are-more.p12" pid="bbmohy-6f0CGdYOvrWpn-w" hash="-lGj7w">Loving may come naturally, but leading is a polished skill that maybe we don’t take seriously enough. We lead by example more strongly than any other way. That is a heavy burden for parents and leaders of youth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/fear-not-for-they-that-be-with-us-are-more.p13" pid="Ec1FKXuAJE-XXx_YJk1hhg" hash="GkRPCw">Can our young people tell by the way we live and talk and pray that we love the Lord? Do they know that their Father in Heaven is a God of love by the way they feel when they are with us? Can they feel secure that we will not be moved by every wind of doctrine or the craftiness of social pressure and worldly acceptance? (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/4.14" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 4:14</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/fear-not-for-they-that-be-with-us-are-more.p14" pid="_F1VF32JO0q2bnFBFpw1mA" hash="-Qff4w">If we are going to lead in righteousness, there can’t be any question where we stand. Small uncertainties on our part can produce large uncertainties in our youth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/fear-not-for-they-that-be-with-us-are-more.p15" pid="nZpm7sptR0atwD5A7GLv1w" hash="bkk2Jw">I wonder sometimes if we as mothers are the ones who make our children feel the pressure to be popular and accepted. Educating our desires so our standards are the Lord’s standards sends a clear message that in the Lord’s kingdom there are no double standards.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/fear-not-for-they-that-be-with-us-are-more.p16" pid="7m9-ql2wn0aoZbTjzOEQGg" hash="ot0B9Q">Following President Hinckley’s talk to the youth last November, a young woman reported to her mother that her Young Women leader had removed her second set of earrings. These scrutinizing young people notice. They notice how short your shorts are or if you had to tuck and pin to wear that blouse; they notice what you wear (or don’t wear) when you are working in your yard; they notice which line you are standing in at the movie theater.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/fear-not-for-they-that-be-with-us-are-more.p17" pid="wHuXE42fC0SphnnS26ccOg" hash="0QX0_Q">We have made covenants with the Lord, and leading often tests the level of our commitment to those covenants.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/fear-not-for-they-that-be-with-us-are-more.p18" pid="b5SqllOgskSfjaOX_pxdZQ" hash="c1N9NA">A young mother said, “It takes an enormous amount of time and energy to be a good parent. It is easier to let my children fall asleep in front of the television while I pick up the house and then put them to bed than it is to read the scriptures to them, have prayers and stories, and tuck them in. But they look forward to this evening ritual, and I know this investment, even when I’m too tired to move, will pay eternal dividends.” Consistent leading helps youth make wise choices, and our trust in them increases.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/fear-not-for-they-that-be-with-us-are-more.p19" pid="x6urWYOfHEaL9rn9wucTCQ" hash="TZpUbQ">I remember when I was about 16 years old overhearing Mom talking to Dad. She was concerned about some choices I was making. I was not guilty of any sin more serious than the immaturity of youth, but Mom was worried. What Dad said seared into my heart. “Don’t worry,” he said to Mom. “I trust Sharon, and I know she’ll do the right thing.” Those hours in the hayfield paid off then and there. From that moment on I was bound to those loving, trusting parents.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/fear-not-for-they-that-be-with-us-are-more.p20" pid="Yv2Dt9ivU0KK8Gy1KD4Uaw" hash="zDWOpQ">One of the greatest tests for parents and leaders is to love the one who seems to be unlovable. This is tough duty. It stretches the heartstrings and wrenches the soul. When heartbroken parents pray for help, the help often comes in the form of angel aunts or uncles, grandmas or grandpas, good friends, and leaders surrounding our loved one. They can reinforce our very message that may put our child on the track we’ve been praying for.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/fear-not-for-they-that-be-with-us-are-more.p21" pid="YS71koDv9kCHY5NmAVJhww" hash="OX1mQA">Loving wisely and leading purposefully will help stem the tide of wickedness as we prepare the next generation for the exhilarating delights of parenthood. We never forget the joys of our 12-year-old when he first passes the sacrament or hearing the sacramental prayer given in the voice of our son. How do you explain the feeling of hearing your daughter bear her testimony of the Savior or watching her receive her Young Womanhood medallion?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/fear-not-for-they-that-be-with-us-are-more.p22" pid="I25VTQ-HHEC1Bwkb7_Il-g" hash="ciPf5Q">We catch a glimpse of heaven when we are in the temple with our child who is kneeling across the altar with a worthy companion. They are prepared to start a life together of promise and accomplishments that we have helped to nurture. This is harvest time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/fear-not-for-they-that-be-with-us-are-more.p23" pid="Xe-xAT5Gz0aUH4CBXdf4oA" hash="XceBcw">I close with my testimony that we are not alone in this sacred trust of parenting, loving, and leading. There is no greater joy. It is worth every sacrifice, every inconvenient minute, every ounce of patience, personal discipline, and endurance. “If God be for us, who can be against us?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rom/8.31" class="scriptureRef">Rom. 8:31</a>). In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2001/10/fear-not-for-they-that-be-with-us-are-more</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2001-general-conference/2001-10-4040-sharon-g-larsen-64k-eng.mp3" length="4546663" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2001 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Standing in Holy Places</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2002/04/standing-in-holy-places?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Standing in holy places is all about being in good company, whether you are alone or with others.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/standing-in-holy-places" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029598_000_038" doc-version="2" hash="c9GiAA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/standing-in-holy-places.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="QJLmrYQs_0yuSBvi2HACZw" hash="JnETtA">Standing in Holy Places</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="jevIM6REfE29LBPTlQqYKQ" hash="dXOe_w">Sharon G. Larsen</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="hQMzoHJ8PUOyM60822IsCg" hash="l3pD6Q">Standing in holy places is all about being in good company, whether you are alone or with others.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/standing-in-holy-places.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-a83.jpg" alt="Sharon G. Larsen" pid="5HXrHOvM_0-RYNujRNZrPA" hash="z6aU6Q" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/standing-in-holy-places.p1" pid="1urK_NQrS0ChAs4OkPa5dA" hash="5un2Qw">It was Thursday night, Mom and Dad’s regular night to work at the Cardston temple. I was in my teens, like you young women. My grandmother, who was living with us, was away, so I would be home alone. As they left, Dad hugged me and said, “Now, Sharon, be in good company.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/standing-in-holy-places.p2" pid="Pw0nKLi0Ak-plr9tACZBLQ" hash="yXOIug">I thought, “What is he thinking? Doesn’t he know I’ll be here by myself?” And then I realized—that is exactly what he was thinking.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/standing-in-holy-places.p3" pid="49VUPrRA8UO7VDmtDK8ckg" hash="38bQfg">Standing in holy places is all about being in good company, whether you are alone or with others. It’s being where the Holy Ghost is our companion—alone or in a crowd. When we determine within ourselves that we will control our thoughts and our actions and be the best we can possibly be, the best of life will come to us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/standing-in-holy-places.p4" pid="k6nvS3V6BkCuxqGMwdK-1w" hash="M_BYSA">A holy place is where we feel safe, secure, loved, and comforted. That’s how it was in our heavenly home. Standing in holy places and being in good company bring feelings of how it must have been in that home we left behind, the home that seems so far away at times.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/standing-in-holy-places.p5" pid="uoG5YbagD0iS3Ic19GuT-g" hash="vEvH0A">Two and a half years after the Church was organized, the Lord warned Joseph Smith of wars and famines and plagues that would come because of wickedness. Then He told us how to be safe in such a world: “Stand ye in holy places, and be not moved, until the day of the Lord come” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/87.8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 87:8</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/standing-in-holy-places.p6" pid="xXQ1mzSRKUOCzwjMl1Wwfg" hash="VV6DvQ">In holy places we are protected from the almost overwhelming commotion of the world. Angels can be our companions and support (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.88" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:88</a>). The great prophet Moroni was surrounded by wickedness and the Lamanites waiting to kill anything in their path. He was alone in hiding for almost 20 years. Imagine that kind of loneliness! Yet his exquisite testimony and counsel in the last few chapters of the Book of Mormon tell us he was in the company of angels and the Holy Ghost. He was not alone. The Holy Ghost can take away the gnawing, aching feeling of loneliness or isolation or rejection and fill us with peace. He is called the Comforter—and He is that!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/standing-in-holy-places.p7" pid="3Q8yOItovEqiwEaLlHTppA" hash="bcPiaw">It is possible the loneliest times are when we are surrounded by people, even friends, who are making wrong choices, and we have to stand alone. There are some places it would not be safe for you to go even to help someone in need. The Lord said to stand in holy places. There are places where the Spirit would never be. You know where those places are. Stay away from them. Do not encourage a curiosity that ought to be stopped. Pay attention to what you are feeling so you will know when you are feeling unsure or uneasy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/standing-in-holy-places.p8" pid="gSizGziTGUy5Ood9Dk6T8Q" hash="zlVHHg">Heather told us about a time she had been invited to a party with the “popular” people of the school. As she walked in the door, the music that was blasting through the house hit her spirit. She felt sick inside. Then friends started disappearing into darkened rooms. Heather said: “At the party I soon realized I had to make a choice: either these people or my standards. I couldn’t have both. I knew I did not want the words I was hearing or the movie scenes to contaminate my thoughts, no matter how popular these people were. I knew I did not belong there. As I was waiting for my mother to come and get me, I looked out the window in the darkened night, and there shining on the hill like a beacon was the temple. It was like the Lord was reassuring me that I was doing the right thing” (used by permission; name has been changed).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/standing-in-holy-places.p9" pid="kgTl7ec6XEeI9CxXyIqj1w" hash="FULbPA">Standing in holy places helps us to become holy, but that is an acquired virtue that takes practice. Practice listening to the Spirit and being obedient. Practice being morally pure. Practice being reverent about sacred things. The Lord has told us to come unto Him and He can make us holy (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/60.7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 60:7</a>). Let Him envelop you in love and forgiveness and peace. Regardless of what is going on around you, you can practice creating an environment of your own, filled with the Spirit of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/standing-in-holy-places.p10" pid="4ayKqNhA_0uYSRN1DNZ82A" hash="M5qWoQ">Instead of asking someone else how short or tight or bare or revealing your clothes can be, <span class="emphasis">you</span> are responsible and you ask yourself, “What can I wear? How should I look and act so the Holy Ghost can be with me and Heavenly Father can bless me?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/standing-in-holy-places.p11" pid="m2Bpix2DaUSOBxtl5M2p7Q" hash="gi-lXg">It is difficult to train your desires to want goodness and beauty when the opposite confronts you constantly and appears to be so much more enticing and fun and popular.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/standing-in-holy-places.p12" pid="a-P_NNIh-kybfT11Rsg-8A" hash="o7C8EQ">When you were baptized, you made covenants to keep the commandments. Those covenants and the blessing of always having the Spirit of the Lord with you are renewed each time you worthily partake of the sacrament. It will strengthen you in the face of temptation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/standing-in-holy-places.p13" pid="Qw8hygVKSUihUisYwB6gRw" hash="XwDh5A">Our daughter brought treats to sacrament meeting to pacify her three little boys. As the sacred emblems of bread were passed down our row, Jake, then three, whispered in my ear: “Tell them we don’t need that bread. We brought our own treats.” To a three-year-old, all he saw was pieces of bread, and he thought he had something better. Identifying what is holy and educating our desires for that is vital to our happiness. A magnificent sunset or star-studded sky, a rose dripping with dew, or a baby kitten—all remind us once more that the things of God are holy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/standing-in-holy-places.p14" pid="TGr6m1Csr06UmY1-x3Ds_w" hash="ptoqcw">Holy places can be wherever you are—alone, in a crowd, with strangers, with friends. The road to Jericho was treacherous and formidable. Thieves infiltrated the bushes and trees waiting to ambush any traveler. It took a kind and courageous Samaritan to change that road from a haunted place to a holy place. There are things you can do to bring holiness to ordinary places: when you spend an afternoon with small children so a tired mother can rest, when you do the dishes for your brother even though it’s his turn, when you clean house for an elderly friend—these things bring feelings of selflessness and sacrifice and holiness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/standing-in-holy-places.p15" pid="ycMpKwqfy0ucVB1HEUXr9A" hash="yRW1wQ">There will be times when the Spirit will whisper that you can make the place where you are better. The Russian town of Omsk in Siberia appeared to me to be rather cold and barren until I heard a group of young women and young men singing “How Great Thou Art” (<span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 86) in their native language. Suddenly the whole world—or at least our world—became warm and loving and joyful, a holy place.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/standing-in-holy-places.p16" pid="ogRYf-WjfUSUfUbKwaUKlw" hash="Qyw0iA">There is a great wealth of intelligence and guidance and safety available to you through regular, thoughtful prayer and scripture study. This keeps your minds firm and steadfast in holy places as you walk the halls at school or shop for clothing or surf the Internet. President James E. Faust said, “I believe reading the scriptures is the best washing machine for unclean or uncontrolled thoughts” (“The Power of Self-Mastery,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 2000, 44).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/standing-in-holy-places.p17" pid="h5SceoODm0SjvdR5IBCQbA" hash="U3hLhQ">Holiness is quiet and gentle, easily missed if we aren’t paying attention. The resurrected Lord walked to Emmaus with two men who were so caught up in the events of His Crucifixion and Resurrection that they did not know it was the Lord Himself who was their walking companion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/standing-in-holy-places.p18" pid="h-8g5G9d_UeDVqCATEY92w" hash="5ElRMQ">Years ago I was singing Handel’s <span class="emphasis">Messiah</span> with a group of people from different faiths. Even though our beliefs were different, we were all singing about the same Messiah, our own personal Savior. I had sung this oratorio many times, but during one particular practice, the Spirit told me that I was not only singing notes, I was singing my testimony: “Surely, he hath borne our griefs, and carried our sorrows” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/53.4" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 53:4</a>). I knew with all my soul that He had done that for me. For a moment the 300 other voices became a whisper and I felt like I was all alone with the Lord. I felt His love and reassurance that He had carried the griefs and the sorrows of my teenage heart, and through my obedience, He would continue to walk with me for the rest of my life. To feel that blessing and comfort and complete love from the Lord is worth any price.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/standing-in-holy-places.p19" pid="piuqzGs2L0mmgmXq1EhwKQ" hash="wEpbeA">Once you understand what holy places are, then you know where to be. It may take sacrifice of our worldly tastes or popularity. It may require humility and forgiveness or complete repentance. It does require “clean hands, and a pure heart” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/24.4" class="scriptureRef">Ps. 24:4</a>). Do whatever you have to do to be able to stand in holy places and be not moved, to stand for truth and righteousness, regardless of shallow enticements and evils and designs of conspiring people (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/89.4" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 89:4</a>) and media. In the words of President Hinckley, “Stand a little higher and let the nobility of good character shine through [your] lives” (“A Time of New Beginnings,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 2000, 88). My dear young women, invite the Lord to walk with you. Let Him be your companion all of your life, every day of your life, so you can return to that home you long for, the holiest place of all.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/standing-in-holy-places.p20" pid="mfb8OTbwTU6mTCCzRYhweQ" hash="5bOa0w">I close with a hymn echoing my prayer for you and for me:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/standing-in-holy-places.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="x_79OCeNHECVGahtPeqygQ" hash="0Ssg2A">
            <span class="emphasis">More purity give me,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="2zb3Xzzl1kGQgxABLzjg6g" hash="UM168g">
            <span class="emphasis">More strength to o’ercome,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="tK5IQMG-KEC5isUb0Kwhxw" hash="7OabDQ">
            <span class="emphasis">More freedom from earth-stains,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="OgTtkYrBekO8SPRsCz53eA" hash="OFRXCA">
            <span class="emphasis">More longing for home.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="JrSZ7gFiNkOVYFaQKoFBPw" hash="vl2YDg">
            <span class="emphasis">More fit for the kingdom,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="bNYXAqq-pEy4JkPdWEE-wQ" hash="PzAmYQ">
            <span class="emphasis">More used would I be,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="jEXgxsYXHUmvAjojYjRsYQ" hash="hRhYTQ">
            <span class="emphasis">More blessed and holy—</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="D8D8L9YlTU-DZW9ACOgWbg" hash="gHmXWg">
            <span class="emphasis">More, Savior, like thee.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/standing-in-holy-places.p21" pid="L545AYUeKUyuGuV5Y5Uwmw" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2002/04/standing-in-holy-places</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-young-women-meeting/2002-general-young-women-meeting/2002-03-0010-sharon-g-larsen-64k-eng.mp3" length="5269866" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2002 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
