<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Spencer J. Condie</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Spencer J. Condie.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Spencer%20J.%20Condie.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Spencer J. Condie.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Mar 1990 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 1990 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Some Scriptural Lessons on Leadership</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I wish to extend a warm welcome to the new members of the Church who “are no more strangers and foreigners, but fellowcitizens with the saints, and of the household of God.” (.)</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_90905_000_015" doc-version="2" hash="DfHu4Q">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="3B-q_YLXkk2Cr--iTsF_hQ" hash="pdKOtg">Some Scriptural Lessons on Leadership</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Aisavyf2_E6nB1sEyud3Gg" hash="Xa3bRQ">Spencer J. Condie</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/ensignlp.nfo-o-2372.jpg" alt="Elder Spencer J. Condie" pid="8fXO899RQ0WIMmvKhNlKQQ" hash="SvS-Cw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership.p1" pid="ZCFMctsgNECDJTgF1gCoeQ" hash="zk9Law">I wish to extend a warm welcome to the new members of the Church who “are no more strangers and foreigners, but fellowcitizens with the saints, and of the household of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/2.19" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 2:19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership.p2" pid="hVg1ESQ9a02WWnZ3Qo4d0w" hash="QYoZyA">Inasmuch as many of you newly baptized members will soon be called to serve as leaders at different times in various Church callings, I would like to share some short scriptural lessons on leadership.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership.p3" pid="n9FutiLrX0uAPmBWKxEDYw" hash="qSyn8Q">In the Pearl of Great Price we learn that as Moses was called to become a prophet of God, he was taken to a mountaintop, where he beheld a panoramic view of all of God’s wondrous creations. Jehovah gave him a vision of his immediate goal, which was to “deliver my people from bondage.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.26" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:26</a>.) The Lord then explained his long-term goal: “This is my work and my glory—to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.39" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:39</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership.p4" pid="9k2TscQ1uk6XMYvaL4aj7Q" hash="8Ym05g">From the Book of Mormon we read of the young prophet Nephi who also beheld a vision on a mountain. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/11.1" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 11:1</a>.) Once he had envisioned the promised land, he could not be dissuaded from building a ship that would take him there. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/17.title" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 17–18</a>.) Once parents have a vision of a son dressed in a missionary suit or of a daughter in the temple dressed in white, then family home evening, family prayer, and scripture study assume their proper place in every home. From Moses and Nephi we learn that <span class="emphasis">a leader must have a vision of the work which lies ahead.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership.p5" pid="6699My-yPEeBmNhEpOaZPw" hash="6iRkTg">Following the Great Exodus from Egypt to the land of promise, the children of Israel were governed by judges for a period of more than three centuries (1429 to 1095 <small>B.C.</small>). These judges were then succeeded by a series of kings, the first of whom was Saul, anointed by the prophet Samuel. (See <a href="/scriptures/ot/1-sam/8.title" class="scriptureRef">1 Sam. 8–10</a>.) For decades Saul enjoyed the adulation and support of the people. But then, lifted up in the pride of his heart, he disregarded the counsel of the Lord’s prophet. At that point Samuel reminded him of the time when he was little in his own sight (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/1-sam/15.17" class="scriptureRef">1 Sam. 15:17</a>) and taught him that immortal lesson: “To obey is better than sacrifice” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/1-sam/15.22" class="scriptureRef">1 Sam. 15:22</a>). From Saul’s life we learn that <span class="emphasis">a leader must be humble and obedient.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership.p6" pid="2P0FVa-kHUOq_f5QbE5VKg" hash="B8J_MQ">Saul was succeeded by King David, whose forty-year reign is considered by many to be the golden age of Israelite history. Indeed, Jerusalem became known as the City of David. But notwithstanding his great leadership abilities, he was tempted to commit a very grievous sin, which he then compounded with an even greater sin. From King David’s life we learn that even kings must be careful. <span class="emphasis">Leadership positions do not totally protect us from temptation.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership.p7" pid="35OO5SY-JUiyMdKpGJt5Rw" hash="Cy7w2Q">Following the death of David, his son Solomon ascended to the throne. At the beginning of his reign, Solomon prayed in deep humility: “O Lord my God, … I am but a little child. … Give therefore thy servant an understanding heart to judge thy people.” And God <span class="emphasis">did</span> give him “a wise and an understanding heart.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/1-kgs/3.7,9,12" class="scriptureRef">1 Kgs. 3:7, 9, 12</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership.p8" pid="dxKM-PUOdEmdmVbCsZKFgw" hash="yQSLUg">Armed with the Spirit of the Lord, Solomon became God’s instrument in building the holy temple for which Israel had hoped and prayed for many generations. But with the passage of time Solomon took him wives outside of Israel “and his wives turned away his heart” and he “did evil in the sight of the Lord.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/1-kgs/11.3,6" class="scriptureRef">1 Kgs. 11:3, 6</a>.) From Solomon we can learn that <span class="emphasis">knowledge and wisdom alone do not qualify people to lead.</span> Perhaps Jacob said it best: “To be learned is good if they hearken unto the counsels of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/9.29" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 9:29</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership.p9" pid="mzkSW_MoSUOolNdRbsWqcw" hash="gdifCw">After Solomon’s forty-year reign, his son Rehoboam went to Shechem to be made the king. He sought the counsel of the elders regarding how he should rule. “And they spake unto him, saying, If thou wilt be a servant unto this people this day, and wilt serve <span class="emphasis">them,</span> and answer <span class="emphasis">them,</span> and speak good words to <span class="emphasis">them,</span> then <span class="emphasis">they</span> will be <span class="emphasis">thy</span> servants for ever.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/1-kgs/12.7" class="scriptureRef">1 Kgs. 12:7</a>; italics added.) The Savior gave his disciples similar counsel when he taught them, “If any man desire to be first, the same shall be last of all, and servant of all.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/9.35" class="scriptureRef">Mark 9:35</a>.) Within the kingdom of God, <span class="emphasis">to lead is to serve.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership.p10" pid="z8dR0VmjF0ygw9pU9RcgjQ" hash="V-zbFQ">But Rehoboam rejected the counsel which required him to humble himself and to serve others. Instead, he chose to reign over Israel with a very heavy hand, thus causing a great division into the northern Kingdom of Israel and the southern Kingdom of Judah. (See <a href="/scriptures/ot/1-kgs/12.20" class="scriptureRef">1 Kgs. 12:20</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership.p11" pid="r8vWoaJaC0WuLyZyWc6MMQ" hash="kapJAg">For the next 220 years the people generally set aside their sacred covenants, thus wandering in the ways of the world. Then a young man named Hezekiah began to reign in Judah. “And he did that which was right in the sight of the Lord,” and “He trusted in the Lord God of Israel.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/2-kgs/18.3,5" class="scriptureRef">2 Kgs. 18:3, 5</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership.p12" pid="DFqgHuRTLkO4qEJbR57KSA" hash="IPwlnA">Hezekiah gathered together the priesthood bearers of the day and said, “Hear me, ye Levites, sanctify now yourselves, and sanctify the house of the Lord God of your fathers, and carry forth the filthiness out of the holy place.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/2-chr/29.5" class="scriptureRef">2 Chr. 29:5</a>.) “Be not ye like your fathers, and like your brethren, which trespassed against the Lord God … but yield yourselves unto the Lord, … and serve the Lord your God.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/2-chr/30.7-8" class="scriptureRef">2 Chr. 30:7–8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership.p13" pid="7expr6vn6keMmKmqQDTYRw" hash="ivX9dA">In response to this assertive leader, who was supported by the prophet Isaiah, “the Lord hearkened to Hezekiah, and healed the people” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/2-chr/30.20" class="scriptureRef">2 Chr. 30:20</a>), and “in their set office they sanctified themselves in holiness” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/2-chr/31.18" class="scriptureRef">2 Chr. 31:18</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership.p14" pid="-ycHS-_0R0GF-vmKE3aNUA" hash="vj4zAw">From King Hezekiah, as from King Benjamin (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/2.title" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 2–5</a>), we can learn a very positive lesson on leadership: circumstances do not always need to remain the same. Leaders <span class="emphasis">can</span> make a difference! <span class="emphasis">Faith in the Lord and high expectations can bring about a mighty change of heart</span> among an entire people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership.p15" pid="YvIqYEimtUqF9afRVvZ4Cg" hash="p_jaBQ">One of the great teachers and prophet-leaders in Israel was Ezra, who “had prepared his heart to seek the law of the Lord, and to do it, and to teach in Israel statutes and judgments.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ezra/7.10" class="scriptureRef">Ezra 7:10</a>.) As Saints of the latter days, we are grateful for a modern-day Ezra, even our beloved prophet, Ezra Taft Benson, who, like Ezra of old, has prepared himself to receive the word of the Lord and is prepared to do the Lord’s will. I bear you my witness that there is a living prophet in Israel today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership.p16" pid="SyoZX3VofUWxmDSngNvD7g" hash="duiIIA">Another great leader who continually sought the will of the Lord was the Prophet Joseph Smith. His very life exemplified Paul’s admonition to live the gospel that we preach. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/9.14" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 9:14</a>.) A great strength of the Prophet was his ability to delegate and develop leadership skills in those around him. The expedition of Zion’s Camp is but one example of Joseph’s leadership based upon the principle “Come Follow Me.” (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/18.22" class="scriptureRef">Luke 18:22</a>.) At the conclusion of Zion’s Camp, the Prophet gave the newly organized high council detailed instructions regarding their callings and then told them, “If I should now be taken away, I [have] accomplished the great work the Lord [has] laid before me.” (<span class="emphasis">History of the Church,</span> 2:124.) Long before his martyrdom the Prophet Joseph was diligently training those who would continue to lead the kingdom after he was gone. Here is another important lesson of leadership: <span class="emphasis">Leaders are duty-bound and obligated to prepare others to take their place</span> at some future time. Brothers and sisters, the cemeteries are filled with leaders who thought they were indispensable.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership.p17" pid="Ava5qqJIVEayuDYIOyH0gA" hash="Q6A0SA">Among the most righteous and effective leaders to ever walk the earth was Enoch, who persistently sought to save every single soul.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership.p18" pid="fDvQfuhD-kuJ1qRTsXYwQw" hash="mecjbA">“And the Lord called his people Zion, because they were of one heart and one mind, and dwelt in righteousness. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership.p19" pid="EtXn7baT7U6cR1GMVNe8bQ" hash="PpmgrQ">“And lo, Zion, in process of time, was taken up into heaven.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/7.18,21" class="scriptureRef">Moses 7:18, 21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership.p20" pid="2qcyC-UpCEeTyRr1rYq84g" hash="cy7HRg">Note the reference to the “process of time.” A great leader must have high expectations, tempered with patience. In section 107 of the Doctrine and Covenants we learn that Enoch was “four hundred and thirty years old when he was translated.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/7.49" class="scriptureRef">Moses 7:49</a>.) Brothers and sisters, I rest my case: <span class="emphasis">perfection takes a long, long time.</span> But still, we are commanded to become perfect, even as our Father in Heaven is perfect. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.48" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:48</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/12.48" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 12:48</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership.p21" pid="tamiD0cKVkyPOR8G_K_aYA" hash="yzIf9A">From the most exemplary life of all, even that of the Savior Jesus Christ, we learn perhaps the most important lesson of all. As the Savior was in the depths of suffering in the Garden of Gethsemane, he prayed that the bitter cup might pass from him, adding in meekness and lowliness of heart: “Nevertheless not <span class="emphasis">my</span> will, but <span class="emphasis">thine,</span> be done.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/22.42" class="scriptureRef">Luke 22:42</a>; italics added.) <span class="emphasis">A leader in the Lord’s kingdom must be meek and lowly of heart.</span> (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/37.34" class="scriptureRef">Alma 37:34</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership.p22" pid="bH1Bhl9gVEGZ-AqR62zE0g" hash="n4XwZA">May each of us engaged in the work of the Lord perform <span class="emphasis">His</span> work in <span class="emphasis">His</span> way, “by persuasion, by long-suffering, by gentleness and meekness, and by love unfeigned;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership.p23" pid="EwsnGklERUyOSEjf2kQSHw" hash="sfpzMA">“By kindness, and pure knowledge …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership.p24" pid="doQEyjogeE-f1r_3VNiHaA" hash="w3aU_g">“Reproving betimes with sharpness, when moved upon by the Holy Ghost; and then showing forth afterwards an increase of love.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.41-43" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:41–43</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership.p25" pid="pbm_W-a4vU2PhR1kKHN0zA" hash="pKpM-A">I humbly pray, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1990/04/some-scriptural-lessons-on-leadership</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1990-general-conference/1990-04-2060-elder-spencer-j-condie-64k-eng.mp3" length="4473460" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 1990 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Mighty Change of Heart</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart?lang=eng</link>
      <description>A few years ago, as Sister Condie and I exited the Tabernacle, a lovely sister approached us and said with a very cheerful voice, “Good morning, President Hinckley.” I replied, “I’m sorry to disappoint you, my dear, but I’m Elder Condie of the Sevent</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_93911_000_008" doc-version="2" hash="60Qalg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="2x_lfQKkMEaE8miZNhoKKg" hash="XfY-tw">A Mighty Change of Heart</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="t_VWQuHNbECz2d2erf0_rg" hash="Xa3bRQ">Spencer J. Condie</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2372.jpg" alt="Elder Spencer J. Condie" pid="2uh20yPu9ka3O3WhppIlIQ" hash="SvS-Cw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.p1" pid="1GTgqm_CBkCd1SvB-5eipA" hash="a5zPmQ">A few years ago, as Sister Condie and I exited the Tabernacle, a lovely sister approached us and said with a very cheerful voice, “Good morning, President Hinckley.” I replied, “I’m sorry to disappoint you, my dear, but I’m Elder Condie of the Seventy.” Her cheerful countenance was crestfallen. Not more than a minute later, we met another sister who greeted us with the same salutation: “Good morning, President Hinckley.” Not wishing to cause her the same disappointment I caused the previous sister, I shook her hand and said, “Bless you, my dear. Have a nice day.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.p2" pid="mxMWF_V0_Umix5GK5ckTDA" hash="OJMTWA">Several months later I confessed my sin to President Gordon B. Hinckley during a regional conference in Portugal, and in his typically loving way he said, “Well, Spencer, if you’re going to impersonate me, I hope you behave yourself.”</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="7qxnP0dcTUm5y4HxciRe7Q" hash="YuqcQw">Be Ye Perfect</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.p3" pid="fOnNZfhe2EeROW3XeHxWuQ" hash="655FGg">The Savior has given each of us the soul-stretching commandment not only to behave ourselves but to become perfect, even as He and His Father are perfect (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.48" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:48</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/12.48" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 12:48</a>). Sometimes this quest for perfection tries our patience and our faith as we continue to wrestle with the weaknesses of the flesh. But a loving Heavenly Father has not left us alone in our battle with the adversary. A recurrent doctrine of the Book of Mormon is that the Holy Ghost is an active participant in our lives, influencing us for good. Both Nephi and Mormon teach us that the Holy Ghost <span class="emphasis">strives</span> with us to help us resist evil (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/26.11" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 26:11</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/morm/5.16" class="scriptureRef">Morm. 5:16</a>). King Benjamin exhorts us to yield to the <span class="emphasis">enticings</span> of the Spirit in order to overcome the natural man, who is an enemy to God (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/3.19" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 3:19</a>). Amulek admonishes us to “<span class="emphasis">contend</span> no more against the Holy Ghost” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/34.38" class="scriptureRef">Alma 34:38</a>; emphasis added), and Moroni assures us that the Holy Ghost <span class="emphasis">persuades</span> us to do good (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/4.11" class="scriptureRef">Ether 4:11</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.p4" pid="2YT0p3ftVU2YAnwI1g0yqg" hash="1MyabA">The words <span class="emphasis">strive, entice, contend,</span> and <span class="emphasis">persuade</span> are all very strong action verbs indicating a positive influence which the Holy Ghost can have in our lives by actively helping us in our quest for perfection. But Lucifer, whose mischief always leads to misery, persistently tries to distract us from reaching our eternal goal. The devil uses thousands of different tactical temptations, but I would submit that all of these temptations could be subsumed within two major satanic strategies.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="ixgx3vhAVEy6jyKq7bEvZg" hash="rRmetA">Pride and Discouragement</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.p5" pid="DUcseRsedkOmL2wvWEzFxw" hash="8VxsLA">The first of these is pride, described by our beloved President Ezra Taft Benson as “the … stumbling block to Zion” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1989, p. 7). Satan’s second major strategy is discouragement, which leads to a loss of faith and hope and patience. Both of these nefarious strategies of the adversary are resistant to change. To the proud, change is threatening because it will require a broken heart and a contrite spirit, a meek and a lowly heart.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.p6" pid="qFHwiioCBkmYSSDQInSx7w" hash="CofM1A">To those who are discouraged, there is the feeling that “there is nothing I can do to change myself or my circumstances.” Whether Satan afflicts us with pride or discouragement, the outcome is largely the same—we begin to accept ourselves as we are, declaring, “That’s just the way I am.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.p7" pid="I1623PsajEemsn7T3i1wig" hash="J6o5xg">One of the powerful doctrines of the Book of Mormon is that we <span class="emphasis">can,</span> indeed we <span class="emphasis">must,</span> undergo a mighty change of heart (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/5.2" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 5:2</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/5.14" class="scriptureRef">Alma 5:14</a>). The Book of Mormon also teaches us that “wickedness never was happiness” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/41.10" class="scriptureRef">Alma 41:10</a>) and that “men are, that they might have joy” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.25" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:25</a>). The journey from wickedness to joy requires a mighty change of heart.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.t4">
        <h3 class="title" pid="RCI5TEvQWkG1irnfoMGuTA" hash="_hqMcg">Overcoming Evil Habits</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.p8" pid="aC6WtqFoIECb0rd_Gg69VA" hash="IrJsvQ">I have a longtime friend who owned a very successful business. Occasionally, to find relief from the stress of his responsibilities, he would partake of substances forbidden by the Word of Wisdom. As the stress in his life increased, so did his consumption of alcohol. Indeed, he was becoming a prisoner to alcohol.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.p9" pid="S1S4NAhC-UqNwlDK2cj7DA" hash="-TvyUA">One afternoon he felt the enticings of the Spirit prompting him to overcome this addiction, which had begun to impair his moral agency. He left his office for several hours and drove to a very secluded spot far removed from the city. There he knelt in humble prayer and pled with the Lord with all the energy of his heart for added strength to overcome this addiction, which robbed his spirituality and threatened to destroy his very soul. He remained on his knees for a very long time, and eventually a sweet, purifying spirit began to distill upon his soul, cleansing him from any desire to drink and fortifying him with a firm resolve to keep the commandments.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.p10" pid="ywAsp8Q6nEu81KJCA8P5UA" hash="jyDPTQ">A spiritually sensitive bishop noticed a change in my friend and extended a call for him to work with the young Aaronic Priesthood brethren of the ward. He was a natural, enthusiastic leader of youth, and about a year later he was called to be the new bishop, dearly loved by all for his ability to counsel those who were prisoners of sin.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.p11" pid="V-bX4vnGFEaA_uDEWqNtnA" hash="o148yA">President Joseph Fielding Smith taught us: “Habits are easily formed. It is just as easy to form good habits as it is to form evil ones” (<span class="emphasis">New Era,</span> July 1972, p. 23).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.p12" pid="TYL1wo9Oj0uKumJCY1KqmQ" hash="k5Eo7w">I know another good man who was reared in a family without the blessings of the gospel. Through a series of unfortunate events in his early youth, he was introduced to homosexuality, and gradually he became a prisoner of this addictive behavior.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.p13" pid="zCzvB_6osk2ltxOqkx-E4A" hash="2lHl6g">One day two young missionaries knocked on his door and asked if he would be interested in learning of the restored gospel of Jesus Christ. In his heart of hearts he wanted to be freed from his prison of uncleanness, but feeling unable to change the direction his life had taken, he terminated the missionary discussions. Before leaving his apartment, the two elders left a copy of the Book of Mormon with him, and testified of its truthfulness.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.p14" pid="Z7tAavdivEuUZVJsYKUL_w" hash="8_neWg">My friend placed the book on his bookshelf and forgot about it for several years. He continued acting out his homosexual tendencies, assuming that such relationships would bring him happiness. But alas, with each passing year, his misery increased.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.p15" pid="dgkmHWfoQU2rOYGU4o9ryQ" hash="4dc8fw">One day in the depths of despair, he scanned his bookshelf for something to read which might edify and uplift him and restore his self-worth. His eye caught hold of the book with a dark-blue cover, which the missionaries had given him several years before. He began to read. On the second page of this book, he read of Father Lehi’s vision in which he was given a book to read, and “as he read, he was filled with the Spirit of the Lord” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/1.12" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 1:12</a>). And as my good friend continued reading, he too was filled with the Spirit of the Lord.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.p16" pid="JNveZ1NOKkSGg8TQp5EUNQ" hash="fHbuCg">He read King Benjamin’s benedictory challenge to undergo a mighty change of heart—not a little change, but a mighty change. He was given hope by the comforting conversion stories of Enos, Alma, Ammon, and Aaron. He was also inspired by the account of the Savior’s visit to the ancient Nephites. By the time he reached the final page of the Book of Mormon, he was prepared to accept Moroni’s loving invitation to “come unto Christ, and be perfected in him, and deny yourselves of all ungodliness” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.32" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 10:32</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.p17" pid="PKYCarM2l0qEOC26vvs8rw" hash="ut_JrA">My friend contacted the Church and was taught the gospel and was baptized. Within a relatively short time, he married a lovely young woman, and they are the parents of several beautiful children. He and his wife are very dynamic and committed servants of the Lord, influencing many others for good.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.t5">
        <h3 class="title" pid="orYeom7BoU-c11fhf3LHYw" hash="o4YPnQ">Strengthening Marriages</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.p18" pid="C_ffvtuJrESi6shhV1lUEQ" hash="DQzm8Q">Sometimes people not only become prisoners to addictive behaviors, but they may also begin to feel like prisoners within a marriage relationship.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.p19" pid="WqB4ejyCAUOvmFAZZZ9nHA" hash="fWU2Vg">A few years ago my wife, Dorothea, and I were walking across the grounds of a temple in a foreign land when we met a very radiant, cheerful, silver-haired sister. Her cheerful, Christlike countenance seemed to set her apart from those around her, and I felt inclined to ask her to explain why she looked so happy and content with life.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.p20" pid="E8nWVMLoDkOmd27K6bPpcg" hash="YfY_xQ">“Well,” she said with a smile, “several years ago I was in a hurry to get married, and quite frankly, after a few months I realized I had married the wrong man.” She continued, “He had no interest in the Church as he had initially led me to believe, and he began to treat me very unkindly for several years. One day I reached the point where I felt I could go on no longer in this situation, and so in desperation I knelt down to pray, to ask Heavenly Father if He would approve of my divorcing my husband.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.p21" pid="sPaFcisC-EuR9bqJyYuDyQ" hash="TQrPdQ">“I had a very remarkable experience,” she said. “After I prayed fervently, the Spirit revealed a number of insights to me of which I had been previously unaware. For the first time in my life, I realized that, just like my husband, I am not perfect either. I began to work on my intolerance and my impatience with his lack of spirituality.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.p22" pid="aDxlh9JXN0SRj8FPoxDrww" hash="_FK2dA">“I began to strive to become more compassionate and loving and understanding. And do you know what happened? As <span class="emphasis">I</span> started to change, my <span class="emphasis">husband</span> started to change. Instead of my nagging him about going to church, he gradually decided to come with me on his own initiative.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.p23" pid="TbGOHfV_l0at50hZUJJwZQ" hash="QTUGNw">“Recently we were sealed in the temple, and now we spend one day each week in the temple together. Oh, he’s still not perfect, but I am so happy that the Lord loves us enough to help us resolve our problems.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.p24" pid="nwKGvGSOy0-kIcwQHsZMcQ" hash="efdVCw">President Benson has said, “Pride is concerned with <span class="emphasis">who</span> is right. Humility is concerned with <span class="emphasis">what</span> is right.” When we humble ourselves, the Spirit will always tell us what is right.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.p25" pid="Pik9PqTwLUie7I9Ip5PVEw" hash="tiRg2Q">In the Doctrine and Covenants the Lord promised us, “The power of my Spirit quickeneth all things” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/33.16" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 33:16</a>). Through the instrumentality of the Holy Ghost, His Spirit comforts those who mourn, teaches and testifies to those who thirst for the truth, purifies the brokenhearted who would be clean, and warns of dangers which lie ahead.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.t6">
        <h3 class="title" pid="d5Vs_lqHj02YPJD7VvK62Q" hash="2o3Y4Q">A Warning Voice</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.p26" pid="TPkrKsk6c0eL9B9lXtzySw" hash="raccjg">In January of 1975, on a dark, rainy night in Tasmania, a 7,300-ton barge smashed into two piers of the Tasman Bridge, which connects Hobart, Tasmania, with its eastern suburbs across the bay. Three spans of the bridge collapsed. An Australian family by the name of Ling were driving across the bridge when suddenly the bridge lights went out. Just then a speeding car passed them and disappeared before their very eyes. Murray Ling “slammed on his brakes and skidded to a stop, one yard from the edge of a black void” (Stephen Johnson, “Over the Edge!” <span class="emphasis">Reader’s Digest,</span> Nov. 1977, p. 128).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.p27" pid="_mNo2_e3xUiNcMV-pXebrQ" hash="J9LTJQ">Murray got his family out of the car and then began warning oncoming traffic of the disaster ahead. As he frantically waved his arms, to his horror, a car “swerved around him and plummeted into the abyss” (ibid.). A second car barely stopped in time, but a third car showed no sign of slowing down and crashed into the Lings’ car at the edge of the bridge.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.p28" pid="x_urD2gB6kGqJBDr57qfhw" hash="__xF3A">Suddenly a loaded bus headed toward Murray, ignoring his waving arms. In desperation, risking his very life, he “ran alongside the driver’s window. ‘There’s a span missing,’ he yelled” (ibid., p. 129). The bus swerved just in time and came to a halt against the railing. Dozens of lives had been saved.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart.p29" pid="Am6xjCZM7U223ISetZicAQ" hash="Rh_W-A">I am grateful for these Brethren whom we sustain as prophets, seers, and revelators who forewarn us of bridges not to be crossed. These great men whom we sustain as prophets, seers, and revelators preach “not with enticing words of man’s wisdom, but in demonstration of the Spirit and of power” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/2.4" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 2:4</a>). Their motives are pure as they strive to build the kingdom of God and to uplift and edify the Saints of God. In the words of the Apostle Paul, they have become “prisoners of Christ” (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/3.1" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 3:1</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/4.1" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 4:1</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/philem/1.1,9" class="scriptureRef">Philem. 1:1, 9</a>; <a href="/scriptures/nt/2-tim/1.8" class="scriptureRef">2 Tim. 1:8</a>), whose only desire is to do the Lord’s will. Nothing more. Nothing less. And nothing else. <span class="emphasis">These are men of God!</span> May we heed their warning voices, I humbly pray in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1993/10/a-mighty-change-of-heart</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1993-general-conference/1993-10-1060-elder-spencer-j-condie-64k-eng.mp3" length="5954765" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 1993 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a Great Benefit to Our Fellow Beings</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2002/04/becoming-a-great-benefit-to-our-fellow-beings?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I pray that you wonderful young men will not only be worthy to receive ministering angels, but that you … will become a ministering angel in the lives of others.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/becoming-a-great-benefit-to-our-fellow-beings" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029598_000_019" doc-version="2" hash="PUNWBQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/becoming-a-great-benefit-to-our-fellow-beings.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="SjzcpyEqUkyleyrtmYdLMA" hash="Gbf4HA">Becoming a Great Benefit to Our Fellow Beings</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="izhNmr-EVUCrIavtFFIvQA" hash="Xa3bRQ">Spencer J. Condie</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="WmjPBzm9aEyyYL2j3skbzg" hash="2yTTIg">I pray that you wonderful young men will not only be worthy to receive ministering angels, but that you … will become a ministering angel in the lives of others.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/becoming-a-great-benefit-to-our-fellow-beings.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-623.jpg" alt="Elder Spencer J. Condie" pid="b76WiViwNkWtaszxxW1Pwg" hash="FSlFIQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/becoming-a-great-benefit-to-our-fellow-beings.p1" pid="S1Oq3RpaGkC4PRpl2sD_0g" hash="twC8TQ">As a young man of 27, Wilford Woodruff was ordained a priest on November 5, 1834. Eight days later he began a two-year mission in the southern states.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> One night he and his companion found lodging with a family who provided them with a bare floor for a bed, which he described as “pretty hard after walking sixty miles without anything to eat.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/becoming-a-great-benefit-to-our-fellow-beings.p2" pid="ZKaAj2E5QkGuMBAF_Zzp_Q" hash="jgHxfQ">The next day they walked 12 miles through the rain until they came to the house of a man who happened to be a member of the Missouri mob. Brother Woodruff said: “The family were about to sit down to breakfast as we came in. In those days it was the custom of the Missourians to ask you to eat even though they were hostile to you; so he asked us to take breakfast, and we were very glad of the invitation. He knew we were Mormons; and as soon as we began to eat, he began to swear about the Mormons. He had a large platter of bacon and eggs, and plenty of bread on the table, and his swearing did not hinder our eating, for the harder he swore the harder we ate, until we got our stomachs full; then we arose from the table, took our hats, and thanked him for our breakfast. The last we heard of him he was still swearing. I trust the Lord will reward him for our breakfast.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/becoming-a-great-benefit-to-our-fellow-beings.p3" pid="WYaT1bHJ0kyuDg14JAA7Pw" hash="uFAMtQ">At the end of the first year of that mission he recounted that he had “traveled three thousand two hundred and forty-eight miles, held one hundred and seventy meetings, [and] baptized forty-three persons.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/becoming-a-great-benefit-to-our-fellow-beings.p4" pid="ZsR6o5fFaUyQ5YRmrQ625Q" hash="EcJWkA">His first mission to the southern states was followed by two brief missions to the Fox Islands off the coast of Maine,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> and then subsequently two missions to England.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> During his latter mission in England, in 1840, he acknowledged that, “through the blessings of God,” he had been an instrument in bringing over 1,800 souls into the Church within a period of eight months.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/becoming-a-great-benefit-to-our-fellow-beings.p5" pid="G_dLakchPUS1EWo5bwTA1g" hash="dBdX6Q">Wilford Woodruff claimed the Book of Mormon promise that “God has provided a means that man, through faith, might work mighty miracles; therefore he becometh a great benefit to his fellow beings.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> My young brethren of the Aaronic Priesthood, I would remind you that our Father in Heaven not only wants you to be good, but to be good for something, to serve and bless the lives of others, and to become a benefit to your fellow beings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/becoming-a-great-benefit-to-our-fellow-beings.p6" pid="51Pp3Vr4-0yFz1Wbj-Qhgw" hash="bsP_kw">We read in the Gospel of Luke that “Jesus increased in wisdom and stature, and in favour with God and man.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> Inasmuch as our earthly quest for perfection involves becoming more like the Savior, then we, too, should increase in wisdom and stature, and in favor with God and man.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/becoming-a-great-benefit-to-our-fellow-beings.p7" pid="uAcnU8iZbEaQXPFpXr6sJQ" hash="W908mg">Priesthood quorum activities and Mutual activities with the young women, when carefully and prayerfully planned and discussed in the bishopric youth committee,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> will help every young man and young woman to grow in wisdom as they gain a greater appreciation for the scriptures and the words of the living prophets and as they participate in Mutual activities involving “anything virtuous, lovely, or of good report or praiseworthy.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/becoming-a-great-benefit-to-our-fellow-beings.p8" pid="z4vadjww00yT3BVWe1We3g" hash="BsCyhw">Counseling together in the bishopric youth committee also provides valuable training for an entire generation of future leaders who learn to work effectively together in councils.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/becoming-a-great-benefit-to-our-fellow-beings.p9" pid="rkilfhKh-0uJA3T57X5I_w" hash="2WQaVQ">You young men will grow in stature and physical strength as you engage in folk dancing, sports, and wholesome, friendly athletic competition characterized by good sportsmanship. You will grow in favor with God as you engage in family history research, perform baptisms in the temple for deceased ancestors, become a faithful home teacher, frequently clean the chapel, visit nursing homes, and help beautify your communities. As you do so, you will exemplify King Benjamin’s counsel that “when ye are in the service of your fellow beings ye are only in the service of your God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> A wise youth leader will place less emphasis on fund-raising activities and a much greater emphasis upon rendering selfless service to others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/becoming-a-great-benefit-to-our-fellow-beings.p10" pid="FNf8hwh4tUCiBKK0pye_nA" hash="UPMBbg">You young men will increase in favor with man and become better prepared for missions, marriage, and future employment as you learn more about various careers and develop greater self-confidence through giving speeches, participating in original one-act plays, and talent shows.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/becoming-a-great-benefit-to-our-fellow-beings.p11" pid="YfGhO6G2Ak6IgoUkqNZOXA" hash="UAHShA">Our youth activities should reflect our belief that “men are, that they might have joy,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> and we should be willing to share that joy with others. Not long ago I met a woman from the East who is now living in the Salt Lake Valley. She is a devout member of another Christian church, and I asked her how she enjoyed living among the Latter-day Saints. She said: “My husband and I get along fine, but I worry about our teenage daughter. Each Wednesday evening about seven o’clock, several girls in our neighborhood walk right past our home headed somewhere together, and not once have they stopped to invite our 14-year-old daughter to go with them.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/becoming-a-great-benefit-to-our-fellow-beings.p12" pid="H2ZSt6ZZVkKb1v9SxqKmXg" hash="Q_a29A">I said, “My dear, this is your lucky day; I am in a position to get that problem fixed.” She readily gave me her daughter’s name and address, and we made contact with both the stake president and the seminary principal.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/becoming-a-great-benefit-to-our-fellow-beings.p13" pid="eRTvUQ05AkSM7JzTPlbZ_Q" hash="1fm-aQ">Our friends and neighbors are children of a loving Father in Heaven who desires that all of us return to Him. Can we be content when not all the members of our quorum are in attendance Sunday morning? Surely we can extend ourselves to the less active and those of other faiths and warmly invite them to our Young Men and Young Women Mutual activities, seminary, Sunday School classes, and sacrament meetings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/becoming-a-great-benefit-to-our-fellow-beings.p14" pid="bEAj2LpLNkSOEWhL7FoRtw" hash="PUZhFQ">When Joseph Smith and Oliver Cowdery received the Aaronic Priesthood under the hands of the resurrected John the Baptist, they received “the keys of the ministering of angels,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> and so did you when you were ordained. I pray that you wonderful young men will not only be worthy to <span class="emphasis">receive</span> ministering angels, but that you, like young Wilford Woodruff, will <span class="emphasis">become</span> a ministering angel in the lives of others as you exercise your faith in working “mighty miracles,” thereby becoming a “great benefit” to your fellow beings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/becoming-a-great-benefit-to-our-fellow-beings.p15" pid="4NV7BWZzmk6dkKUS1J0t5w" hash="p5k6Fw">Satan would diminish your faith and dilute your priesthood power to work mighty miracles, but a loving Heavenly Father has provided you with providential protection—the gift of the Holy Ghost. In the first chapter of the Book of Mormon we learn that as Lehi read the scriptures “he was filled with the Spirit of the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> Nephi later promises us that as we “feast upon the words of Christ … the words of Christ will tell [us] all things what [we] should do.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/becoming-a-great-benefit-to-our-fellow-beings.p16" pid="EfUyMYX9FEW_iEunK2ns0g" hash="iY9oow">You may be facing decisions regarding a mission, your future career, and, eventually, marriage. As you read the scriptures and pray for direction, you may not actually see the answer in the form of printed words on the page, but as you read you will receive distinct impressions, and promptings, and, as promised, the Holy Ghost “will show unto you all things what ye should do.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/becoming-a-great-benefit-to-our-fellow-beings.p17" pid="mzrZvhokHEuvu4dTK90qEQ" hash="QmPNzw">Satan would have you surrender your moral agency to various forms of addictive behavior, but a loving Heavenly Father has promised you through His prophet Isaiah that through sincere fasting, as you subdue your physical appetites, He will help you “loose the bands of wickedness” and “break every yoke.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> Claim that promise through fasting. Our emptiness will provide more room for the fulness of the gospel. The hollowing precedes the hallowing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/becoming-a-great-benefit-to-our-fellow-beings.p18" pid="8Dp0M0h-Vku9jtId2WvfLQ" hash="qPGHJg">Scripture study and fasting, preceded and followed by prayer, really can “change the night to day.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> The entire life of the Prophet Joseph Smith demonstrates the power of prayer and the fulfillment of the Lord’s promise that “if thou shalt ask, thou shalt receive revelation upon revelation.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> One important revelation you will receive will be insight into how you can best touch the lives of others who have lost their way. In so doing, it is well to remember President Hinckley’s wise counsel: “The Holy Ghost is the Testifier of Truth, who can teach men things they cannot teach one another.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/becoming-a-great-benefit-to-our-fellow-beings.p19" pid="ZTylmRv3ZkyTXY5ihGoVbw" hash="-fxtFw">President Gordon B. Hinckley considers good friends to be one of the key ingredients in retaining new converts and in reclaiming the less active, and Robert Browning eloquently described how this is so:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/becoming-a-great-benefit-to-our-fellow-beings.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="ZGiF4NQplkabB1x8jSJphg" hash="2u7vug">
            <span class="emphasis">… Were I elect like you,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="iSVY23WQ60O42lpQ9Sw9zg" hash="KbnkTQ">
            <span class="emphasis">I would encircle me with love, and raise</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="Fw-59oJcrUaHuL50rPomZA" hash="J70cng">
            <span class="emphasis">A rampart of my fellows; it should seem</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="H5nl0IYf-Eenbj5x7qjHpA" hash="rlNOFw">
            <span class="emphasis">Impossible for me to fail, so watched</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="gJTpXnthyEegneqFYyC-hg" hash="OVfuKA">
            <span class="emphasis">By gentle friends who made my cause their own.</span>
            <span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/becoming-a-great-benefit-to-our-fellow-beings.p20" pid="mUvXbjLE202RIMZXdPtUcg" hash="Z3RE9w">Late in life, as President of the Church, Wilford Woodruff declared: “It does not make any difference whether a man is a Priest or an Apostle, if he magnifies his calling. A Priest holds the keys of the ministering of angels. Never in my life, as an Apostle, as a Seventy, or as an Elder, have I ever had more of the protection of the Lord than while holding the office of a Priest. The Lord revealed to me by visions, by revelations, and by the Holy Spirit, many things that lay before me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/becoming-a-great-benefit-to-our-fellow-beings.p21" pid="y3vUSE8RvUeXnJCLfn_RNA" hash="qSFucw">My young beloved brethren, I pray that each of us, through our faith, will use our priesthood power to work mighty miracles through sharing the gospel and serving others, thereby becoming a great benefit to our fellow beings, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2002/04/becoming-a-great-benefit-to-our-fellow-beings</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2002-general-conference/2002-04-3030-elder-spencer-j-condie-64k-eng.mp3" length="4939900" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2002 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Claim the Exceeding Great and Precious Promises</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The Lord makes generous promises, and He certifies that He will not vary from these promises.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00008332_000_007" doc-version="2" hash="9gTcbQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="mRYlDoDSlE6Zv1eIZWxOWg" hash="bPictQ">Claim the Exceeding Great and Precious Promises</h1><p class="authorName" guid="1c7150db-3dd8-46db-bbfb-36062c4f5a02" pid="fFetC6mQoUa7-8hV7Ow3jg" hash="Xa3bRQ">Spencer J. Condie</p><p class="kicker" pid="ADTezmzmWkeL8Rrwk3lrDw" hash="ht0VYg">The Lord makes generous promises, and He certifies that He will not vary from these promises.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="da5ac558-cc6b-4359-8c34-d03e09ef1b43">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises.t1">
      <img src="CondieSJ_all.ob.jpg" alt="Elder Spencer J. Condie" guid="6476a958-1375-4b06-984f-e2d5367d44cb" pid="jV6qQPDopkmsf3Wt0yFvgA" hash="FqQ-Ng" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises.p" pid="vVadWxlCNEaIM_WCxfhjXQ" hash="Lq4uxA">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="16"></span>I bring you the love and greeting of the faithful Saints in the South Pacific.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises.p" pid="LKeJKBwpWUmZ7DLRPi-54w" hash="jPyYRg">The first principle of the gospel is faith in the Lord Jesus Christ. This includes faith in His divine birth and heavenly heritage and faith that, under His Father’s direction, He created the earth and all things that dwell therein (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/1.10" class="scriptureRef">John 1:10</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/3.8" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 3:8</a>). At the very heart of our faith in Christ is the assurance that through His atoning sacrifice, though our sins may be as scarlet, they can become as white as snow (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/1.18" class="scriptureRef">Isaiah 1:18</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises.p" pid="EFhQfTezNUqepc2sRIIlDA" hash="97ouzw">Faith in Christ includes the knowledge that following His Crucifixion, He arose from the tomb, and His Resurrection made it possible for all mankind to live again (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/15.21-23" class="scriptureRef">1 Corinthians 15:21–23</a>). Faith in Christ is the assurance that He and His Heavenly Father appeared to a young man, Joseph Smith, paving the way for the Restoration of all things in the dispensation of the fulness of times. Jesus Christ is the head of the Church, which bears His holy name.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises.p" pid="_ip_iSeobkO_jELDyxhcZQ" hash="cx-toQ">Faith in the Lord Jesus Christ is evident when we believe His teachings and claim His “exceeding great and precious promises” and become “partakers of the divine nature” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-pet/1.4" class="scriptureRef">2 Peter 1:4</a>). Innumerable promises are proclaimed by His prophets, and the Lord assures us, “My word shall not pass away, but shall all be fulfilled, whether by mine own voice or by the voice of my servants, it is the same” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.38" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:38</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises.p" pid="BX7QIIUq6kalUNlxtdyxRw" hash="-uRo7w">In these latter days, the Lord revealed that “when we obtain any blessing from God, it is by obedience to that law upon which it is predicated” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/130.21" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 130:21</a>). The Lord makes generous promises, and He certifies that He will not vary from these promises, for, said He, “I, the Lord, am bound when ye do what I say; but when ye do not what I say, ye have no promise” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/82.10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 82:10</a>).</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises.t2" guid="0dc94521-1179-4dda-b922-4f64f9400917">
        <h3 class="title" guid="db0a234e-1fa9-4c36-8e13-5cd1c8e00c24" pid="S4RGXbS-aky-_T7t9DBFjA" hash="pxRI6A">Exceeding Great and Precious Promises</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises.p" pid="59c1Wopv3Eu2UsQL1U8ozA" hash="5dKB8w">The Lord’s countless exceeding great and precious promises include forgiveness of our sins when we “confess them and forsake them” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.43" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:43</a>; see also <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.32" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:32</a>). Opening the windows of heaven is a promise claimed by those who pay a faithful tithe (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/mal/3.10" class="scriptureRef">Malachi 3:10</a>), and finding “great treasures of knowledge” accrues to those who observe the Word of Wisdom (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/89.19" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 89:19</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises.p" pid="vjSd1WfMRkOh_cRz3li7SQ" hash="SnAdwQ">Becoming unspotted from the world is a promise to those who keep the Sabbath holy (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/59.9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 59:9</a>; <a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/31.13" class="scriptureRef">Exodus 31:13</a>). Divine guidance and inspiration are promised to those who “feast upon the words of Christ” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/32.3" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 32:3</a>) and who “liken all scriptures” unto themselves (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/19.23" class="scriptureRef">1 Nephi 19:23</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises.p" pid="L_TOCSvJbkGmGbWYTiRrtg" hash="yPHcWw">The Lord also promised that “whatsoever ye shall ask the Father in my name, which is right, believing that ye shall receive, behold it shall be given unto you” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/18.20" class="scriptureRef">3 Nephi 18:20</a>). We are promised that the Holy Ghost will be our constant companion when we “let virtue garnish [our] thoughts unceasingly” (see <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.45-46" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:45–46</a>). We can claim the spiritually liberating promise of fasting, which will “loose the bands of wickedness,” undo our “heavy burdens,” and “break every yoke” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/58.6" class="scriptureRef">Isaiah 58:6</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises.p" pid="KoobR8iu2EKcWBRADh0-jw" hash="zTlA0Q">Those who are sealed in holy temples and who faithfully keep their <span class="pageBreak" page-number="17"></span>covenants will receive God’s glory, which “shall be a fulness and a continuation of the seeds forever and ever” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/132.19" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 132:19</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises.p" pid="MEcrMUDCSkWI4E0XWZ3ofg" hash="9MaGuw">Sometimes, in our earthly impatience, we may lose sight of the Lord’s precious promises and disconnect our obedience from the fulfillment of these promises. The Lord has declared:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises.p" pid="LvJwpUKbRk6VMxY8nByP7Q" hash="0T-WpA">“Who am I, saith the Lord, that have promised and have not fulfilled?</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises.p" pid="G9pgBebbYkCcwmdNv7-oZQ" hash="s83y1g">“I command and men obey not; I revoke and they receive not the blessing.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises.p" pid="vN4uaH7xZEyfVh3UonVibA" hash="ht-Oog">“Then they say in their hearts: This is not the work of the Lord, for his promises are not fulfilled. But wo unto such, for their reward lurketh beneath, and not from above” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.31-33" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:31–33</a>).</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises.t3" guid="7a55a677-178c-4819-9aaf-082f207808d9">
        <h3 class="title" guid="bbda602d-6872-48f1-84d0-08e53f452ea9" pid="PS-f0wxADkmOA2-fpQLiUQ" hash="ci-AMQ">Seeing the Promises Afar Off</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises.p" pid="DvuyJDFc_kqmbXW3voj6cw" hash="oByUyw">Important components of faith are patience, long-suffering, and enduring to the end. The Apostle Paul recounts the faith of Abel, Enoch, Noah, Abraham, and Sara, concluding that “these all died in faith, not having received the promises, but having seen them afar off, and were persuaded of them, and embraced them, and confessed that they were strangers and pilgrims on the earth” (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/heb/11.4-13" class="scriptureRef">Hebrews 11:4–13</a>). These faithful Saints knew that this earth life was a journey, not their final destination.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises.p" pid="l7AO92uRT0GmZ2QAOjLQlg" hash="q6CsRg">When Abram was 75 years old, the Lord promised him, “I will make of thee a great nation”—this at a time when he and Sarai as yet had no children (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/12.2" class="scriptureRef">Genesis 12:2</a>). He was 86 when Sarai’s handmaiden Hagar “bare Ishmael to Abram” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/16.16" class="scriptureRef">Genesis 16:16</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises.p" pid="MDqtn0jX70e6SASZoBEeVg" hash="AXsiow">And the Lord changed Abram’s name to Abraham and Sarai’s name to Sarah, and when he was nearly a hundred and she was 90 they were promised that Sarah would bear a son to be named Isaac (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/17.17,19" class="scriptureRef">Genesis 17:17, 19</a>). Amidst their disbelief the Lord asked: “Is any thing too hard for the Lord?” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/18.14" class="scriptureRef">Genesis 18:14</a>). And “Sarah conceived, and bare Abraham a son in his old age” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/21.2" class="scriptureRef">Genesis 21:2</a>), and the Lord promised: “I will multiply thy seed as the stars of the heaven, and as the sand which is upon the sea shore” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/22.17" class="scriptureRef">Genesis 22:17</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises.p" pid="uR8WyIHnIUOxnzphWWTR1w" hash="M5PEfg">Young Isaac grew into manhood, and when he was 40 years old he married Rebekah. “And Isaac intreated the Lord for his wife, because she was barren: and the Lord was intreated of him, and Rebekah his wife conceived” and bore twin sons, Esau and Jacob, when their father was 60 years old. (See <a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/25.20-26" class="scriptureRef">Genesis 25:20–26</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises.p" pid="v3u1eAhbpkWwZ5IgvWG5yQ" hash="4GS-6Q">As Jacob matured and became of appropriate age, his parents sent him to the household of Laban, where he would meet Laban’s two daughters, Leah and Rachel. Jacob told Laban, “I will serve thee seven years for Rachel thy younger daughter. … And Jacob served seven years for Rachel; and they seemed unto him but a few days, for the love he had to her” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/29.18,20" class="scriptureRef">Genesis 29:18, 20</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises.p" pid="Ja1u3thk3Ey6KALCf3tWEg" hash="-cJ5Bg">
          <span class="pageBreak" page-number="18"></span>You will recall how Laban beguiled young Jacob into first marrying Leah and then Rachel. “And when the Lord saw that Leah was hated, he opened her womb: but Rachel was barren” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/29.31" class="scriptureRef">Genesis 29:31</a>). And Leah bore Reuben, then Simeon, then Levi, and Judah. Meanwhile, Rachel remained childless (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/29.32-35" class="scriptureRef">Genesis 29:32–35</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises.p" pid="CAle9Zic_EG_xS64Qs2oOg" hash="jIwp_w">With ever-increasing envy and mounting desperation, one day Rachel explosively demanded of Jacob, “Give me children, or else I die” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/30.1" class="scriptureRef">Genesis 30:1</a>). Leah subsequently bore two more sons and a daughter.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises.t4" guid="d36aca6b-5a77-4d63-93f1-d672ad71dc54">
        <h3 class="title" guid="3ceb7689-43ed-4aa7-9562-4c338e40b984" pid="gDn8D3doGUS9KgN_K4YABw" hash="GJdSbA">The Lord Is Not Slack Concerning His Promise</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises.p" pid="vaF4aAWqLkumFUfSlL4akw" hash="A4kLsg">The Apostle Peter testified that “the Lord is not slack concerning his promise, as some men count slackness; but is longsuffering” toward us (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-pet/3.9" class="scriptureRef">2 Peter 3:9</a>). In this age of one-hour dry cleaning and one-minute fast-food franchises, it may at times seem to us as though a loving Heavenly Father has misplaced our precious promises or He has put them on hold or filed them under the wrong name. Such were the feelings of Rachel.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises.p" pid="GJ2O7aWetEWpoO4RniPaxw" hash="87i6aA">But with the passage of time, we encounter four of the most beautiful words in holy writ: “And God remembered Rachel” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/30.22" class="scriptureRef">Genesis 30:22</a>). And she was blessed with the birth of Joseph and later the birth of Benjamin. There are millions on earth today who are descendants of Joseph who have embraced the Abrahamic promise that through their efforts “shall all the families of the earth be blessed, even with the blessings of the Gospel, which are the blessings of salvation, even of life eternal” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/2.11" class="scriptureRef">Abraham 2:11</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises.p" pid="kr_Hck3l6EKPEHgXqxXx5g" hash="B_2uDg">When heaven’s promises sometimes seem afar off, I pray that each of us will embrace these exceeding great and precious promises and never let go. And just as God remembered Rachel, God will remember you. I so testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div><div class="resources">
    <img src="CondieSJ_all.ob.jpg" alt="Elder Spencer J. Condie" guid="6476a958-1375-4b06-984f-e2d5367d44cb" pid="H5v4u84rs0WgHEDHkdYi9w" hash="FqQ-Ng1" />
    <unknown name="digitalAssets" guid="">
      <unknown name="assetGroup" guid="">
        <unknown name="path" guid="6476a958-1375-4b06-984f-e2d5367d44cb"></unknown>
      </unknown>
    </unknown>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2007/10/claim-the-exceeding-great-and-precious-promises</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2007-general-conference/2007-10-1060-elder-spencer-j-condie-64k-eng.mp3" length="3903727" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2007 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
