<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Stephen W. Owen</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Stephen W. Owen.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Stephen%20W.%20Owen.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Stephen W. Owen.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 18:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>The Greatest Leaders Are the Greatest Followers</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers?lang=eng</link>
      <description>&lt;div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_13285_000_42owen" doc-version="2" hash="9H5dTA"&gt;
	
	&lt;div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.head1"&gt;
		&lt;h1 class="title" pid="WoK8dNL4vUW-7fzQT2N0GQ" hash="egPbzg"&gt;The Greatest Leaders Are the Greatest Followers&lt;/h1&gt;
		&lt;div class="byline"&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p2" pid="TWttEu_e1kKYekFrChxqXw" hash="QsJFAQ1"&gt;By Stephen W. Owen&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p3" pid="4vO5v-5FSkGBSQVFa2HMoA" hash="pUbbMg"&gt;Young Men General President&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=zekka97I2kWVn0pujkieaA"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" altText="Stephen W. Owen" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1456695/644817ce7d844784a87b54968b830d8c/100x139.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x69="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1456695/644817ce7d844784a87b54968b830d8c/50x69.jpg" data-src-100x139="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1456695/644817ce7d844784a87b54968b830d8c/100x139.jpg" data-src-200x278="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1456695/644817ce7d844784a87b54968b830d8c/200x278.jpg" data-src-320x446="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1456695/644817ce7d844784a87b54968b830d8c/320x446.jpg" data-src-460x641="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1456695/644817ce7d844784a87b54968b830d8c/460x641.jpg" data-src-640x892="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1456695/644817ce7d844784a87b54968b830d8c/640x892.jpg" data-src-1024x1427="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1456695/644817ce7d844784a87b54968b830d8c/1024x1427.jpg" data-src-2048x2855="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1456695/644817ce7d844784a87b54968b830d8c/2048x2855.jpg" data-src-3893x5428="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1456695/644817ce7d844784a87b54968b830d8c/3893x5428.jpg" webURL="stephen-woodruff-owen-young-men-presidency_1456695.jpg" pid="zekka97I2kWVn0pujkieaA" hash="AAAAAA"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;p class="kicker" pid="u_zYPSBhQ0WG2vdMHxKuBw" hash="S0mUNQ"&gt;There will be times when the path ahead seems dark, but keep following the Savior. He knows the way; in fact, He &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the way.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="authorName" pid="5c5Y4P3PlECwtSexdKMTxg" hash="QsJFAQ"&gt;By Stephen W. Owen&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class="bodyBlock"&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p5" pid="I1WVi4Qw3kOVJMTPAnalRQ" hash="viwFxw"&gt;When I was 12 years old, my father took me hunting in the mountains. We woke up at 3:00 in the morning, saddled our horses, and set out up the forested mountainside in total darkness. As much as I loved hunting with my dad, at that moment I felt a little nervous. I had never been in these mountains before, and I couldn’t see the trail—or much of anything else, for that matter! The only thing I could see was the small flashlight my dad was carrying as it cast a faint light on the pine trees ahead of us. What if my horse slipped and fell—could he even see where he was going? But this thought comforted me: “Dad knows where he’s going. If I follow him, everything will be OK.”&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p6" pid="7SyM16lzsUemLDUVkn0Vkw" hash="0ImZMA"&gt;And everything was OK. Eventually the sun came out, and we had a wonderful day together. As we started toward home, my dad pointed to a majestic, sloping peak that stood out among the others. “That’s Windy Ridge,” he said. “That’s where the good hunting is.” Instantly, I knew that I wanted to come back and climb to Windy Ridge someday.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p7" pid="e5RRhZoxuEyexcac37lNVA" hash="5xDN1Q"&gt;In the years that followed, I would often hear my father talk about Windy Ridge, but we never went back—until one day, 20 years later, I called my dad and said, “Let’s go to Windy.” Once again we saddled our horses and started up the mountainside. I was now an experienced rider in my 30s, yet I was surprised to feel the same nervousness I had felt as a 12-year-old boy. But my dad knew the way, and I followed him.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p8" pid="ccJMYT2S-k6qTc7vNBlLHA" hash="4-tLNQ"&gt;Finally we made it to the top of Windy. The view was exhilarating, and the overwhelming feeling I had was that I wanted to come back—not for me this time but for my wife and my children. I wanted them to experience what I had experienced.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p9" pid="I0RuoFgl7US9s_9h2sehEQ" hash="0NjfnQ"&gt;Over the years, I’ve had many opportunities to lead my sons and other young men to mountaintops, just as my father led me. These experiences have prompted me to ponder what it means to lead—and what it means to follow.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.t1"&gt;
			&lt;h2 pid="_CFREHmfj0uIh_PCJLemSg" hash="nWu5zA"&gt;Jesus Christ, the Greatest Leader and the Greatest Follower&lt;/h2&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p11" pid="YnopZOHhkUmk2sXx1mBs4Q" hash="QEUj9A"&gt;If I were to ask you, “Who is the greatest leader who ever lived?”—what would you say? The answer, of course, is Jesus Christ. He sets the perfect example of every imaginable leadership quality.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p12" pid="KkdlPxNbYkq8ATo9nnSF9w" hash="-ibaOg"&gt;But what if I were to ask you, “Who is the greatest &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;follower&lt;/span&gt; who ever lived?”—wouldn’t the answer again be Jesus Christ? He is the greatest leader &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;because&lt;/span&gt; He is the greatest follower—He follows His Father perfectly, in all things.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p13" pid="LtLgPt0UkU2zRkw_SAiNcg" hash="spghMg"&gt;The world teaches that leaders must be mighty; the Lord teaches that they must be meek. Worldly leaders gain power and influence through their talent, skill, and wealth. Christlike leaders gain power and influence “by persuasion, by long-suffering, by gentleness and meekness, and by love unfeigned.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p14" pid="9tZ0JOBJLE-H7ExWkFRM-Q" hash="7SrUVw"&gt;In God’s eyes, the greatest leaders have always been the greatest followers.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p15" pid="aoosWupheEeWCrclf5yndg" hash="a-jKCg"&gt;Allow me to share two experiences from my recent interactions with the young men of the Church that have taught me about leading and following.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.t2"&gt;
			&lt;h2 pid="blpSL-OW4UOTeDz54g71WA" hash="GcZJJw"&gt;We Are All Leaders&lt;/h2&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p17" pid="g5mD2NMTHUKRFI4t-H0P_A" hash="EOOBZg"&gt;Recently my wife and I attended a sacrament meeting away from our home ward. Just before the meeting started, a young man approached me and asked if I would help pass the sacrament. I said, “I’d be happy to.”&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p18" pid="Ne7MgaYG4USRwTa0owqugg" hash="rLCfqQ"&gt;I took my seat with the other deacons and asked one who was sitting next to me, “What is my assignment?” He told me I was to start passing at the back of the chapel in the middle section and that he would be on the other side of the same section, and together we would work our way to the front.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p19" pid="8qQ2Mn-cakmfEVPObOcoUg" hash="rmNZUw"&gt;I said, “I haven’t done this for a long time.”&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p20" pid="5T_WYMw45UiysPj781EAng" hash="iDYFQQ"&gt;He replied, “That’s OK. You’ll be fine. I felt the same way when I started.”&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p21" pid="dSakoyPmH0-sL988d5YuNg" hash="tB_YrA"&gt;Later the youngest deacon in the quorum, ordained only weeks earlier, gave a talk in sacrament meeting. After the meeting, the other deacons rallied around him to tell him how proud they were of their fellow quorum member.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p22" pid="3a-nZHjIgkmCOVBMeRM7Cw" hash="YqQQcQ"&gt;As I visited with them that day, I found out that each week, members of all the Aaronic Priesthood quorums in that ward reach out to other young men and invite them to be part of their quorums.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p23" pid="Ky0xjTJb7kCCMhU_OKiyAw" hash="NleyEw"&gt;These young men were all great leaders. And they clearly had some wonderful behind-the-scenes Melchizedek Priesthood holders, parents, and others who mentored them in their duties. Caring adults like these see young men not just as they are but as they can become. When they talk to or about the young men, they do not dwell on their shortcomings. Instead, they emphasize the great leadership qualities they are demonstrating.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p24" pid="sfmFSXDcLkCA-kGNya2J4g" hash="okqZmg"&gt;Young men, this is how the Lord sees you. I invite you to see yourself this way. There will be times in your life when you are called upon to lead. At other times, you will be expected to follow. But my message to you today is that regardless of your calling, you are always a leader, and you are always a follower. Leadership is an expression of discipleship—it is simply a matter of helping others come unto Christ, which is what true disciples do. If you are striving to be a follower of Christ, then you can help others follow Him and you can be a leader.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p25" pid="lUZD54KVRkq1Fw4QnbA17Q" hash="Nzcaag"&gt;Your ability to lead does not come from an outgoing personality, motivational skills, or even a talent for public speaking. It comes from your commitment to follow Jesus Christ. It comes from your desire to be, in Abraham’s words, “a greater follower of righteousness.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; If you can do that—even if you aren’t perfect at it, but you’re trying—then you &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; a leader.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.t3"&gt;
			&lt;h2 pid="Ar5B67CK8US5sQNayANz5g" hash="v-b9ig"&gt;Priesthood Service Is Leadership&lt;/h2&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p27" pid="3_VSTK2Py0GUfYHTc_22xA" hash="_epMbg"&gt;On another occasion, I was in New Zealand visiting the home of a single mother with three teenage children. The oldest son was 18 and had received the Melchizedek Priesthood just the previous Sunday. I asked if he had been able to exercise this priesthood yet. He said, “I’m not sure what that means.”&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p28" pid="I8Fx-ZnEt06E84BXMBCZ2w" hash="93AUTQ"&gt;I told him he now had the authority to give a priesthood blessing of comfort or healing. I looked at his mother, who had not had a Melchizedek Priesthood holder by her side for many years. “I think it would be wonderful,” I said, “if you would give your mom a blessing.”&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p29" pid="SdkbRbac_0iK2rfu_FNFpw" hash="aQF_Rw"&gt;He replied, “I don’t know how.”&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p30" pid="MFTo0q33iUOXpZBE8UI4AA" hash="hDVt2Q"&gt;I explained that he could put his hands on his mother’s head, state her name, state that he is giving her a blessing by the authority of the Melchizedek Priesthood, say whatever the Spirit puts in his mind and heart, and close in the name of Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p31" pid="fBIpkudn_0yUDYjbkrntEg" hash="0_p3-w"&gt;The next day, I received an email from him. It read in part: “Tonight I blessed my mum. … I felt very, very nervous and inadequate, so I prayed continually to ensure I had the Spirit with me, because I could not give a blessing without it. As I started, I completely forgot myself and my weaknesses. … I [did not expect] the immense spiritual and emotional power I felt. … Afterwards the spirit of love hit me so hard I could not contain my emotions, so I hugged my mum and wept like a baby. … Even now as I write this, [I feel] the Spirit [so much that] I never want to sin again. … I love this gospel.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p32" pid="Erpnv9kuxUKtSCbTX2mcyA" hash="ZQXRAw"&gt;Isn’t it inspiring to see how a seemingly ordinary young man can accomplish great things through priesthood service, even when he feels inadequate? I recently learned that this young elder has received a mission call and will enter the missionary training center next month. I believe he will lead many souls to Christ because he has learned how to follow Christ in his priesthood service—beginning in his own home, where his example is having a profound influence on his 14-year-old brother.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p33" pid="F1wocd5wpE61V-5o6feuIg" hash="-Er0IQ"&gt;Brethren, whether we realize it or not, people are looking up to us—family members, friends, even strangers. It is not enough for us as priesthood holders just to come unto Christ; our duty now is to “invite &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;all&lt;/span&gt; to come unto Christ.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4"&gt;4&lt;/span&gt; We cannot be satisfied receiving spiritual blessings for ourselves; we must lead the people we love to those same blessings—and as disciples of Jesus Christ, we must love everyone. The Savior’s charge to Peter is also a charge to us: “When thou art converted, strengthen thy brethren.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.t4"&gt;
			&lt;h2 pid="511EWRhXqEG55rYZLolyWA" hash="oOX2zQ"&gt;Follow the Man of Galilee&lt;/h2&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p35" pid="mKzaKf7Yd0yMp3CYlxH2SQ" hash="pJf_tA"&gt;There will be times when the path ahead seems dark, but keep following the Savior. He knows the way; in fact, He &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the way.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6"&gt;6&lt;/span&gt; The more earnestly you come unto Christ, the more deeply you will desire to help others experience what you have experienced. Another word for this feeling is charity, “which [the Father] hath bestowed upon all who are true followers of his Son, Jesus Christ.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7"&gt;7&lt;/span&gt; Then you will find that in the very act of following Christ, you are also leading others to Him, for in the words of President Thomas S. Monson, “As we follow that Man of Galilee—even the Lord Jesus Christ—our personal influence will be felt for good wherever we are, whatever our callings.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8"&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers.p36" pid="m0NC749G_E-TnRiulQfOyQ" hash="jCsRIQ"&gt;I bear witness that this is Christ’s true Church. We are led by a prophet of God, President Monson—a great leader who is also a true follower of the Savior. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2016/04/the-greatest-leaders-are-the-greatest-followers</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2016-general-conference/2016-04-3020-stephen-w-owen-64k-eng.mp3" length="5337650" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Repentance Is Always Positive</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Brother Owen teaches that repentance is a gift offered by the Savior. Like the prodigal son, we make daily choices that will lead us to our Heavenly Father.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD60003502_000_33owen" doc-version="1" hash="8aFW2g">
		
		<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.head1">
			<h1 class="title" pid="rfiWyk5cz0qlFCJlBJ0m3Q" hash="fWV9-w">Repentance Is Always Positive</h1>
			<div class="byline">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.p2" pid="R5jFs62kRUWrQeATG6KhPg" hash="QsJFAQ1">By Stephen W. Owen</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.p3" pid="YcA41leF50uufgWJZrsg1g" hash="pUbbMg">Young Men General President</p>
			</div>
			<p class="kicker" pid="YQ4KsstR2UyEIZUfxmTluw" hash="Td5dKQ">The moment we set foot on the path of repentance, we invite the Savior’s redeeming power into our lives.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="8Z-doNz9n0uFnRfCaYEQEg" hash="QsJFAQ">By Stephen W. Owen</p></div>
		<div class="bodyBlock">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.p5" pid="mkk6XuDD0k257W6alGtD1g" hash="DodLGA">Several years ago, President Gordon B. Hinckley attended a college football game. He was there to announce that the stadium would be named after the team’s longtime, beloved coach, who was about to retire. The team desperately wanted to win the game to honor their coach. President Hinckley was invited to visit the locker room and share some encouraging words. Inspired by his words, that team on that day went on to win that game and ended the season with a winning record.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.p6" pid="7s3G64DB0UuN1qC9LCySQQ" hash="gFHbWg">Today, I would like to speak to those who may worry that they are not winning in life. The truth is, of course, that we “all have sinned, and come short of the glory of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> While there may be undefeated seasons in sports, there aren’t any in life. But I testify that the Savior Jesus Christ worked out a perfect Atonement and gave us the gift of repentance—our path back to a perfect brightness of hope and a winning life.</p>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.t1">
				<h2 pid="TSWQ4grf3keJGiO3puEahw" hash="wGYhkQ">Repentance Brings Happiness</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.p8" pid="Vplk28rsokiM89Gn9W7QpA" hash="JyAO9w">Too often we think of repentance as something miserable and depressing. But God’s plan is the plan of happiness, not the plan of misery! Repentance is uplifting and ennobling. It’s sin that brings unhappiness.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> Repentance is our escape route! As Elder D. Todd Christofferson explained: “Without repentance, there is no real progress or improvement in life. … Only through repentance do we gain access to the atoning grace of Jesus Christ and salvation. Repentance … points us to freedom, confidence, and peace.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> My message to all—especially to the youth—is that repentance is always positive.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.p9" pid="OxDvvdJl_0COP6rJXfmJ3w" hash="k5x9fg">When we speak of repentance, we aren’t just talking about self-improvement efforts. True repentance is more than that—it is inspired by faith in the Lord Jesus Christ and His power to forgive our sins. As Elder Dale G. Renlund has taught us, “Without the Redeemer, … repentance becomes simply miserable behavior modification.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> We can try to change our behavior on our own, but only the Savior can remove our stains and lift our burdens, enabling us to pursue the path of obedience with confidence and strength. The joy of repentance is more than the joy of living a decent life. It’s the joy of forgiveness, of being clean again, and of drawing closer to God. Once you’ve experienced that joy, no lesser substitute will do.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.p10" pid="jNvepkFea0OGIvaU92600w" hash="xjEzMA">True repentance inspires us to make our obedience a commitment—a covenant, beginning with baptism and renewed each week at the Lord’s Supper, the sacrament. There we receive the promise that we can “always have his Spirit to be with [us],”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> with all of the joy and peace that come from His constant companionship. This is the fruit of repentance, and this is what makes repentance joyful!</p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.t2">
				<h2 pid="EwOZY1XLikqJxEvECBpOeA" hash="FPKmdw">Repentance Requires Persistence</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.p12" pid="plTGvefzz06m6puB8ZI32A" hash="-6WNqg">I love the parable of the prodigal son.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> There’s something poignant about that pivotal moment when the prodigal “came to himself.” Sitting in a pigsty, wishing he could “have filled his belly with the husks that the swine did eat,” he finally realized that he had wasted not only his father’s inheritance but also his own life. With faith that his father might accept him back—if not as a son then at least as a servant—he determined to put his rebellious past behind him and go home.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.p13" pid="UvtlpNRNQ0-V9Zxx7i4eYw" hash="QayKlA">I’ve often wondered about the son’s long walk home. Were there times when he hesitated and wondered, “How will I be received by my father?” Perhaps he even took a few steps back toward the swine. Imagine how the story would be different if he had given up. But faith kept him moving, and faith kept his father watching and waiting patiently, until finally:</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.p14" pid="ab3fsD6--k6oW6Wq9RyTwQ" hash="7qAnHg">“When he was yet a great way off, his father saw him, and had compassion, and ran, and fell on his neck, and kissed him.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.p15" pid="YJhY4ljrNEaCUX0xvZEcvg" hash="72CbNg">“And the son said unto him, Father, I have sinned against heaven, and in thy sight, and am no more worthy to be called thy son.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.p16" pid="GxBGgflJek-f5Vbb3JWuNA" hash="H8KARQ">“But the father said to his servants, Bring forth the best robe, and put it on him; and put a ring on his hand, and shoes on his feet: …</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.p17" pid="AsDYc5DjuUiYZqsqqv_jFQ" hash="HTzMpQ">“For this my son was dead, and is alive again; he was lost, and is found.”</p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.t3">
				<h2 pid="FVbONIz-zE63D9flRharWg" hash="KBnS1w">Repentance Is for Everyone</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.p19" pid="skhQUE_uMUChSi80wVD_MA" hash="9St45g">Brothers and sisters, we are all prodigals. We all have to “come to ourselves”—usually more than once—and choose the path that leads back home. It’s a choice we make daily, throughout our lives.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.p20" pid="gOuf2fqWgUSLNckuo7IZCQ" hash="AsnoiQ">We often associate repentance with grievous sins that require “a mighty change.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> But repentance is for everyone—those who are wandering in “forbidden paths and [are] lost”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> as well as those who “have gotten into [the] strait and narrow path” and now need to “press forward.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> Repentance both puts us on the right path and keeps us on the right path. It is for those who are just beginning to believe, those who have believed all along, and those who need to begin again to believe. As Elder David A. Bednar taught: “Most of us clearly understand that the Atonement is for sinners. I am not so sure, however, that we know and understand that the Atonement is also for saints—for good men and women who are obedient, worthy, and … striving to become better.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.p21" pid="SZuj1JaS6EyzXqoVA87zfQ" hash="R4rIsQ">Recently I visited a missionary training center when a group of brand-new missionaries arrived. I was deeply moved as I watched them and observed the light in their eyes. They seemed so bright and happy and enthusiastic. Then a thought came to me: “They have experienced faith unto repentance. This is why they are filled with joy and hope.”</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.p22" pid="mPbG7ZO5aUSPLoz_34PdZA" hash="n35LGg">I don’t think that means they all had serious transgressions in their past, but I do think they knew how to repent; they had learned that repentance is positive; and they were ready and eager to share this joyful message with the world.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.p23" pid="LlIJL5TVKESKKGlEz4AKjA" hash="6xjQ_Q">This is what happens when we feel the joy of repentance. Consider the example of Enos. He had his own “coming to himself” moment, and after his “guilt was swept away,” his heart turned immediately to the welfare of others. Enos spent the rest of his life inviting all people to repent and “rejoiced in it above that of the world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> Repentance does that; it turns our hearts toward our fellowman because we know that the joy we feel is meant for everyone.</p>
			</div>
			<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.t4">
				<h2 pid="H6CT_FPwskCIWKl8yJ8jzw" hash="sAKZ9Q">Repentance Is a Lifelong Pursuit</h2>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.p25" pid="1d_CdBkUwE-31esCYjDM1Q" hash="knAZtA">I have a friend who grew up in a less-active Latter-day Saint family. When he was a young adult, he too “came to himself” and decided to prepare for a mission.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.p26" pid="ZffC0oaUbkqBUuau2qgvzQ" hash="NqOqQg">He became an excellent missionary. On his last day before returning home, the mission president interviewed him and asked him to bear his testimony. He did so, and after a tearful embrace, the president said, “Elder, you could forget or deny everything you have just testified of in a matter of months if you do not continue to do the things that built your testimony in the first place.”</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.p27" pid="Te1M537fOUqEcZ78qrzv_w" hash="LLDaOw">My friend later told me that he has prayed and read the scriptures daily since he returned from his mission. Being constantly “nourished by the good word of God” has kept him “in the right way.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.p28" pid="8OChcJqxiEKrSOOw1jZNsQ" hash="yxtJaQ">You who are preparing for full-time missions and you who are returning, take note! It is not enough just to gain a testimony; you have to maintain it and strengthen it. As every missionary knows, if you stop pedaling a bicycle, it will fall, and if you stop feeding your testimony, it will weaken. This same principle applies to repentance—it is a lifelong pursuit, not a once-in-a-lifetime experience.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.p29" pid="oMSHBpSFp0W2mgMTBty7Ng" hash="MmXJnw">To all who seek forgiveness—the youth, young single adults, parents, grandparents, and yes, even great-grandparents—I invite you to come home. Now is the time to begin. Do not procrastinate your day of repentance.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.p30" pid="Ja6ZbTuns0G8VJLMGCJtxw" hash="mHagLA">Then, once you have made that decision, keep following the path. Our Father is waiting, longing to receive you. His arms are outstretched “all the day long” for you.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> The reward is worth the effort.</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.p31" pid="xN12z9dGLkGDsfqz4bJp6A" hash="2YBFpw">Remember these words from Nephi: “Ye must press forward with a steadfastness in Christ, having a perfect brightness of hope, and a love of God and of all men. Wherefore, if ye shall press forward, feasting upon the word of Christ, and endure to the end, behold, thus saith the Father: Ye shall have eternal life.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive.p32" pid="6NePwDt7dEiyNxpJlRxQyw" hash="06dNNg">Sometimes the journey will seem long—after all, it is the journey toward eternal life. But it can be a joyous journey if we pursue it with faith in Jesus Christ and hope in His Atonement. I testify that the moment we set foot on the path of repentance, we invite the Savior’s redeeming power into our lives. That power will steady our feet, expand our vision, and deepen our resolve to keep moving forward, step by step, until that glorious day when we finally return to our heavenly home and hear our Father in Heaven say to us, “Well done.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
			</div>
		</div>
		
	</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2017/10/repentance-is-always-positive</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2017-general-conference/2017-09-2030-stephen-w-owen-64k-eng.mp3" length="4831084" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
