<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Steven E. Snow</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Steven E. Snow.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Steven%20E.%20Snow.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Steven E. Snow.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2001 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Gratitude</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2001/10/gratitude?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Gratitude may be increased by constantly reflecting on our blessings and giving thanks for them in our daily prayers.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/gratitude" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029371_000_019" doc-version="2" hash="mzh8Sg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/gratitude.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="uri5hd0wt0GTg4F2ufmR3g" hash="gk1uRw">Gratitude</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="0pO3acvLwUi8CI74GbYvcQ" hash="EqQgBw">Steven E. Snow</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="aWMqcnu3L0ebpLlTqdqd6g" hash="yjAt_w">Gratitude may be increased by constantly reflecting on our blessings and giving thanks for them in our daily prayers.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/gratitude.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-57f.jpg" alt="Elder Steven E. Snow" pid="8XNfRMjK2UO4tYzBHPeztg" hash="FdQzMw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/gratitude.p1" pid="kf8OllQ9pkifgXcHV6r_pA" hash="PKUEOg">Growing up in southern Utah, some of us sought employment at the many gasoline service stations that lined old Highway 91 as it made its way through downtown St. George. My younger brother, Paul, then 18, worked at Tom’s Service, a station located about three blocks from our home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/gratitude.p2" pid="t-e3boJI_EeaLXXkL1RjWA" hash="leoong">One summer day, a car with New York license plates pulled in the station and asked for a fill-up. (For you brethren under the age of 30, in those days someone actually came out and filled your car with gas, washed your windows, and checked your oil.) While Paul was washing the windshield, the driver asked him how far it was to the Grand Canyon. Paul replied that it was 170 miles.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/gratitude.p3" pid="FEKbbR5jGEG2Dt-e1gyqPA" hash="VAL5cg">“I’ve waited all my life to see the Grand Canyon,” the man exclaimed. “What’s it like out there?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/gratitude.p4" pid="l2gdvJZEjEKwkwE9oyUMpA" hash="m5Lw8A">“I don’t know,” Paul answered. “I’ve never been there.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/gratitude.p5" pid="y8Vr4B9SsEGpQEVvnF7fGQ" hash="HZBgow">“You mean to tell me,” the man responded, “that you live two and a half hours from one of the seven wonders of the world and you’ve never been there!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/gratitude.p6" pid="-RxA9aWSIU6atFWZNWs_Ug" hash="7-FQ7w">“That’s right,” Paul said.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/gratitude.p7" pid="YjvgDqQb40q-wRx_SU7v8A" hash="I08eMA">After a moment, the man replied, “Well, I guess I can understand that. My wife and I have lived in Manhattan for over 20 years, and we’ve never visited the Statue of Liberty.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/gratitude.p8" pid="crpSM8DRV0OnnOqsui1KfA" hash="pE4Ohw">“I’ve been there,” Paul said.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/gratitude.p9" pid="k0xEkoCsYkGgWLZ7eB_m9Q" hash="Ct6lRQ">Isn’t it ironic, brethren, that we will often travel many miles to see the wonders of nature or the creations of man, but yet ignore the beauty in our own backyard?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/gratitude.p10" pid="FV813jDL5Uur_gZLNBO_0w" hash="GRryxQ">It is human nature, I suppose, to seek elsewhere for our happiness. Pursuit of career goals, wealth, and material rewards can cloud our perspective and often leads to a lack of appreciation for the bounteous blessings of our present circumstances.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/gratitude.p11" pid="dnrnwxrejESBnpPoAotupA" hash="195RXw">It is precarious to dwell on why we have not been given more. It is, however, beneficial and humbling to dwell on why we have been given so much.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/gratitude.p12" pid="-twnCilsBEiO7A6MAdMSoQ" hash="zwCg4Q">An old proverb states, “The greater wealth is contentment with a little.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/gratitude.p13" pid="sbBUKywXWUGl6g12xXVjlA" hash="KIfwMw">In his letter to the Philippians, Paul wrote, “Not that I speak in respect of want: for I have learned, in whatsoever state I am, therewith to be content” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/philip/4.11" class="scriptureRef">Philip. 4:11</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/gratitude.p14" pid="gkG8Zib2sEGbEr2ti54Jeg" hash="TQz62A">Alma instructed his son Helaman, giving him counsel that all fathers should teach their children: “Counsel with the Lord in all thy doings, and he will direct thee for good; yea, when thou liest down at night lie down unto the Lord, that he may watch over you in your sleep; and when thou risest in the morning let thy heart be full of thanks unto God; and if ye do these things, ye shall be lifted up at the last day” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/37.37" class="scriptureRef">Alma 37:37</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/gratitude.p15" pid="PhGna5bieEq5TEU8KyersA" hash="zak_QA">Alma says, “Let thy heart be full of thanks unto God.” The Lord desires that we give thanks. In Thessalonians we read, “In every thing give thanks: for this is the will of God in Christ Jesus concerning you” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-thes/5.18" class="scriptureRef">1 Thes. 5:18</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/gratitude.p16" pid="pObFHbAhQEKgdLMTOqjc4A" hash="VfF4Hg">As holders of the priesthood we should constantly strive to increase our gratitude. Gratitude may be increased by constantly reflecting on our blessings and giving thanks for them in our daily prayers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/gratitude.p17" pid="edm9asztSUePxOJUHSnhlA" hash="ZD3w1w">President David O. McKay has said: “The young man who closes the door behind him, who draws the curtains, and there in silence pleads with God for help, should first pour out his soul in gratitude for health, for friends, for loved ones, for the gospel, for the manifestations of God’s existence. He should first count his many blessings and name them one by one” (in Conference Report, Apr. 1961, 7–8).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/gratitude.p18" pid="jwZqVyML1UiH7YrA0dMAxw" hash="YsXz3Q">A constant expression of gratitude should be included in all our prayers. Often prayers are given for specific blessings which we, in our incomplete understanding, believe we need. While the Lord does answer prayers according to His will, He certainly must be pleased when we offer humble prayers of gratitude.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/gratitude.p19" pid="MKgXkAc_Hk6-JEWfy34O7g" hash="z8hCMg">Brethren, the next time we pray, instead of presenting the Lord petition after petition for some action in our behalf, give Him thoughtful thanks for all with which He has blessed us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/gratitude.p20" pid="BFdU214hBk6R9js0sLH3Lw" hash="XMlXfw">President Joseph F. Smith has instructed us that “the spirit of gratitude is always pleasant and satisfying because it carries with it a sense of helpfulness to others; it begets love and friendship, and engenders divine influence. Gratitude is said to be the memory of the heart” (<span class="emphasis">Gospel Doctrine, </span>5th ed. [1939], 262).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/gratitude.p21" pid="1ZCXmxY_P0mFzpzanNibLg" hash="fthLhQ">In October of 1879 a group of 237 Latter-day Saints from several small southwestern Utah settlements was called to blaze a new route and colonize what is today known as San Juan County in southeastern Utah. The journey was to have taken six weeks but instead took nearly six months. Their struggles and heroics are well documented, particularly their seemingly impossible task of crossing the Colorado River at a place called Hole-in-the-Rock. Those who have visited this place marvel that wagons and teams could have been lowered through this narrow crack in the red rock canyon walls to reach the Colorado River far below. Once the Colorado was crossed, however, many other severe tests awaited them on the trail to San Juan County. Tired and worn out, early in April 1880 they faced their final obstacle, Comb Ridge. The Comb is a ridge of solid sandstone forming a steep wall nearly 1,000 feet high.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/gratitude.p22" pid="AyVhj8PTRk6KIeSWM7exsw" hash="Vxyljw">One hundred and twenty years later, our family climbed Comb Ridge on a bright spring day. The ridge is steep and treacherous. It was difficult to imagine that wagons, teams, men, women, and children could make such an ascent. But beneath our feet were the scars from the wagon wheels, left as evidence of their struggles so long ago. How did they feel after enduring so much? Were they bitter after the many months of toil and privation? Did they criticize their leaders for sending them on such an arduous journey, asking them to give up so much? Our questions were answered as we reached the top of Comb Ridge. There inscribed in the red sandstone so long ago were the words, “We thank Thee, O God.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/gratitude.p23" pid="xNkH9Ga1r0G7dOwqPkk7Vg" hash="nrOkxg">Brethren, I pray that we might keep our hearts full of thanks and appreciation for what we have and not dwell on what is not ours. As holders of the priesthood, let us adopt an attitude of gratitude in all we do is my prayer, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2001/10/gratitude</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2001-general-conference/2001-10-3030-elder-steven-e-snow-64k-eng.mp3" length="3445887" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2001 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Service</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2007/10/service?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Look for ways to bless the lives of others through seemingly simple acts of service.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/service" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00008332_000_038" doc-version="2" hash="Pbf_MA"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/service.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="mkiw21wYGkqlFrQq2VOvcg" hash="s6TuxQ">Service</h1><p class="authorName" guid="42c67b9b-d4ba-447d-a6b3-ed40ce7f7c74" pid="tYQXFQz540O5d80H_mSTTw" hash="EqQgBw">Steven E. Snow</p><p class="kicker" pid="hwZ1LH21P0aNAnM9VAmASw" hash="ekyZ0g">Look for ways to bless the lives of others through seemingly simple acts of service.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="f223fcf0-7b21-43f8-9663-fe441bdd18e1">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/service.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/SnowSE_07.jpg" alt="Elder Steven E. Snow" guid="63390591-0033-4ac7-8177-de4a8ed93de1" pid="RRVlo1uRgEukH8UnjEhsWw" hash="LAIJRQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/service.p" pid="2C58C9IFP0SniSA8f3G6jw" hash="hiSWFQ">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="102"></span>President David O. McKay once quoted Abraham Lincoln as saying, “All that I am or hope to be I owe to my angel mother.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> These words well explain my feelings about my own mother. Viola Jean Goates Snow, Jeanie to all who knew her, was born in 1929 and died shortly after her 60th birthday in 1989. She taught me and she encouraged me. She truly convinced me I could accomplish anything I wanted. She also disciplined me. As my own sons say of their mother, “She was the travel agent for guilt trips.” Mom was a wonderful mother, a great role model, and scarcely a day passes I do not think of her and miss her.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/service.p" pid="ZYSTY8suREqPJ3rp10uKZg" hash="qqgVmg">A few years before she passed away, she was diagnosed with cancer, a disease she fought with great courage. As a family we learned, strangely enough, that cancer is a disease of love. It provides opportunities to mend fences, say goodbyes, and express love. A few weeks before my mother’s death, we were visiting in the family room of my boyhood home. Mom had fine taste and liked nice things. She also longed to travel, but our family lived on a modest budget, and these dreams were not quite realized. Knowing this, I asked her if she had any regrets. I fully expected to hear she had always wanted a larger, more beautiful home or perhaps an expression of sadness and disappointment over never having traveled. She pondered my question for a few moments and replied simply, “I wish I had served more.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/service.p" pid="5ODOkqJ3y0-OvR1m2SgNvQ" hash="N3fa_g">I was shocked at her response. My mother had always accepted Church callings. She served as ward Relief Society president, Sunday School teacher, visiting teacher, and in the Primary. As children we were always delivering casseroles, jam, and bottled fruit to neighbors and members of the ward. When I reminded her of all this, she was undeterred. “I could have done more” was all she said. My mother had lived an exemplary and full life. She was loved by family and friends. She had accomplished much in a life that was often hard and which was cut short by disease and sickness. In spite of all of this, her greatest regret was she had not given enough service. Now, I have no doubt my mother’s earthly sacrifice has been accepted by the Lord and that she has been welcomed by Him. But why was it foremost in her mind just days before her passing? What is service, and why is it so important in the gospel of Jesus Christ?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/service.p" pid="Wd4xuKExC0WjSvReNR1BAg" hash="gdujxA">First, we are commanded to serve one another. The first commandment is to love God. “And the second is like unto it, Thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/service.p" pid="39e1ojsXBEqrly8xkT2bgg" hash="LPiw0g">We demonstrate our love when we help and serve each other.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/service.p" pid="N0gmgwIZmUGj9j5uHU22Zw" hash="ZIfOcg">President Gordon B. Hinckley has said: “No man can be a true Latter-day Saint who is unneighborly, who does not reach out to assist and help others. It is inherent in the very nature of the gospel that we do so. My brothers and sisters, we cannot live unto ourselves.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/service.p" pid="OS0Nmms3CUqix_2r3m7YJA" hash="48V3Nw">The Savior taught His disciples this important principle in Matthew:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/service.p" pid="naKnS_7Of0qmhKOtVui9Mw" hash="dDRlag">“Lord, when saw we thee an hungred, and fed thee? or thirsty, and gave thee drink?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/service.p" pid="yNwegyEocE2UOzMenY269w" hash="3nEFVQ">“When saw we thee a stranger, and took thee in? or naked, and clothed thee?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/service.p" pid="N-m16WopV0WmlY8WTVfBEQ" hash="8EgWfQ">“Or when saw we thee sick, or in prison, and came unto thee?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/service.p" pid="hdWuW3ukmEioP6KKLozR-w" hash="a22PFg">“And the King shall answer and say unto them, Verily I say unto you, Inasmuch as ye have done it unto one of the least of these my brethren, ye have done it unto me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/service.p" pid="D8NfxyhYFk-xJ7HRJajayQ" hash="C7BHZg">This service is to be given unselfishly, with no thought of personal gain or reward. It is to be given as needed, not when convenient. Opportunities to serve may not always seem obvious, as it is human nature to worry about our own wants and needs. We must resist such tendencies and look for opportunities to serve. When we visit with those who are suffering from sickness, loss of loved ones, or other heartbreak, it is not enough to simply say, “Call if there is anything I can do.” Rather, look for ways to bless the lives of <span class="pageBreak" page-number="103"></span>others through seemingly simple acts of service. It is better to do even things of little consequence than to do nothing at all.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/service.p" pid="HoYrOY_G0EKztsgJVa-03w" hash="aUUKSA">Second, we have an obligation as members of the Church to accept callings to serve in building the kingdom of God on earth. As we serve in our various callings, we bless the lives of others. In missionary work lives are changed as people learn of the gospel of Jesus Christ and receive a testimony of its truth. By the sacred work in the temple we bless the lives of those who have gone on before us. In gospel service we have the privilege to teach others, to strengthen the youth, and to bless the lives of the little children as they learn the simple truths of the gospel. In Church service we learn to give of ourselves and to help others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/service.p" pid="DOUdFP71oEyFsOzbdozKtQ" hash="d4hkuA">President Spencer W. Kimball, a great example of service, said: “God does notice us, and he watches over us. But it is usually through another mortal that he meets our needs. Therefore, it is vital that we serve each other in the kingdom.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> The responsibility of service in the Church, however, does not relieve us of our responsibility to serve our families and our neighbors. President Kimball went on to warn, “None of us should become so busy in our formal Church assignments that there is no room left for quiet Christian service to our neighbors.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/service.p" pid="DLJomC5-Gky53wnGfqgmwQ" hash="CoegZw">Finally, we have a responsibility to render service in our communities. We should work to improve our neighborhoods, our schools, our cities, and our towns. I commend those in our midst who, regardless of their political persuasion, work within our local, state, and national governments to improve our lives. Likewise, I commend those who volunteer their time and resources to support worthy community and charitable causes, which bless the lives of others and make the world a better place. My grandfather taught me at an early age, “The public service we render is the rent we pay for our place on earth.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/service.p" pid="O2CpFQgpbkeuQxcqMapxnQ" hash="qSQFhw">Service requires unselfishness, sharing, and giving. My wife and I learned a valuable lesson during our time of service in Africa. We were assigned to a district conference in Jinja, Uganda. Early Saturday morning before our meetings began, we took the opportunity to tour a new chapel in the area. As we arrived at the building, we were greeted by a young boy <span class="pageBreak" page-number="104"></span>of three to four years of age. He had come to the Church grounds to see what was going on. Struck by his broad smile, Sister Snow reached in her purse and handed him a wrapped piece of hard butterscotch candy. He was delighted.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/service.p" pid="WhxbGzlzdEGWbGT1rUp-6g" hash="nSnoBw">We spent a few minutes touring the chapel before returning outside. We were met by more than a dozen smiling children, who each wanted to meet the new neighborhood candy lady.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/service.p" pid="9_GVK4V61kiorH3eOVPuFg" hash="8LbrMw">Phyllis was heartbroken, as she had given the boy her last piece of candy. She disappointedly gestured to the children there was no more. The small boy who initially greeted us then handed the candy back to Sister Snow, gesturing for her to unwrap it. With a heavy heart, Phyllis did so, fully expecting the boy to pop the butterscotch candy into his mouth in full view of his envious friends.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/service.p" pid="IFei_z_rTk2LqhlnHN-CRg" hash="eulUew">Instead, to our great surprise, he went to each of his friends, who stuck out their tongues and received one delicious lick of the butterscotch candy. The young boy continued around the circle, occasionally taking his own lick, until the candy was gone.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/service.p" pid="cP35U-WiWkeoDgGhkqZRGA" hash="0j5QnQ">Now, one can argue the lack of sanitation with this gesture of sharing, but no one can dispute the example set by this young boy. Unselfishness, sharing, and giving are essential to service. This child learned that lesson well.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/service.p" pid="eLUHLw8WVkGR9B8DCRmg9A" hash="5H1IrA">It is my hope and prayer we can all do more in giving service. If we fail to serve, we fail to receive the fulness of the privileges and blessings of the restored gospel. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div><div class="resources">
    <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/service.f1"><title>Notes</title><ol class="number" guid=""><li guid="f3cf56ce-dc50-4cbe-afe5-fe09def0ac51" pid="iLpt9X7be06IXWDJKH6aFg" hash="x6LFDg1">
        <span class="label">1.</span>
        <p guid="13841a9c-583e-42f0-a513-0ace87f5a963" pid="Frukv-b4L0yM4U5D5kbuuQ" hash="Zb6jAA">
          <span class="emphasis">Pathways to Happiness,</span> comp. Llewelyn R. McKay (1957), 183.</p>
      </li><li guid="cdd4565a-7fc9-424f-b112-a6ef2092fab7" pid="pH3xk2N_rES0uaXS1sh7GA" hash="PkwCFg1">
        <span class="label">2.</span>
        <p guid="f8543187-82aa-4d2b-bfaf-2c8ac14fc275" pid="LKIFGmD0V0qaF6ovMULc0Q" hash="JdNGCQ">
          <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.39" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 22:39</a>.</p>
      </li><li guid="c6ea0a8e-7795-4e08-bba9-dd1331075c82" pid="lkwbrz8xxkaiVzRURE91tw" hash="0_Oydg1">
        <span class="label">3.</span>
        <p guid="ebce66fc-2e79-4c79-8d68-c3a14e82f7e5" pid="4x1g8un6kUixh04cImMKkw" hash="EF5tqg">“Latter-day Prophets Speak: Service,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Sept. 2007, 49.</p>
      </li><li guid="2824a622-fddb-465c-bbb1-b3fd41f1aca9" pid="BC9P1G3htUiDrUW7yz71_Q" hash="_JOOHA1">
        <span class="label">4.</span>
        <p guid="5484aac5-5b54-4609-831b-e9b8018a2829" pid="1ayBZX2u40KewViBP3y1dA" hash="vYZx1w">
          <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/25.37-40" class="scriptureRef">Matthew 25:37–40</a>.</p>
      </li><li guid="36d5b1f4-a93d-4419-8d14-74a0e0c9b5d5" pid="4GVe6AAy3EayJMObn4HsAA" hash="aghhSA1">
        <span class="label">5.</span>
        <p guid="609ad2c3-2629-4f49-bb25-d4610b08c871" pid="w1RRWLEvh0GjE8xMc2AvjQ" hash="iIZpDQ">
          <span class="emphasis">Teachings of Presidents of the Church: Spencer W. Kimball</span> (2006), 82.</p>
      </li><li guid="c868e687-6d2b-4c12-91db-3eb82cbcd732" pid="NCSc6ED5dUWV2_GhXuvW2w" hash="yeEDgA1">
        <span class="label">6.</span>
        <p guid="16a4c797-968d-4f39-8f58-c4265b3cc182" pid="Vhh-MX29SU6270gykiHHJg" hash="Jrui0A">
          <span class="emphasis">Teachings: Spencer W. Kimball,</span> 82.</p>
      </li></ol></div>
    <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/SnowSE_07.jpg" alt="Elder Steven E. Snow" guid="63390591-0033-4ac7-8177-de4a8ed93de1" pid="96kvbCbH0kKUU4_avD2ZqA" hash="LAIJRQ1" />
    <unknown name="digitalAssets" guid="">
      <unknown name="assetGroup" guid="">
        <unknown name="path" guid="63390591-0033-4ac7-8177-de4a8ed93de1"></unknown>
      </unknown>
    </unknown>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2007/10/service</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2007-general-conference/2007-10-5070-elder-steven-e-snow-64k-eng.mp3" length="4374004" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2007 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get On with Our Lives</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives?lang=eng</link>
      <description>By listening to the prophets, keeping an eternal perspective, having faith, and being of good cheer, we can face life’s unexpected challenges.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50015887_000_027" doc-version="2" hash="HfztlQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="5ZYXEYjadkiv9WUSSM30sQ" hash="UytQ8A">Get On with Our Lives</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="Xg5u209PAk6kdzIzNi5XPA" hash="B2OOYA">Elder Steven E. Snow</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="fyGrUlT-5UqkSTMUylVSCA" hash="3BCm8Q">By listening to the prophets, keeping an eternal perspective, having faith, and being of good cheer, we can face life’s unexpected challenges.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives.p1" pid="K8yk0UwgTEGurEKk5yiEPQ" hash="WmTTcQ">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="81"></span>During the very early years of her life, our niece Lachelle spent the mornings with her grandmother. The two shared a special bond from these hours together. Lachelle soon turned five years old and was preparing to begin school. On their last morning together, Grandma Squire read her granddaughter a story and rocked her in the big rocking chair. “We have had so much fun together, Lachelle,” she told her, “and now it is time for you to go to school. I love you so much; what will I ever do without you?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives.p2" pid="JVU0DH95skyvJsHiYfZttQ" hash="cqMyaQ">With wisdom beyond her five years, Lachelle looked up at her grandmother with big brown eyes. “Grandma,” she said, “I love you too, but it is time I got on with my life.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives.p3" pid="4SS5swZQ9UK98B2nLSH4gQ" hash="W0Rcxw">That is good counsel for all of us. We too need to “get on with our lives.” Most of us do not seek or even welcome dramatic changes. But change is an essential part of life’s experiences.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives.p4" pid="oAQL1RkgE0-0vVTTAaEuVA" hash="upjSXA">Many of these changes come as we naturally make our way through our earthly journey. Our lives change as we progress from childhood through youth and on into adulthood and finally old age. Schooling, missions, marriage, employment, and retirement are all examples of milestones of change.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives.p5" pid="fvJBeay2fUC4oCjIszPzEQ" hash="HzbKBA">Too often we are reluctant to enter the next stage, begin the next challenge. Maybe we are too comfortable, fearful, or lacking in faith. Grandmother’s lap is often more comfortable than the trials of kindergarten. Our parents’ basement, with unlimited video games, may be more appealing than college, marriage, or a career.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives.p6" pid="w5a7pjyiZEmQk9kY3EZY9A" hash="Ztt06A">How can we then best prepare for the changes we must inevitably face as we progress through life?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives.p7" pid="Edxmt5XnwUS19RmQex658Q" hash="GrezBA">First, follow the prophets. Listen to and abide by the counsel of the Brethren. Prophets often raise a voice of warning but also provide steady, pragmatic counsel to help us weather the storms of life. In the opening section of the Doctrine and Covenants, the Lord reminds us, “Whether by mine own voice or by the voice of my servants, it is the same” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.38" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:38</a>). Prophets help us confront the changes and challenges we constantly face. The popular Primary song “Follow the Prophet” reminds us of this important principle: “We can get direction all along our way, if we heed the prophets—follow what they say” (<span class="emphasis">Children’s Songbook,</span> 111).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives.p8" pid="DafT8XFHa0qDXzVM1sW5Vg" hash="fZN5BQ">Second, keep an eternal perspective. Understand that change and challenges are part of God’s plan. By design this mortal existence is a time of testing or a time “to see if they will do all things whatsoever the Lord their God shall command them” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.25" class="scriptureRef">Abraham 3:25</a>). In order to test our use of our God-given agency, we as mortals undergo a series of changes, challenges, trials, and temptations as we proceed through life. Only then are we properly tested.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives.p9" pid="iIjfkDyC80qc0IS_GqyZ_Q" hash="RmsDbw">In 2 Nephi we read: “For it must needs be, that there is an opposition in all things. If not so, … righteousness could not be brought to pass, neither wickedness, neither holiness nor misery, neither good nor bad” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.11" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 2:11</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives.p10" pid="zicyVpwIQkaMee0Fq8Jf-g" hash="IOXkcw">Life’s challenges and changes provide opportunities for us to grow as we exercise our agency in making righteous decisions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives.p11" pid="FMeEHtkj8kWRTrBicsHKQg" hash="5lsYOw">Third, have faith. President Gordon B. Hinckley always encouraged members of the Church to move forward with faith (see “God Hath Not Given Us the Spirit of Fear,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Oct. 1984, 4). As we daily confront a world full of negativity, doubt, fear, and even dread can creep into our hearts. President Thomas S. Monson has counseled us that “faith and doubt cannot exist in the same mind at the same time, for one will dispel the other” (“Come unto Him in Prayer <span class="pageBreak" page-number="82"></span>and Faith,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona,</span> Mar. 2009, 4; <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Mar. 2009, 6). In Moroni we read that “without faith there cannot be any hope” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.42" class="scriptureRef">Moroni 7:42</a>). We must exercise faith to take on life’s challenges and changes. It is how we learn and progress.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives.p12" pid="3lhHnJX1QU2BKbsAzMOoCA" hash="_T85QQ">Fourth, be of good cheer. Many of our members across the globe are facing challenges, economic and otherwise. At such times it is easy to feel despondent and forgotten. During the early, difficult days of the Church, the Lord counseled the Saints to be happy: “Be of good cheer, little children; for I am in your midst, and I have not forsaken you” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/61.36" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 61:36</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives.p13" pid="Ws58XLqOE0exSvH11G4bdg" hash="jMn0BA">In his last conference talk, six months ago, Elder Joseph B. Wirthlin taught how to respond to adversity. Part of his counsel included: “The next time you’re tempted to groan, you might try to laugh instead. It will extend your life and make the lives of all those around you more enjoyable” (“Come What May, and Love It,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 2008, 27). Laughter and a good sense of humor can soften the bumps along life’s journey.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives.p14" pid="LsTDJDfJdkmFF-kDkwBr3g" hash="Jiijvw">It would be nice if we could anticipate all the changes that would occur in a lifetime. Some changes we see coming. Certainly all Latter-day Saint young men are taught to prepare for a full-time mission, a life-changing experience. Every worthy young single adult understands the importance of choosing a spouse and being sealed in the holy temple. We know these changes are coming, and we can plan for them. But what about the changes which are thrust upon us rather unexpectedly? These are changes over which we seemingly have no control. Economic downturn, unemployment, debilitating sickness or injury, divorce, and death are examples of change we do not expect, anticipate, or welcome. How do we deal with such unexpected setbacks in life’s journey?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives.p15" pid="Gpf41dPkjkapGUevlpHU9Q" hash="WMAQww">The answer is the same. By listening to the prophets, keeping an eternal perspective, having faith, and being of good cheer, we can face life’s unexpected challenges and “get on with our lives.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives.p16" pid="TlRRzlio20yBkPLt-k9mlg" hash="GRImLw">The lives of the early pioneers are excellent examples of how we should accept change and overcome challenges and difficulties.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives.p17" pid="cimOgZqSR0yq1c7NZghibg" hash="59MX4g">Robert Gardner Jr. was baptized into the Church in January of 1845 in a frozen pond in the backwoods of eastern Canada. Faithful and industrious, he made his way with his family to Nauvoo and, after much hardship, arrived in the Salt Lake Valley in October of 1847. After entering the valley, they camped at a place called Old Fort, located a few blocks from this Conference Center. In his handwritten history, he recorded, “I unyoked my oxen and sat down on my broken wagon tongue, and said I could not go another day’s journey” (“Robert Gardner Jr. Self History and Journal,” Church History Library, 23).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives.p18" pid="oCWZYmWYS0KznectNS9Jpg" hash="6by2dg">Starting with nothing, Robert began to create a new life for himself and his family. The first years were hard, but gradually things improved as he and his brother Archibald began to develop mills on Mill Creek and the Jordan River. A few years later he suffered a reversal of fortune. The water powering his mill was taken upstream, leaving his portion of the stream dry. An attempt to build a six-mile (10-km) canal to the mill failed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives.p19" pid="W6cmJaFuVkKT6aIMd6eORg" hash="D8JGlQ">Again from his history: “The canal kept breaking until it proved a failure. The failure caused me to lose all my crops and my mill would not run. My stock was all gone and I was flat broke” (“Robert Gardner Jr. Self History and Journal,” 26).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives.p20" pid="totIOQeDHUeHRZL6OGC5cA" hash="-dUn8Q">If that was not test enough, his next entry in his history informs us he has been called on a mission to Canada. A few months later he left his <span class="pageBreak" page-number="83"></span>family and with a contingent of missionaries traveled by handcart, steamboat, and railroad to his field of labor.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives.p21" pid="6i6dc7brmUWDXQ2yNudayQ" hash="6ALhLQ">He completed this mission, returned to his family, and through hard work and diligence once again established himself and began to prosper.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives.p22" pid="LV6BUrAsKEuq8TDLedjrZw" hash="2h-EfA">Just a few years later Brother Gardner was entertaining some friends at his farm in Millcreek in the Salt Lake Valley. One remarked, “I am glad to see you so well recovered from being broke. You are nearly as well off as you were before you lost your property and went on your mission.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives.p23" pid="D6T_X8UOx0C15H1KGuQApQ" hash="oV7p2Q">Robert’s history records: “My reply was; ‘Yes I was well off once and it all went off, and I am almost afraid of another [mission] call.’ Sure enough, a few hours later some of my neighbors, who had been to a meeting in Salt Lake City called in and told me that my name was amongst a number of names who were called today to go south on a mission to make a new settlement and raise cotton. We were to start right away.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives.p24" pid="gHFSL4nhaU2tJMjMcmWdEA" hash="VcAM2Q">He records, <span class="emphasis">“I looked and spit, took off my hat and scratched [my head] and thought and said; ‘All right’”</span> (“Robert Gardner Jr. Self History and Journal,” 35; emphasis added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives.p25" pid="iZ7dZgcDN0eZRq5d3mwlpA" hash="-FXBKw">Robert Gardner knew what it meant to deal with change in his life. He followed the counsel of the Brethren, accepting calls to serve when it was not convenient. He had a great love for the Lord and demonstrated strong, unbending faith with amazing good humor and grace. Robert Gardner Jr. went on to become a leading pioneer in the colonization effort of southern Utah. It is he and countless pioneers like him who give us inspiration to carry on and confront fearlessly the many changes and challenges which come into our lives. As we move forward and “get on with our lives,” may we be obedient, faithful, and cheerful is my prayer in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2009/04/get-on-with-our-lives</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2009-general-conference/2009-04-4030-elder-steven-e-snow-64k-eng.mp3" length="5117021" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2009 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hope</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2011/04/hope?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Our hope in the Atonement empowers us with eternal perspective.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50028768_000_3020" doc-version="2" hash="wKGCyQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.head1">
    <h1 class="title" pid="Og815bRIHUK-Bzp_aSd1Cg" hash="LwzFQQ">Hope</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="G2lpRtHzWUmDJnSyyAbo1A" hash="EqQgBw">Steven E. Snow</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="Z38Q3zXccUWfeuj8Zv_hag" hash="2u6MIg">Our hope in the Atonement empowers us with eternal perspective.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.p1" pid="1jX_Lgm-hUWf29gdjXMRRw" hash="iIJGCg">Our family grew up in the high desert country of southern Utah. Rain is rare, and hope abounds that there will be sufficient moisture for the coming heat of summer. Then, as now, we hoped for rain, we prayed for rain, and in dire times, we fasted for rain.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.p2" pid="eEtWWzuocEeuxebiqya5EQ" hash="tJXaug">The story is told there of the grandfather who took his five-year-old grandson for a walk around town. Ultimately, they found themselves at a small grocery store on Main Street where they stopped for a cold soda pop. A car from out of state pulled up and the driver approached the old-timer. Pointing to a small cloud in the sky, the stranger asked, “Do you think it’s going to rain?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.p3" pid="BeKwCbAR6EKG0vcrJbnwHA" hash="6dQQtQ">“I certainly hope so,” replied the old man, “if not for my sake, for the boy’s. I’ve seen it rain.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.p4" pid="ecVE-60lzUmPu-uecebZAA" hash="F0EcIw">Hope is an emotion which brings richness to our everyday lives. It is defined as “the feeling that … events will turn out for the best.” When we exercise hope, we “look forward … with desire and reasonable confidence” (dictionary.reference.com/browse/hope). As such, hope brings a certain calming influence to our lives as we confidently look forward to future events.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.p5" pid="8KLJO6lABkurBlzExIH9rg" hash="U88fHQ">Sometimes we hope for things over which we have little or no control. We hope for good weather. We hope for an early spring. We hope our favorite sports team will win the World Cup, the Super Bowl, or the World Series.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.p6" pid="gbTlxmg_LEuR-bp_mw21JQ" hash="Uym1QA">Such hopes make our lives interesting and can often lead to unusual, even superstitious behavior. For example, my father-in-law is a huge sports fan, but he is convinced if he <span class="emphasis">doesn’t</span> watch his favorite basketball team on television, they are more likely to win. When I was 12 years old, I insisted on wearing the same pair of unwashed socks to every Little League baseball game in the hopes of winning. My mother made me keep them on the back porch.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.p7" pid="kEqEiL1ea0WqkLMY3x_UDQ" hash="FLQhWw">Other times our hopes can lead to dreams which can inspire us and lead us to action. If we have the hope to do better in school, that hope can be realized by dedicated study and sacrifice. If we have the hope to play on a winning team, that hope can lead to consistent practice, dedication, teamwork, and ultimately success.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.p8" pid="h0TjYlR84EmbG-xSe3Jexw" hash="KkbVDA">Roger Bannister was a medical student in England who had an ambitious hope. He desired to be the first man to run a mile (1.6 km) under four minutes. For much of the first half of the early 20th century, field and track enthusiasts had anxiously awaited the day the four-minute-mile barrier would be broken. Over the years many outstanding runners had come close, but still the four-minute barrier stood. Bannister dedicated himself to an ambitious training schedule with the hope of realizing his goal of setting a new world record. Some in the sporting community had begun to doubt whether the four-minute mile could be broken. Supposed experts had even hypothesized the human body was physiologically unable to run at such speeds over such a long distance. On a cloudy day on May 6, 1954, Roger Bannister’s great hope was realized! He crossed the finish line in 3:59.4, setting a new world record. His hope to break the four-minute-mile barrier became a dream which was accomplished through training, hard work, and dedication.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.p9" pid="6qQg26OjCkyLMS3m6uiGNw" hash="nMGCtg">Hope can inspire dreams and spur us to realize those dreams. Hope alone, however, does not cause us to succeed. Many honorable hopes have gone unfulfilled, shipwrecked on the reefs of good intentions and laziness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.p10" pid="lm89p__E60aEl9mUizm_Kg" hash="AQXfiw">As parents, we find our fondest hopes center around our children. We hope they will grow up to lead responsible and righteous lives. Such hopes can be easily dashed if we do not act as good examples. Hope alone does not mean our children will grow in righteousness. We must spend time with them in family home evening and worthwhile family activities. We must teach them to pray. We must read with them in the scriptures and teach them important gospel principles. Only then is it possible our fondest hopes will be realized.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.p11" pid="gT3RTHcBfU-_3rJ0j5DxfA" hash="KWxNxg">We should never let hope be displaced by despair. The Apostle Paul wrote that we “should plow in hope” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/9.10" class="scriptureRef">1 Corinthians 9:10</a>). The exercise of hope enriches our lives and helps us look forward to the future. Whether we are plowing fields to plant or plowing through life, it is imperative we, as Latter-day Saints, have hope.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.p12" pid="OkPsS7Z-tES-uFRNtvMghQ" hash="1zDxsw">In the gospel of Jesus Christ, hope is the desire of His followers to gain eternal salvation through the Atonement of the Savior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.p13" pid="Cz_cLBAf7ka9aoayEaL1gQ" hash="N5dDmA">This is truly the hope we must all have. It is what sets us apart from the rest of the world. Peter admonished the early followers of Christ to “be ready always to give an answer to every man that asketh you a reason of the hope that is in you” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-pet/3.15" class="scriptureRef">1 Peter 3:15</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.p14" pid="GzxXZIdjN0eSymUUWtKt4Q" hash="AGz8fg">Our hope in the Atonement empowers us with eternal perspective. Such perspective allows us to look beyond the here and now on into the promise of the eternities. We don’t have to be trapped in the narrow confines of society’s fickle expectations. We are free to look forward to celestial glory, sealed to our family and loved ones.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.p15" pid="5tDS-Q7PJEe4OZKDjCOowA" hash="MEtHqw">In the gospel, hope is almost always related to faith and charity. President Dieter F. Uchtdorf has taught: “Hope is one leg of a three-legged stool, together with faith and charity. These three stabilize our lives regardless of the rough or uneven surfaces we might encounter at the time” (“The Infinite Power of Hope,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 2008, 21).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.p16" pid="eTIYaJfShkKXdwRi0Nnqtg" hash="v0M1ag">In the last chapter of the Book of Mormon, Moroni wrote:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.p17" pid="PlrF5h7DfEKmbCNQk1LyWQ" hash="s380qw">“Wherefore, there must be faith; and if there must be faith there must also be hope; and if there must be hope there must also be charity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.p18" pid="oPp4coBr5kaIo-9oXYzQBw" hash="k-YHnw">“And except ye have charity ye can in nowise be saved in the kingdom of God; neither can ye be saved in the kingdom of God if ye have not faith; neither can ye if ye have no hope” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.20-21" class="scriptureRef">Moroni 10:20–21</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.p19" pid="MpG04pL01U6a9Nvf8PI6Ng" hash="VXEdog">Elder Russell M. Nelson has taught that “<span class="emphasis">faith</span> is rooted in Jesus Christ. <span class="emphasis">Hope</span> centers in the Atonement. <span class="emphasis">Charity</span> is manifest in the ‘pure love of Christ.’ These three attributes are intertwined like strands in a cable and may not always be precisely distinguished. Together they become our tether to the celestial kingdom” (“A More Excellent Hope,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Feb. 1997, 61).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.p20" pid="KUN6j1GwCkGZQ70fwbEUrA" hash="QAXyrA">When Nephi prophesied of Jesus Christ at the closing of his record, he wrote, “Wherefore, ye must press forward with a steadfastness in Christ, having a perfect brightness of hope, and a love of God and of all men” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/31.20" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 31:20</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.p21" pid="AiSMiTjszEiPI-tPgzNZXw" hash="9nQM5g">This “perfect brightness of hope” of which Nephi speaks is the hope in the Atonement, eternal salvation made possible by the sacrifice of our Savior. This hope has led men and women through the ages to do remarkable things. Apostles of old roamed the earth and testified of Him and ultimately gave their lives in His service.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.p22" pid="e8Are5q1hUadWUnw4w0pAw" hash="7o6yCQ">In this dispensation many early members of the Church left their homes, their hearts full of hope and faith as they made their way west across the Great Plains to the Salt Lake Valley.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.p23" pid="33ioC9GVIEmLkc5ur5yNEw" hash="J8j6xw">In 1851, Mary Murray Murdoch joined the Church in Scotland as a widow at age 67. A small woman at four feet seven inches (1.2 m) tall and barely 90 pounds (41 kg), she bore eight children, six of whom lived to maturity. Because of her size, her children and grandchildren affectionately called her “Wee Granny.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.p24" pid="gFmtkYzSo0eWOvlP59GKqw" hash="QZkTNg">Her son John Murdoch and his wife joined the Church and left for Utah in 1852 with their two small children. In spite of his family’s own hardships, four years later John sent his mother the necessary funds so she might join the family in Salt Lake City. With a hope much greater than her small size, Mary began the arduous journey west to Utah at age 73.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.p25" pid="cCK-9KZP60yLYdWi9GxKKg" hash="gWeZJw">After a safe passage across the Atlantic, she ultimately joined the ill-fated Martin handcart company. On July 28 these handcart pioneers began the journey west. The suffering of this company is well known. Of the 576 members of the party, almost one-fourth died before they reached Utah. More would have perished if not for the rescue effort organized by President Brigham Young, who sent wagons and supplies to find the stranded, snowbound Saints.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.p26" pid="MaWE2rKmoUag3bLrGQymRQ" hash="0BZOwg">Mary Murdoch died on October 2, 1856, near Chimney Rock, Nebraska. Here she succumbed to fatigue, exposure, and the hardships of the journey. Her frail body simply gave out under the physical hardships the Saints encountered. As she lay clinging to life, her thoughts were of her family in Utah. The last words of this faithful pioneer woman were “Tell John I died with my face toward Zion.” (See Kenneth W. Merrell, <span class="emphasis">Scottish Shepherd: The Life and Times of John Murray Murdoch, Utah Pioneer</span> [2006], 34, 39, 54, 77, 94–97, 103, 112–13, 115.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.p27" pid="ayPC0tKlVUCEzERGU9biew" hash="NgtAbQ">Mary Murray Murdoch exemplifies the hope and faith of so many of the early pioneers who made the courageous journey west. The spiritual journeys of today require no less hope or faith than those of the early pioneers. Our challenges may be different, but the struggles are just as great.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/hope.p28" pid="0q0TvMSGL0yoZYkSxBP_nQ" hash="eYYqyA">It is my prayer that our hopes will lead to the fulfillment of our righteous dreams. I particularly pray our hope in the Atonement will strengthen our faith and charity and give us an eternal perspective of our future. May we all have this perfect brightness of hope, I pray in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2011/04/hope</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2011-general-conference/2011-04-3020-elder-steven-e-snow-64k-eng.mp3" length="5530221" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be Thou Humble</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2016/04/be-thou-humble?lang=eng</link>
      <description>&lt;div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/be-thou-humble" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_13285_000_26snow" doc-version="3" hash="7cxqJQ"&gt;
	
	&lt;div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/be-thou-humble.head1"&gt;
		&lt;h1 class="title" pid="fSNnIY0-k0Cv19ThdAbG7g" hash="w9Xp1g"&gt;Be Thou Humble&lt;/h1&gt;
		&lt;div class="byline"&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/be-thou-humble.p2" pid="l_ahVxj2TUm_eiobvdDXTQ" hash="AepZDg1"&gt;By Elder Steven E. Snow&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/be-thou-humble.p3" pid="ndk7TrLHak-Ob8XAlxtP5g" hash="sSmk3g"&gt;Of the Seventy&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=6pzdKgyEA0GjR9MGLbTWfQ"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" altText="Elder Steven E. Snow" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255580/d4c931bc275a48d2ad070f36443609d1/100x140.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x70="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255580/d4c931bc275a48d2ad070f36443609d1/50x70.jpg" data-src-100x140="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255580/d4c931bc275a48d2ad070f36443609d1/100x140.jpg" data-src-200x280="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255580/d4c931bc275a48d2ad070f36443609d1/200x280.jpg" data-src-320x448="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255580/d4c931bc275a48d2ad070f36443609d1/320x448.jpg" data-src-460x644="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255580/d4c931bc275a48d2ad070f36443609d1/460x644.jpg" data-src-640x896="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255580/d4c931bc275a48d2ad070f36443609d1/640x896.jpg" data-src-1024x1434="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255580/d4c931bc275a48d2ad070f36443609d1/1024x1434.jpg" data-src-2048x2868="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255580/d4c931bc275a48d2ad070f36443609d1/2048x2868.jpg" data-src-4087x5724="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255580/d4c931bc275a48d2ad070f36443609d1/4087x5724.jpg" webURL="steven-snow-lds-church-historian_1255580.jpg" pid="6pzdKgyEA0GjR9MGLbTWfQ" hash="AAAAAA"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;p class="kicker" pid="1x7Ot7G_sEWVQ2hltOr9UQ" hash="6GNLcg"&gt;Humility enables us to be better parents, sons and daughters, husbands and wives, neighbors and friends.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="authorName" pid="iXkUx3qi1kWCEIiWzvIVqA" hash="AepZDg"&gt;By Elder Steven E. Snow&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class="bodyBlock"&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/be-thou-humble.p5" pid="2YKWYzvgAU27E2bAU6fDFg" hash="dwtHew"&gt;We are blessed in the Church to have a collection of hymns which help us worship through song. In our Church meetings, “the hymns invite the Spirit of the Lord, create a feeling of reverence, unify us as members, and provide a way for us to offer praises to the Lord. Some of the greatest sermons are preached by the singing of hymns.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/be-thou-humble.p6" pid="-zVouJDgFUi-BDERk_V-Vg" hash="fMgoiQ"&gt;Just a few months after the Church was organized, a revelation was received by the Prophet Joseph Smith for his wife Emma. The Lord directed her “to make a selection of sacred hymns, as it shall be given thee, which is pleasing unto me, to be had in my church.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/be-thou-humble.p7" pid="wrjGF-iEiEGjQq-m7M1IpQ" hash="QzdxxA"&gt;Emma Smith assembled a collection of hymns which first appeared in this Kirtland hymnal in 1836.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt; There were only 90 songs included in this thin little booklet. Many of them were hymns from Protestant faiths. At least 26 of them were written by William W. Phelps, who later prepared and assisted in the printing of the hymnal. Only the lyrics were written; no musical notes accompanied the texts. This humble little hymnal proved to be a great blessing to early members of the Church.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=GRbVQL6zjECoEUHT1SFk6g"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709226/a228fda23dbd4a6faf4b868394bd4a70/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709226/a228fda23dbd4a6faf4b868394bd4a70/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709226/a228fda23dbd4a6faf4b868394bd4a70/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709226/a228fda23dbd4a6faf4b868394bd4a70/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709226/a228fda23dbd4a6faf4b868394bd4a70/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709226/a228fda23dbd4a6faf4b868394bd4a70/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709226/a228fda23dbd4a6faf4b868394bd4a70/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709226/a228fda23dbd4a6faf4b868394bd4a70/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709226/a228fda23dbd4a6faf4b868394bd4a70/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709226/a228fda23dbd4a6faf4b868394bd4a70/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Page from Emma Smith’s hymnbook" pid="GRbVQL6zjECoEUHT1SFk6g" hash="7iq4-A"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=FJcZ2wCrs0uuonrOvkCmcg"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709225/dd878e5b2fc74912b7f59fb0b71820a3/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709225/dd878e5b2fc74912b7f59fb0b71820a3/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709225/dd878e5b2fc74912b7f59fb0b71820a3/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709225/dd878e5b2fc74912b7f59fb0b71820a3/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709225/dd878e5b2fc74912b7f59fb0b71820a3/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709225/dd878e5b2fc74912b7f59fb0b71820a3/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709225/dd878e5b2fc74912b7f59fb0b71820a3/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709225/dd878e5b2fc74912b7f59fb0b71820a3/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709225/dd878e5b2fc74912b7f59fb0b71820a3/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709225/dd878e5b2fc74912b7f59fb0b71820a3/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Title page from Emma Smith’s hymnbook" pid="FJcZ2wCrs0uuonrOvkCmcg" hash="0PXi7g"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/be-thou-humble.p8" pid="Bj7rRl-4VkmxMH1Zl5z9IQ" hash="HZxFvw"&gt;The latest edition of our English-language hymnal was published in 1985. Many of the selections which Emma chose so many years earlier are still included in our hymnbook, such as “I Know That My Redeemer Lives” and “How Firm a Foundation.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4"&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/be-thou-humble.p9" pid="kE35nBSdz0Kqpmj9Yuk0Fg" hash="CXGD-w"&gt;One song that was new to the 1985 hymnal is “Be Thou Humble.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt; This tranquil hymn was written by Grietje Terburg Rowley, who passed away last year. She joined the Church in 1950 in Hawaii, where she was teaching school. Sister Rowley served on the General Music Committee and helped to adapt the hymns into multiple languages. She based her text for “Be Thou Humble” on two verses of scripture: &lt;a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/112.10" class="scriptureRef"&gt;Doctrine and Covenants 112:10&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/12.27" class="scriptureRef"&gt;Ether 12:27&lt;/a&gt;. The verse in Ether reads: “And if men come unto me I will show unto them their weakness. I give unto men weakness that they may be humble; … for if they humble themselves before me, and have faith in me, then will I make weak things become strong unto them.”&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/be-thou-humble.p10" pid="HneRfEVk4EGZ-6ZmIzQjPA" hash="COyrJw"&gt;Like all of the Church’s hymns, “Be Thou Humble” teaches pure and simple truths. It teaches us that if we humble ourselves, our prayers are answered; we enjoy peace of mind; we serve more effectively in our callings; and, if we continue to be faithful, we will ultimately return to the presence of our Heavenly Father.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/be-thou-humble.p11" pid="ZsQrCWQsNUyC-AqhCV3Blg" hash="7cc1dw"&gt;The Savior taught His followers that they must humble themselves as a little child in order to enter into the kingdom of heaven.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6"&gt;6&lt;/span&gt; As we raise our own children, we need to help them remain humble as they mature into adulthood. We do not do this by breaking their spirit through unkindness or by being too harsh in our discipline. While nurturing their self-confidence and self-esteem, we need to teach them the qualities of selflessness, kindness, obedience, lack of pride, civility, and unpretentiousness. We need them to learn to take joy in the successes of siblings and friends. President Howard W. Hunter taught that “our genuine concern should be for the success of others.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7"&gt;7&lt;/span&gt; If not, our children can become obsessed with self-promotion and outdoing others, jealousy, and resentment for the triumphs of peers. I’m grateful for a mother who, when seeing I was becoming too full of myself as a boy, would say, “Son, a little bit of humility right now would go a long way.”&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/be-thou-humble.p12" pid="5DDpt2Gd_kS4pq2d2HADsQ" hash="jTmP-w"&gt;But humility is not something reserved to be taught only to children. We must all strive to become more humble. Humility is essential to gain the blessings of the gospel. Humility enables us to have broken hearts when we sin or make mistakes and makes it possible for us to repent. Humility enables us to be better parents, sons and daughters, husbands and wives, neighbors and friends.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/be-thou-humble.p13" pid="qzbsFDK4rUuyD5FTRjNiFA" hash="vJnh8w"&gt;On the other hand, unnecessary pride can dissolve family relationships, break up marriages, and destroy friendships. It is especially important to remember humility when you feel contention rising in your home. Think of all the heartache you can avoid by humbling yourself to say, “I’m sorry”; “That was inconsiderate of me”; “What would you like to do?”; “I just wasn’t thinking”; or “I’m very proud of you.” If these little phrases were humbly used, there would be less contention and more peace in our homes.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/be-thou-humble.p14" pid="ssdOGFLMHE-2wbk-BT5MRg" hash="23aWWg"&gt;Simply living life can be and often is a humbling experience. Accident and illness, the death of loved ones, problems in relationships, even financial reversals can bring us to our knees. Whether these difficult experiences come through no fault of our own or through bad decisions and poor judgment, these trials are all humbling. If we choose to be spiritually attuned and remain humble and teachable, our prayers become more earnest and faith and testimony will grow as we overcome the tribulations of mortal existence. All of us look forward to exaltation, but before this can occur, we must persevere through what has been referred to as the “valley of humility.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8"&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/be-thou-humble.p15" pid="PlCkAQiAnUmglHWl4QQ74w" hash="lA35sw"&gt;Many years ago, our 15-year-old son Eric suffered a serious head injury. Seeing him in a coma for over a week broke our hearts. The doctors told us they were uncertain about what would happen next. Obviously, we were thrilled when he began to regain consciousness. We thought now everything was going to be fine, but we were mistaken.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/be-thou-humble.p16" pid="I5H8zGi1Dku-ZZN1G-PuAw" hash="cyu8xg"&gt;When he awoke, he could not walk or talk or feed himself. Worst of all, he had no short-term memory. He could remember most everything before the accident, but he had no ability to remember events after, even things which had happened only minutes earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/be-thou-humble.p17" pid="Jm9svt2aMk-rfB58uNjmNQ" hash="2AdLig"&gt;For a time, we worried we would have a son locked in the mind of a 15-year-old. Things had come very easily to our son before the accident. He was athletic, popular, and did very well in school. Before, his future seemed bright; now we worried he may not have much of a future, at least one he could remember. He now struggled to relearn very, very basic skills. This was a very humbling time for him. It was also a very humbling time for his parents.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/be-thou-humble.p18" pid="jPBq8IEsj0at3SZuiNdB2g" hash="KBkPvg"&gt;Honestly, we wondered how such a thing could happen. We had always strived to do the right things. Living the gospel had been a high priority for our family. We couldn’t understand how something so painful could happen to us. We were driven to our knees as it soon became apparent his rehabilitation would take months, even years. More difficult still was the gradual realization he would not be as he was before.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/be-thou-humble.p19" pid="bek9-B33s06o0xhu5G-OTQ" hash="-Wcvlg"&gt;During this time, many tears were shed and our prayers became even more heartfelt and sincere. Through the eyes of humility, we gradually began to see the small miracles which our son experienced during this painful time. He began making gradual improvement. His attitude and outlook were very positive.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/be-thou-humble.p20" pid="Eb2tUVr6okuGMwKnXyMRUQ" hash="yLa6HA"&gt;Today, our son Eric is married to a wonderful companion, and they have five beautiful children. He is a passionate educator and contributor to his community, as well as the Church. Most important, he continues to live in the same spirit of humility he gained long ago.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/be-thou-humble.p21" pid="Y1raqNfaKUqSXGZSMTBUHQ" hash="lnW1Iw"&gt;But what if we could be humble before we walk through that “valley of humility”? Alma taught:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/be-thou-humble.p22" pid="S_jEu7W2G0qWp22A5HzzDA" hash="9cTMEw"&gt;“Blessed are they who humble themselves without being compelled to be humble.”&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/be-thou-humble.p23" pid="zPEmRlnZTUKoeF16c9c24Q" hash="mMqhFw"&gt;“Yea, [they are] much more blessed than they who are compelled to be humble.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9"&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/be-thou-humble.p24" pid="t0tpPouGNEadT9Du_4IMPw" hash="ZE3jmQ"&gt;I am grateful for prophets, like Alma, who have taught us the worth of this great attribute. Spencer W. Kimball, the 12th President of the Church, said: “How does one get humble? To me, one must constantly be reminded of his dependence. On whom dependent? On the Lord. How remind one’s self? By real, constant, worshipful, grateful prayer.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/be-thou-humble.p25" pid="cMskpEXsWEG1Tjrv1JxoAw" hash="Amk7dw"&gt;It should come as no surprise that President Kimball’s favorite hymn was “I Need Thee Every Hour.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11"&gt;11&lt;/span&gt; Elder Dallin H. Oaks reported that this was the most oft-sung opening hymn by the Brethren in the temple during his early years in the Quorum of the Twelve. He said, “Picture the spiritual impact of a handful of the Lord’s servants singing that song before praying for his guidance in fulfilling their mighty responsibilities.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12"&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/be-thou-humble.p26" pid="dNC-tkzxfUaT66k7NqwUyA" hash="s7lcfw"&gt;I testify of the importance of humility in our lives. I am grateful for the individuals like Sister Grietje Rowley who have penned inspiring words and music which help us learn the doctrine of the gospel of Jesus Christ, which includes humility. I am grateful we have a legacy of hymns, which helps us to worship through song, and I am grateful for humility. It is my prayer we will all strive for humility in our lives so we might become better parents, sons and daughters, and followers of the Savior. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2016/04/be-thou-humble</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2016-general-conference/2016-04-1060-steven-e-snow-64k-eng.mp3" length="5248854" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
