<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Ted E. Brewerton</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Ted E. Brewerton.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Ted%20E.%20Brewerton.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Ted E. Brewerton.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 1983 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Profanity and Swearing</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Which of the Lord’s Ten Commandments is probably broken the most frequently? I believe it would be taking the name of God in vain. (See .)</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03161_000_031" doc-version="2" hash="ALG1Zw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="5t8vjwX3yUCgbLDajgUEzA" hash="3Hr9vA">Profanity and Swearing</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="OrQ2u01vikC8mxUC1Us5WA" hash="fY7CfQ">Ted E. Brewerton</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-213e.jpg" alt="Elder Ted E. Brewerton" pid="ZG0lAsQjmkS1nfzGolxxRw" hash="2cdP6w" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p1" pid="-trJqaDDYUO7JYngywnn3A" hash="cn5qfQ">Which of the Lord’s Ten Commandments is probably broken the most frequently? I believe it would be taking the name of God in vain. (See <a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/20.7" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 20:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p2" pid="mrLXhZkaIEG3rdiJRLIXpg" hash="mOHbfg">Today I should like to treat the important subject of profanity and swearing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p3" pid="kFd1zuYt6kuvwKoB5zDsCA" hash="eTswdg">According to <span class="emphasis">Modern Guide to Synonyms</span> (p. 469), <span class="emphasis">profanity, blasphemy, cursing, obscenity, swearing,</span> and <span class="emphasis">vulgarity</span> all refer to crude or foul language. Profanity and blasphemy usually refer to the irreverent use of the name of Deity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p4" pid="uAkf-0phHUeiJzfSYiS-xw" hash="pBTBWw">Socrates said to a young man who was introduced to him, “Talk in order that I may see you.” (<span class="emphasis">Communication of Ideas,</span> p. 72.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p5" pid="f4LXQ0iyyEytEBi6uYN-AA" hash="gAvGdA">We reveal ourselves with our speech. Shakespeare urged in <span class="emphasis">King Lear,</span> “Mend your speech a little, lest it may mar your fortunes.” (act 1, sc. 1, line 96.) If we err, then remember the words of Confucius: “A man who has committed a mistake and doesn’t correct it is committing another mistake.” (<span class="emphasis">Vital Quotations,</span> sel. Emerson Roy West, Salt Lake City: Bookcraft, 1968, p. 228.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p6" pid="cvLVaTsJZk6mEZPVKMeZ0w" hash="5XtPxg">I desire to read to you many of the Lord’s words given through his prophets over the years so we might understand and think as he does regarding improper words.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p7" pid="XziTWSWFHkSEfi9bZLALjQ" hash="oBUaTA">“Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord thy God in vain; for the Lord will not hold him guiltless that taketh his name in vain.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/20.7" class="scriptureRef">Ex. 20:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p8" pid="yxfQfc4-VESojKGZOkv6GA" hash="XEYzqw">“But now ye also put off all these; anger, wrath, malice, blasphemy, filthy communication out of your mouth.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/col/3.8" class="scriptureRef">Col. 3:8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p9" pid="jNGUbWB7OEyOFYkCGdHWlw" hash="u90QMQ">Have we ever asked ourselves what is the harm or end result of swearing? Jeremiah expresses one thought about it in this way:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p10" pid="CCeYpNivT06rMDz2lLNZnw" hash="9tM1hA">“For because of swearing the land mourneth; the pleasant places of the wilderness are dried up.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/jer/23.10" class="scriptureRef">Jer. 23:10</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p11" pid="mnFV6LT4Jk2xVvMFKY6yGQ" hash="Jul1fQ">President McKay speaks clearly regarding profane language: “No parent can consistently teach faith in Christ who profanes the name of Deity. Profanity is never heard in the well-ordered home. Swearing is a vice that bespeaks a low standard of breeding. Blasphemous exclamations drive out all spirit of reverence.” (<span class="emphasis">Gospel Ideals,</span> Salt Lake City: <span class="emphasis">Improvement Era, </span>1953, p. 420.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p12" pid="tW9lDzfGp0uK1zd8N9niJQ" hash="nQZXqg">Judith Martin of the <span class="emphasis">Washington Post</span> writes the article “Miss Manners,” which is syndicated in seventy-five other newspapers. She says regarding rudeness of speech:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p13" pid="goq7Y_wOMk-xS0k7Q7h3vQ" hash="0vCPXw">“How does one deal with a rude person? Politely. I don’t believe in answering rudeness with rudeness under any circumstances.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p14" pid="oXY1EjHKhESJxAREO6979g" hash="EHjybw">“How is that accomplished? With the stare or smile. I do not recommend the snappy comeback and putdown.” (<span class="emphasis">People Magazine,</span> Aug. 1982, p. 38.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p15" pid="OCR4QKYqAUu3mA9oCAmKZg" hash="ATqoXA">Politeness achieves much more than answering rudeness with rudeness. “Be patient in afflictions, <span class="emphasis">revile not against those that revile</span>.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/31.9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 31:9</a>; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p16" pid="WLXxPS7feE2aoYFgSuxxLA" hash="ckQGkQ">The Lord speaks with clarity on this subject through his prophets. President Joseph Fielding Smith states: “Profanity is filthiness. A person is known as much by his language as he is by the company he keeps. … Filthiness in any form is degrading and soul-destroying and should be avoided.” (<span class="emphasis">Doctrines of Salvation,</span> Salt Lake City: Bookcraft, 1:13.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p17" pid="uQtIM8MHpku7ujhivuGmMw" hash="NwzlbA">If we are not most careful with our thoughts and speech, the words we use will use us. Language has its own ethics, and one who communicates truth is like a bright light in the darkness. We must nurture language like that.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p18" pid="u7CgbQw1Ak-TcEo7NXfd4Q" hash="H6WRwQ">How interesting it is to hear nonmembers of the Church express their feelings about bad language. I like very much the title and comments used by Bob Greene of the Field Newspaper Syndicate who speaks of swearing in these terms. The title he uses is “<span class="emphasis">Hear</span> Pollution.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p19" pid="LHXIre549kugOUfEPb2RiA" hash="Kw_JeQ">“Obscenity, the open use of which used to be a mark of lower social strata, has somehow become acceptable in everyday conversation for everyday people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p20" pid="cMryQ-R3KkSCANe_DXe9jA" hash="nyE7HQ">“And yet, I am offended—not out of a sense of morality or of prudishness—but because foul language used casually in public comes close to the idea of a violation of privacy. I know that there are some around who feel assaulted by hearing it. I chose that word very carefully; certain language is an assault on the senses.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p21" pid="6x6VjIW2AEScwTuaL_X8pQ" hash="oUJOGA">“Those who disagree are probably saying, ‘after all, it’s only words.’ But words are vehicles; they convey messages. And to some people, the message of profanity is a message of ugliness and aggressiveness and a disrespect for civil behavior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p22" pid="FOwZ0XQRwEqrR7oGtwt_3Q" hash="cBvPvA">“Bathroom and sexual obscenities can now be heard in certain popular songs on the radio, and even some magazines and newspapers have begun to print language that would have been unthinkable five years ago. This practice is usually defended under the name of ‘freedom.’ But whose freedom is it? If the language of ugliness becomes so much a part of our society that it is impossible to escape no matter where one turns, then who is free and who isn’t?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p23" pid="IHX6_QR1FkqHRXwUauqLdg" hash="A-pGXg">These assaults on the senses and the messages they carry do not elevate—they pull people down.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p24" pid="azQcZBP29Uajx2P5DXa_Mw" hash="Qk2zcA">There is no place in this Church or in any of our families for pessimism or negativism. We should be incurable optimists.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p25" pid="qUFYJcfqT0SKnjGj9pyTHQ" hash="sbHqHw">Irrespective of the condition of a person, he who is a cynic, a pessimist, or negative has the least progress, happiness, and prosperity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p26" pid="xspVf7tFdkKS62pSuMF0Rg" hash="VqZVKw">On the other hand, the Lord’s way is that the optimist with faith, who is positive, elevating, and edifying, is the individual in or out of the Church who is the most progressive, happy, and prosperous. The Lord said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p27" pid="SAPynvZT2022lFgeOeOkFQ" hash="7S7l5Q">“Therefore, strengthen your brethren in all your conversation, in all your prayers, in all your exhortations, and in all your doings.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/108.7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 108:7</a>.)</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.f2">
	<p pid="d3bCpHVkE0yNltGmfkoS-A" hash="bPcHMQ">We should—</p>
	<ul class="bullet">
	  <li pid="hEQQ_L_alkCebyjjOoZpuQ" hash="Vz9zzg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="Xf7CO8FRfkCJ3BDVzlKEiA" hash="7NQM_w">enlighten</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="iH4YurvwcEWxALy9khxbww" hash="Tts8Rw">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="ldwA4Qdl4k-6g_OOil5N_w" hash="_qYLrw">edify</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="9fn2_7HLGEmRprAg8lqcgQ" hash="sVsCOQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="Cnhq83YyG0Oc0nDVSCctwg" hash="3EEsbA">lift</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="MYcDTpaAYk2iRAmmz22-NA" hash="YsGsfg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="DhNk0crGxEyoHG9jmWYC3Q" hash="qz1bMg">motivate</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="GMVuDLUprUy7KVAjyvLgrA" hash="XktRlA">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="AB1_iF6MEkemmA1vawz8rg" hash="rxI-0A">elevate</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="CBihDlNedEmvmsH0BgclGA" hash="Y481Ow">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="JBgeFuUqUESIPNX6fZ08tg" hash="YVlx_A">build and uplift</p>
        </li>
	</ul>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p28" pid="uBjANPBY9EWHcJwFARHYug" hash="Cz1BKg">
        <span class="emphasis">in all of our conversations and doings.</span>
      </p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p29" pid="TwvC1rrocUeqcOlVZXwKew" hash="MAu4zg">Now listen to the prophet’s words as I read them, regarding encouraging, lifting, and edifying:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p30" pid="6WhcqZF-DUyDShta57C-qw" hash="kDETbw">“Let no corrupt communication proceed out of your mouth, but that which is good to the use of edifying, that it may minister grace unto the hearers.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/4.29" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 4:29</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p31" pid="h40lHQD_dUyHX9rQt8qJtA" hash="6Lh7pg">“Cease to contend one with another; cease to speak evil one of another.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p32" pid="DloeUafHmk2xHMWccRyieA" hash="Q8titQ">“… Let your words tend to edifying one another.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/136.23-24" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 136:23–24</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p33" pid="0yAj7T_Pp06gt55WAUOJ9A" hash="wjvwAw">In the magazine <span class="emphasis">Success Unlimited,</span> Dec. 1982, Dwight Chapin draws to our attention a crucial aspect of creating only positive emotions:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p34" pid="L5vvn3qNuUG4hmbBLEzWbA" hash="V6Rh2Q">“Every time a business in the service industry creates a negative emotion in the mind of a customer or client, that individual will share his dissatisfaction with an average of ten people before the emotion dissipates.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p35" pid="zun7wuH550CGXr2ZlOdfMA" hash="TtCeYQ">“The same research shows that a person who is impressed with a service will share that positive emotion with an average of only three other people at most. Given this situation it’s obvious why negative news travels faster and farther than positive news.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p36" pid="ecBpxslx9EOzCUuJUrI_xw" hash="-UoO7Q">That gives us all the more reason to be uplifting and positive. Profane words <span class="emphasis">never</span> edify.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p37" pid="XNM3km2WbEu6S88IGc2pJg" hash="m-fH0g">There is some value in this expression of an unknown author: “I shall return again, for I like myself more when I am with you.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p38" pid="X76fZZ4-B0GQiJUbRJw09w" hash="2pA0Sg">Peter and the associates of the Savior were greater because of the Savior. He built them, lifted them, and treated them as they were to become.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p39" pid="kEd0hpd9rkaj3jrs1UzSJQ" hash="iHRyYA">The associates of Joseph Smith were greater because of Joseph Smith. He raised them and strengthened them. So it has been with all the Presidents of the Church—men are greater because of them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p40" pid="plGvq10EbESC6hv8EjiACA" hash="6PT1wA">Church leaders do <span class="emphasis">not</span> spend time pulling down people or other institutions. They proclaim their own truths and allow others to express themselves.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p41" pid="HCu9KfRo5US6tSimpPGFEg" hash="hAPHWQ">The Brethren of the First Presidency have upon their shoulders the heaviest burden and responsibilities of any mortal—yet they are never heavyhearted; one who enters their offices always leaves a better person than when he entered.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p42" pid="h8wdCAL4mEeCml5UPrynJg" hash="TqVKgA">The Lord’s counsel is very clear: “Give ye ear, and hear my voice; hearken, and hear my speech.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/28.23" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 28:23</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p43" pid="Gaho7dw4i0KOFDNZICX0Hw" hash="WRPp0g">Do we really <span class="emphasis">listen</span> as we read the scriptures? Do we really hear his voice, hearken, and do his will? There are many who <span class="emphasis">do</span> hear and follow him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p44" pid="5Uv-lkqlE0uWbcq3LJRjIg" hash="kOVYUw">Here are some good examples of hearing and doing the Lord’s counsel:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p45" pid="8jaEpi0g1ka8t4myklfJsg" hash="4eTK0Q">In 1974 there were only about eight or ten Brazilians serving missions. Then President Kimball asked for more missionaries. By mid-1979 Brazil had over five hundred full-time local missionaries serving, and Mexico had over seven hundred.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p46" pid="zMK22bXXOEmjhMeHR7jSjw" hash="HjcRSw">They heard his counsel, did they not?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p47" pid="njPiz1O8aUSPxcsS8DBmFQ" hash="9_Kd5Q">When I was a mission president in Central America some years ago, two of the elders brought a Catholic Benedictine monk into my office.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p48" pid="xfkYNNawGU6kgPajzcKJYg" hash="g_bH9Q">He had noticed the <span class="emphasis">elevating nature</span> of the Church due to an in-depth study he and others had been commissioned to do of 243 different churches. This study had been ordered by the Catholic church with honorable intent; they wished to know the similarities of the 243 churches to see the possibilities of more union and brotherhood.</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.f3">
	<p pid="klv2T9eqVkSPGAWLl7oLSg" hash="n3BspQ">After researching for over five years, they came to at least these two conclusions:</p>
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="s6Qw-0fiD0enSlrFPVF9qw" hash="rFa4Bg">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="_z7i_IY7tUCOW1hpoSyU3A" hash="FZoeig">There were only two churches that had high moral values; one was The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="mmIKfwl100KzeJg_Oj1qKA" hash="9VPbug">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="R9SslLMfHkq5vPyi8S-nTA" hash="bv6lLg">There was only one church that followed all the prophetic utterances of old—in other words, accepted and followed all the Old and New Testament—that was the Mormons.</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p49" pid="BhzZMRIr3k2UEHMBKIX4oQ" hash="HZYB5Q">This monk accepted the challenge to study the Book of Mormon and prayed to have divine verification of its truthfulness. As a result, he accepted the Savior by being baptized into this, His church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p50" pid="bay8VbLIoECzl9JVTOsWGA" hash="mL-QHg">He is now an active teacher in a high priests quorum in Central America.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p51" pid="WWlGDgtnFUyE0W93qo5Sqw" hash="KKC04Q">He saw by investigation the edifying, lifting influence of the Church and hearkened unto the voice of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p52" pid="NJocq1Rgc0K7miIiAapERg" hash="Y9DNmg">A prominent man who had not visited a certain northern Utah high school for some two years attended a sports event and was appalled and offended by the escalation of profanity and crude language he heard.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p53" pid="tJI8Ik0WxUCB1dFR0L-4cw" hash="KWo5Ag">Parents, do we wonder where our families or children are hearing obscene, crude, and foul words? Certainly <span class="emphasis">never</span> in our homes, for our homes are next to the temple in sacredness. They are an uplifting refuge, in which we instruct our families as to what the Lord expects of us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p54" pid="71FRaHc5aU-R3Zt2qw2Kfw" hash="632g4A">Self-control is an effective quality that lifts anyone above the crowd; a memory of a self-controlled person will always be pleasant. We should never lower our dignity by lowering our language. We don’t ever repeat a profane comment made by someone else. In the text <span class="emphasis">Teaching—No Greater Call</span> we read this regarding self-mastery:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p55" pid="5UCpl085yUSViRlD8yzu_Q" hash="tIYSrg">“The height of a man’s success is gauged by his self-mastery; the depth of his failure by his self-abandonment. There is no other limitation in either direction. And this law is the expression of eternal justice.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p56" pid="BgUUVHlDYUqbTeVs76bnbg" hash="BAj5pA">“He who cannot establish a dominion over himself will have no dominion over others, he who masters himself shall be king.” (As cited by Spencer W. Kimball, <span class="emphasis">Improvement Era,</span> June 1966, p. 525.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p57" pid="yL3AoNydsEOKxeqiNItzig" hash="80HMJg">Shouldn’t we all have mastery over our tongues and words <span class="emphasis">all</span> of the time, and only elevate and edify?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing.p58" pid="nnfTXC30q0ye2YMRH-fl3g" hash="TYuDLg">We are in the presence of and being directed by living prophets. This is an absolute truth. The Lord himself directs this, his only true and living church, and I testify to this in the name of Jesus Christ, the Master, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1983/04/profanity-and-swearing</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1983-general-conference/1983-04-5040-elder-ted-e-brewerton-64k-eng.mp3" length="5217879" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 1983 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Son and Yours—Each a Remarkable One</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My thoughts at this time will be in the form of a dialogue between me and my fourteen-year-old son, Michael, who resides with us in Argentina. I will talk about how important he is and how much the Lord and I love him. At the same time I address thes</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03206_000_013" doc-version="2" hash="vxPeRw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="DStiZE3AfkyTqJGcoGZ1ew" hash="f9aynQ">My Son and Yours—</h1>
    <p class="subtitle" pid="uDLu7_F-hEm4EH6X3r68PQ" hash="lIqtHw">Each a Remarkable One</p>
    <p class="authorName" pid="VSPElEWFgU-BXG3Isaht-A" hash="fY7CfQ">Ted E. Brewerton</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-213e.jpg" alt="Elder Ted E. Brewerton" pid="TzFzGrxIkUGparbBk0Dnuw" hash="2cdP6w" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p1" pid="t7oy-rE8YU6X8vUK38Q0ag" hash="HWKrHg">My thoughts at this time will be in the form of a dialogue between me and my fourteen-year-old son, Michael, who resides with us in Argentina. I will talk about how important he is and how much the Lord and I love him. At the same time I address these critical thoughts to him, they would be the same as I would express to my son David, the eldest of my six children, or to their four beautiful sisters, my daughters, Michelle, Andrea, Leanne, and Lycia.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p2" pid="hg5vzj1dTEOy_80xwm9gKA" hash="Afo_8Q">Fathers, would you like to join me and share the same thoughts as if directed to your sons and daughters, describing their singular importance in the eyes of our Heavenly Father?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p3" pid="rH4Hbf9bCEWTFd912-2FDg" hash="oYkheQ">Hi, Michael, you know how much I trust and love you, don’t you? Let me try to show you who you are and how very important you are as a literal son of our Father in Heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p4" pid="8FHe3IZDiUuWzV69nYC0Uw" hash="UgOxzA">President Harold B. Lee said that this understanding of who we are is “of first importance,” and without it we lack “the basis of a solid foundation upon which to build [our] lives” (in Conference Report, Oct. 1973, p. 5).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p5" pid="yhHjkdNCcE-VKJJ8PVijow" hash="pV9QDQ">First, Mike, we know by reasoning, seeing, and the impressions of the Spirit that the Lord is a living perfect man. Many have seen him: for example, Adam, Enoch, the brother of Jared, Abraham, Moses, Joseph Smith, Isaac, Jacob, Seth, Nephi, Isaiah, Emer, Joshua, Manoah and his wife, Solomon, Sidney Rigdon, Alma, Moroni, Stephen, and John. Alma states, “Many, exceedingly great many” have seen him (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/13.12" class="scriptureRef">Alma 13:12</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p6" pid="VJq3ekWiw0eNWr4fCX-yYg" hash="1fcvdg">Now another evidence of God: speaking of the planets and orbs, the Lord says, “Any man who hath seen any or the least of these hath seen God moving in his majesty and power” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.47" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:47</a>). “The heavens declare the glory of God; and the firmament sheweth his handywork” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/19.1" class="scriptureRef">Ps. 19:1</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p7" pid="RMNJthNpS0Sce9UWxeJkGQ" hash="o-gdrg">Mike, let’s visualize three scenes together.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p8" pid="Gj4LWNZG7UySICTafVNasw" hash="wiAMXQ">
        <span class="emphasis">Scene 1.</span> First of all, we see before us, Michael, our solar system: our sun, together with the earth and the eight other heavenly bodies that revolve around it. We see law, beauty, order, and perfection.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p9" pid="MfS45PAREEePwQcX2tMEcw" hash="3OJBiA">
        <span class="emphasis">Scene 2.</span> Now, Michael, in this next scene, we see this same solar system in its place in our galaxy, the Milky Way. We marvel at the order and arrangement. Our planets are so small they can’t be detected here, but our sun and its nine planets appear as one of these shining orbs and are situated about two-thirds of the way from the center, about thirty thousand light years from the middle of the Milky Way. Our planets move about the sun; the sun itself moves in a circular path at a speed of 130 miles per second, yet even at that speed, Mike, a complete turn around the Milky Way takes two hundred billion years. <span class="emphasis">This, our star system, has about two hundred billion blazing suns</span> and is one hundred thousand light years wide.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p10" pid="Y2toaC5B7UqWnZkiBlzUYQ" hash="pe5IgA">
        <span class="emphasis">Scene 3.</span> Now in this next scene, Michael, we see our galaxy, the Milky Way, in space along with other galaxies. You know, Mike, it is conservatively estimated that <span class="emphasis">there are ten billion star systems like these galaxies.</span> Incomprehensible? I should say! We have soared out far beyond our imaginations.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p11" pid="C8M5TdUp4UKzKeuDDw2cYQ" hash="zw2z0A">What is a billion, Michael? One thousand million—that’s right.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p12" pid="j7CoUK-VakqlAXYyzAyZYw" hash="Cvv-oA">What’s a definition of a million, Michael? That’s good; you say a million is like your mother telling you to clean up your room 274 times every day for ten years.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p13" pid="OMofvXpSpUaCh_FHh1ijgQ" hash="FU3faA">How fast does light travel, Mike? That’s right: 186,000 miles per second. Hold up your left fist as if it represented the earth. Now whirl your right index finger around it. If your index finger spun around it about seven times in one second, you have shown how fast light would travel around the earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p14" pid="m6zUmt1MTEWmuSod6LQOTQ" hash="YNTuZw">It takes about eight minutes for light to reach the earth, and just over one second for light to reach the moon from the earth. Imagine how far light could travel in one day of 86,400 seconds. Wow! Then in one year … it is beyond our ability to understand.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p15" pid="kRl1ysM55USM_3XIqAoVUg" hash="YqA-GQ">The Lord said: “And worlds without number have I created; and I also created them for mine own purpose; and by the Son I created them, which is mine Only Begotten.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p16" pid="ONWEqIoFGEGndFIGFGy2hA" hash="Aa-lcg">“And the Lord God spake unto Moses, saying: The heavens, they are many, and they cannot be numbered unto man; but they are numbered unto me, for they are mine” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.33,37" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:33, 37</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p17" pid="V8MNriGgkE6QBywodKtNNg" hash="PqtmVg">He further said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p18" pid="Pb9HRDAR00ues1edj4ofRw" hash="mTc45g">“And were it possible that man could number the particles of the earth, yea, millions of earths like this, it would not be a beginning to the number of thy creations” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/7.30" class="scriptureRef">Moses 7:30</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p19" pid="AfxejkYVAkyd92h-YqR2mg" hash="TOKm2A">Isn’t that exciting, Mike?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p20" pid="nykfO_rkxUOTFm-Bp2diuw" hash="HGCM-A">From <span class="emphasis">The Amazing Universe</span> we read: “As the sum of knowledge grows, the astronomer continues to seek answers to man’s most profound questions: ‘What is the grand design of the universe? How was it created? How did we get here? Are we alone?’” (p. 10).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p21" pid="O_AsTX5wJEqbmnIpgxjPTw" hash="h3ZmBg">We again read, “It is impossible to any sensitive person to look at a star-filled sky without being stirred by thoughts of creation and eternity” (<span class="emphasis">The Amazing Universe, </span>p. 166). “A super-giant elliptical galaxy may contain more than ten trillion stars and measure 300,000 light-years across.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p22" pid="OBgo-oroD060me5WeefmEQ" hash="G0f_Eg">
        <span class="emphasis">The sheer immensity of such systems suggest eternal qualities of stability and predictability</span> (<span class="emphasis">The Amazing Universe, ,</span> p. 134; italics added). See, Mike, the scientific world sees the evidence of a supreme being.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p23" pid="e-azr7Fn8kyVszRr3jZT5Q" hash="AFRCag">With all this massive, orderly creation, are you, Michael, a single human being, important? The scriptures state:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p24" pid="_aE3rKfGW0CHUbdevH6_zw" hash="NgDJbA">“When I consider thy heavens, the work of thy fingers, the moon and the stars, which thou hast ordained;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p25" pid="PDJXQOy3i0CY8fXrgcJcmQ" hash="lE0Qkw">“What is man, that thou art mindful of him? and the son of man, that thou visitest him?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p26" pid="jzNqym3NnkmQ1ueTgGbAvw" hash="sZeBHg">“For thou hast made him a little lower than the angels, and hast crowned him with glory and honour.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p27" pid="9VirY628UEaCWQIi5icvBg" hash="h5sjqQ">“Thou madest him to have dominion over the works of thy hands; thou hast put all things under his feet” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/8.3-6" class="scriptureRef">Ps. 8:3–6</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p28" pid="xKTu3J_ap0ePiqPPevcLUA" hash="OnPV1Q">Yes, <span class="emphasis">you,</span> Michael, are <span class="emphasis">everything;</span> you are <span class="emphasis">why</span> the heavens were created.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p29" pid="eOHNEJlDZEWWGwl3XlRvRQ" hash="FkGB0w">Mike, you must realize a truth: that God knows who you are and what you may become. He knows where you are and what he expects of you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p30" pid="H5UYIv37JkegyDtyCUkJKg" hash="OivvRQ">You, Michael, are God’s son, hence heir to all he has. His purpose and goal is to bring to pass <span class="emphasis">your</span> immortality and eternal life. You are the most important thing that exists—his most important creation. So we must be master of our beings and control ourselves, and not be controlled by some habit or by someone else. We must be lifters and not leaners. Reach for the stars.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p31" pid="528lUo0PbE-7H4vBYHFfeQ" hash="JqwBtg">You, Mike, with the Lord’s help, have an unlimited potential. Let’s follow the perfect example of the Master, our Savior. How easy it is to have hope: “Hope is the strongest weapon in the spiritual arsenal of youth” (<span class="emphasis">Royal Bank Newsletter,</span> vol. 66, no. 6).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p32" pid="Yd8tzr1CpEWMSBK6iHC1HA" hash="AaKzBQ">The sun is <span class="emphasis">our</span> star, the only source of all light and energy for us. It makes life possible.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p33" pid="5naKPgwbbU64lDJD8EQZlA" hash="F6DCfg">
        <span class="emphasis">One</span> star—a remarkable one. There are about two hundred billion blazing <span class="emphasis">ones,</span> or suns, in our star system alone, and over ten billion star systems; yet one sun is a remarkable one. <span class="emphasis">You,</span> Michael, are like a sun—a remarkable <span class="emphasis">one.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p34" pid="zAdpp84B10OBSBKtXGgJPg" hash="FVQGvw">Jesus, the Redeemer, had no office or public function, yet he shaped the world’s history. He wishes you to understand that you should be a remarkable <span class="emphasis">one,</span> for the power is in <span class="emphasis">you</span> to make things happen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p35" pid="WHhMFYsR-Eu9XZI7KZAJUg" hash="humTpg">Here is a true story that relates a simple experience of a nineteen-year-old who became a remarkable <span class="emphasis">one.</span> He was magnified and had great powers beyond his natural abilities as the Lord acted through him. There was a young nineteen-year-old admirer of Joseph Smith, Philemon Merrill, who had come with other loyal followers to rescue their prophet from the hands of sheriffs Reynolds and Wilson. While returning to Nauvoo, the company rested “in a little grove of timber.” One of the lawyers for the sheriff and the kidnappers boasted of his wrestling powers. He offered a wager that he could throw any man in Illinois. Stephen Markham, a bodyguard of Joseph’s and a huge man, also an experienced wrestler, took up the challenge. The boaster threw Stephen, and a taunting shout went up from the Prophet’s enemies.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p36" pid="FKjpBVdr7k-swHUXvjmo_A" hash="tf2P0A">As the taunts continued, Joseph Smith turned to young Philemon Merrill and said: “‘Get up and throw that man.’”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p37" pid="4HKxpV0nEUuN2gsD4UwF0w" hash="ZFhezw">The boy was about to refuse, to excuse himself by saying he was not a wrestler, but the look in the Prophet’s eye silenced his tongue. “He arose to his feet filled with the strength of a Samson.” Philemon “lifted his arms” and told the lawyer to take his choice of sides.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p38" pid="XCd_neWQBEyWE4gLJoKxuw" hash="bkwJEg">“The man took the left side with his right hand under,” which gave him a decided advantage. Philemon Merrill’s friends protested, but young Philemon felt such confidence in the words of the Prophet that it made little difference to him what advantage his antagonist took. As they began to grapple, Joseph instructed him, “‘Philemon, when I count three, <span class="emphasis">throw him</span>!’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p39" pid="zXkJyYE7DUONfOQ5hv2jbQ" hash="Zz_erg">“On the instant after the word of three dropped from Joseph’s lips,” Philemon Merrill, “with the strength of a giant, threw the lawyer over his left shoulder, and he fell striking his head upon the earth.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p40" pid="DXQ5I_PfWUqYBbDwNcJuuQ" hash="o0qKIw">Little wonder it is reported that “awe fell upon the opponents of the Prophet when they saw this, and there were no more challenges to wrestle during the journey” (George Q. Cannon, <span class="emphasis">Life of Joseph Smith the Prophet,</span> Classics in Mormon Literature, Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1986, pp. 450–51).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p41" pid="YzK8zDL1t02AHBKUmslM7A" hash="elxWsA">Here’s another example of a remarkable <span class="emphasis">one,</span> Michael—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p42" pid="oQUbMVCfCUWkQHWyu1zD8Q" hash="xiWRmw">John Taylor, in his book <span class="emphasis">The Gospel Kingdom,</span> relates how the <span class="emphasis">one</span> is magnified by the Spirit and <span class="emphasis">makes</span> extraordinary things happen:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p43" pid="wLvgIY0BbUuSrtsWiHCTfQ" hash="G9TUKQ">“Some … years ago, in Far West, a mob—one of those semi-occasional occurrences—had come against us with evil intent, placing themselves in position to give us battle. … We had one fellow who … ordered our people to retreat. As soon as Joseph heard this sound, he exclaimed, ‘Retreat! where in the name of God shall we retreat to?’ He then led us out to the prairie, facing the mob, and placed us in position. And the first thing we knew a flag of truce was seen coming towards us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p44" pid="MCGESA4BgEyea6Jw15Ymsg" hash="-d_Gug">“… Joseph Smith, our leader, then sent word back by this messenger. Said he, ‘Tell your general to withdraw his troops or I will send them to hell.’ <span class="emphasis">I thought that was a pretty bold stand to take, as we only numbered about two hundred to their thirty-five hundred.</span> But they thought we were more numerous than we really were. It may be that our numbers were magnified in their eyes. But they took the hint and left. … The Lord, through simple means, is able to take care of and deliver his people, but they must put implicit faith and confidence in him” (<span class="emphasis">Gospel Kingdom,</span> sel. G. Homer Durham, Salt Lake City: Bookcraft, 1964, pp. 354–355).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p45" pid="h5TMv5OeJUOkJM-YG-zb9Q" hash="T4YLHg">Another example of a remarkable <span class="emphasis">one.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p46" pid="HoWC7YO_6UKgn_AbeJ7tTw" hash="__Y9pQ">Let me quote Elder James E. Talmage, a former member of the Quorum of the Twelve: “What is man [or if I may add, what is Michael Brewerton] in this boundless setting of sublime splendor? I answer you: Potentially now, actually to be, he [or Michael] is greater and grander, more precious according to the arithmetic of God, than all the planets and suns of space. For him were they created; they are the handiwork of God; man is his son. In this world man is given dominion over a few things; it is his privilege to achieve supremacy over many things” (Aug. 9, 1931).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p47" pid="3erTD7Oy7EStVj3Stb76Vg" hash="WLf1xQ">With the exception of the few years when the Savior graced the earth, this, Mike, is the most exciting time to live. We have the gospel in its fulness, so many scriptures are being fulfilled, and so much history is being made. You are an important part of it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one.p48" pid="vQ37FK06ukSZ2VHyJY8arw" hash="8PMErw">Let me express my true feelings to you about the Church. I know, Michael, in a decisive, indelible manner—due to the Spirit—that Jesus is our Redeemer. He lives, as does his Father. He is the living Son of a living God. President Benson and the First Presidency are his living servants through whom His will is given to all the world. Watch them, Mike, listen to them, follow them. This is the only church of Jesus Christ on the earth, Michael, and you are just as important as any human being in all history. You are of infinite worth. I love you, pal. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1986/10/my-son-and-yours-each-a-remarkable-one</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1986-general-conference/1986-10-2060-elder-ted-e-brewerton-64k-eng.mp3" length="5568050" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 1986 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Light</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1991/10/light?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My brethren and sisters, on this bright and beautiful day, I should like to address the subject of light. The dictionary defines light as something that makes vision possible or something that enlightens or informs.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_91911_000_006" doc-version="2" hash="lVrXoQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="CdtO2_-D_kuWm_NIgwYBsg" hash="Yq9PwA">Light</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="z0E8iQvOZUWbBsB9hcXuwA" hash="fY7CfQ">Ted E. Brewerton</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-213e.jpg" alt="Elder Ted E. Brewerton" pid="muo6_P3geU2-3x0rHRIKHQ" hash="2cdP6w" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p1" pid="OzB6OW4GDE6lx-QlTQ3ZeQ" hash="s5QfPw">My brethren and sisters, on this bright and beautiful day, I should like to address the subject of light. The dictionary defines light as something that makes vision possible or something that enlightens or informs.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p2" pid="KoMpjWv-FUasiaZIAisrcQ" hash="ilKubg">Two types of light are physical light and spiritual light.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p3" pid="RFVQKiboZUiPcytzKkUO2A" hash="9FmNwQ">
        <span class="emphasis">Physical light,</span> especially natural light, affects the moods of people. When summer’s light begins to fade, days grow shorter, and the winter season looms darkly ahead, natural light becomes a more precious commodity, especially to people who live in extreme northern climates. There, where darkness reigns for up to three months a year and then summer blooms into three months of constant daylight, moods swing with the seasons.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p4" pid="dbdaJ2n6Tk2tkl-wHiHAjw" hash="6FD-8g">Light does have a profound effect on human mood and behavior. Mounting evidence indicates that people who are feeling a little down and need a lift can get it by going outside in daylight. Walking in the light is a natural mood booster. Many who simply walk for half an hour or more during the daylight hours receive a distinct benefit. (See <span class="emphasis">The Walking Magazine,</span> Jan./Feb. 1989, pp. 28–30.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p5" pid="UPCkp7euskGScv5-AGLO_g" hash="Efgl9w">Scientists are not entirely certain which wavelengths cause light’s mood-boosting effects. Researchers believe that these effects are traceable to light taken in <span class="emphasis">through the eyes</span> and not through the skin.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p6" pid="eGmvOokrbESUOFBy-m7u2A" hash="P0XrEg">A second medical use of light is light therapy for treating some cancers. Certain chemicals combined with light can destroy cancer cells. Research is under way to identify the best source of light and to determine how to direct it to body areas. (See <span class="emphasis">Time,</span> Canadian ed., Nov. 1989.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p7" pid="iQa_LU4HBEiyhE6-6cCcbQ" hash="6ajsOA">Shifting from these brief remarks about physical light, I should like to consider a kind of light that has infinitely greater power and effect. I speak of <span class="emphasis">spiritual light.</span> It comes from God and his gospel. In the scriptures, we find reference to a relationship between the physical light of the sun and spiritual light. We read in the Doctrine and Covenants, section 88, of “the light of truth;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p8" pid="Mf_Ddt-5g0y6EBdUWd9L9g" hash="VMjSlw">“Which truth shineth. This is the light of Christ. As also he is in the sun, and the light of the sun, and the power thereof by which it was made. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p9" pid="bpfPVfUpXEGCzfOd3AaVRQ" hash="RVtFSQ">“And the light which shineth, which giveth you light, is through him who enlighteneth your eyes, which is the same light that quickeneth your understandings;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p10" pid="HZXCIbMxOkO5TUXOKSFTAA" hash="BZhM3g">“Which light proceedeth forth from the presence of God to fill the immensity of space—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p11" pid="ul9GFYvwL0-FTqADHgNYMw" hash="mdqc5Q">“The light which is in all things, which giveth life to all things, which is the law by which all things are governed.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.6-7,11-13" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:6–7, 11–13</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p12" pid="hXmZ7Xi5Z02abNKe73PhPQ" hash="GxAoBw">This earth will be a celestial sphere, like a sea of glass and fire. The prophet Brigham Young said: “It will not then be an opaque body as it now is, but it will be like the stars of the firmament, full of light and glory: it will be a <span class="emphasis">body of light.</span> John compared it, in its celestialized state, to a sea of glass.” (<span class="emphasis">Journal of Discourses,</span> 7:163; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p13" pid="Z1KvbNjcIUm3gWzfPjrqWg" hash="HhHILQ">In section 88 we read:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p14" pid="V8wR-n41eE6iVbBvqnK30w" hash="sLQqJQ">“And again, verily I say unto you, the earth abideth the law of a celestial kingdom, for it filleth the measure of its creation, and transgresseth not the law—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p15" pid="1YJixOIAXUGRiZCzm9WPHw" hash="n8e46Q">“Wherefore, it shall be sanctified; yea, notwithstanding it shall die, it shall be quickened again, and shall abide the power by which it is quickened, and the righteous shall inherit it.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.25-26" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:25–26</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p16" pid="s_ZwPK5QvESf5CJKCxCvEg" hash="eazICg">In section 84:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p17" pid="OojiYxQ6dEW8lCqNamn8lA" hash="Hnjzcw">“For the word of the Lord is truth, and whatsoever is truth is light, and whatsoever is light is Spirit, even the Spirit of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p18" pid="HQ-VV8895UqGWKA-zbkjLg" hash="QAilrw">“And the Spirit giveth light to every man that cometh into the world; and the Spirit enlighteneth every man through the world, that hearkeneth to the voice of the Spirit.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.45-46" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:45–46</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p19" pid="bzQ3StkaaEmSey0fFWFoRQ" hash="UmgXzw">This word <span class="emphasis">light</span> appears 535 times in the scriptures.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p20" pid="ms2_4peaQUmy7qyhz5boxQ" hash="96Bajw">Light has a relationship to the Son of God: “And if your eye be single to my glory, your whole bodies shall be filled with light, and there shall be no darkness in you; and that body which is filled with light comprehendeth all things.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.67" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:67</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p21" pid="xsugjfaJnE6TrQI9Zs_09Q" hash="TYqP6Q">
        <span class="emphasis">Jesus Christ is the Light of the world.</span> Moroni said: “And now, my brethren, seeing that ye know <span class="emphasis">the light</span> by which ye may judge, <span class="emphasis">which light</span> is the <span class="emphasis">light of Christ,</span> see that ye do not judge wrongfully; for with that same judgment which ye judge ye shall also be judged.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.18" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:18</a>; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p22" pid="_syvEAYIh0mzYK6aoTrynA" hash="bZhKWw">John said: “Then spake Jesus again unto them, saying, <span class="emphasis">I am the light of the world:</span> he that followeth me shall not walk in darkness, but shall have the light of life.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/8.12" class="scriptureRef">John 8:12</a>; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p23" pid="21ME0kB3wkWT-HsrGEus2A" hash="2ijqPg">
        <span class="emphasis">Our Lord is the Light of the world in at least three ways.</span> Elder Bruce R. McConkie has written:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p24" pid="8z1DKNPslUWmYWeyRne4OA" hash="k43Pkg">“1. Through the Light of Christ he governs and controls the universe and gives life to all that therein is.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p25" pid="z5d0ks4o20SMdlGpWAma6g" hash="VbUFlQ">“2. By this same immensity-filling light—and to certain faithful ones, by the power of the Holy Ghost!—he enlightens the mind and quickens the understanding.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p26" pid="8R9iLQQrV0u-6gijyb9rvQ" hash="FIG9Pg">“3. By his own upright, sinless, and perfect course, in [premortal life], in mortality, and in resurrected glory, he sets a perfect example and is able to say to all men: ‘Follow thou me.’” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/31.10" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 31:10</a>.) (<span class="emphasis">The Promised Messiah,</span> Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1978, p. 208.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p27" pid="XZLDJXmdykCd4wSm3agLuQ" hash="GnOUXw">In the First Vision, <span class="emphasis">light</span> released the boy Joseph from oppressive darkness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p28" pid="gYHlknaBDk2JiUgHoA51ww" hash="vj4CAA">How does light enter into us? How do we receive it? “But if thine eye be evil, thy whole body shall be full of darkness. If therefore the light that is in thee be darkness, how great is that darkness!” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/6.23" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 6:23</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p29" pid="ZOvZGUAFHEizSIleHtJCwA" hash="uG58kQ">Commenting on this passage, Elder Bruce R. McConkie states: “Christ is the light; the gospel is the light; the plan of salvation is the light; ‘that which is of God is light; and he that receiveth light, and continueth in God, receiveth more light; and that light groweth brighter and brighter until the perfect day.’ As the light of the sun enters the body <span class="emphasis">through our natural eyes,</span> so the light of heaven—the light of the Spirit which illuminates our souls—enters through our spiritual eyes.” (<span class="emphasis">The Mortal Messiah,</span> Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1980, 2:153; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p30" pid="yyGbSDyuzkyQ2enBpVfNpg" hash="OaOdDw">President Joseph F. Smith said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p31" pid="jhhynVCQOkyCifzKQAJVEQ" hash="yqgl4A">“One fault to be avoided by the Saints, young and old, is the tendency to live on <span class="emphasis">borrowed light,</span> with their own hidden under a bushel; to permit the savor of their salt of knowledge to be lost; and the light within them to be reflected, rather than original. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p32" pid="iRozfM_umkKiXtUNaczRJw" hash="inDGdQ">“Men and women should become settled in the truth, and <span class="emphasis">founded in the knowledge of the gospel,</span> depending upon no person for borrowed or reflected light, but trusting only upon the Holy Spirit, who is ever the same, shining forever and testifying to the individual and the priesthood, who live in harmony with the laws of the gospel, of the glory and the will of the Father. They will then have light everlasting which cannot be obscured. By its shining in their lives, they shall cause others to glorify God; and by their well-doing put to silence the ignorance of foolish men, and show forth the praises of him who hath called them out of darkness into his marvelous light.” (<span class="emphasis">Gospel Doctrine,</span> 5th ed., Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1939, pp. 87–88; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p33" pid="RWQDvG545E2iNC-SSOOyfg" hash="1fT7eA">Light persuades us to do good; it leads us to Christ. It led my family as it has led yours, and it can and will lead all to him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p34" pid="ISmlnSi9FE-LGBh9YYRpoQ" hash="gD70dg">Archibald Stewart and his wife, Esther Lyle, are my great-great-grandparents. The Stewart family had learned to face persecution and hardship. Their ancestors had been forced to flee from Scotland to Northern Ireland, where they had been promised protection. But instead of finding peace, they again became victims of persecution at the hands of the Irish Greens. Independence and strong conviction were part of their heritage.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p35" pid="6uMJtK2UI0KQMg4nX0r3Sw" hash="3me9rg">The Stewart family characteristics of love and devotion and a deep religious faith made them receptive to the gospel. When the Mormon missionaries came to the Stewart house, Elizabeth, the third child, immediately felt the truthfulness of their message. She began to study and search for more assurance of the things she felt within. Her feelings and study stirred an immediate response in her old granny, who was the matriarch of the Stewart household. Elizabeth spent many hours telling her granny about the new prophet of God, Joseph Smith, who had brought back to earth the simple, direct message that Christ was alive and had appeared to man. Elizabeth felt a testimony burning within and asked permission to be baptized. Because of the unpopularity of the Mormons, her parents objected. Elizabeth’s granny came to her rescue. “Let the child alone,” she said. “I have read all her books, and I do believe the child is right.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p36" pid="EiBQe90QeEC8NRef59J4Rw" hash="lyaagw">As Elizabeth left her home to go to her baptism, her granny was at her side. The two walked to the river, where the elders had broken a hole in the ice that wintry March day. When the elders came toward Elizabeth to baptize her, her granny stepped up and said, “Watch your manners, child; never step in front of your elders.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p37" pid="-IK1y3EzCUec3GoXJDaX5A" hash="v5Jajg">The elders baptized Granny in her street clothes; she even had on her little white cap. She had brought no extra clothes, so she walked home in her wet, frozen clothes. She did not take cold even though she did not change her clothes until the other family members had gone to bed. She said nothing about her baptism to the family but went about her usual tasks as if nothing had happened. After the others had gone to bed, she hung her clothing around the fireplace. In the morning when Archibald got up, he saw the clothes drying. He began to joke with the others about Granny having been dipped in the river along with Elizabeth. Granny listened to their fun and then said: “Archibald, if you don’t want people to hear, stop shouting so loudly. You can’t talk about Granny now, for she can hear better than any of you.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p38" pid="3Xwl7T8xhU2mZUP-HRc2tw" hash="agUtvA">Granny had been virtually deaf for twenty years, but a miracle had restored her hearing at the time she was baptized. From that day until her death, she could hear distinctly. Archibald said laughingly that she heard too much.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p39" pid="Z-89Eh-v7UiW-fsXb_Um4A" hash="m7wzXg">Most of the family members soon were baptized, in 1841.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p40" pid="-bJZ9Ebo8UK_byMc9IKVSg" hash="9Uo1CA">The light of the gospel illuminates the path of life to eternity that otherwise would be dark and nondirecting.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p41" pid="GmZLu6UDQEG9H4luQ_CRPg" hash="BaEuLA">We can be like a mirror and direct light even into dark places. We are not the sources of light; nevertheless, through us light can be reflected to others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1991/10/light.p42" pid="ZxTGBWCdH069ph5u4T6VZQ" hash="TzxVBg">I must return and report my stewardship and <span class="emphasis">my words</span> in the heavens when I leave this mortal life. Therefore, I testify with no hesitancy that God lives. Jesus is his holy son, the one through whom we gain salvation. This is his Church and kingdom, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1991/10/light</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1991-general-conference/1991-10-1040-elder-ted-e-brewerton-64k-eng.mp3" length="5376561" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 1991 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Book of Mormon: A Sacred Ancient Record</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Some people place faith in good luck symbols, even a rabbit’s foot, but remember, it didn’t do the rabbit any good.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_95911_000_015" doc-version="2" hash="S1eLwA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="QuTk_bqDZ0ajjplvzig2og" hash="WUV6sw">The Book of Mormon:</h1>
    <p class="subtitle" pid="0a1ndwhGZUWTJFs3zUhejw" hash="GKewZA">A Sacred Ancient Record</p>
    <p class="authorName" pid="f4C4zRQI-0aHOJB7j10mYA" hash="fY7CfQ">Ted E. Brewerton</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-213e.jpg" alt="Elder Ted E. Brewerton" pid="WG8GothByECFOjcWxvafDw" hash="2cdP6w" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p1" pid="RyBBK1LbIUm8K0ngDUSHSw" hash="i7Wa6Q">Some people place faith in good luck symbols, even a rabbit’s foot, but remember, it didn’t do the rabbit any good.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p2" pid="NWwEDJHREE-hVfe5C6M0Ug" hash="4h9bhw">I do not wish to be light-minded, but I believe we should ask ourselves if we truly and seriously place our faith where it belongs and rely upon the merits of Christ. Do we have an assurance that salvation comes only through him and that he will take upon himself our burdens and sorrows if we place unwavering faith in him?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p3" pid="9gXyUBNiNkOj_Psdfv154w" hash="zGl9bw">The scriptures state, “They are they which testify of [God]” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/5.39" class="scriptureRef">John 5:39</a>). Eternal life is knowing God and his Holy Son (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/17.3" class="scriptureRef">John 17:3</a>). One can know him by searching the Book of Mormon. Every page testifies of him. The changes published in the Book of Mormon in 1981 go back beyond the first edition of 1830 to the handwritten manuscript.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p4" pid="QBT2Yb44GEa9ADvu7Am6pQ" hash="fipCjw">The Book of Mormon is a sacred, ancient American document recorded by writers as the events unfolded, starting more than two thousand years ago.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p5" pid="sWie73xkAEKU1_I1vwSpCA" hash="g6gRCw">The Book of Mormon is a record of families that the Lord led to the Americas for specific purposes. Three groups left the land of Jerusalem and crossed the oceans, beginning several centuries <span class="emphasis">before</span> the birth of our Savior, and arrived in the promised land, the Americas.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p6" pid="5XYbl5vudkmfuTlhCmH02A" hash="AuavOg">Ancient American texts written by native Americans support this origin. For example, a translator of the <span class="emphasis">Title of the Lords of Totonicapán,</span> the original text of which was recorded in 1554 in the language of the Quiché of Guatemala from legends centuries old, states:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p7" pid="6EzC-fcpDEKnpK99gTRMpA" hash="O8VSBg">“The three great Quiché nations … are descendants of the Ten Tribes of the Kingdom of Israel, whom Shalmaneser reduced to perpetual captivity and who, finding themselves on the border of Assyria, resolved to emigrate. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p8" pid="Hwun2Wcub0O7nWTpz0uiKA" hash="s6URlA">“These, then, were the three nations of Quichés, and they came from where the sun rises, descendants of Israel, of the same language and same customs. … They were sons of Abraham and Jacob. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p9" pid="99YC-ITSK0O61zrz7CMVKQ" hash="AC2CaA">“Now on the twenty-eighth of September of 1554 we sign this attestation in which we have written that which by tradition our ancestors told us, who came from the other part of the sea, from Civán-Tulán, bordering on Babylonia” (<span class="emphasis">Title of the Lords of Totonicapán,</span> trans. Dionisio José Chonay and Delia Goetz, Norman, Oklahoma: University of Oklahoma Press, 1953, pp. 167, 170, 194).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p10" pid="9osVRCcFQEawHAGYUaqSkA" hash="_RERoQ">Elder Mark E. Petersen, a member of the Council of the Twelve Apostles, wrote: “As the ancient Israelites suffered a dispersion which sprinkled them among all the nations, so the descendants of Laman and Lemuel [sons of Lehi] were sifted over the vast areas of the western hemisphere. <span class="emphasis">They are found from pole to pole</span>” (<span class="emphasis">Children of Promise,</span> Salt Lake City: Bookcraft, 1981, p. 31; emphasis added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p11" pid="JseOXrs6ykWrHgZWTJEdvA" hash="DjAANA">
        <span class="emphasis">Many</span> migratory groups came to the Americas, but none was as important as the three mentioned in the Book of Mormon. The blood of these people flows in the veins of the Blackfoot and the Blood Indians of Alberta, Canada; in the Navajo and the Apache of the American Southwest; the Inca of western South America; the Aztec of Mexico; the Maya of Guatemala; and in other native American groups in the Western Hemisphere and the Pacific islands.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p12" pid="wKq1F_X0sEybXoui0GETJw" hash="C6xvgw">These choice native people recognize the truth of the Book of Mormon, which was recorded for them by their own ancestors. President Spencer W. Kimball said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p13" pid="rmjAP5AGvUu0Eey9r_oyiw" hash="bHSFwA">“The converted Lamanite is devout. Few ever apostatize. Some lose their way as they partake of the worldliness about them, but generally the children of Lehi of the twentieth century have inherited that grace and ability to believe like their ancestors of the long ago. We read in <a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/6.36" class="scriptureRef">Hel. 6:36</a>: ‘And thus we see that the Lord began to pour out his Spirit upon the Lamanites, because of <span class="emphasis">their easiness and willingness to believe in his words</span>’” (<span class="emphasis">The Teachings of Spencer W. Kimball,</span> ed. Edward L. Kimball [Salt Lake City: Bookcraft, 1982], p. 178; emphasis added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p14" pid="-2aXQ6dFOEqGk5JMMSGEmA" hash="nBkVsg">Every ecclesiastical authority of <span class="emphasis">any church</span> and every agnostic should rejoice and praise God for having sent the priceless Book of Mormon to them or to us. <span class="emphasis">Why?</span> Because it is a sacred, second, undeniable witness to the world that God lives and Jesus is the very Christ, our Redeemer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p15" pid="Ey1E7xdAjUSPq5T6yzfrgg" hash="3zyDoQ">The <span class="emphasis">first witness</span> is the Holy Bible, which testifies of the Master from the Middle East. The Lord said in <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/10.16" class="scriptureRef">John 10:16</a> that other sheep would hear His voice. The Lord came to the Americas after His resurrection and said: “And verily I say unto you, that ye are they of whom I said: Other sheep I have which are not of this fold; them also I must bring, and they shall hear my voice; and there shall be one fold, and one shepherd” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/15.21" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 15:21</a>). Two such witnesses cannot be denied without placing the soul in peril.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p16" pid="jm0pfNlpVkWVRViLN_B6vQ" hash="vv-fBA">The crucial messages or purposes of the Book of Mormon are shown on its title page: “To show unto the remnant of the House of Israel what great things the Lord hath done for their fathers; and that they may know the covenants of the Lord … And also to the convincing of the Jew and Gentile that J<small>ESUS</small> is the C<small>HRIST</small>, the E<small>TERNAL</small> G<small>OD</small>, manifesting himself unto all nations.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p17" pid="2oHc5KJUkUqt9euG_JbmTQ" hash="32qsiA">Ancient American literature contains references to a white, bearded god who descended out of the heavens. He is called by many names; one example is Quetzalcoatl. Historians of the sixteenth century, whose texts I have, recorded pre-Hispanic beliefs concerning the white, bearded god who came to the Americas <span class="emphasis">long before</span> the arrival of the Spanish conquerors. The following paragraphs contain examples of these beliefs.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p18" pid="iOeEDuPnZUyIblu_2GJZpw" hash="CFywPQ">
        <span class="emphasis">Bernardo de Sahagun</span> (born 1499) wrote: “Quetzalcoatl was esteemed and considered as a god, and was worshipped in older times. He had long hair and was bearded. The people worshipped only the Lord” (<span class="emphasis">Historia General de las Cosas de Nueva España,</span> Mexico: Editorial Porrua, S. A., 1985, pp. 195, 598).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p19" pid="Fb3KuQ6J8UCVdhFVZWoRkQ" hash="0faSqA">
        <span class="emphasis">Diego Duran</span> (born 1537) wrote: “A great man—a person venerable and religious—bearded, tall, long hair, dignified deportment, heroic acts, miracles—I affirm he could have been one of the blessed apostles” (<span class="emphasis">Historia de las Indias de Nueva España,</span> 1867, first ed., 2 vols., Mexico: Editorial Porrua, S. A., 1967, 1:9).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p20" pid="okFAHhTsJkelQMgKkV1flw" hash="J3yM2g">
        <span class="emphasis">Bartolomé de las Casas</span> (born 1474) wrote that Quetzalcoatl, the plumed serpent, was white, had a rounded beard, was tall, and came from the sea in the east, from whence he will return (see <span class="emphasis">Los Indios de Mexico y Nueva España Antologiá,</span> Mexico: Editorial Porrua, S. A., 1982, pp. 54, 218, 223).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p21" pid="zx9Hw8Df20-w8eQI0d_ZdA" hash="9k52KA">The Tamanacos Indian tribes in Venezuela have the same legend of a white, bearded god: “[Amalivacá] had a face the color of the light fluffy clouds of the morning, and white was his long head of hair. … He said: ‘I am Amalivacá, and I come in the name of my father INA-UIKI’” (Arturo Hellmund Tello, <span class="emphasis">Leyendas Indígenas del Bajo Orinoco,</span> trans. Ted E. Brewerton, Buenos Aires, Argentina: Imprenta Lopez Peru 666, 1948, pp. 19–22).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p22" pid="D5K8Yfd9rU2CdrShzcDXHg" hash="CuqbvA">The Book of Mormon gives an accurate account of the coming of the Lord to ancient America.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p23" pid="gbUeYb-mCEaDJJ375OlVGw" hash="Qy4TqA">When we accept the ancient roots of the book and believe that Joseph Smith did have ancient records that could not be in English, we then may ask how he translated them. The only reasonable answer is the way he said: by divine revelation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p24" pid="ud3PmbzLLEaOGZkZBWyR_Q" hash="QHktKg">What would be more perilous to us, eternally, than to say the Book of Mormon is holy scripture if it were not? Those who have questions or concerns about the Church may cling in security to this firm anchor that is immutable and tangible evidence of the truthfulness of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p25" pid="5d5yIMSdlk2CTgI21LHL7g" hash="b0cfIQ">The Book of Mormon prophet Nephi wrote: “For we labor diligently to write, to persuade our children, and also our brethren, to believe in Christ, and to be reconciled to God; for we know that it is by grace that we are saved, after all we can do” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/25.23" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 25:23</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p26" pid="dotLH3F9WUuZwMngUqNGhQ" hash="BzgnaQ">Elder B. H. Roberts wrote in 1909:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p27" pid="Mv-V5M5GF0yEaNdntcLuiw" hash="Im8hPA">“[The Holy Ghost] must ever be the chief source of evidence for the truth of the Book of Mormon. All other evidence is secondary to this, the primary and infallible. No arrangement of evidence, however skilfully ordered; no argument, however adroitly made, can ever take [the] place [of the Holy Ghost]. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p28" pid="zXdmUXylnkma06oTauBbPg" hash="DGT4Aw">“Secondary evidences in support of truth, like secondary causes in natural phenomena, may be of firstrate importance, and mighty factors in the achievement of God’s purposes” (<span class="emphasis">New Witnesses for God,</span> Salt Lake City, Deseret News, 1909, pp. vi–vii).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p29" pid="BN2EyexTOkSTJSRQxhWHaw" hash="LhJRKA">The sun rises rather quietly, and at times we think that the Lord’s voice is that quiet, but his voice is audible if we will only pray, meditate, and listen as he places clear thoughts in our minds.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p30" pid="e-29xzab3Uuut2PjXYw8Iw" hash="Of2rCA">As surely as the sun rises, God lives, as does his Almighty Son. As surely as the sun rises daily, The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is <span class="emphasis">his.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p31" pid="NROCWzm3vkeJ8ITYy85gmQ" hash="XNGnwQ">Because the sun rises, we see everything else.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p32" pid="4eHpd9t5UEa7LojYAuVD8g" hash="pm9OAA">Because Jesus Christ lives, we see by his light eternal, unchanging truths and an illuminated path showing the purpose of our premortal life, the reason for our current existence, and the effect of premortal and mortal life on our life after what we call death.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p33" pid="TFlvqUcgEUmjtiQz105rQQ" hash="PQ3cLA">The Bible is a witness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p34" pid="NC0YZXr2zkee0boqWa9MXw" hash="W4YYlg">The Book of Mormon is a witness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record.p35" pid="QdedP6YUF0STXYQ7TJdGYQ" hash="zDXWXw">I am one of the witnesses that he <span class="emphasis">is</span> risen, and he <span class="emphasis">is</span> coming. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1995/10/the-book-of-mormon-a-sacred-ancient-record</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1995-general-conference/1995-10-2050-elder-ted-e-brewerton-64k-eng.mp3" length="4804861" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 1995 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
