<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Ulisses Soares</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Ulisses Soares.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Ulisses%20Soares.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Ulisses Soares.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2005 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2005 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>“Feed My Sheep”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep?lang=eng</link>
      <description>People are most receptive to our influence when they feel that we truly love them, and not only because we have a calling to fulfill.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10033479_000_034" doc-version="2" hash="4updJQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="6x002TgTdUmkImMxjSjezw" hash="pjx3IA">“Feed My Sheep”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="gGiNpWkEb0yQTHWHPDsXsQ" hash="Vso5pw">Elder Ulisses Soares</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="vGrIiAoSwEqWguI3B4Aalg" hash="PF0hTA">People are most receptive to our influence when they feel that we truly love them, and not only because we have a calling to fulfill.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-119.jpg" alt="Elder Ulisses Soares" pid="-3dUVLzefUebtKmdthDgWQ" hash="44rt3A" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p1" pid="-s84dDxrhkWL5i1LxNd5vQ" hash="qhvOFw">On one occasion the Savior asked a question to Peter three times:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p2" pid="OiFAAT3zLUiEBuXzitADzg" hash="-Adydw">“Simon, son of Jonas, lovest thou me? He saith unto him, Yea, Lord; thou knowest that I love thee. [Jesus] saith unto him, Feed my sheep.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p3" pid="C0hF47p_TkmQ78qTeraGiw" hash="X0_L7w">Because He was deeply concerned with the welfare of our Heavenly Father’s children, the Lord gave Peter the special charge of feeding the sheep. He reaffirmed this same concern in modern times through a revelation given to Joseph Smith:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p4" pid="D9ig-cDIXEOdecXVNYkjJQ" hash="OA_1fg">“Now, I say unto you, and what I say unto you, I say unto all the Twelve: Arise and gird up your loins, take up your cross, follow me, and feed my sheep.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p5" pid="DES61uNVZEKmUtyqO3M4dA" hash="tyaLCA">As we study the scriptures, we notice that the Savior ministered to people according to their specific needs. A good example of this occurred when He was near Capernaum, and Jairus, a ruler of the synagogue, fell down at Jesus’s feet and pleaded with the Lord to come into his house and bless his daughter, who was dying. Jesus went with Jairus even though the crowd made it difficult for Him to move fast.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p6" pid="q3oJhO08hUy6EaXKI76NUw" hash="w7Ov8g">And then a messenger came telling Jairus his daughter was already dead. Even grieving as he was, Jairus kept his steadfast faith in the Lord, who comforted the heart of that father, saying:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p7" pid="-n4uW7wLQ0ekCqk8mhPP8g" hash="GrxSFw">“Fear not: believe only, and she shall be made whole.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p8" pid="CpsJwmuzxkOHV7qcEO3A8w" hash="G18Oxw">“And when he came into the house, he suffered no man to go in, save Peter, and James, and John, and the father and the mother of the maiden.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p9" pid="dOmQd2OxRU2vSfS6by_G7Q" hash="Rns_Hw">“And all wept, and bewailed her: but he said, Weep not; she is not dead, but sleepeth. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p10" pid="cjKFdz3F0kmsCvuQyBzI_Q" hash="VV0rww">“… And took her by the hand, and called, saying, Maid, arise.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p11" pid="C4E8bCau_UOybfkPloYUbQ" hash="fl0pBQ">“And her spirit came again, and she arose straightway: and he commanded to give her meat.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p12" pid="_INmJ669n0OOmzyjb3a_TA" hash="2CAUhw">Jesus showed patience and love to all who came to Him seeking relief for their physical, emotional, or spiritual illnesses and who felt discouraged and downtrodden.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p13" pid="lQT5f31hYUeqIWoF26EeRw" hash="0sxUTw">To follow the Savior’s example, each one of us must look around and reach out to the sheep who are facing the same circumstances and lift them up and encourage them to proceed on the journey towards eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p14" pid="MyGOrw26LUqsQTYO-ER1MA" hash="e9-vPw">This need today is as great as or perhaps even greater than when the Savior walked on this earth. As shepherds we must understand that we should nurture each one of our sheep to bring them to Christ, which is the purpose of all we do in this Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p15" pid="UnzJrs8_HUad-rhEZX47Sg" hash="28oJpw">Any activity, meeting, or program should focus on this same objective. As we stay in tune with the needs of the people, we can strengthen them and help them overcome their challenges, so they will remain steadfast in the way which will lead them back to our Heavenly Father’s presence and help them endure to the end.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p16" pid="n0rnrDuG8kaV43KvDIXCWw" hash="xmQcew">The gospel of Jesus Christ is about people, not programs. Sometimes, in the haste of fulfilling our Church responsibilities, we spend too much time concentrating on programs, instead of focusing on people, and end up taking their real needs for granted. When things like that happen, we lose the perspective of our callings, neglect people, and prevent them from reaching their divine potential to gain eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p17" pid="XZV5NqkI2EG4XVPd_5gz2g" hash="eWYNOQ">As I was about to have my 12th birthday, my bishop invited me for an interview and taught me how to prepare to receive the Aaronic Priesthood and be ordained a deacon. As the interview was coming to an end, he pulled out a set of forms from his desk and challenged me to fill them out. They were mission call papers. I was astonished. After all, I was only 11. But that bishop had a vision of the future and of the blessings that would be mine if I prepared properly to serve a mission when my time came.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p18" pid="XDQYL5h7v0G_l1a5dEq1hQ" hash="b48-uA">He showed he really cared about me. He told me the steps I should take to prepare both financially and spiritually to serve the Lord. After that day, he, and then the bishop who was called after him, interviewed me at least twice a year until I was 19 and encouraged me to remain faithful in my preparation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p19" pid="-0ZBjrjzPkKjIgN04uKkqQ" hash="zvszLw">They kept my missionary forms in the files and mentioned them whenever we had an interview. With my parents’ help and with the encouragement of loving and patient bishops, I served a mission. The mission helped me gain a perspective of the blessings God has in store for all who endure to the end.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p20" pid="O8r-zHGhFU-nwyOCtJSfJQ" hash="_BWZ7A">It does not matter whether it is a child, youth, or adult—everyone needs to feel loved. We have been counseled for several years to focus on working with new converts and less-active members. People will remain in the Church when they feel someone cares for them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p21" pid="Gc_f2OYSvEi5FXATHqUrug" hash="6-L-Ag">Among the last instructions the Savior gave His Apostles, He said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p22" pid="tlEIW2392k6iX5A12lsXMg" hash="fUNUGQ">“A new commandment I give unto you, That ye love one another; as I have loved you, that ye also love one another.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p23" pid="9JWXqH_rO0m6Juje_op0Pw" hash="53o52A">“By this shall all men know that ye are my disciples, if ye have love one to another.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p24" pid="Yoz6Jc6eeUup25LUwGV7pQ" hash="weRErw">People are most receptive to our influence when they feel that we truly love them, and not only because we have a calling to fulfill. As we express true love for people, they will be able to feel the influence of the Spirit and may feel motivated to follow our teachings. It is not always easy to love people for what they are. The prophet Mormon explained what we should do if such challenges arise:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p25" pid="IPQosi-NL0yOA4_3QxmNMQ" hash="-zRFBg">“Wherefore, my beloved brethren, pray unto the Father with all the energy of heart, that ye may be filled with this love, which he hath bestowed upon all who are true followers of his Son, Jesus Christ; that ye may become the sons of God; that when he shall appear we shall be like him, for we shall see him as he is; that we may have this hope; that we may be purified even as he is pure.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p26" pid="EMVQEs3BdkiHeD5v5KDeDQ" hash="ocYoqw">Christ Himself ministered to people, lifting the heavy laden, giving hope to the disheartened, and seeking after the ones who were lost. He showed people how much He loved and understood them and how precious they were. He acknowledged their divine nature and eternal value. Even when calling people to repentance, He condemned the sin without condemning the sinner.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p27" pid="wWvOUWQx9UmNeepQK4uj3Q" hash="k7tMQw">In his first epistle to the Corinthians, the Apostle Paul emphasized the need of expressing this true love to each sheep of the Lord’s flock:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p28" pid="TeY7cjUOo0eStRPDlojKcg" hash="F5VNLg">“And though I bestow all my goods to feed the poor, and though I give my body to be burned, and have not charity, it profiteth me nothing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p29" pid="3CV0-62PFEmZlXCOSlPewA" hash="W32NZQ">“Charity suffereth long, and is kind; charity envieth not; charity vaunteth not itself, is not puffed up.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p30" pid="2cwUoJofeUOPNDGgnTpHCg" hash="XpwV8A">“Doth not behave itself unseemly, seeketh not her own, is not easily provoked, thinketh no evil;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p31" pid="z7xPjy70dkm2efdRdpOTRg" hash="UkB12A">“Rejoiceth not in iniquity, but rejoiceth in the truth;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p32" pid="eU4kFIMemEGUQdp89hmitQ" hash="yHqsqw">“Beareth all things, believeth all things, hopeth all things, endureth all things. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p33" pid="q0j_IYheDECXVnzmefo0zw" hash="bxjE0A">“And now abideth faith, hope, charity, these three; but the greatest of these is charity.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p34" pid="wcTXBJAA5kquONEaGjD_RA" hash="Es36zQ">As we follow the Savior’s example and teachings, we can assist people to fulfill their earthly mission and return to live with our Heavenly Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep.p35" pid="pJ0JxL7bmkaqyqMPWNwlgQ" hash="Zm5NiA">Of this I bear you my testimony in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2005/10/feed-my-sheep</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2005-general-conference/2005-10-5060-elder-ulisses-soares-64k-eng.mp3" length="3746453" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2005 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abide in the Lord’s Territory!</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2012/04/abide-in-the-lords-territory?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Our daily question must be, “Do my actions place me in the Lord’s or in the enemy’s territory?”</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/abide-in-the-lords-territory" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10485_000_26soare" doc-version="2" hash="8oYhsQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/abide-in-the-lords-territory.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="-6ASum1mtU6ZrJAp8veQ_w" hash="ORbY2Q">Abide in the Lord’s Territory!</h1><p class="authorName" pid="LoQUq8dmlUeCrR_om7c0vg" hash="Ujr5oA">By Elder Ulisses Soares</p><p class="kicker" pid="7LGnRI1tC0OJWV8sqCYm1A" hash="BMndcg">Our daily question must be, “Do my actions place me in the Lord’s or in the enemy’s territory?”</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/abide-in-the-lords-territory.p5" pid="ls1wNztKxEuDBa1s54feKA" hash="_v9ubg">
      <span class="pageBreak" page-number="39"></span>President Thomas S. Monson once said: “May I provide a simple formula by which you can measure the choices which confront you. It’s easy to remember: ‘You can’t be right by doing wrong; you can’t be wrong by doing right’” (“Pathways to Perfection,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona,</span> July 2002, 112; <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 2002, 100). President Monson’s formula is simple and direct. It works the same way as the Liahona given to Lehi did. If we exercise faith and are diligent in obeying the Lord’s commandments, we will easily find the correct direction to follow, especially when we face our day-to-day choices.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/abide-in-the-lords-territory.p6" pid="lq_qBCzSKUO_MC5YE53k0w" hash="qBaVRQ">The Apostle Paul exhorts us about the importance of sowing in the Spirit and being aware of not sowing in the flesh. He said:</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/abide-in-the-lords-territory.p7" pid="00_0yjSTnEWsAzgzyMMF2w" hash="sk5idg">“Be not deceived; God is not mocked: for whatsoever a man soweth, that shall he also reap.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/abide-in-the-lords-territory.p8" pid="e5XTmqeqEEe3U5QNjlilsA" hash="WXQC6Q">“For he that soweth to his flesh shall of the flesh reap corruption; but he that soweth to the Spirit shall of the Spirit reap life everlasting.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/abide-in-the-lords-territory.p9" pid="ybeEDltcNk-Jp06dIRcKGA" hash="h8av3g">“And let us not be weary in well doing: for in due season we shall reap, if we faint not” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/gal/6.7-9" class="scriptureRef">Galatians 6:7–9</a>).</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/abide-in-the-lords-territory.p10" pid="fObrtEOSh0ishu05xsUinw" hash="68LEFw">To sow in the Spirit means that all our thoughts, words, and actions must elevate us to the level of the divinity of our heavenly parents. However, the scriptures refer to the flesh as the physical or carnal nature of the natural man, which allows people to be influenced by passion, desires, appetites, and drives of the flesh instead of looking for inspiration from the Holy Ghost. If we are not careful, those influences together with the pressure of the evil in the world may conduct us to adopt vulgar and reckless behavior which may become part of our character. In order to avoid those bad influences, we have to follow what the Lord instructed the Prophet Joseph Smith about continuously sowing in the Spirit: “Wherefore, be not weary in well-doing, for ye are laying the foundation of a great work. And out of small things proceedeth that which is great” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/64.33" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 64:33</a>).</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/abide-in-the-lords-territory.p11" pid="dmDEuyeLHUW-UAumCVCoJg" hash="Lkp1mQ">To enhance our spirit, it is required that we “let all bitterness, and wrath, and anger, and clamour, and evil speaking, be put away from [us], with all malice” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/4.31" class="scriptureRef">Ephesians 4:31</a>) and that we “be wise in the days of [our] probation [and] strip [ourselves] of all uncleanness” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/morm/9.28" class="scriptureRef">Mormon 9:28</a>).</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/abide-in-the-lords-territory.p12" pid="lD7jmVhmY0uIN-MBDnn1cQ" hash="1Mf_uQ">
      <span class="pageBreak" page-number="40"></span>As we study the scriptures, we learn that the promises made by the Lord to us are conditional upon our obedience and encourage righteous living. Those promises must nourish our soul, bringing us hope by encouraging us not to give up even in the face of our daily challenges of living in a world whose ethical and moral values are becoming extinct, thus motivating people to sow in the flesh even more. But how can we be certain that our choices are helping us to sow in the Spirit and not in the flesh?</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/abide-in-the-lords-territory.p13" pid="K6Trzcjf-kGPaFUiCXIsiQ" hash="C1jJUg">President George Albert Smith, repeating counsel from his grandfather, once said: “There is a line of demarcation well defined between the Lord’s territory and the devil’s territory. If you will stay on the Lord’s side of the line you will be under his influence and will have no desire to do wrong; but if you cross to the devil’s side of that line one inch you are in the tempter’s power and if he is successful, you will not be able to think or even reason properly because you will have lost the Spirit of the Lord” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of Presidents of the Church: George Albert Smith</span> [2011], 191).</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/abide-in-the-lords-territory.p14" pid="8sZixMTntU6OmcjjOBm8jw" hash="BaWOgg">Therefore, our daily question must be, “Do my actions place me in the Lord’s or in the enemy’s territory?”</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/abide-in-the-lords-territory.p15" pid="zjV8_GwezE6f8p8dg2hwgw" hash="65u4-g">Mormon the prophet alerted his people about the importance of having the ability to distinguish good from evil:</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/abide-in-the-lords-territory.p16" pid="8cYxVIqnI0O7NJjeRYF80g" hash="bOzzJg">“Wherefore, all things which are good cometh of God; and that which is evil cometh of the devil; for the devil is an enemy unto God, and fighteth against him continually, and inviteth and enticeth to sin, and to do that which is evil continually.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/abide-in-the-lords-territory.p17" pid="ENSLxxo1N0-oGEkYb6cTIw" hash="mIaQYQ">“But behold, that which is of God inviteth and enticeth to do good continually” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.12-13" class="scriptureRef">Moroni 7:12–13</a>).</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/abide-in-the-lords-territory.p18" pid="shEaFvzCW0K4ffp3Nb9iIQ" hash="Mfza_g">The Light of Christ together with the companionship of the Holy Ghost must help us determine if our manner of living is placing us in the Lord’s territory or not. If our attitudes are good, they are inspired of God, for every good thing comes from God. However, if our attitudes are bad, we are being influenced by the enemy because he persuades men to do evil.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/abide-in-the-lords-territory.p19" pid="lcb5RCcUn0eFw95xjN33XQ" hash="z7rS6Q">The African people have touched my heart because of their determination and diligence to stay in the Lord’s territory. Even in adverse circumstances in life, those who accept the invitation to come unto Christ become a light to the world. A few weeks ago while visiting one of the wards in South Africa, I had the privilege to accompany two young priests, their bishop, and their stake president in a visit to less-active young men of their quorum. I was greatly impressed by the courage and humility that those two priests showed as they invited the less-active young men to return to church. While they talked to those less-active young men, I noticed that their countenances reflected the Savior’s light and at the same time filled with light all those around them. They were fulfilling their duty to “succor the weak, lift up the hands which hang down, and strengthen the feeble knees” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/81.5" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 81:5</a>). The attitude of those two priests placed them in the Lord’s territory, and they served as instruments in His hands as they invited others to do the same.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/abide-in-the-lords-territory.p20" pid="niYCaQba5UiV9RnyN7BNuA" hash="ukts6Q">In <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.37" class="scriptureRef">Doctrine and Covenants 20:37</a>, the Lord teaches us what it means to sow in the Spirit and what really places us in the Lord’s territory, as follows: humble ourselves before God, come forth with broken hearts and contrite spirits, witness before the Church that we have truly repented of all our sins, take upon ourselves the name of Jesus Christ, have a <span class="pageBreak" page-number="41"></span>determination to serve Him to the end, manifest by our works that we have received the Spirit of Christ, and be received by baptism into His Church. Our disposition to fulfill these covenants prepares us to live in God’s presence as exalted beings. The remembrance of these covenants must guide our behavior in relation to our family, in our social interaction with other people, and especially in our relationship with the Savior.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/abide-in-the-lords-territory.p21" pid="d6ygc6LWjUuhI_7v8Y2kqg" hash="a45BMQ">Jesus Christ established the perfect behavior pattern by which we can build upon our attitudes to be able to fulfill these sacred covenants. The Savior banished from His life any influence that might take His focus away from His divine mission, especially when He was tempted by the enemy or by his followers while He ministered here on earth. Although He never sinned, He had a broken heart and a contrite spirit, full of love for our Heavenly Father and for all men. He humbled Himself before our Father in Heaven, denying His own will to fulfill what the Father had asked of Him in all things until the end. Even at that moment of extreme physical and spiritual pain, carrying the burden of the sins of all mankind on His shoulders and shedding blood through His pores, He told the Father, “Nevertheless not what I will, but what thou wilt” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/14.36" class="scriptureRef">Mark 14:36</a>).</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/04/abide-in-the-lords-territory.p22" pid="8OB6uoObrUykUd3L8evK9w" hash="xsVD1g">My prayer, brothers and sisters, as we think about our covenants is that we may keep ourselves strong against “the fiery darts of the adversary” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/15.24" class="scriptureRef">1 Nephi 15:24</a>), following the Savior’s example so that we may sow in the Spirit and abide in the Lord’s territory. Let us remember President Monson’s formula: “You can’t be right by doing wrong; you can’t be wrong by doing right.” I say these things in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2012/04/abide-in-the-lords-territory</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2012-general-conference/2012-04-2070-elder-ulisses-soares-64k-eng.mp3" length="4335273" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be Meek and Lowly of Heart</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Being meek does not mean weakness, but it does mean behaving with goodness and kindness.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10791_000_13soares" doc-version="6" hash="UNLBww">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="ZcTnMXO9CEW-OwrYAtNrbg" hash="7Cp91Q">Be Meek and Lowly of Heart</h1>
		<p class="authorName" pid="7TgVeBxdq0y6aU_ZrKlRQw" hash="Ujr5oA">By Elder Ulisses Soares</p>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/liahona/2013/11/saturday-morning-session/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p2" pid="Bvxql_Pr4kaxdvB8UanVMQ" hash="Ujr5oA1">By Elder Ulisses Soares</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/liahona/2013/11/saturday-morning-session/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p3" pid="0s4F9x_24EegafbjstVCyg" hash="hptprg">Of the Presidency of the Seventy</p>
		</div>
		<img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/leaders/ulisses-soares.jpg" alt="Elder Ulisses Soares" pid="7dv8-Sna3kCIskRuQ5huzQ" hash="JN290g" />
		<p class="kicker" pid="NWt1PEH3xU2CoAzk55AVtQ" hash="070qEw">Being meek does not mean weakness, but it does mean behaving with goodness and kindness.</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock" pid="m7jBHqz1BEiOK8cV8_Djxw" hash="Rebr9Q">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p5" pid="aAjYwgsRhU-vrbn-v7WkFg" hash="nRY-Dg"><span class="pageBreak" page-number="9"></span>Mormon taught that a man “cannot have faith and hope, save he shall be meek, and lowly of heart.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> He added that without such attributes, “faith and hope is vain, for none is acceptable before God, save the meek and lowly in heart.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p6" pid="v1D3YQGjGUqOeDNw-G93qw" hash="qH8Elw">Meekness is the quality of those who are “Godfearing, righteous, humble, teachable, and patient under suffering.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> Those who possess this attribute are willing to follow Jesus Christ, and their temperament is calm, docile, tolerant, and submissive.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p7" pid="6Sxb8rqBJEivLv7Lks09Sg" hash="pprnJg">The Apostle Paul taught that meekness is a fruit of the Spirit.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> Therefore, it can most easily be attained if we “live in the Spirit.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> And to live in the Spirit, our lifestyle must reflect righteousness before the Lord.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p8" pid="vVzpJetLcUSme01vnAD-Ew" hash="gaSdXw">As we take Christ’s name upon us, it is expected that we strive to emulate His attributes and change our character to become more like Him each day. The Savior, admonishing His disciples, said, “Be ye therefore perfect, even as your Father which is in heaven is perfect.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> If we “come unto Christ, … deny [ourselves] of all ungodliness; … and love God,” then through Christ’s grace the day will come when we may be perfect in Him.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p9" pid="ND0cx1erMk64Y_Y0qwA8ow" hash="e1x0cQ">“Christlike attributes are gifts from God. [These attributes] come as [we] use [our] agency righteously. …With a desire to please God, [we have to] recognize [our] weaknesses and be willing and anxious to improve.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p10" pid="ZjmJZMB_qkWSjGG6XLx1CQ" hash="t0u3Yg">Meekness is vital for us to become more Christlike. Without it we won’t be able to develop other important virtues. Being meek does not mean weakness, but it does mean behaving with goodness and kindness, showing strength, serenity, healthy self-worth, and self-control.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p11" pid="6YDK7ET850yjeDk1pefsEw" hash="OaNAOA">Meekness was one of the most abundant attributes in the Savior’s life. He Himself taught His disciples, “Learn of me; for I am meek and lowly in heart.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p12" pid="AOISEPeII0Gx711CUMsKiA" hash="aj9eCg">We are blessed to be born with the seed of meekness in our hearts. We need to understand that it is not possible to grow and develop that seed in the twinkling of an eye but rather through the process of time. Christ asks us to “take up [our] cross daily,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> meaning that it must be a constant focus and desire.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p13" pid="G63ybaCJqkm7T_gIo9rgeQ" hash="xhgqhg">President Lorenzo Snow, the fifth prophet of our dispensation, taught, “It is our duty to try to be perfect, … to improve each day, and look upon our course last week and do things better this week; do things better today than we did them yesterday.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> So the first step to becoming meek is to improve day by day. Each day we need to try to be better than the previous as we move forward through this process.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p14" pid="qbaVTdv-c0u0chgAFeQ2bw" hash="zbLI9Q">President Snow added:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p15" pid="18JxS2b5-EGQ93qmT0BXWQ" hash="J5747g">“We have our little follies and our weaknesses; we should try to overcome them as fast as possible, and … should [instill] this feeling in the hearts of our children … that they may learn to [behave] properly before Him under all circumstances.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p16" pid="zThaKJLJWEuWhv-NMbN_rw" hash="Gm2wAA">“If the husband can live with his wife one day without quarrelling or without treating anyone unkindly or without grieving the Spirit of God … he is so far perfect. Then let him try to be the same the next day. But supposing he should fail in this his next day’s attempt, that is no reason why he should not succeed in doing so the third day.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p17" pid="xZisV45NrUCWevz-3vYDwQ" hash="z-tHQQ">Upon acknowledging our dedication and perseverance, the Lord will give us that which we are not able to attain due to our imperfections and human weaknesses.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p18" pid="oAaYgcrFik-v726AD8G1sQ" hash="u7SbEQ">Another important step to becoming meek is learning how to control our temper. Because the natural man dwells within each one of us and because we live in a world full of pressure, controlling our temper may become one of the challenges in our lives. Think for a few seconds how you react when someone does not comply with your desires the moment you want them to. What about when people disagree with your ideas, even though you are absolutely sure that they represent the proper solution to a <span class="pageBreak" page-number="10"></span>problem? What is your response when someone offends you, critiques your efforts, or is simply unkind because he or she is in a bad mood? At these moments and in other difficult situations, we must learn to control our temper and convey our feelings with patience and gentle persuasion. This is most important within our homes and within our relationships with our eternal companions. During the 31 years I’ve been married to my sweetheart, she has often given me gentle reminders of this as we have faced life’s unsettling challenges.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p19" pid="n-_F1W8Gp0KXUlg6RkCjTg" hash="NR4Btg">Among instructions found in his Second Epistle to Timothy, the Apostle Paul said:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p20" pid="LhXC55FK6EmsLpWJhoTtKQ" hash="M_gHJw">“And the servant of the Lord must not strive; but be gentle unto all men, apt to teach, patient,</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p21" pid="ejomhS-lD0WCX5Vj7Q1R7A" hash="qHV5rA">“In meekness instructing those that oppose themselves; if God peradventure will give them repentance to the acknowledging of the truth;</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p22" pid="p5YGlA34LEakx0aYUPibdw" hash="730wTg">“And that they may recover themselves.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p23" pid="XM76stNCCUqlKZwEsmjw4w" hash="mE9WtQ">By controlling our reactions, being calm and temperate, and avoiding contention, we will begin to qualify for the gift of meekness. President Henry B. Eyring once said, “When we with faith control our tempers and subdue our pride, the Holy Ghost gives His approval, and sacred promises and covenants become sure.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p24" pid="cOKg8dl_TUKMCEamD_bKuQ" hash="JeKq2A">Another step to attain meekness is to become humble. The Lord instructed Thomas B. Marsh through the Prophet Joseph Smith, saying, “Be thou humble; and the Lord thy God shall lead thee by the hand, and give thee answer to thy prayers.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p25" pid="pf5XBVbk7ki4D-V5xTUulg" hash="G0m-4A">I believe, brothers and sisters, that only those who are humble are able to acknowledge and understand the Lord’s answers to their prayers. The humble are teachable, recognizing how dependent they are on God and desiring to be subject to His will. The humble are meek and have the ability to influence others to be the same. God’s promise to the humble is that He will lead them by the hand. I truly believe that we will avoid detours and sadness in our lives as long as we walk hand in hand with the Lord.</p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p26" pid="9h3UuS42ykqFC2uJRbSMig" hash="5ONKfg">One of the most beautiful modern-day examples of meekness that I am aware of is that of Brother Moses Mahlangu. His conversion began in 1964, when he received a copy of the Book of Mormon. He was fascinated as he read this book, but it was not until the early ’70s that he saw an LDS Church sign on a building in Johannesburg, South Africa, as he was walking down a street. Brother Mahlangu was intrigued and entered the building to learn more about the Church. He was kindly told that he could not attend the services or be baptized because the country’s laws did not allow it at that time.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p27" pid="P73e4fl8Z0W9QnM4nWC-Sg" hash="ieP3aA">Brother Mahlangu accepted that decision with meekness, humility, and without resentment, but he continued to have a strong desire to learn more about the Church. He asked the Church leaders if they could leave one of the meetinghouse windows open during the Sunday meetings so he could sit outside and listen to the services. For several years, Brother Mahlangu’s family and friends attended church regularly “through the <span class="pageBreak" page-number="11"></span>window.” One day in 1980 they were told that they could attend church and also be baptized. What a glorious day it was for Brother Mahlangu.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p28" pid="6cOqQlo9dkySzRtcqlVUvg" hash="HZgY3Q">Later the Church organized a branch in his neighborhood in Soweto. This was possible only because of the determination, courage, and faithfulness of people like Brother Mahlangu who remained faithful for so many years under difficult circumstances.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p29" pid="qIDz-VOXdkKC0q6f5lftPA" hash="WLhxlA">One of Brother Mahlangu’s friends, who had joined the Church at the same time, recounted this story to me when I visited the Soweto stake. At the end of our conversation, he gave me a hug. At that moment, brothers and sisters, I felt as if I was encircled in the Savior’s loving arms. Meekness emanated from this good brother’s eyes. With a heart full of goodness and deep gratitude, he asked if I could just tell President Thomas S. Monson how grateful and blessed he and many others were for having the true gospel in their lives. Brother Mahlangu and his friend’s example of meekness truly influenced many lives for good—especially mine.</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p30" pid="k3k062jgdEea4n1TJjhBag" hash="ZLz-zA">Brothers and sisters, I believe the Savior Jesus Christ is the supreme example of meekness. Even during the last moments of His mortal life, being unfairly accused and condemned, painfully carrying His cross up to Golgotha, being mocked and cursed by His enemies, being abandoned by many who knew Him and had witnessed His miracles, He was nailed on the cross.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p31" pid="wXkyiRXATUamJTZ-6j3UMw" hash="rgL9Bg">Even after the most intense physical suffering, the Lord turned to His Father and spoke from the bottom of His meek and humble heart: “Father, forgive them; for they know not what they do.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> Christ faced extreme physical and spiritual suffering, giving us the opportunity to change our spiritual character and become meek like Him.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart.p32" pid="ttWN6TJEWUK_beYLtdTCMg" hash="jprowQ">I bear my witness that Jesus Christ is our Savior. I testify to you that, thanks to His love, it is possible to change. It is possible to leave our weaknesses behind. It is possible to reject the evil influences in our lives, control our anger, become meek, and develop the attributes of our Savior. He showed us the way. He gave us the perfect example and commanded each one of us to become as He is. His invitation to us is to follow Him, follow His example, and become like Him. Of these truths I bear testimony in His sacred name, even Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2013/10/be-meek-and-lowly-of-heart</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2013-general-conference/2013-10-1030-elder-ulisses-soares-64k-eng.mp3" length="5460899" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yes, We Can and Will Win!</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder Ulisses Soares testifies that if we will stay true to our testimony of Jesus Christ and His gospel, we will win our battles against evil.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_12565_000_32soares" doc-version="5" hash="g0ry1A">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="MfpLFR0oCUGybwfKz9541g" hash="TVc5RQ">Yes, We Can and Will Win!</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win.p2" pid="5Cu8Fww9-kuzVe9fAC9tVw" hash="Ujr5oA">By Elder Ulisses Soares</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win.p3" pid="Rl5WjVrCWEKAYjLJOp_fQw" hash="hptprg">Of the Presidency of the Seventy</p>
			<a href="gl://image/?pid=lkbycVAf8UyQX3kBgBPW9w"><img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" type="jpg" uri="ulisses-soares-10.jpg" translate="no" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255581/f56391497b3f4964b1d4d3c1f8bd1c61/100x125.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x62="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255581/f56391497b3f4964b1d4d3c1f8bd1c61/50x62.jpg" data-src-100x125="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255581/f56391497b3f4964b1d4d3c1f8bd1c61/100x125.jpg" data-src-200x250="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255581/f56391497b3f4964b1d4d3c1f8bd1c61/200x250.jpg" data-src-320x400="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255581/f56391497b3f4964b1d4d3c1f8bd1c61/320x400.jpg" data-src-460x576="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255581/f56391497b3f4964b1d4d3c1f8bd1c61/460x576.jpg" data-src-640x801="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255581/f56391497b3f4964b1d4d3c1f8bd1c61/640x801.jpg" data-src-1024x1282="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255581/f56391497b3f4964b1d4d3c1f8bd1c61/1024x1282.jpg" data-src-2048x2565="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255581/f56391497b3f4964b1d4d3c1f8bd1c61/2048x2565.jpg" pid="lkbycVAf8UyQX3kBgBPW9w" hash="agPDaQ"></img></a>
		</div>
		<p class="kicker" pid="c1fZLNXtf06moOgbbv6tZw" hash="uhtNKg">We must hold ever more tightly to our testimony of the gospel of Jesus Christ. Then we will win the daily battles against evil.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="xEMepLgIC0mpwvs-3DG62w" hash="Ujr5oA1">By Elder Ulisses Soares</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock" pid="hAsl9-9vy0W4_NXdOfREiQ" hash="dhDl6A">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win.p5" pid="P69IX7jE0E6Cir-jjmepcQ" hash="fChCfA">Dear brethren, I am humbled by the privilege I have to speak to you, the bearers of the priesthood of God throughout the Church today.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win.p6" pid="nNHdyDeO80qwA5VOuwca5A" hash="fAOmjA">President Thomas S. Monson once said:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win.p7" pid="wyWpC63mHkSKaUQFk-fjNA" hash="5Y05Yw">“The world can at times be a frightening place in which to live. The moral fabric of society seems to be unraveling at an alarming speed. None—whether young or old or in-between—is exempt from exposure to those things which have the potential to drag us down and destroy us. …</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win.p8" pid="IZRXC_6fD0SMPDyOXKG2nQ" hash="oIAHZA">“… But we need not despair. … We are waging a war with sin. … It is a war we can and will win. Our Father in Heaven has given us the tools we need in order to do so.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win.p9" pid="9aHddTRT50ynEhN9XWDOow" hash="F5_IVw">All of us, young and old, are faced daily with the war mentioned by President Monson. The enemy and his angels are trying to distract us. Their purpose is to encourage us to deviate from the covenants that we have made with the Lord, causing us to lose sight of our eternal inheritance. They know well our Heavenly Father’s plan for His children, for they were present with us in that great Council in Heaven when it was all presented. They try to take advantage of our weaknesses and frailties, deceiving us with “mists of darkness … , which blindeth the eyes, and hardeneth the hearts of the children of men, and leadeth them away into broad roads, that they perish and are lost.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win.p10" pid="q144dQrMT0uSeJbozxvBUg" hash="S2JedA">Despite the opposition we face, as President Monson has taught, this is a war that we can and will win. The Lord trusts in our capacity and determination to do so.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win.p11" pid="fOzXSYfSMk26q65HjbMrxg" hash="E9Ftyw">The scriptures contain countless examples of those who have won their wars even in the midst of very hostile situations. One of these examples is Captain Moroni in the Book of Mormon. This remarkable young man had the courage to defend the truth at a time when there were many dissensions and wars which put at risk the very survival of the entire Nephite nation. Although he was brilliant in exercising his responsibilities, Moroni remained humble. This and other attributes made him an extraordinary instrument in the hands of God at that time. The book of Alma explains that if all men had been like Moroni, “the very powers of hell would have been shaken forever; [and] the devil would never have power over the hearts of the children of men.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> All of Moroni’s attributes stemmed from his great faith in God and in the Lord Jesus Christ<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> and his firm determination to follow the voice of God and His prophets.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win.p12" pid="2Wrhz0G82katf-LjgMdLjA" hash="7oflRQ">Figuratively, all of us need to transform ourselves into modern Captain Moronis in order to win the wars against evil. I know a very faithful young deacon who transformed himself into a modern Captain Moroni. Inasmuch as he has sought to follow the counsel of his parents and Church leaders, his faith and determination have been tested every day, even at his young age. He told me one day he was surprised by a very difficult and uncomfortable situation—his friends were accessing pornographic images on their cell phones. In that exact moment, this young man had to decide what was most important—his popularity or his righteousness. In the few seconds that followed, he was filled with courage and told his friends that what they were doing was not right. Moreover, he told them that they should stop what they were doing or they would become slaves to it. Most of his classmates ridiculed his counsel, saying that it was a part of life and that there was nothing wrong with it. However, there was one among them who listened to the counsel of that young man and decided to stop what he was doing.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win.p13" pid="sfYYYNZHyUiSSRw6SQ3-Jg" hash="dz79AA">This deacon’s example had a positive influence on at least one of his classmates. Undoubtedly, he and his friend faced mockery and persecution because of that decision. On the other hand, they had followed the admonition of Alma to his people when he said, “Come ye out from the wicked, and be ye separate, and touch not their unclean things.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win.p14" pid="3MPoJRuArE-KN0ZBc4qbtw" hash="aNkqEg">The pamphlet <span class="emphasis">For the Strength of Youth</span> contains the following counsel, approved by the First Presidency for the youth of the Church: “You are responsible for the choices you make. God is mindful of you and will help you make good choices, even if your family and friends use their agency in ways that are not right. Have the moral courage to stand firm in obeying God’s will, even if you have to stand alone. As you do this, you set an example for others to follow.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win.p15" pid="SJ0nR4BgOUakWO663wHzdA" hash="CRm3WQ">The war of good against evil will continue throughout our lives since the adversary’s purpose is to make all people as miserable as he is. Satan and his angels will try to shroud our thoughts and assert control by tempting us to sin. If they can, they will corrupt all that is good. Nevertheless, it is essential to understand that they will have power over us only if we allow it.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win.p16" pid="vhh0LjcI6keu5r4TNMVJlQ" hash="Z6w0uw">The scriptures also contain several examples of those who gave that permission to the adversary and ended up becoming confused and even destroyed, like Nehor, Korihor, and Sherem. We need to be alert to this danger. We cannot allow ourselves to be confused by popular messages that are easily accepted by the world and that contradict the doctrine and true principles of the gospel of Jesus Christ. Many of these worldly messages represent nothing more than an attempt of our society to justify sin. We need to remember that, at the end, all will stand before Christ to be judged of our works, whether they are good or whether they are evil.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> As we encounter these worldly messages, great courage and a solid knowledge of the plan of our Heavenly Father will be required to choose the right.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win.p17" pid="SlI0usOH506J3v5qSQaCgQ" hash="mFJH4A">All of us can receive the strength to choose the right if we seek the Lord and place all our trust and faith in Him. But, as the scriptures teach, we need to have “a sincere heart” and “real intent.” Then the Lord, in His infinite mercy, “will manifest the truth unto [us], by the power of the Holy Ghost. And by the power of the Holy Ghost [we] may know the truth of all things.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win.p18" pid="pZgGz6K32E--IBveVLMpCQ" hash="m_YEEg">This knowledge acquired through the Holy Ghost is nothing more than our testimony, which propels our faith and determination to follow the teachings of the restored gospel in these latter days, regardless of the popular messages we hear from the world. Our testimony must be our shield to protect us against the fiery darts of the adversary in his attempts to attack us.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> It will guide us safely through the darkness and confusion that exist in the world today.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win.p19" pid="4ICwuTPyZ02TptXirTqm0Q" hash="5Ztz8g">I learned this principle when I served as a young missionary. My companion and I were serving in a very small and faraway branch of the Church. We tried to speak with every person in the city. They received us very well, but they liked to debate the scriptures and asked us for concrete evidence regarding the truthfulness of what we were teaching.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win.p20" pid="RWoqGsGJME2DTD_VyLyFaA" hash="_ViVcg">I recall that each time my companion and I set out to try to prove something to people, the Spirit of God left us and we felt totally lost and confused. We felt that we should more strongly align our testimonies with the truths of the gospel we were teaching. From that time on, I remember that when we bore a testimony with all our hearts, a silent confirming power coming from the Holy Ghost filled the room, and there was no space for confusion or discussion. I learned that no evil forces exist that are capable of confusing, deceiving, or subverting the power of a sincere testimony of a true disciple of Jesus Christ.</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win.p21" pid="9oQkt7WdXECwbFsyJd_ALQ" hash="LhOyKg">As the Savior Himself taught, the adversary desires to sift us as wheat, causing us to lose our ability to influence the world for good.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win.p22" pid="owuulR1OQUOM3gXE86sbQg" hash="Q39epQ">My dear brethren, because of the wave of confusion and doubt spreading throughout the world today, we must hold ever more tightly to our testimony of the gospel of Jesus Christ. Then will our ability to defend truth and justice greatly increase. We will win the daily battles against evil, and, rather than fall on the battlefields of life, we will rally others to the Master’s standards.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win.p23" pid="rdtFgWVrSUyDwo_o5P4ZxQ" hash="xqCgow">I invite all to find safety in the teachings contained in the scriptures. Captain Moroni aligned his faith in God and his testimony of the truth with the knowledge and wisdom found in the scriptures. In this way, he trusted that he would receive the blessings of the Lord and would obtain many victories, which is what, in fact, happened.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win.p24" pid="lV3HkBthA0OzzS8Nk14nfQ" hash="rZu9dQ">I invite all to find safety in the wise words of our current prophets. President Thomas S. Monson said: “We who have been ordained to the priesthood of God can make a difference. When we maintain our personal purity and honor our priesthood, we become righteous examples for others to follow … [and we] help to illuminate an increasingly dark world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win.p25" pid="OvW6Kr7SSUSrddkyXtZ0lg" hash="KCvM7w">I invite all to trust in the merits and in the power of the Atonement of Jesus Christ. Through His atoning sacrifice, we can gain the courage to win all the wars of our time, even in the midst of our difficulties, challenges, and temptations. Let us trust in His love and power to save us. Christ Himself said:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win.p26" pid="KcFVQZYJ8UGdt9aoRkRIoA" hash="FYeBOg">“I am the way, the truth, and the life: no man cometh unto the Father, but by me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win.p27" pid="xeke_oRO-UuiPMJH2N_U4g" hash="BjJKdQ">“I am the light of the world: he that followeth me shall not walk in darkness, but shall have the light of life.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win.p28" pid="X4HXLNz8pk-gHQSdkvZqDQ" hash="irwgPw">“These things I have spoken unto you, that in me ye might have peace. In the world ye shall have tribulation: but be of good cheer; I have overcome the world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span></p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win.p29" pid="8kUOKlUlw0ungB6l4LAqQA" hash="euf4Yg">I bear testimony of these truths in the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
	
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2015/04/yes-we-can-and-will-win</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2015-general-conference/2015-04-3020-elder-ulisses-soares-64k-eng.mp3" length="5751024" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confide in God Unwaveringly</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Elder Soares teaches that we must be steadfast and not waver in our faith.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD60003501_000_25soares" doc-version="1" hash="2Q3lew">
		
		<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.head1">
			<h1 class="title" pid="ClFqVSVSRkyBS2Pz5M3ZjQ" hash="UkEQfQ">Confide in God Unwaveringly</h1>
			<div class="byline">
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p2" pid="beFQfx34JkK1_8fXgbMohA" hash="Ujr5oA1">By Elder Ulisses Soares</p>
				<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p3" pid="kuS8J-pZI06JxzLQZIQG2A" hash="hptprg">Of the Presidency of the Seventy</p>
			</div>
			<p class="kicker" pid="l6bIidagH0mKSI46TRwN-A" hash="1civHQ">If we are steadfast and do not waver in our faith, the Lord will increase our capacity to raise ourselves above the challenges of life.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="79jQe31rBk-hRnPyJOBt_g" hash="Ujr5oA">By Elder Ulisses Soares</p></div>
		<div class="bodyBlock">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p5" pid="x5IwJXSZSkGc_9LcE9_JrA" hash="BnCyDA">Dear brothers and sisters, I want to begin my message today by testifying that I know that President Thomas S. Monson is the prophet of God in our day. His counselors in the First Presidency and the Twelve Apostles are also, in fact, prophets, seers, and revelators. They represent the Lord Jesus Christ and have the right to declare His mind and will as it is revealed to them. I testify that there is safety in following their counsel. The Lord is inspiring them to emphasize strengthening our faith in Heavenly Father and in His Son, Jesus Christ, and in His Atonement so that we will not waver as we face the challenges of our day.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p6" pid="PFp4VKjQ3EmRGbqNCRGvRA" hash="Kl-D6g">In the Book of Mormon, we read about a man named Ammon who was sent from the land of Zarahemla to the land of Lehi-Nephi to inquire concerning his brethren. There he found King Limhi and his people, who were in bondage to the Lamanites. King Limhi was encouraged by the things Ammon shared with him about his people in Zarahemla. His heart was filled with such great hope and joy that he gathered his people to the temple and said:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p7" pid="YVwCPBO0yUiIRStmT9NQtw" hash="GRQswA">“Therefore, lift up your heads, and rejoice, and put your trust in God. …</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p8" pid="KVG472Jgr0WheDbPoGILZA" hash="0B-tBA">“… If ye will turn to the Lord with full purpose of heart, … and serve him with all diligence of mind, … he will, according to his own will and pleasure, deliver you out of bondage.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p9" pid="qqaYA9MOE02px57Vk5H4gw" hash="dRCaRQ">The faith of King Limhi’s people was so profoundly affected by the words of Ammon that they made a covenant with God to serve Him and to keep His commandments, regardless of their difficult circumstances. Because of their faith, they were able to devise a plan to escape from the hands of the Lamanites.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p10" pid="rrr257WHUUOSiuERxcPJtw" hash="bWkDlQ">Brothers and sisters, please consider the importance of the invitation King Limhi gave to his people and its relevance to us. He said, “Lift up your heads, and rejoice, and put your trust in God.” With these words, Limhi invited his people to look to the future through the eyes of faith; to replace their fears with the optimism of hope born of faith; and to not waver in placing their trust in God regardless of circumstance.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p11" pid="MWwuiZKkfUurkCCrldmf6A" hash="2PjRAw">Mortal life is a period of testing where we will be proven to see if we will do all things that the Lord our God shall command us.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span> This will require unwavering faith in Christ even in times of great difficulty. It will require that we press forward with steadfast faith in Christ, being led by the Spirit and trusting that God will provide for our needs.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p12" pid="ve5M9ubibkaSPsASeP1naA" hash="dFRJ4A">At the conclusion of His earthly ministry, just before being taken prisoner, the Savior taught His disciples, “In the world ye shall have tribulation: but be of good cheer; I have overcome the world.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p13" pid="uxPYb4KDd0C4lIvxbN12PA" hash="umTkdA">Ponder with me for a moment—Jesus Christ, the Only Begotten Son of the Father, lived a sinless life and overcame all the temptations, pains, challenges, and afflictions of the world. He shed drops of blood in Gethsemane; He suffered terrible pain beyond any power of description. He took upon Himself all our pains and sicknesses. He stands ready to help—to help each of us—with every burden. Through His life, suffering, death, and Resurrection, He removed every impediment to our rejoicing and finding peace on this earth. The benefits of His atoning sacrifice are extended to all those who accept Him and deny themselves and to those who take up His cross and follow Him as His true disciples.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> Therefore, as we exercise faith in Jesus Christ and in His Atonement, we will be strengthened, our burdens will be eased, and through Him we will overcome the world.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p14" pid="k7w6p3qzlUy-2D4_ltmOMw" hash="mdqp4w">Brothers and sisters, as we contemplate the strength and hope that we can receive from the Savior, we do have reason to lift up our heads, rejoice, and press forward in faith without wavering, “for he that wavereth is like a wave of the sea driven with the wind and tossed. … A double minded man is unstable in all his ways.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p15" pid="IC042mld1k6tyV-NU6Y_Nw" hash="df0FqQ">King Limhi likewise urged, “Turn to the Lord with full purpose of heart, … serve him with <span class="emphasis">all </span>diligence of mind, if ye do this, he will, according to his own will and pleasure, deliver you out of bondage.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p16" pid="nEq1UTIxj0iqeqk8Y8mcAw" hash="LyWVFA">Listen to the Savior’s own words as He entreats us:</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p17" pid="EJeaJUQ0YkmzNtnfa03euw" hash="SrHIxg">“Let not your heart be troubled: ye believe in God, believe also in me. …</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p18" pid="SS9xF1sq1UegaJoY1fdPJQ" hash="qTuuRw">“If ye love me, keep my commandments. …</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p19" pid="nzHxZp6qrkC_tJQeYRIA1w" hash="o1Xg7A">“He that hath my commandments, and keepeth them, he it is that loveth me: and he that loveth me shall be loved of my Father, and I will love him, and will manifest myself to him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p20" pid="7_xd81BeDEiKmakthiGFJQ" hash="komiYQ">God blesses us according to our faith.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> Faith is the source of living with divine purpose and eternal perspective. Faith is a practical principle that inspires diligence. It is a vital, living force manifest in our positive attitude and desire to willingly do everything that God and Jesus Christ ask of us. It takes us to our knees to implore the Lord for guidance and to arise and act with confidence to achieve things consistent with His will.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p21" pid="ZGmhCYtQrEuKK-x4IiyywA" hash="E0pIGQ">Years ago while serving as a mission president, I received a phone call from the parents of one of our beloved missionaries informing me about the death of his sister. I remember, in the tenderness of that moment, that missionary and I discussed God’s marvelous plan of salvation for His children and how this knowledge would comfort him.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p22" pid="0YvD2iuZOUWcxl_blXt4_g" hash="cXpjiw">Although he was stunned and saddened by that adversity, this missionary—through his tears and with faith in God—rejoiced in his sister’s life. He expressed unwavering confidence in the tender mercies of the Lord. Resolutely, he told me that he would continue to serve his mission with all faith and diligence in order to be worthy of the promises that God had for him and his family. In this time of need, that faithful missionary turned his heart to God, placed all of his trust in Him, and renewed his commitment to serve the Lord with faith and with all diligence.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p23" pid="y7rtGU7zgEifUf_MX4pY7A" hash="9kimyQ">Brothers and sisters, if we are not rooted by steadfast trust in God and the desire to serve Him, the painful experiences of mortality can lead us to feel as though we are burdened by a heavy yoke; and we can lose the motivation to live the gospel fully. Without faith, we will end up losing the capacity to appreciate those designs of our God regarding the things that will happen later in our life.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p24" pid="sVRC7C55Xk6pwCMqbjevDg" hash="kM6N7g">In these moments of trial, the adversary—who is always on the lookout—tries to use our logic and reasoning against us. He tries to convince us that it is useless to live the principles of the gospel. Please remember that the logic of the natural man “receiveth not the things of the Spirit of God: for they are foolishness unto him.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> Remember that Satan “is an enemy [of] God, and [he] fighteth against him continually, and inviteth and enticeth [us] to sin, and to do that which is evil continually.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> We must not allow him to deceive us; for when we do, we falter in our faith and lose the power to obtain God’s blessings.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p25" pid="u2r_eAy4cEC-BZEVA97Mlw" hash="O5wYLQ">If we are steadfast and do not waver in our faith, the Lord will increase our capacity to raise ourselves above the challenges of life. We will be enabled to subdue negative impulses, and we will develop the capacity to overcome even what appear to be overwhelming obstacles. This was what enabled King Limhi’s people to make a spectacular escape from their Lamanite captivity.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p26" pid="XZPtuPv9MUaGgGG8fuWSEg" hash="5_1cFQ">Brothers and sisters, I invite you to place all of your trust in God and in the teachings of His prophets. I invite you to renew your covenants with God, to serve Him with all your heart, regardless of the complex situations of life. I testify that by the power of your unwavering faith in Christ, you will become free of the captivity of sin, of doubt, of unbelief, of unhappiness, of suffering; and you will receive all of the promised blessings from our loving Heavenly Father.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p27" pid="pXDEusMDlUir89CjUoV3pQ" hash="LMHUtA">I testify that God is real. He lives. He loves us. He listens to our prayers in our moments of happiness and in our moments of doubt, sadness, and desperation. I testify that Jesus Christ is the Savior of the world. He is the Redeemer.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p28" pid="-XXm-RdxeE2i9GKnickUiw" hash="4aQe5g">I close my remarks today with the lyrics of the hymn “Not Now but in the Coming Years,” found in the Portuguese hymnal:</p>
			<div class="poetry">
				<div class="stanza">
					<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p29" pid="LW2pBuOP70y-VQkIsrqTOw" hash="_Tew8Q">If clouds instead of sun spread shadows o’er our heart,</p>
					<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p30" pid="esTj5Iu8r0-sr8jErbapDg" hash="zrzTdQ">If pain afflicts us, never mind; we will soon know who Thou art.</p>
					<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p31" pid="V8v1dh6YkEKo-tt6YBuS-A" hash="2-nMuw">Jesus guides us with His hand, and He will tell us why;</p>
					<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p32" pid="5LVrsxNWNESZO0XsgsfzfQ" hash="CD_4oA">If we listen to His voice, He will tell us by and by.</p>
					<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p33" pid="sTDtnkcvLEeyzksfmSBDYQ" hash="jIM_wQ">Confide in God unwaveringly, and let Him us sustain;</p>
					<p class="line" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p34" pid="LhzR5yB1_0O7eDMs198HnA" hash="B90m6g">Sing His glory endlessly, for later He’ll explain.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
				</div>
			</div>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly.p35" pid="l4sTunf_qUeJA8s_7gok8Q" hash="0vlaSg">I say these things in the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
		
	</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2017/04/confide-in-god-unwaveringly</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2017-general-conference/2017-04-1050-ulisses-soares-64k-eng.mp3" length="5292173" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
