<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By W. Craig Zwick</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by W. Craig Zwick.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/W.%20Craig%20Zwick.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by W. Craig Zwick.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 1995 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Encircled in the Savior’s Love</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1995/10/encircled-in-the-saviors-love?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My heart trembles with deep humility as I occupy this sacred spot for the first time. I know, with full assurance, that President Hinckley’s voice and thoughts represent the Savior’s desires for each of us.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/encircled-in-the-saviors-love" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_95911_000_007" doc-version="2" hash="RgvJkQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/encircled-in-the-saviors-love.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="gbZxu2CnoEai4ETZQeKvQg" hash="3-7KiQ">Encircled in the Savior’s Love</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="DiSbeFaK7kSC1-HfzaviGA" hash="o5VSKg">W. Craig Zwick</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/encircled-in-the-saviors-love.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2106.jpg" alt="Elder W. Craig Zwick" pid="XXIui4YxzEeqqyPEmPyPIw" hash="qO5BCw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/encircled-in-the-saviors-love.p1" pid="kkZmn8tU1k2yqP4YTc6YzQ" hash="SMc6Qw">My heart trembles with deep humility as I occupy this sacred spot for the first time. I know, with full assurance, that President Hinckley’s voice and thoughts represent the Savior’s desires for each of us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/encircled-in-the-saviors-love.p2" pid="sabgioMxbUGM4KP67WDO7Q" hash="srt3nA">On a beautiful summer morning, our family attended the Special Olympics to watch our son Scott participate. The Special Olympics are held each year to allow people with disabilities to enjoy friendly competition. We observed that as the runners were taking their positions for the fifty-yard dash, they were being encouraged by special friends affectionately known as huggers. Seconds before the start of the race, these huggers took their places at the finish line of the race. It didn’t matter who crossed the finish line first. What did matter was that every runner completed the race and that every runner received a congratulatory hug. Both the courageous runners and the caring huggers taught important principles of truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/encircled-in-the-saviors-love.p3" pid="gnbDCeQGt0KTZkpZwn-Q6A" hash="Z3WK8w">The Lord spoke in plainness, “Be faithful and diligent in keeping the commandments of God, and I will encircle thee in the arms of my love” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/6.20" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 6:20</a>). We all want to feel the comfort of the Savior’s embrace.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/encircled-in-the-saviors-love.p4" pid="kE_GqVouTkSwJkjFBuxxrA" hash="1WWoSQ">During His ministry, the Savior, with great compassion, saw beyond the imperfections of body and mind and looked upon the heart. Our discipleship includes the sacred responsibility to follow His example of reaching out and loving those with disabilities. Valiant disciples seek meaningful ways to stretch their souls in service and love to others.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/encircled-in-the-saviors-love.p5" pid="Q-GO01ECtki6GZIjpg9EMg" hash="9Bbf2g">Elder Richard G. Scott’s counsel is precise: “You become an instrument through which the Lord can bless another. The Spirit will let you feel the Savior’s concern and interest, then the warmth and strength of His love” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1994, p. 9).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/encircled-in-the-saviors-love.p6" pid="rwC27uiR4Ue7m14NuMtbXQ" hash="6brMzw">Our task, facilitated by prayer, is to recognize even the slight limitations of each person who may be suffering pain or discouragement. It may be a minor learning disability, dyslexia, or a slight hearing impairment. Without our help, they may be unable to partake of the Savior’s goodness or enjoy the fulness of life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/encircled-in-the-saviors-love.p7" pid="JhXNaJxlDk6Q-3paMQ-Jfg" hash="oq6sWQ">Each person wants to feel safe in what is sometimes a very cruel, competitive world. Everyone is of great worth because each is a spirit child of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/encircled-in-the-saviors-love.p8" pid="WLtxRbxIb0Cx6hS6bCIZZw" hash="ykik9Q">Mary, a young girl with mental disabilities and not a member of the Church, was limited, but she wanted very much to be included. Sensitive to her needs, several young women invited her to participate in the ward road show. Her family was invited to the performance. Mary’s father wanted to know more about a church whose people cared enough about his daughter to include her. The whole family embraced the gospel and were baptized.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/encircled-in-the-saviors-love.p9" pid="-PKHGXTTpUKsAKTFeueNSw" hash="QnB4RA">Thank you to each thoughtful friend, teacher, bishop, and all who ensure that no one feels alone or out of place. There is an ever-present need for meaningful involvement. We are all enriched and enhanced in the process.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/encircled-in-the-saviors-love.p10" pid="WJX5TwqXukal5eM4xG9chg" hash="Q395Mg">Sister Navarro lives in a small village in southern Chile. Her body is afflicted with arthritis, and she suffers significant pain as she walks with the help of a cane. Every Sunday for nineteen years, she takes the hand of her daughter who is mentally disabled and, aided by a cane, shuffles two miles to attend church. Her calling as chorister in the Relief Society means everything to dear Sister Navarro. Her willingness to reach out to others is like a magnet for others to be of help to her disabled daughter.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/encircled-in-the-saviors-love.p11" pid="jEjOegpsdEyYda_KRkp84w" hash="ChYsIQ">The Savior in his infinite goodness allows all to enjoy. “All men are privileged the one like unto the other, and none are forbidden” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/26.28" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 26:28</a>). Each person has unique gifts, and each needs to contribute as well as receive.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/encircled-in-the-saviors-love.p12" pid="j21ZYvjenkaTa2BQVfeZxQ" hash="78a-1A">Jamie Wheeler is an exceptional sixteen-year-old. He was born with Down syndrome. Jamie has a calling in the ward and helps the bishop in other meaningful ways. He participates actively in the Boy Scout program. Truly he contributes and also receives genuine love and appreciation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/encircled-in-the-saviors-love.p13" pid="X1xP_dOEMUGeKN4dfEvQjg" hash="uDSErA">The Prophet Joseph Smith taught, “All the minds and spirits that God ever sent into the world are susceptible of enlargement” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of the Prophet Joseph Smith,</span> p. 354).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/encircled-in-the-saviors-love.p14" pid="_rLu2cT9sUyXkPNCSMB_oQ" hash="jmRKsg">Our lives are blessed as we learn lessons from trusted friends whose disabilities and humility invite the Spirit. They teach us a new dimension of faith, courage, patience, love, and individual worth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/encircled-in-the-saviors-love.p15" pid="5A6W9WLE-Eqno8EqzURrbg" hash="77hJTQ">Four young men with severe disabilities work in the São Paulo Temple. Each has a different challenge, but each is blessing the lives of thousands as they contribute to the sweet spirit within this beautiful temple. “Remember the worth of souls is great in the sight of God” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/18.10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 18:10</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/encircled-in-the-saviors-love.p16" pid="4sRMkqUltkirJF3UBb63pQ" hash="mi3lmw">My soul is stirring with deep appreciation and love for our oldest son, Scott, mentally disabled from birth. His courage and love have allowed many friends and each member of our family to feel through the Spirit the “Savior’s concern and interest, then the warmth and strength of His love” (Richard G. Scott, <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1994, p. 9). I am grateful for my eternal companion, Jan, whose faith and tender love for each of our children has made our home a peaceful setting. She truly looks for ways to make each child of God feel comforted.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/encircled-in-the-saviors-love.p17" pid="1U9obNQs2UGh1vjtDxu2_Q" hash="kbb43w">Ponder in your hearts the feelings of the Savior as He expresses His love for each child of God. “They were in tears, and did look steadfastly upon him as if they would ask him to tarry a little longer with them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/encircled-in-the-saviors-love.p18" pid="pBTKzC42pEC0Z1gtDDo26w" hash="ONkmTg">“And he said unto them: Behold, my bowels are filled with compassion towards you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/encircled-in-the-saviors-love.p19" pid="pgeSsak9gk-0xbFAY10Wug" hash="YLpZTg">“Have ye any that are … afflicted in any manner? Bring them hither and I will heal them, for I have compassion upon you. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/encircled-in-the-saviors-love.p20" pid="44f-5hj350WejhB0nGn16g" hash="WZqwZw">“… I see that your faith is sufficient that I should heal you” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/17.5-8" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 17:5–8</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1995/10/encircled-in-the-saviors-love.p21" pid="vUQP3Fg5X06f5O-XY4GxMg" hash="oyg0yw">I pray that our faith may be sufficient for each of us to feel encircled in the arms of our Savior’s love. I know that our Savior lives, and that He intimately knows each of us. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1995/10/encircled-in-the-saviors-love</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1995-general-conference/1995-10-1050-elder-w-craig-zwick-64k-eng.mp3" length="3503237" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 1995 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Lord Thy God Will Hold Thy Hand</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand?lang=eng</link>
      <description>If we will … walk hand in hand with Him in His paths, we will go forward with faith and never feel alone.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10030835_000_013" doc-version="2" hash="hSHouw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="3PrqqI1CXEO8N4eNNnl9pg" hash="BWnyeg">The Lord Thy God Will Hold Thy Hand</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="pXU4mkdroESfV3hzxhnlfw" hash="o5VSKg">W. Craig Zwick</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="uIQScj35SEq2RKby0PDZ3g" hash="z38pkA">If we will … walk hand in hand with Him in His paths, we will go forward with faith and never feel alone.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-afb.jpg" alt="Elder W. Craig Zwick" pid="C3kt0xmuu0quEFbXgttlmQ" hash="KgCnXw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p1" pid="6QrFSOuEYEeUtfcOLAgF8w" hash="ofoZ6Q">In the eyes and hearts of many people in the world today, there is evidence of doubt, fear, and hopelessness. Much of the insecurity in the world has filtered into our homes and personal lives. No matter what our age or circumstance, we all have a need to know that we have power in the present and hope in the future.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p2" pid="NLRg-_3dzUmZ6ECRvLxnng" hash="_XmsDA">Listen to the words of Mormon: “Know ye not that ye are in the hands of God? Know ye not that he hath all power?” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/morm/5.23" class="scriptureRef">Morm. 5:23</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p3" pid="OUcMkkxY8EybpC7N_OPD4w" hash="4pSnTg">Hands are one of the symbolically expressive parts of the body. In Hebrew, <span class="emphasis">yad,</span> the most common word for “hand,” is also used metaphorically to mean power, strength, might (see William Wilson, <span class="emphasis">Old Testament Word Studies</span> [1978], 205). Thus, hands signify power and strength.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p4" pid="y35nxOjsRU-r0vTYQ3D7oA" hash="8rH_Ww">The extended hand of our living prophet, President Gordon B. Hinckley, strengthens, lifts, and inspires people all across the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p5" pid="f-al5D7P00-EAjiQlg4Tqw" hash="BAngag">To be in the hands of God would suggest that we are not only under His watchful care but also that we are guarded and protected by His wondrous power.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p6" pid="Yjz5SSh4REC9xmochJ4XzQ" hash="KEqXoA">Throughout the scriptures, reference is made to the hand of the Lord. His divine assistance is evidenced over and over again. His powerful hands created worlds, and yet they were gentle enough to bless the little children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p7" pid="Iq6b7jXnyk2vgtrGV_Sk5Q" hash="e7aG6A">Consider John’s words describing the resurrected and glorified Savior: “And when I saw him, … he laid his right hand upon me, saying unto me, Fear not; … I am he that liveth, and was dead; and, behold, I am alive for evermore” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rev/1.17-18" class="scriptureRef">Rev. 1:17–18</a>). When He lays His hand upon us, we, like John, can be alive in Him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p8" pid="Q4GHwQ9atkqYPrv3VynQsA" hash="caTrzA">Twenty-four years ago, our tiny newborn son struggled for his life in the intensive care unit of a hospital. His lungs were not fully developed because of his premature birth, and he desperately fought for each breath of air. He was so small but with so much will to live. As young and inexperienced parents, my courageous and ever faithful wife, Jan, and I prayed that the Lord’s hand would reach out and somehow help our baby boy continue to breathe. As I put my trembling hand through the small opening into the isolette, I felt so inadequate and powerless. I took hold of the tiny but perfect hand of our newborn son, and there was a powerful spiritual connection never to be forgotten. Two fingers from each of my hands covered his tiny head as I administered to him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p9" pid="b7Lwj8CAn0au--aeoceLDA" hash="-3h5Fg">Our desire for him was pure, but we knew that his earthly experience rested in the Lord’s hands and not in ours or in the medical team who cared for him. I then humbly realized that my quivering hands held power and authority well beyond my own. My fingers on his head symbolized the placing of God’s hands and power upon our son. Following that blessing, in a moment of emotional peace, my eternal companion and I looked at each other across the isolette, feeling the spirit of renewed hope and comfort born of faith in the Lord Jesus Christ and in the personal effect of His Atonement. It was a powerful witness of His love for an infant son who had just left His presence. We were then better prepared to accept His will for our son. We truly felt we had placed our hands in the hands of the Savior. It was as if the Savior’s own hands provided the critical respiratory aid, allowing our son to breathe and gain sustenance. With each breath and with each incremental bit of progress, we expressed prayerful thanks. Today, our healthy son and his indebted parents continue to be so grateful for the Savior’s willing hands.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p10" pid="Q_4MYJybzES87N73_QeTtA" hash="LXzukg">Among the supernal promises of coming forth in the morning of the First Resurrection and inheriting “thrones, kingdoms, principalities, and powers” are the additional promises of “all heights and depths” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/132.19" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 132:19</a>). The great plan of happiness includes a proverbial roller coaster of challenging times along with the most joyful times. Yes, we all have our moments of difficulty and heartbreak. Occasionally, they are so difficult for us that we just want to give up. There are times when our steps are unsteady, when we feel discouraged and even reach out in desperation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p11" pid="-LgyD3VGekCv6bkUDoRIQQ" hash="h4PwFg">Elder Holland reminds us that the “symbol of the cup that cannot pass is a cup that comes in our life as well as in [the Savior’s]. It is in a much lesser way, to a much lesser degree, but it comes often enough to teach us that we have to obey” (<span class="emphasis">Trusting Jesus</span> [2003], 42).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p12" pid="DlaFWD4eVUSLRSSBs9Y5pQ" hash="gMXmJg">Every one of us needs to know that we can go on in the strength of the Lord. We can put our hand in His, and we will feel His sustaining presence lift us to heights unattainable alone.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p13" pid="eyUqOEiR2UG8_QuEr5v4KQ" hash="X7d_fg">When a stricken father brought his terribly afflicted son to Jesus, Mark records that “Jesus took him by the hand, and lifted him up; and he arose” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/9.27" class="scriptureRef">Mark 9:27</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p14" pid="GnMJ4iA2BESQTq_145fWqQ" hash="c9PuLg">We must trust in the Lord. If we give ourselves freely to Him, our burdens will be lifted and our hearts will be consoled.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p15" pid="_qiNlttUSUi_s4fMaiE_pg" hash="jgzTbw">Elder Scott has recently counseled: “Trust in God … no matter how challenging the circumstance. … Your peace of mind, your assurance of answers to vexing problems, your ultimate joy depend upon your trust in Heavenly Father and His Son, Jesus Christ” (“The Sustaining Power of Faith in Times of Uncertainty and Testing,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 2003, 76, 78).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p16" pid="BBnz-whhtEGek3HBpcVLig" hash="07D30w">How do we learn to trust? How do we learn to extend our hand and connect to the comfort provided by the Lord?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p17" pid="fVLIE065mkWVG-J49TZcBg" hash="8NSfog">Clear instruction came from the Lord to Joseph Smith: “Learn of me, and listen to my words; walk in the meekness of my Spirit, and you shall have peace in me. … Pray always, and I will pour out my Spirit upon you” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/19.23,38" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 19:23, 38</a>).</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.f2">
	<p pid="4BGa6KcJREGRQG1Sps8l1g" hash="juIttQ">Here are four keys:</p>
	<ul class="bullet">
	  <li pid="GQNIaXSQXE-aktZnM9UaNg" hash="WAfYgA">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="NICQz9m2iE-THHPooMiTGQ" hash="yahVvA">Learn</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="g_zPM6Oh2ESgDD-Cm-1qlQ" hash="0ae5SA">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="vH1hBy_BakuzRtT6oopatg" hash="HPjE0w">Listen</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="qE35C2BtcUOxF2CqNsEg8Q" hash="B1dpXA">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="thkrSdShE0qzKNQL73NIHQ" hash="-itk6Q">Seek the Spirit</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="cSMT8Yz1m02pd0HfsoWMiQ" hash="3I9Jkw">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="S6UQY9LEO062DJdmxseVHg" hash="d-VUYA">Pray always</p>
        </li>
	</ul>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p18" pid="6SUJ4SNSRU6kPES8-ecP2g" hash="jEDXig">The Lord will provide sustenance and support if we are willing to open the door and receive His hand of divine assistance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p19" pid="tH1YraFtF0m_qrDGUfHxlQ" hash="cylJtQ">President Thomas S. Monson reminds us of the Savior’s willing hand of rescue: “Adored is the hand that saves—even the hand of Jesus Christ, the Son of God. … With that hand he knocks upon the door of our understanding” (“Hands,” <span class="emphasis">Tambuli,</span> Mar. 1991, 5; <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Aug. 1990, 5).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p20" pid="5bYhyoByjkC5FOVsoVMJVg" hash="1P0Liw">Recently our daughter and son-in-law were preparing to enjoy an evening together. They were rushing around trying to get ready and give the babysitter some last-minute instructions. They didn’t really notice the sad countenance of one of the children and the tears in the eyes of another until they were at the door, ready to leave. They realized that their children were apprehensive about their mommy and daddy being away from them. So their parents gathered their four precious children around them. Their daddy asked them to put their hands out in front of them. All eight tiny hands were extended. Mom and Dad then kissed each hand and told them that when they missed them or they were frightened or needed to feel their love, they could put their little hands up to their cheeks and they would be able to feel Mommy’s and Daddy’s presence anytime. They were so happy, and when our daughter and son-in-law left, they saw four little children standing at the window with smiles on their faces and hands on their cheeks.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p21" pid="TKQWRhMhx0G1mIEXO2XMvA" hash="YrwGeQ">They trusted their parents. They knew they were loved.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p22" pid="2q74_O-xD0ilpXsNv-UIVA" hash="51K2FQ">Just as little children trust, each of us must have that same childlike, unreserved trust. We must all remember that we are sons and daughters of God and that He loves us very much. If we truly understand who we are, we will have an unfailing source of hope and comfort.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p23" pid="dpWBgMK47kyUgsVtS1u3FQ" hash="Tqiceg">We can never complete “the race that is set before us” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/heb/12.1" class="scriptureRef">Heb. 12:1</a>) without placing our hand in the Lord’s.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p24" pid="2gQPI2jpUUKB3k9kkpFI3w" hash="bc9rww">Several years ago, our only daughter decided to compete in a marathon. She trained and worked very hard, along with some of her friends. The race was difficult, and there were times when she wanted to quit. But she kept going, just concentrating on one step at a time. As she was approaching the middle part of the course, she heard someone behind her shout out, “Blind man on your left.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p25" pid="jSFKkpuQLEGEQvM0oASiUw" hash="-jY_mQ">She turned her head only to see a blind man overtake her, holding the hand of another man. They were both running the race. As they passed, she could see how tightly the blind man held the hand of his friend.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p26" pid="88EAv7FjP0OUxO594NnJJQ" hash="PEVmdw">Overcome with her own physical pain, she was lifted as she watched these two men run hand in hand. He who could see was motivated by his blind friend, and the blind man depended upon the connection he had to his friend’s hand. Our daughter knew the blind man could never finish the race alone. She was inspired by the trust of the blind man and the devoted love of his friend.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p27" pid="gS7-lG03y0e2wumdAwL1Dw" hash="7j3yNw">In like manner, the Savior has stretched forth His hand to each of us so that we don’t have to run alone. “To those [of us] who [occasionally] stagger or stumble, He is there to steady and strengthen” (<span class="emphasis">Trusting Jesus,</span> 43). As we advance toward the finish line, He will be there to save us; and for all this He gave His life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p28" pid="nUzbNXjlC02BPfwAvQwT2w" hash="HQFR0A">Imagine the wounds in His hands. His weathered hands, yes, even His hands of torn flesh and physical sacrifice, give our own hands greater power and direction.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p29" pid="zhKkpXrgE06NO5S4K8d6AQ" hash="LomzdQ">It is the wounded Christ who leads us through our moments of difficulty. It is He who bears us up when we need more air to breathe or direction to follow or even more courage to continue.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p30" pid="KbLS-AQc0kyazuE7c9RGJA" hash="x5V6fA">If we will keep the commandments of God and walk hand in hand with Him in His paths, we will go forward with faith and never feel alone.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p31" pid="BBi0uoMOlkCCLhQCIBG6xQ" hash="wNeE9w">Trust in His promise of eternal life, and allow peace and hope to distill upon you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p32" pid="jhZfF25X7UKF_X1LfMH52w" hash="ZCszaw">When we connect with the Author of Peace and with His perfect and redeeming love, then we can come to know the reality of the Lord’s promise: “I the Lord thy God will hold thy right hand, saying … , Fear not; I will help thee” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/41.13" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 41:13</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p33" pid="bgKssJuC9UClU3hhrIAZBQ" hash="9DK68w">I testify of Jesus Christ, our Redeemer and living Savior.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand.p34" pid="bg7lrVeI3Ey-HZ2mRGUoIQ" hash="cFjTzQ">I testify that He lives and extends His loving hand to each of us. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2003/10/the-lord-thy-god-will-hold-thy-hand</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2003-general-conference/2003-10-2050-elder-w-craig-zwick-64k-eng.mp3" length="6026736" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2003 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Will Not Yield, We Cannot Yield</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Live by your standards. Stand up for what you believe in.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00009475_000_034" doc-version="2" hash="3u2qXA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="uqMpz13lUkuwaEpXmByGBQ" hash="XU2rkA">We Will Not Yield, We Cannot Yield</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="OCnixpObwEiq0bRPQUUdCA" hash="AdIj5w">Elder W. Craig Zwick</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="EdgQ6-POak2vpisP281pvg" hash="siLWaA">Live by your standards. Stand up for what you believe in.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield.p1" pid="yD3qSciV_EGIUGo6Y8y9Qg" hash="ZHrj-Q">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="97"></span>With each of you, I gratefully sustain God’s will for His people. Thank you, President Monson, for the purity of your heart.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield.p2" pid="CXWlD6F3D0maSmMtUR7Omw" hash="AyNaUA">When young Joseph Smith told the truth about his sacred experience in the grove, he was persecuted and mistreated. The adversary used ridicule as a weapon against him. “I was an obscure boy, … yet men of high standing would take notice sufficient to excite the public mind against me, and create a bitter persecution.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield.p3" pid="FM40rLOyT0unuWECyAXULA" hash="t19R1Q">Joseph grew in patience, temperance, and faith, notwithstanding the presence of enemies on every front. In Joseph’s own words: “Evil and designing men have combined to destroy the innocent, … yet the glorious Gospel in its fullness is spreading.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> “No unhallowed hand can stop the work from progressing.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield.p4" pid="hQc86sZvXUWnwgNl5kpaHQ" hash="E7KqkA">Even today there are those who misunderstand our doctrine and challenge the unchanging values by which we are invited to live.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield.p5" pid="9Vo03IKUaUObjKfM-GEV3g" hash="wyiZeA">Ethan, a young friend of mine, approached his mother with a weighty question. Like most teenagers, Ethan wants to be independent, self-sufficient, and surrounded by good friends. He is trying to make good choices on his own. He is exceedingly valiant, works hard on his grades, and studies the scriptures daily. Like all young people, Ethan faces tremendous temptations. It comes in the halls of his school, on the Internet, in the movies and music. It can be heard in bad language and seen in provocative clothing. That which is wrong is often made to look right. Anxiety and fear of rejection are common among teenagers. Peer pressure is often overpowering. Ethan was feeling bombarded with opposing values.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield.p6" pid="JzXZBDwWH06pIdpFJBGkrQ" hash="iWV1Xw">This is the question he asked his mother: “Mom, do I need to lower my standards to keep my friends?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield.p7" pid="FsLlxcSYz0WvuExZjFtbcg" hash="dmFN2g">It is a profound question for each of us to consider at all stages of life. Are we lowering our standards to fit into our neighborhoods? Are we altering our values to suit the situation in <span class="pageBreak" page-number="98"></span>the workplace or to be popular at school?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield.p8" pid="NN_5ypD61UOImg9HdmwEUA" hash="TkxMSw">Ethan’s loving mother answered him with a resounding no.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield.p9" pid="P1Ie_o8AAkSNx1NnxPkGQA" hash="SjLvOQ">I, too, unequivocally answer, “Don’t do it, Ethan. Never forget that you are a son of God. He loves you. Live by your standards. Stand up for what you believe in. Sometimes it is not easy, and you may be standing alone for awhile. Look for friends with integrity and character, then go to them and express appreciation for their examples. You might even find someone who has been feeling as lonely as you. Pray for guidance and protection from the Lord. He will sustain you. He will become a trusted friend, and you will discover that your example will attract many friends who will take courage from your strength of character.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield.p10" pid="q4MheFs3uU2q9xcXobmpQw" hash="lNHWEw">Nephi taught us a powerfully simple principle in recounting his father’s dream of the tree of life. He described a strait and narrow path leading to a tree and a great and spacious building. This building was filled with people who were dressed in exceedingly fine and fashionable clothing. They were all in an attitude of mocking and pointing fingers toward those who were partaking of the fruit. They were trying to get people off the path and into the building. From all appearances, the people inside seemed to be having a great time. What an indelible image of temptation. In Elder Neal A. Maxwell’s words, “The laughter of the world is merely loneliness pathetically trying to reassure itself.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield.p11" pid="lFTGtPCKGke3N0o09iZqrg" hash="3B2yTw">“And great was the multitude that did enter into that strange building. … They did point the finger of scorn at me and those that were partaking of the fruit also; <span class="emphasis">but we heeded them not.”</span><span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield.p12" pid="Kty0fz8x-EC7RXV8SoRh3g" hash="EJL5jw">There at the end of the verse is Nephi’s powerful principle, an answer to unwanted peer pressure: “But we heeded them not.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield.p13" pid="QjhkfbsiN0KFvDueu7v6Fg" hash="cvGRLw">President Boyd K. Packer has recently emphasized this guiding principle: “However out of step we may seem, however much the standards are belittled, however much others yield, we will not yield, we cannot yield.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield.p14" pid="tXPQklGmakuv6LxCQBWfXA" hash="iUBqTQ">Do we recognize temptation when it is so well camouflaged?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield.p15" pid="DYiD83nZSU66uLRpb6DGww" hash="h0b-WA">Are we willing to fight the unpopular battle?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield.p16" pid="Hj7M1cHvAUeHuAhzjBDf1w" hash="AFU80Q">Paul clearly warned that we should not be “men-pleasers; but [be] the servants of Christ, doing the will of God from the heart.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield.p17" pid="myo-aJzLm024iVwetlPUAQ" hash="ej3Zng">The time has come when we must take an unyielding stand. We must shore up our spiritual underpinnings, listen to the prophets of God, and follow their counsel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield.p18" pid="zOZxIxIybUmWlVVx8w7LNA" hash="1Q268g">Said Paul to Timothy: “For God hath not given us the spirit of fear; but of power, and of love, and of a sound mind. Be not thou therefore ashamed of the testimony of our Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield.p19" pid="LcpETgcMQEe6CsWJoQp9Kw" hash="hOe-jg">It requires courage to make good choices, even when others around us choose differently. As we make righteous choices day by day in little things, the Lord will strengthen us and help us choose the right during more difficult times.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield.p20" pid="cxtY2MJYgkCGSScDREmAJg" hash="bd3dOQ">The teachings and values we cherish the most are not embraced by a secular world. To maintain a firm stance for ourselves and our children, the message of the restored gospel must be firmly planted in our hearts and taught in our homes.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield.p21" pid="MklY8cKwO0y7vixzkHN18A" hash="Cq4k-g">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="99"></span>Abinadi, a Nephite prophet, as recorded in just a few powerful pages in Mosiah, teaches us timeless lessons that perfectly meet the challenges of the 21st century.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield.p22" pid="k78FhZoH6Eqk10GmrWOAhw" hash="o6coMQ">Abinadi was a man of unwavering courage who stood for truth when it was unpopular to do so. As he courageously called the people to repentance, he knew his own life was in jeopardy. In your mind’s eye, you can see the riveting scene of Abinadi, who has just had the death sentence pronounced upon him. He had an opportunity to save himself by denying his faith and testimony, but instead he fearlessly proclaimed, “I say unto you, I will not recall the words which I have spoken unto you concerning this people, for they are true.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield.p23" pid="5nXQxcZIoEK88SMVPEtCPQ" hash="FVCyUw">We may not have to lose our lives in defense of truth, but we can, just like Abinadi, draw ourselves to full stature, and with full heart and energy, valiantly proclaiming that Jesus Christ is our Savior. He was and is the Son of the Almighty. He lives and He loves us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield.p24" pid="8XRE8OCwi0y0EevoYAv0Yg" hash="i6970Q">As we follow Him, we will be able to make sacrifices and keep our sacred covenants. The Lord has said to us: “Therefore, fear not, little flock; do good; let earth and hell combine against you, for if ye are built upon my rock, they cannot prevail. … Look unto me in every thought; doubt not, fear not.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield.p25" pid="6CLu1TLBwkSPgoQRQoDhhQ" hash="SoeZ2w">We must fortify ourselves. That sure spiritual fortification is found in two words—Jesus Christ. Of Him I humbly testify in the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2008/04/we-will-not-yield-we-cannot-yield</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2008-general-conference/2008-04-5030-elder-w-craig-zwick-64k-eng.mp3" length="4393559" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2008 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Are You Thinking?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking?lang=eng</link>
      <description>W. Craig Zwick encourages empathy for others and teaches that we must strive to understand what others are thinking.
		</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10985_000_28zwick" doc-version="3" hash="IO14eQ">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="3FVem6T-rkSVItT8HOfg7Q" hash="JeTD-g">What Are You Thinking?</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p" pid="2ZrgY0riZUGG0M4TVWquhA" hash="ZeTcrg">By Elder W. Craig Zwick</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p" pid="zJuCiZ1w_E2C__rX8wx_Qw" hash="sSmk3g">Of the Seventy</p>
		</div>
		<img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/leaders/w-craig-zwick.jpg" altText="Elder W. Craig Zwick" pid="kO1PXBHx5ku4etruLfIM0A" hash="aL_xwg" />
		<p class="kicker" pid="wsW3i0raCEKac-Z6kxQM3g" hash="F_kI3Q">I plead with you to practice asking this question, with tender regard for another’s experience: “What are you thinking?”</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="IevLoEQMJU2NkMVIIUp0hw" hash="ZeTcrg1">By Elder W. Craig Zwick</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock" pid="_cjKsR-xhUSgPA-7SsTt2w" hash="pf2_6A">
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p5" pid="sx0ehthOj0qIQrQLGdFLXQ" hash="izPn3g">Forty-one years ago I climbed into the driver’s seat of an 18-wheel semitruck with my beautiful wife, Jan, and our infant son, Scotty. We were taking a heavy load of construction materials across several states.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p6" pid="DA7yNyIQPEu-jAaIq9ga1g" hash="CaeYsA">In those days there were no seat-belt restrictions or infant car seats. My wife held our precious son in her arms. Her comment “We sure are high off the ground” should have given me a clue about her feelings of apprehension.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p7" pid="8txC3EqWSkKhi0nSvSJc5g" hash="5rIL8A">As we made our descent over historic Donner Pass, a steep section of highway, the cab of the semi suddenly and unexpectedly filled with thick smoke. It was difficult to see, and we could hardly breathe.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p8" pid="yzjvGFCkGE2sxFXlcqg1wg" hash="pHGTjg">With a heavy rig, brakes alone are not enough to rapidly decrease speed. Using the engine brakes and gearing down, I frantically attempted to stop.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p9" pid="4VZpNI6M30yoRCPjo_9-eA" hash="8DQcBg">Just as I was pulling to the side of the road, but before we had come to a full stop, my wife opened the door of the cab and jumped out with our baby in her arms. I watched helplessly as they tumbled in the dirt.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p10" pid="Y_f5rrOCAEq9GkKTnhnvMg" hash="HnFMhw">As soon as I had the semi stopped, I bolted from the smoking cab. With adrenaline pumping, I ran through the rocks and weeds and held them in my arms. Jan’s forearms and elbows were battered and bleeding, but thankfully she and our son were both breathing. I just held them close as the dust settled there on the side of the highway.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p11" pid="6vqTbk-jAEy0Nu5YigGk4w" hash="avM-DQ">As my heartbeat normalized and I caught my breath, I blurted out, “What in the world were you thinking? Do you know how dangerous that was? You could have been killed!”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p12" pid="PE5oGgeof0OJFLDGoiaqaA" hash="QCWLyQ">She looked back at me, with tears running down her smoke-smudged cheeks, and said something that pierced my heart and still rings in my ears: “I was just trying to save our son.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p13" pid="Kac5xLcZZkqQDunGf9E-Tw" hash="mhYiog">I realized in that moment she thought the engine was on fire, fearing the truck would explode and we would die. I, however, knew it was an electrical failure—hazardous but not fatal. I looked at my precious wife, softly rubbing the head of our infant son, and wondered what kind of woman would do something so courageous.</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p14" pid="TospFdbxckimDEI0fix5hA" hash="d5RHbw">This situation could have been as emotionally hazardous as our literal engine failure. Gratefully, after enduring the silent treatment for a <span class="pageBreak" page-number="42"></span>reasonable amount of time, each of us believing the other person was at fault, we finally expressed the emotions that were churning beneath our heated outbursts. Shared feelings of love and fear for the other’s safety kept the hazardous incident from proving fatal to our cherished marriage.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p15" pid="eZNn4BLJUkGhS7BPS_GjGg" hash="tD0Lmw">Paul warned, “Let no corrupt communication proceed out of your mouth, but [only] that which is good [and] edifying, that it may minister grace unto the hearers” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/4.29" class="scriptureRef">Ephesians 4:29</a>). His words resonate with a certain purity.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p16" pid="_RLFLPK2rUKW68_wNgryOQ" hash="z8foZA">What does the phrase “no corrupt communication” mean to you? We all regularly experience highly charged feelings of anger—our own and others’. We have seen unchecked anger erupt in public places. We have experienced it as a sort of emotional “electrical short” at sporting events, in the political arena, and even in our own homes.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p17" pid="NldvfnUwm0aVSFM7TaraiQ" hash="nkzJNw">Children sometimes speak to beloved parents with tongues as sharp as blades. Spouses, who have shared some of life’s richest and most tender experiences, lose vision and patience with each other and raise their voices. All of us, though covenant children of a loving Heavenly Father, have regretted jumping headlong from the high seat of self-righteous judgment and have spoken with abrasive words before we understood a situation from another’s perspective. We have all had the opportunity to learn how destructive words can take a situation from hazardous to fatal.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p18" pid="RCbpvCLJM0CpqJbk5ZjP7A" hash="B9VQUA">A recent letter from the First Presidency states clearly, “The gospel of Jesus Christ teaches us to love and treat all people with kindness and civility—even when we disagree” (First Presidency letter, Jan. 10, 2014). What a masterful reminder that we can and should participate in continuing civil dialogue, especially when we view the world from differing perspectives.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p19" pid="NgfBYroQLU-DVtyXph_vzg" hash="Ny4otQ">The writer of Proverbs counsels, “A soft answer turneth away wrath: but grievous words stir up anger” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/prov/15.1" class="scriptureRef">Proverbs 15:1</a>). A “soft answer” consists of a reasoned response—disciplined words from a humble heart. It does not mean we never speak directly or that we compromise doctrinal truth. Words that may be firm in information can be soft in spirit.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p20" pid="eyjjONmTxUSWq2r1BWQMmg" hash="SBRAxw">The Book of Mormon contains a striking example of affirming language also given in the context of a marital disagreement. The sons of Sariah and Lehi had been sent back to Jerusalem to get the brass plates and had not returned. Sariah believed her sons were in harm’s way, and she was filled with anger and needed someone to blame.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p21" pid="73Somh4efkSzAGuKKx0MTg" hash="9O2Bgw">Listen to the story through the eyes of her son Nephi: “For [my mother] had supposed that we had perished in the wilderness; and she also had complained against my father, telling him that he was a visionary man; saying: Behold thou hast led us forth from the land of our inheritance, and my sons are no more, and we perish in the wilderness” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/5.2" class="scriptureRef">1 Nephi 5:2</a>).</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p22" pid="KCGdS6J59U6X_dHFJ_ME_A" hash="DGhTXA">Now, let’s consider what Sariah may have been thinking. She was filled with anxiety about her quarrelsome sons returning to the place where her husband’s life had been threatened. She had traded her lovely home and friends for a tent in an isolated wilderness while still in her childbearing years. Pushed to the breaking point <span class="pageBreak" page-number="43"></span>of her fears, Sariah seems to have jumped heroically, if not rationally, from the height of a hurtling truck in an attempt to protect her family. She expressed legitimate concerns to her husband in the language of anger and doubt and blame—a language in which the entire human race seems to be surprisingly proficient.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p23" pid="mRbDsrCLikCiz0xaHWb2wQ" hash="OSnd8w">The prophet Lehi listened to the fear that underpinned his wife’s anger. Then he made a disciplined response in the language of compassion. First, he owned the truth of what things looked like from her perspective: “And … my father spake unto her, saying: I know that I am a visionary man; … but [if I] had tarried at Jerusalem, [we would have] perished with my brethren” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/5.4" class="scriptureRef">1 Nephi 5:4</a>).</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p24" pid="zJmPzT18_Ua5WHOrQ0McYQ" hash="niPdMg">Then her husband addressed her fears concerning the welfare of their sons, as the Holy Ghost undoubtedly testified to him, saying:</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p25" pid="GkVVCHlc_kSnNrxFZlticQ" hash="FMLeFQ">“But behold, I have obtained a land of promise, in the which things I do rejoice; yea, and I know that the Lord will deliver my sons out of the hands of Laban. …</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p26" pid="A9jxhPlzxUqn1NvXotIjzg" hash="SeBlIA">“And after this manner of language did my father, Lehi, comfort my mother … concerning us” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/5.5-6" class="scriptureRef">1 Nephi 5:5–6</a>).</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p27" pid="z7ExdCuUM0u6IwMA8kGf4g" hash="vxZbxg">There exists today a great need for men and women to cultivate respect for each other across wide distances of belief and behavior and across deep canyons of conflicting agendas. It is impossible to know all that informs our minds and hearts or even to fully understand the context for the trials and choices we each face.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p28" pid="H_XCE5IYi0uvLHyybDm83A" hash="63Q92g">Nevertheless, what would happen to the “corrupt communication” Paul spoke about if our own position included empathy for another’s experience first? Fully owning the limits of my own imperfections and rough edges, I plead with you to practice asking this question, with tender regard for another’s experience: “What are you thinking?”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p29" pid="hiXYLIJLuUq9ItgpZ8X0Qw" hash="xNUqAQ">Remember when the Lord surprised Samuel and Saul by choosing a little shepherd boy, David of Bethlehem, as king of Israel? The Lord told His prophet, “For the Lord seeth not as man seeth; for man looketh on the outward appearance, but the Lord looketh on the heart” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/1-sam/16.7" class="scriptureRef">1 Samuel 16:7</a>).</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p30" pid="6vBV6z-pL0y8MwvfDzoaZA" hash="bVZosg">When our truck cab filled with smoke, my wife acted in the bravest manner she could imagine to protect our son. I too acted as a protector when I questioned her choice. Shockingly, it did not matter who was more right. What mattered was listening to each other and understanding the other’s perspective.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p31" pid="M-7cEoDmAEiW8VBpluOAHw" hash="9TU5CQ">The willingness to see through each other’s eyes will transform “corrupt communication” into “minister[ing] grace.” The Apostle Paul understood this, and on some level each of us can experience it too. It may not change or solve the problem, but the more important possibility may be whether ministering grace could change us.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking.p32" pid="d7YxjzP4WUK65pff9OIZow" hash="Oel14w">I bear humble witness that we can “minister grace” through compassionate language when the cultivated gift of the Holy Ghost pierces our hearts with empathy for the feelings and context of others. It enables us to transform hazardous situations into holy places. I testify of a loving Savior who “looketh on [our] heart” and cares what we are thinking. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2014/04/what-are-you-thinking</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2014-general-conference/2014-04-2080-elder-w-craig-zwick-64k-eng.mp3" length="5200988" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2014 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
