<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By W. Christopher Waddell</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by W. Christopher Waddell.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/W.%20Christopher%20Waddell.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by W. Christopher Waddell.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>The Opportunity of a Lifetime</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Through your devoted service and willing sacrifice, your mission will become holy ground to you.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50029123_000_3030" doc-version="2" hash="0okAGw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="cLQlz00Ah0qSI4KPxH9YfA" hash="whc8xA">The Opportunity of a Lifetime</h1><p class="authorName" guid="039f76fb-42d6-45af-9cf6-77732a459481" pid="MV1yGFit9kmD2O-909e_eQ" hash="GR7T3w">W. Christopher Waddell</p><p class="kicker" pid="vwtdzQ7Ei0WkFbKVy3WTDw" hash="HqfBNQ">Through your devoted service and willing sacrifice, your mission will become holy ground to you.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="a8b43bd6-c19f-450a-9da5-7d2030cdd8cd">
		<div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime.t1">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime.p1" guid="828e3b84-99b6-4fc8-9490-9612f225d4ab" pid="oQkKZOIsF0imPEUJXUKa7A" hash="JcSMsA">
				<span class="pageBreak" page-number="50"></span>A milestone in the life of a missionary is his or her final, or “exit,” interview with the mission president. At the heart of the interview will be a discussion of what seems to be a lifetime of memorable experiences and key lessons that have been gained in just 18 to 24 months.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime.p2" guid="e89bca3d-d1ce-411f-9c56-4c2e007d46ac" pid="Qy4YEV4lQkWigzyhI6Xz5A" hash="OW80Yg">While many of these experiences and lessons may be common to missionary service, each mission is unique, with challenges and opportunities that stretch and test us according to our particular needs and personalities.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime.p3" guid="dc1e6063-7daf-4cde-8d41-edbce2966e74" pid="eIwNu1pMMkW1f7EB48CSUQ" hash="Ya2wug">Long before leaving our earthly home to serve a full-time mission, we left heavenly parents to fulfill our mortal mission. We have a Father in Heaven, who knows us—our strengths and weaknesses, our abilities and potential. He knows which mission president and companions and which members and investigators we need in order to become the missionary, the husband and father, and the priesthood holder we are capable of becoming.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime.p4" guid="8fb0a078-ad82-4f52-bbee-f47d6b5ac5c9" pid="4x-ixnaxMkSKs_p6n7r2Fg" hash="xOjeUQ">Prophets, seers, and revelators assign missionaries under the direction and influence of the Holy Ghost. Inspired mission presidents direct transfers every six weeks and quickly learn that the Lord knows exactly where He wants each missionary to serve.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime.p5" guid="d3256627-30f8-45f0-b3b7-7e69b2185fe4" pid="CUfsGumGCEWkE5sdKAB32w" hash="_a6lHA">A few years ago, Elder Javier Misiego, from Madrid, Spain, was serving a full-time mission in Arizona. At that time, his mission call to the United States appeared somewhat unusual, as most young men from Spain were being called to serve in their own country.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime.p6" guid="94f35b73-4641-4a8c-8423-d76fd890db03" pid="r9WGpiXrLUWtdcuqke6bBQ" hash="1IpKsA">At the conclusion of a stake fireside, where he and his companion had been invited to participate, Elder Misiego was approached by a less-active member of the Church who had been brought by a friend. It was the first time this man had been inside a chapel in years. Elder Misiego was asked if he might know a José Misiego in Madrid. When Elder Misiego responded that his father’s name was José Misiego, the man excitedly asked a few more questions to confirm that this was <span class="emphasis">the</span> José Misiego. When it was determined that they were speaking about the same man, this less-active member began to weep. “Your father was the only person I baptized during my entire mission,” he explained and described how his mission had been, in his mind, a failure. He attributed his years of inactivity to some feelings of inadequacy and concern, believing that he had somehow let the Lord down.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime.p7" guid="61bee718-7b42-4c42-bdf6-2054598fea88" pid="qhZdEGGQEEWQ96dT0TZK2Q" hash="PdqH-g">Elder Misiego then described what this supposed failure of a missionary meant to his family. He told him that his father, baptized as a young single adult, had married in the temple, that Elder Misiego was the fourth of six children, that all three boys and a sister had served full-time missions, that all were active in the Church, and that all who were married had been sealed in the temple.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime.p8" guid="80f6c747-f293-4654-81bc-1fdb047a2f91" pid="p9iJ2LVJ60yM1IpsJc_Khw" hash="wIAaLA">The less-active returned missionary began to sob. Through his efforts, he now learned, scores of lives had been blessed, and the Lord had sent an elder from Madrid, Spain, all the way to a fireside in Arizona to let him know that he had not been a failure. The Lord knows where He wants each missionary to serve.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime.p9" guid="7f3bea8f-9f5f-4da6-adfe-fc66abb5d83a" pid="jIVVTw-BXEWP0v1-03JUgw" hash="pr0RvA">In whatever manner the Lord may choose to bless us during the course of a mission, blessings of missionary service are not designed to end when we are released by our stake president. Your mission is a training ground for life. The experiences, lessons, and testimony obtained through faithful service are meant to provide a gospel-centered foundation that will last throughout mortality and into the eternities. However, for the blessings to continue after the mission, there are conditions that must be met. In the Doctrine and Covenants we read, “For all who will have a blessing at my hands shall abide the law which was appointed for that blessing, and the conditions thereof” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/132.5" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 132:5</a>). This principle is taught in the story of the Exodus.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime.p10" guid="4f28a37a-3427-4a51-b8fd-7a497cac680e" pid="dlcUa6uzBUa3oFtum1OlCg" hash="PRfPEw">After receiving his commission from the Lord, Moses returned to Egypt to lead the children of Israel out of captivity. Plague after plague failed to <span class="pageBreak" page-number="51"></span>secure their freedom, leading to the 10th and final plague: “For I will pass through the land of Egypt this night, and will smite all the firstborn in the land of Egypt” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/12.12" class="scriptureRef">Exodus 12:12</a>).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime.p11" guid="a37889f7-c878-4747-88a3-0aba13211d6a" pid="uJ2icrsjC06aBMW4jTN_fg" hash="A56s4A">For protection against “the destroyer” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/12.23" class="scriptureRef">verse 23</a>), the Lord instructed His people to offer a sacrifice, a lamb “without blemish” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/12.5" class="scriptureRef">verse 5</a>), and to collect the blood from the sacrifice. They were then to “take of the blood” and apply it to the entrance of each home—“the two side posts and … the upper door post” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/12.7" class="scriptureRef">verse 7</a>)—with this promise: “And when I see the blood, I will pass over you, and the plague shall not be upon you to destroy you” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/12.13" class="scriptureRef">verse 13</a>).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime.p12" guid="df94fd81-b13e-4ff7-b640-5573b7cbf6a4" pid="SZol6w3LJUK2oNIyKCvYXQ" hash="nxKdoQ">“The children of Israel went away, and did as the Lord had commanded” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/12.28" class="scriptureRef">verse 28</a>). They offered the sacrifice, collected the blood, and applied it to their homes. “And it came to pass, that at midnight the Lord smote all the firstborn in the land of Egypt” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ex/12.29" class="scriptureRef">verse 29</a>). Moses and his people, according to the promise of the Lord, were protected.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime.p13" guid="46b0be93-db6e-4e9f-be40-b56fe23c9f45" pid="IGnyFABNMUOGew6uKkef_A" hash="BVSL0A">The blood used by the Israelites, symbolic of the Savior’s future Atonement, was a product of the sacrifice they had offered. Nevertheless, the sacrifice and the blood alone would not have been sufficient to obtain the promised blessing. <span class="emphasis">Without the application of the blood to the door posts, the sacrifice would have been in vain.</span>
			</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime.p14" guid="7e853d18-28c9-482f-8d38-d6da0432c109" pid="Tr0wTwUGUkWNIv04xjOLYQ" hash="iAeBAw">President Thomas S. Monson has taught: “Missionary work is difficult. It taxes one’s energies, it strains one’s capacity, it demands one’s best effort. … No other labor requires longer hours or greater devotion or such sacrifice and fervent prayer” (“That All May Hear,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1995, 49).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime.p15" guid="606142b9-9c5b-416e-b390-0484b7d1c49d" pid="ya5rYxAmvUK3JNloWXbxjw" hash="aY7q5w">As a result of that sacrifice, we return from our missions with our own gifts: The gift of faith. The gift of testimony. The gift of understanding the role of the Spirit. The gift of daily gospel study. The gift of having served our Savior. Gifts carefully packaged in worn scriptures, tattered copies of <span class="emphasis">Preach My Gospel,</span> missionary journals, and grateful hearts. However, as with the children of Israel, the ongoing blessings associated with missionary service require application after the sacrifice.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime.p16" guid="7c664af9-669e-412c-8567-6d556e1e1049" pid="tpZdxhnjEUWcN8wKu6zxtQ" hash="C-AqxQ">A few years ago, while Sister Waddell and I presided over the Spain Barcelona Mission, I would extend one last assignment to each missionary during their final interview. As they returned home, they were asked to immediately take time to consider the lessons and gifts provided to them by a generous Father in Heaven. They were asked to prayerfully list and consider how to best apply those lessons in post-mission life—lessons that would impact every facet of their lives: education and career choice, marriage and children, future Church service, and most important, who they would continue to become and their continued development as disciples of Jesus Christ.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime.p17" guid="f1a96767-69f5-40ab-8323-3e86bd352632" pid="WIDtGNAB_ECDmjfksBVpQQ" hash="PU9nNw">There is no returned missionary for whom it is too late to consider the lessons obtained through faithful service and to apply them more diligently. As we do so, we will feel the influence of the Spirit more fully in our <span class="pageBreak" page-number="52"></span>lives, our families will be strengthened, and we will draw closer to our Savior and Father in Heaven. In a previous general conference, Elder L. Tom Perry extended this invitation: “I call on you returned missionaries to rededicate yourselves, to become reinfused with the desire and spirit of missionary service. I call on you to look the part, to be the part, and to act the part of a servant of our Father in Heaven. … I want to promise you there are great blessings in store for you if you continue to press forward with the zeal you once possessed as a full-time missionary” (“The Returned Missionary,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona,</span> Jan. 2002, 88, 89; <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 2001, 77).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime.p18" guid="84a71c09-03c0-4c4b-baab-f9c56dfc4be1" pid="v9KkDnJlUkSL4RwVKaPjxg" hash="QVioKQ">Now, to the young men who have yet to serve a full-time mission, I share President Monson’s counsel from last October: “I repeat what prophets have long taught—that every worthy, able young man should prepare to serve a mission. Missionary service is a priesthood duty—an obligation the Lord expects of us who have been given so very much” (“As We Meet Together Again,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 2010, 5–6).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime.p19" guid="e67e994f-7c32-445a-92c3-070697af579f" pid="y9Np0g4Y4UGmZy3XEQGqXg" hash="KTgDrA">Just as with missionaries past and present, the Lord knows you and has a mission experience prepared for you. He knows your mission president and his wonderful wife, who will love you as their own children and who will seek inspiration and direction on your behalf. He knows each of your companions and what you will learn from them. He knows each area in which you will labor, the members you will meet, the people you will teach, and the lives you will impact for eternity.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime.p20" guid="aeac8f5f-ed75-476c-ae9d-8a9038b50597" pid="OoS0o1ITiEmXghhi7suHZA" hash="hQdomg">Through your devoted service and willing sacrifice, your mission will become holy ground to you. You will witness the miracle of conversion as the Spirit works through you to touch the hearts of those you teach.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime.p21" guid="fd4f4bbd-f053-4c70-9e6e-ded1e68f7344" pid="HDG0YmM2GUiWOux5v0Efnw" hash="IaeMbA">As you prepare to serve, there is much to do. Becoming an effective servant of the Lord will require more than being set apart, putting on a name tag, or entering a missionary training center. It is a process that begins long before you are referred to as “Elder.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime.p22" guid="1bea13a1-f1aa-48f3-87dd-67731d326206" pid="q2M64UJXlUqgrb-ytrtKHg" hash="BIesEg"><span class="strong">Arrive on your mission with your own testimony of the Book of Mormon,</span> obtained through study and prayer. “The Book of Mormon is powerful evidence of the divinity of Christ. It is also proof of the Restoration through the Prophet Joseph Smith. … As a missionary, you must first have a personal testimony that the Book of Mormon is true. … This witness of the Holy Ghost [will become] a central focus of your teaching” (<span class="emphasis">Preach My Gospel: A Guide to Missionary Service</span> [2004], 103).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime.p23" guid="7f750761-d069-490d-91cd-8eb37e3d13f9" pid="74nn137GKUyZKHBhWK4nSA" hash="mwJdQw"><span class="strong">Arrive on your mission worthy of the companionship of the Holy Ghost.</span> In the words of President Ezra Taft Benson: “The Spirit is the most important single element in this work. With the Spirit magnifying your call, you can do miracles for the Lord in the mission field. Without the Spirit, you will never succeed <span class="emphasis">regardless</span> of your talent and ability” (in <span class="emphasis">Preach My Gospel,</span> 176).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime.p24" guid="34c1fc04-6575-4429-9dac-47c2c1b4f103" pid="Hgxgttrgnki6Zwdhj_ksOA" hash="Sir07A"><span class="strong">Arrive on your mission ready to work.</span> “Your success as a missionary [will be] measured primarily by your commitment to find, teach, baptize, and confirm.” You will be expected to “work effectively every day, [doing] your … best to bring souls to Christ” (<span class="emphasis">Preach My Gospel,</span> 10, 11).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime.p25" guid="55cba7cc-7d91-4fe9-b9aa-3dad364e7715" pid="QfOWvp8V50Wqj-iEiq4n_A" hash="LE_j0Q">I repeat Elder M. Russell Ballard’s invitation, given to a previous group of young men preparing to serve: “We look to you, my young brethren of the Aaronic Priesthood. We need you. Like Helaman’s 2,000 stripling warriors, you also are the spirit sons of God, and you too can be endowed with power to build up and defend His kingdom. We need you to make sacred covenants, just as they did. We need you to be meticulously obedient and faithful, just as they were” (“The Greatest Generation of Missionaries,” <span class="emphasis">Liahona</span> and <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 2002, 47).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime.p26" guid="217f6f70-13c0-41f2-9874-a128cccdad2c" pid="30CbQnjT00aWzLWVo3K37Q" hash="7dkEKg">As you accept this invitation, you will learn a great lesson, as did Elder Misiego and all who have faithfully served, returned, and applied. You will learn that the words of our prophet, President Thomas S. Monson, are true: “The missionary opportunity of a lifetime is yours. The blessings of eternity await you. Yours is the privilege to be not spectators but participants on the stage of priesthood service” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1995, 49). I testify that this is true in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
		</div>
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2011/10/the-opportunity-of-a-lifetime</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2011-general-conference/2011-10-3030-elder-w-christopher-waddell-64k-eng.mp3" length="5379179" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Pattern for Peace</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace?lang=eng</link>
      <description>&lt;div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_13285_000_53waddell" doc-version="3" hash="Y3pvsA"&gt;
	
	&lt;div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.head1"&gt;
		&lt;h1 class="title" pid="EmKigZNO7EqZFrSdRvo9vA" hash="tOR3lA"&gt;A Pattern for Peace&lt;/h1&gt;
		&lt;div class="byline"&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p2" pid="YwAP9_wyFEOHhGXZf0kAhA" hash="q_ZIxA1"&gt;By Bishop W. Christopher Waddell&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p3" pid="hlEGuBSMRUGgONg0kX2fWg" hash="9-VD6g"&gt;Second Counselor in the Presiding Bishopric&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=gUe94_PD5keoJUmKW91deg"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" altText="Bishop W. Christopher Waddell" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255593/02187b3cb3f740258d60939b64c0c0d3/100x139.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x69="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255593/02187b3cb3f740258d60939b64c0c0d3/50x69.jpg" data-src-100x139="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255593/02187b3cb3f740258d60939b64c0c0d3/100x139.jpg" data-src-200x279="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255593/02187b3cb3f740258d60939b64c0c0d3/200x279.jpg" data-src-320x447="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255593/02187b3cb3f740258d60939b64c0c0d3/320x447.jpg" data-src-460x643="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255593/02187b3cb3f740258d60939b64c0c0d3/460x643.jpg" data-src-640x895="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255593/02187b3cb3f740258d60939b64c0c0d3/640x895.jpg" data-src-1024x1432="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255593/02187b3cb3f740258d60939b64c0c0d3/1024x1432.jpg" data-src-2048x2864="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255593/02187b3cb3f740258d60939b64c0c0d3/2048x2864.jpg" data-src-3550x4965="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1255593/02187b3cb3f740258d60939b64c0c0d3/3550x4965.jpg" webURL="w-christopher-waddell-first-quorum-seventy_1255593.jpg" pid="gUe94_PD5keoJUmKW91deg" hash="AAAAAA"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;p class="kicker" pid="hMAyEg-3tEeOv6d_JNTGzA" hash="j7YNjw"&gt;The peace we all seek requires us to act—by learning of Jesus Christ, by listening to His words, and by walking with Him.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="authorName" pid="sZxQZI00VEOlReCnoK9ZpA" hash="q_ZIxA"&gt;By Bishop W. Christopher Waddell&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class="bodyBlock"&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p5" pid="XO_iaSdpRU6986_r7OmE1A" hash="ho9pZQ"&gt;A few years ago, our daughter and son-in-law were asked to team teach a Primary class of five active four-year-old little boys. Our daughter was the designated teacher and our son-in-law the designated enforcer, doing their best to maintain a sense of calm amidst occasional chaos in order to teach gospel principles to the children.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p6" pid="-ElWgvwa6UidIS7zokVsbA" hash="VDXnYw"&gt;During one especially rough class, after a number of warnings to an energetic little boy, our son-in-law escorted the four-year-old out of the classroom. Once outside the room, and about to talk to the little boy about his behavior and the need to find his parents, the little boy stopped our son-in-law before he could say a word and, with his hand up in the air, and with great emotion, blurted out, “Sometimes—sometimes—it’s just hard for me to think about Jesus!”&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p7" pid="MN4qRDGLJke28LRLGd4kDA" hash="LpoIAg"&gt;In our journey through mortality, as glorious as our intended destination may be and as exhilarating as the journey may prove, we will all be subject to trials and sorrow along the way. Elder Joseph B. Wirthlin taught: “The dial on the wheel of sorrow eventually points to each of us. At one time or another, everyone must experience sorrow. No one is exempt.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; “The Lord in His wisdom does not shield anyone from grief or sadness.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; However, our ability to travel this road in peace is, in large part, dependent on whether or not we too have a hard time thinking about Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p8" pid="emOyIRcQwk2QABobNg-tkA" hash="Ud0cbw"&gt;Peace of mind, peace of conscience, and peace of heart are not determined by our ability to avoid trials, sorrow, or heartache. Despite our sincere pleas, not every storm will change course, not every infirmity will be healed, and we may not fully understand every doctrine, principle, or practice taught by prophets, seers, and revelators. Nevertheless, we have been promised peace—with a condition attached.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p9" pid="-fnpHQAuxUqZmNPGB4Z4dA" hash="aAOOow"&gt;In the Gospel of John, the Savior taught that despite the tribulations of life, we can be of good cheer, we can be of good hope, and we need not fear, because He declared, “&lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;In me&lt;/span&gt; ye might have peace.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt; Faith in Jesus Christ and His atoning sacrifice is, and forever will be, the first principle of the gospel and the foundation upon which our hope for “peace in this world, and eternal life in the world to come” is built.&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4"&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p10" pid="F4sK9oWY8Ei8MQELGPi1Ag" hash="uu7jAA"&gt;In our search for peace amidst the daily challenges of life, we’ve been given a simple pattern to keep our thoughts focused on the Savior, who said: “Learn of me, and listen to my words; walk in the meekness of my Spirit, and you shall have peace in me. I am Jesus Christ.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p11" pid="wtjsA8Vt-kaykr4J-UY-hg" hash="mjwBMA"&gt;Learn, listen, and walk—three steps with a promise.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.t1"&gt;
			&lt;h2 pid="4gEvRSmFKkCdBqqX9Pyx3w" hash="_c27HA"&gt;First Step: “Learn of Me”&lt;/h2&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p13" pid="KnBVgfuQKke3BbIqcKBmnw" hash="eubTJA"&gt;In Isaiah we read, “And many people shall go and say, Come ye, and let us go up to the mountain of the Lord, to the house of the God of Jacob; and he will teach us of his ways.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6"&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p14" pid="K63tqv2c9kOMiYlRhFi-NA" hash="DidxOg"&gt;In the ever-increasing number of temples dotting the earth, we learn of Jesus Christ and His role in the Father’s plan as the Creator of this world, as our Savior and Redeemer, and as the source of our peace.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p15" pid="OaaE9NABzkqOmhS6SQb6hQ" hash="VpxG4g"&gt;President Thomas S. Monson has taught: “The world can be a challenging and difficult place in which to live. … As you and I go to the holy houses of God, as we remember the covenants we make within, we will be more able to bear every trial and to overcome each temptation. In this sacred sanctuary we will find peace.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7"&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p16" pid="7X_rOwJC-Em7ELjILw_S1A" hash="-Gcauw"&gt;During a stake conference assignment a few years ago while serving in South America, I met a couple that was grieving the recent death of their infant son.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p17" pid="R0O7jWQX3UiuAl8nDf_AvQ" hash="H1KHXg"&gt;It was in an interview during the course of the conference that I first met with Brother Tumiri and learned of his loss. As we spoke, he shared that not only was he deeply saddened by the death of his son, but he was also devastated at the thought of never seeing him again. He explained that as relatively new members of the Church, they had saved enough money to attend the temple just one time, prior to the birth of their little boy, where they had been sealed as a couple and had their two daughters sealed to them. He then described how they had been saving money for a return trip to the temple but hadn’t yet been able to take their little boy in order to be sealed to him as well.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p18" pid="1Y0A4FPEKk-HyjLrgwZBkA" hash="1x-NDg"&gt;Recognizing a possible misunderstanding, I explained that he would indeed see his son again, if he remained faithful, because the sealing ordinance that had bound him to his wife and daughters was also sufficient to bind him to his son, who had been born in the covenant.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p19" pid="lWArFdMmTE2D9t9noc81SA" hash="Cp3LGw"&gt;Amazed, he asked if this was really true, and when I confirmed that it was, he then asked if I would be willing to speak with his wife, who had been inconsolable during the two weeks since their son’s death.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p20" pid="rAxXx3YXgUOApOwcl95bfw" hash="Xzqi7w"&gt;Sunday afternoon, following the conference, I met with Sister Tumiri and explained this glorious doctrine to her as well. With the pain of her loss still fresh, but now with a glimmer of hope, she tearfully asked, “Will I really be able to hold my little boy in my arms again? Is he really mine forever?” I assured her that as she kept her covenants, the sealing power found in the temple, effective because of the authority of Jesus Christ, would indeed allow her to be with her son again and hold him in her arms.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p21" pid="xqa_aHBDpE-_1THKh_eL8w" hash="4GZiIg"&gt;Sister Tumiri, though heartbroken by the death of her son, left our meeting with tears of gratitude and filled with peace because of the sacred ordinances of the temple, made possible by our Savior and Redeemer.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p22" pid="nGsZy2_uAkmgjq_Srdnk5A" hash="b_YYOw"&gt;Each time we attend the temple—in all that we hear, do, and say; in every ordinance in which we participate; and in every covenant that we make—we are pointed to Jesus Christ. We feel peace as we hear His words and learn from His example. President Gordon B. Hinckley taught, “Go to the house of the Lord and there feel of His Spirit and commune with Him and you will know a peace that you will find nowhere else.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8"&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.t2"&gt;
			&lt;h2 pid="dyOtAngibUOXkF8ADA5TVQ" hash="vXKLzQ"&gt;Second Step: “Listen to My Words”&lt;/h2&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p24" pid="kQMD6zQc_UWF_IE5ZLq5Kg" hash="lBu9tg"&gt;In the Doctrine and Covenants we read, “Whether by mine own voice or by the voice of my servants, it is the same.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9"&gt;9&lt;/span&gt; From the days of Adam and down through the ages to our current prophet, Thomas Spencer Monson, the Lord has spoken through His authorized representatives. Those who choose to listen and give heed to the words of the Lord, as delivered through His prophets, will find safety and peace.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p25" pid="_nrE0oV4MEOZw2DiMjBE9g" hash="pceeqw"&gt;In the Book of Mormon we find many examples of the importance of following prophetic counsel and standing with the prophet, including a lesson learned from Lehi’s vision of the tree of life, found in &lt;a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/8" class="scriptureRef"&gt;1 Nephi chapter 8&lt;/a&gt;. Never has the great and spacious building been more crowded or the noise coming from its open windows more misguided, mocking, and confusing than in our day. In this passage we read of two groups of people and their responses to the shouts from the building.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=HbVzAGgRJk2jB9AKYH2t6Q"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709254/fc7f72bb952b48238e7b63489f5ca50e/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709254/fc7f72bb952b48238e7b63489f5ca50e/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709254/fc7f72bb952b48238e7b63489f5ca50e/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709254/fc7f72bb952b48238e7b63489f5ca50e/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709254/fc7f72bb952b48238e7b63489f5ca50e/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709254/fc7f72bb952b48238e7b63489f5ca50e/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709254/fc7f72bb952b48238e7b63489f5ca50e/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709254/fc7f72bb952b48238e7b63489f5ca50e/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709254/fc7f72bb952b48238e7b63489f5ca50e/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709254/fc7f72bb952b48238e7b63489f5ca50e/2790x1800.jpg" altText="Lehi’s dream" pid="HbVzAGgRJk2jB9AKYH2t6Q" hash="QueV1g"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p26" pid="swP3LF0RV0-J-qTJ1scFMA" hash="N6IH4Q"&gt;Beginning in &lt;a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/8.26" class="scriptureRef"&gt;verse 26&lt;/a&gt;, we read:&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p27" pid="9AuIa70S-k-zviqJyYEJUg" hash="o-4PLQ"&gt;“And I also cast my eyes round about, and beheld, on the other side of the river of water, a great and spacious building. …&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p28" pid="AX3z1vrVt0eFQnYuX6A-Jg" hash="r_uX0g"&gt;“And it was filled with people, … and they were in the attitude of mocking and pointing their fingers towards those who had come … and were partaking of the fruit.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p29" pid="jt01N7SjN0yDK9DYLXiFPw" hash="XCwXvw"&gt;“And after they had &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;tasted&lt;/span&gt; of the fruit they were ashamed, because of those that were scoffing at them; and they fell away into forbidden paths and were lost.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p30" pid="JExsPq-e20KbS0nVFilFkA" hash="w8H3Fg"&gt;In &lt;a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/8.33" class="scriptureRef"&gt;verse 33&lt;/a&gt; we read of others who had a different response to the scoffing and mocking coming from the building. The prophet Lehi explains that those in the building “did point the finger of scorn at me and those that were &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;partaking&lt;/span&gt; of the fruit also; but we heeded them not.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11"&gt;11&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p31" pid="EhbZJbudL0iy62PXJEraOQ" hash="l0wEYg"&gt;A key difference between those who were ashamed, fell away, and were lost and those who did not heed the mocking from the building and stood with the prophet is found in two phrases: first, “after they had &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;tasted,&lt;/span&gt;” and second, “those that were &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;partaking.&lt;/span&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p32" pid="l1pRc_s8OE2NgW7sqpuF1A" hash="1KD4bw"&gt;The first group had arrived at the tree, stood for a time with the prophet, but only &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;tasted&lt;/span&gt; the fruit. By not continuing to eat, they allowed the taunting from the building to affect them, drawing them away from the prophet and into forbidden paths, where they were lost.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p33" pid="keOw-8VC4k-b_uemMs9xeg" hash="A7WDZA"&gt;In contrast to those who tasted and wandered off were those who were found continuously &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;partaking&lt;/span&gt; of the fruit. These individuals ignored the commotion from the building, stood by the prophet, and enjoyed the accompanying safety and peace. Our commitment to the Lord and His servants cannot be a part-time commitment. If so, we leave ourselves vulnerable to those who seek to destroy our peace. As we listen to the Lord through His authorized servants, we stand in holy places and cannot be moved.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p34" pid="6sXawFly_UquCwyicczpbA" hash="QCBSsg"&gt;The adversary offers counterfeit solutions that may appear to provide answers but take us even further from the peace we seek. He offers a mirage that has the appearance of legitimacy and safety but ultimately, like the great and spacious building, will collapse, destroying all who seek peace within its walls.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p35" pid="8tyP3kcUb0ubCTywiSQDgg" hash="f9r30Q"&gt;Truth is found in the simplicity of a Primary song: “Words of a prophet: Keep the commandments. In this there is &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;safety&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;peace.&lt;/span&gt;”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12"&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.t3"&gt;
			&lt;h2 pid="FTWXNWaiYkapRjis9OGWuQ" hash="mnkD3w"&gt;Third Step: “Walk in the Meekness of My Spirit”&lt;/h2&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p37" pid="nIK-gvOb1UGxm1t5cW8SRg" hash="YZFncw"&gt;However far we may wander from the path, the Savior invites us to return and walk with Him. This invitation to walk with Jesus Christ is an invitation to accompany Him to Gethsemane and from Gethsemane to Calvary and from Calvary to the Garden Tomb. It is an invitation to observe and apply His great atoning sacrifice, whose reach is as individual as it is infinite. It is an invitation to repent, to draw upon His cleansing power, and to grasp His loving, outstretched arms. It is an invitation to be at peace.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=qIKvszdqqEKPyiCI_XpG1g"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709255/8efa8d7a6e654e9a984dc3bd4d72e4c6/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709255/8efa8d7a6e654e9a984dc3bd4d72e4c6/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709255/8efa8d7a6e654e9a984dc3bd4d72e4c6/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709255/8efa8d7a6e654e9a984dc3bd4d72e4c6/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709255/8efa8d7a6e654e9a984dc3bd4d72e4c6/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709255/8efa8d7a6e654e9a984dc3bd4d72e4c6/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709255/8efa8d7a6e654e9a984dc3bd4d72e4c6/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709255/8efa8d7a6e654e9a984dc3bd4d72e4c6/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709255/8efa8d7a6e654e9a984dc3bd4d72e4c6/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709255/8efa8d7a6e654e9a984dc3bd4d72e4c6/2790x1800.jpg" altText="We are invited to walk with Him." pid="qIKvszdqqEKPyiCI_XpG1g" hash="E8Hg7g"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p38" pid="crp0bhDNeECODwti735ZHg" hash="NToi6w"&gt;We have all felt, at some time in our lives, the pain and heartache associated with sin and transgression, for “if we say that we have no sin, we deceive ourselves, and the truth is not in us.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13"&gt;13&lt;/span&gt; However, “though [our] sins be as scarlet,” as we apply the Atonement of Jesus Christ and walk with Him through sincere repentance, “they shall be as white as snow.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14"&gt;14&lt;/span&gt; Though we have been weighed down with guilt, we shall obtain peace.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=_961_33uUUqTq4J0K8FD1Q"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709282/e7d5b309ac404e6e963103ecd7079958/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709282/e7d5b309ac404e6e963103ecd7079958/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709282/e7d5b309ac404e6e963103ecd7079958/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709282/e7d5b309ac404e6e963103ecd7079958/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709282/e7d5b309ac404e6e963103ecd7079958/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709282/e7d5b309ac404e6e963103ecd7079958/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709282/e7d5b309ac404e6e963103ecd7079958/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709282/e7d5b309ac404e6e963103ecd7079958/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709282/e7d5b309ac404e6e963103ecd7079958/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709282/e7d5b309ac404e6e963103ecd7079958/2790x1800.jpg" altText="We are invited to repent." pid="_961_33uUUqTq4J0K8FD1Q" hash="vvaQFA"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p39" pid="WEXRapbafU-3HpDbkzF_uw" hash="BbCkdw"&gt;Alma the Younger was compelled to confront his sins when visited by an angel of the Lord. He described his experience in these words:&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p40" pid="cyp_tqCAv0ugT2-QQtyW9w" hash="r8ehYw"&gt;“My soul was harrowed up to the greatest degree and racked with all my sins.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p41" pid="YJdDB1K0DUyNlKhPi63Eew" hash="sATR6w"&gt;“… Yea, I saw that I had rebelled against my God, and that I had not kept his holy commandments.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15"&gt;15&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p42" pid="J_7Eou7RDUiTJppF79500w" hash="0dojKg"&gt;As serious as his sins were, and in the midst of this ordeal, he continues:&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p43" pid="uMOaCBJkwkOOJiPLhnzYxw" hash="symoQA"&gt;“I remembered also to have heard my father prophesy unto the people concerning the coming of one Jesus Christ, a Son of God, to atone for the sins of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p44" pid="-X501yIlPkeamgTH9SD8WQ" hash="lcY7Jg"&gt;“… I cried within my heart: O Jesus, thou Son of God, have mercy on me.”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16"&gt;16&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p45" pid="Ga5Sr1NLr06l8YKxOUtoiA" hash="8HFamQ"&gt;“And never, until I did cry out unto the Lord Jesus Christ for mercy, did I receive a remission of my sins. But behold, I did cry unto him and &lt;span class="emphasis"&gt;I did find peace to my soul.&lt;/span&gt;”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17"&gt;17&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p46" pid="De5MHR3t70eD9if4CAJOsg" hash="a9v_UA"&gt;Like Alma, we too will find peace to our souls as we walk with Jesus Christ, repent of our sins, and apply His healing power in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p47" pid="Z9eFNJtAUUaVpC_SOkzC4w" hash="i4lOLQ"&gt;The peace we all seek requires more than a desire. It requires us to act—by learning of Him, by listening to His words, and by walking with Him. We may not have the ability to control all that happens around us, but we can control how we apply the pattern for peace that the Lord has provided—a pattern that makes it easy to think often about Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;a href="gl://image/?pid=uisThwQtXkurNdF4a3qB8w"&gt;&lt;img xmlns="" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" src="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709283/bb4057bca69d489da566f79242e68e26/200x129.jpg" data-multi-src="true" data-src-50x32="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709283/bb4057bca69d489da566f79242e68e26/50x32.jpg" data-src-100x64="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709283/bb4057bca69d489da566f79242e68e26/100x64.jpg" data-src-200x129="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709283/bb4057bca69d489da566f79242e68e26/200x129.jpg" data-src-320x206="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709283/bb4057bca69d489da566f79242e68e26/320x206.jpg" data-src-460x296="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709283/bb4057bca69d489da566f79242e68e26/460x296.jpg" data-src-640x412="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709283/bb4057bca69d489da566f79242e68e26/640x412.jpg" data-src-1024x660="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709283/bb4057bca69d489da566f79242e68e26/1024x660.jpg" data-src-2048x1321="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709283/bb4057bca69d489da566f79242e68e26/2048x1321.jpg" data-src-2790x1800="https://edge.ldscdn.org/mobile/images/1709283/bb4057bca69d489da566f79242e68e26/2790x1800.jpg" altText="We can apply the Savior’s pattern." pid="uisThwQtXkurNdF4a3qB8w" hash="Hqvjpw"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace.p48" pid="pV6Esl8Ti0m47pml-A2Z9Q" hash="jYC8Hw"&gt;I testify that Jesus Christ is “the way, the truth, and the life”&lt;span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18"&gt;18&lt;/span&gt; and that only through Him can we obtain true peace in this life and eternal life in the world to come. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2016/04/a-pattern-for-peace</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2016-general-conference/2016-04-4030-w-christopher-waddell-64k-eng.mp3" length="6253152" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
