<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By W. Grant Bangerter</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by W. Grant Bangerter.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/W.%20Grant%20Bangerter.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by W. Grant Bangerter.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Oct 1975 18:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 1975 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>The Power of the Priesthood</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brethren, I believe that what I have to say is a companion to what Bishop Brown has already spoken tonight. And I trust that the Spirit of the Lord will bless its delivery.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03063_000_031" doc-version="3" hash="exBSNg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="rbzehci2QU2PLbjiCE0tmA" hash="0XIc0A">The Power of the Priesthood</h1><p class="authorName" pid="1Qko1ZDl1UaSIeRmx_ZNYw" hash="-Spxuw">W. Grant Bangerter</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2e68.jpg" alt="Elder W. Grant Bangerter" pid="xOuCDh3cRUCAMsnKsrQhvw" hash="UQU9fA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood.p1" pid="pl8tvK6aVUqHXDrOP90YJA" hash="eALomQ">My dear brethren, I believe that what I have to say is a companion to what Bishop Brown has already spoken tonight. And I trust that the Spirit of the Lord will bless its delivery.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood.p2" pid="PX6HhBNn80WGWWOnCLnMUg" hash="18JV5A">Without presuming to be an authority on the subject of the priesthood, I have nevertheless spent years along with you considering its purpose and the power which pertains to it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood.p3" pid="xe2OlYNNTEuPCMD_mFWnEw" hash="zSxERg">In the Church, testimonies are often expressed in general terms. For example, we speak of our knowledge that God lives, that Jesus is the Christ, and that this is the true Church. There are times, however, when we do not always show the same faith in more specific parts of the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood.p4" pid="c5Yck7Ow6EayVnMOyzlMzw" hash="njBRgg">I have heard some say that they believe in everything but the welfare plan or everything except tithing. Some people used to say they could follow the Prophet Joseph Smith or David O. McKay, but not Brigham Young or Heber J. Grant. Now such selectivity is simply not consistent.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood.p5" pid="AgbIMHw_R0aMkDiOpUqr8A" hash="Jw-ujQ">I would like to ask tonight, “What kind of a testimony do you have concerning the power of the priesthood?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood.p6" pid="6YpOSbaEMki5FanrZrm8dg" hash="n9CL2w">How many brethren here are home teachers? Would you please raise your hands. Those of you who are listening in may also raise your hands. Now since we have just closed out the month of September, how many of you home teachers “got your home teaching done?” Well, brethren, that’s a catch phrase. You know, the devil taught us to say those words: “Did you get your home teaching done?” That is a very poor way to refer to the comprehensive mission embodied in home teaching. By getting us to ask “Did you get your home teaching done?” the devil destroys 90 percent of our effectiveness. All that question implies is a quick visit the last day of the month so that we can send in the report.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood.p7" pid="_--w7NFPdUWT8TwRGHNcrA" hash="2oPVpw">Now there are other examples that we don’t always fully appreciate the nature of the priesthood. When the bishopric wants some event to be especially well organized, to whom do they assign the responsibility? That’s right—it’s the Relief Society. Now why not the priesthood? It’s because we have a habit of saying, “The priesthood won’t do it.” Why don’t some stake presidents use their home teachers to bring the people to stake conference? It’s because there’s a saying abroad in the land that “the home teachers won’t do it.” Other sayings are “Fathers won’t do it,” or “People in our ward won’t accept assignments.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood.p8" pid="gDp2RANoPkqaKGCboTgBog" hash="4KI9mg">Seriously, these expressions indicate either a lack of faith in or lack of understanding of the power of God. When one fine stake president, without thinking, let those words slip out, “The home teachers won’t do it,” I answered him, “President, do you know what you have just said? I think you just said that although the Lord established a procedure by which we should lead his church, his system won’t work. So you have devised a better one.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood.p9" pid="1B_7COVmS0KujXvB2xBsPw" hash="CTvItg">I went to a conference in President Rex Reeve’s stake. He took me through the building and showed me 2,000 chairs prepared for the people. I asked him how he knew there would be 2,000 people present, and he answered, “We sent the home teachers out to invite everyone to come, and they have given us their report. They have informed us that 2,000 people will be here tomorrow.” Evidently the word got out that I would be one of the speakers because seventy-five of those 2,000 didn’t show up. But they had an attendance of 49 percent and it has since grown much higher.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood.p10" pid="qNYpIw61FkWsWSRGQm30CA" hash="bsdZXg">For several years I had the privilege of sitting at the feet of President Marion G. Romney, who taught us about the “constitution of the Church”—meaning that revelation given on the occasion of the organization of the Church wherein the Lord outlined the procedures by which it should be governed. The elders, it says in section 20 of the Doctrine and Covenants, assisted by the lesser priesthood, are to “watch over the Church.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.42,53" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:42, 53</a>.) A part of that “watching over” is done by visiting the houses of the members and in instructing them to do their duty. In another revelation the elders quorum is specifically mentioned as a body of “standing ministers.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/124.137" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 124:137</a>.) Those who hold the Aaronic Priesthood are also called “standing ministers.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.111" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:111</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood.p11" pid="uhRE8OiU6UyPBIXbEftBNg" hash="YrGVUQ">Five years ago if you had asked, “Who’s the ‘minister’ of your Church?” most of us would have answered, “Oh, the bishop.” Today we can’t give that simple answer because we know that many of the duties have now been shifted over to the elders, where the revelations say they rightfully belong. Now a ward should have at least fifty “ministers” in place of the one we thought of a few years ago.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood.p12" pid="oOptFjEsrU6reXi2-SBEiQ" hash="IBj1Gw">Now think of the increased power to carry the gospel forward when fifty men do their duty as the bishop has done it in the past.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood.p13" pid="woh6XIY7TkOplh6UE5y_0g" hash="ytQ96A">“Oh, but the home teachers won’t do it.” Well, do you have faith in the Lord’s system or don’t you, and why not try it?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood.p14" pid="FSyMmxC5-EyJ1DKlzOr8Dw" hash="5ZOJiA">To further mention limited understanding concerning the priesthood, I refer you to an incident common in the fast and testimony meeting. Someone frequently gives the experience that a relative or friend was very ill and the elders were called in to administer to him. The person was healed. And so we say we have a testimony of the power of the priesthood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood.p15" pid="hSzgi0E6VUqRiwRi9sqtmw" hash="VnXNKw">Now please understand, I do not belittle the virtue of this sacred and wonderful ordinance. It frequently means the difference between life and death for ourselves and our loved ones, and I have witnessed its marvelous influence. But why limit your testimony to that? Why not as readily send the elders to administer help to a father whose son is about to die spiritually on drugs or alcohol? Why not call on the priesthood to bless a home that is about to die through divorce or transgression? Why not administer through the priesthood to those who love the world more than God? Why do we blithely say, “We did our home teaching” when half of the families in the Church are in a condition to be “wasted” when the Savior comes because they have not been “sealed up” to eternal life? There is a ministry here for the elders far more extensive than that of laying hands on the sick. A person healed of bodily sickness will eventually become sick again and die. When you administer the gospel, the cure can be permanent.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood.p16" pid="vQutWipa1k-y5883QLE4mw" hash="IasqDg">Now this is an appropriate time to think in terms of an expanded power in the priesthood because everyone here knows the watchwords for our day are “lengthen your stride,” “quicken your pace,” and “extend your vision.” When I first became a mission president and during a visit by President Kimball, I expressed my concern that I would not be able to keep up the vigorous pace of the former president. His answer went something like this: “Now here, here, we won’t listen to any more of that kind of talk. You can’t be satisfied with what happened in the past. Everything in the Church has to go forward. Didn’t you know that? Now remember, under your leadership things must improve.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood.p17" pid="iLF1r7mR4kWtf1eF3frArA" hash="w6M3dg">Now you can see why I have a testimony of the power of the priesthood. I was told to go out and get one. And I really do have one.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood.p18" pid="zgnboiGU3EGs5-VoHwzBMA" hash="ldmloQ">“Which priesthood,” saith the Lord, “continueth in the church of God in all generations.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.17" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:17</a>.) No one else on earth has it. “And this greater priesthood administereth the gospel and holdeth the key of the mysteries of the kingdom.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.19" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood.p19" pid="cFv6wl1IfU6shVM7cZyywQ" hash="zaWxeg">Our missionaries are out every day teaching people who don’t even believe in God. But because of the “great power” which has been given to them, and through their great faith, the Holy Ghost draws near to them. Its influence is felt, and people respond, repent, and obey. When these elders administer baptism to such a person, the teaching and the ordinance combine to be a powerful administration of the priesthood. Children of God are reborn into eternal life. And when this army of missionaries is increased from 10,000 to 20,000, the power of the priesthood is vastly increased.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood.p20" pid="g-aqQ8Vp3U6JNCs6Dx8jpQ" hash="YI32sw">In the quorums the same thing ought to be true. If we expand from one “minister” to fifty, we should multiply the power of the priesthood by fifty. And the miracles they can perform should multiply vastly beyond those performed on the physically sick. When you have the great joy of hearing someone say, “There’s the man who brought me the gospel,” or “There is the man who changed my whole life,” you can bear your testimony to a great miracle.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood.p21" pid="DJ9L8YImPU2ji5zbIbzxvA" hash="V98JIQ">Now the priesthood president of deacons, teachers, and priests is the bishop and their quorum presidents. The priesthood president of fathers in the Church is the elders quorum president or, of course, in some cases the high priests and seventies presidents. All fathers must, says the scripture, “come unto this priesthood.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.42" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:42</a>.) If not, their families will be subject to the judgment predicted by the prophet Malachi—wasted, not bound to fathers. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/2.title" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 2</a>.) This is why the gospel was restored, so that the earth would not be wasted at His coming.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood.p22" pid="No843DjcnU6cVRfF_ThkhQ" hash="xFKaYA">The Melchizedek Priesthood president, who is in most cases the elders quorum president, must see that the fulness of the gospel is administered to every member of the Church. That is the function of this priesthood. He should administer the gospel personally and through the “standing ministers” in his quorum, now called the home teachers. If you don’t believe in that system and if you don’t use it, you don’t have a true testimony of the power of the priesthood, and you cannot succeed. If you use this system and are faithful, your success is guaranteed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood.p23" pid="SQQb6HbBOUmlIe6q6UhkiA" hash="iiHwAw">I know people respond when you obtain the power of God which pertains to the priesthood. I have heard Elder LeGrand Richards say, “If you were to divide your ward and put all the active members in one ward and the inactive in the other, and give me the inactive ones, within a year I would give you a ‘run for your money.’” I know he would, and I know he would also have the most fun.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood.p24" pid="qYYpVD6TRU-JjzDunrXZhw" hash="0Aogiw">I once heard a stake president mention the great success of one of his elders quorum presidents. He said, “His name is Hershel Pedersen. Perhaps you have heard of him. They used to call him ‘Bones’ when he played for BYU.” Well, I, along with many of you had heard of Brother Pedersen. As a matter of fact he grew up in my stake. He is one of the seven sons of Oliver Cowdery Pedersen, who all went on missions, most of them to Denmark. I heard his report when he returned from his mission, and I signed his temple recommend when he was married. So I was interested.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood.p25" pid="IeEiuRkf6UuBcBf4tzP3eA" hash="cxm7VA">The stake president continued: “Brother Pedersen has committed himself to qualify every man in his quorum for a temple recommend. They are all qualified now except six.” Some time later when I was with the Church Home Teaching Committee, we remembered this story and asked Brother Pedersen to report on how his quorum had turned out. He said, “We got them all but three. Then they released me to become president of the stake mission. But since my release we got the other three.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood.p26" pid="86ecUYjy40mcTcyNAxxFuw" hash="UGwnJw">Think of the potential if all who bear the priesthood were deeply involved in the work of the Lord. Compared to what is available, we have been running on only one or two cylinders.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood.p27" pid="5aoeOPoJ1kWSeA3N42X3vA" hash="PYpT6Q">In missionary work some stakes have raised their sights so much that each ward is going to bring in as many new members as the entire stake used to. In temple work I have seen stakes, who worked through priesthood power, make yearly increases that were greater than the total performance of average stakes nearby. In every activity in which the priesthood is involved, I become excited when I see how far we can go if we have faith enough to mobilize the great army of men of the priesthood. Not a testimony like Laman and Lemuel. And I know some say, “He doesn’t understand how tough it is in our quorum.” Well, Nephi didn’t either; but Nephi had a testimony. In the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1975/10/the-power-of-the-priesthood</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1975-general-conference/1975-10-5020-elder-william-grant-bangerter-64k-eng.mp3" length="7258923" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 1975 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Voice of the Lord Is unto All People</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1979/10/the-voice-of-the-lord-is-unto-all-people?lang=eng</link>
      <description>President Kimball has already suggested that what we say may be supportive of the things he has already declared. “God, who at sundry times and in divers manners spake in time past unto the fathers by the prophets,</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-voice-of-the-lord-is-unto-all-people" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03115_000_005" doc-version="2" hash="jm7AXg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-voice-of-the-lord-is-unto-all-people.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="emrYXyIgUEWdxQs_6tID7A" hash="I7LcGA">The Voice of the Lord Is unto All People</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="BJ9RUrihEUGXgoxwim2oJA" hash="-Spxuw">W. Grant Bangerter</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-voice-of-the-lord-is-unto-all-people.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2e68.jpg" alt="Elder W. Grant Bangerter" pid="FWEUgKmJUEabajx0M33y_g" hash="UQU9fA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-voice-of-the-lord-is-unto-all-people.p1" pid="MUJHAA2GSEWfzztWzLrkvg" hash="OZV3xQ">President Kimball has already suggested that what we say may be supportive of the things he has already declared. “God, who at sundry times and in divers manners spake in time past unto the fathers by the prophets,</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-voice-of-the-lord-is-unto-all-people.p2" pid="WZOaG5TUekSj3Y8n4KuoMg" hash="gYh8nw">“Hath in these last days spoken unto us by his Son, whom he hath appointed heir of all things, by whom also he made the worlds” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/heb/1.1-2" class="scriptureRef">Heb. 1:1–2</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-voice-of-the-lord-is-unto-all-people.p3" pid="fO-38l3Q2keA_h20YZpCtA" hash="xyRKPg">One of the principal purposes of this general conference of the Church is to announce again that God has raised up a prophet by whom he declares his will to the peoples of this world. This means that not only is the prophet sent to those who accept his words, such as the members of the Church, but also he is speaking in the name of God to all the inhabitants of the earth. He says, as did an ancient prophet, “Hear, O heavens, and give ear, O earth: for the Lord hath spoken” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/1.2" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 1:2</a>). He has been sent especially to you who do not believe in God or in prophets. Wouldn’t you like to know what he is saying? He says that in these last days God has restored the ancient gospel in its fulness and wishes to make a new covenant with all people. He says that Jesus Christ will shortly come again to the earth to save and judge the world and that we should all get ready. Now whether you believe it or not, this is earthshaking news.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-voice-of-the-lord-is-unto-all-people.p4" pid="nWxPtFaf-E2Cc1GKz-TIgQ" hash="oAS6Dg">The interesting thing about prophets is that most people don’t listen to them. That is why prophets often seem to be impatient or even angry. That is how the Lord feels about us when we don’t listen. That is how you feel when your children won’t listen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-voice-of-the-lord-is-unto-all-people.p5" pid="9BuGiFGoZ0yO_t-TwNaejg" hash="cjiWKA">We know some of you say that you do not believe in God. Some of you have even been so unwise as to say there is no God. That kind of statement raises some interesting questions. Do you think your unbelief makes any difference? He won’t go away just because you don’t believe in him. Reportedly, when Galileo was forced to say, contrary to his knowledge, that the earth did not turn, he then added, “And yet it turns” (see <span class="emphasis">Cassell’s Book of Quotations, Proverbs, and Household Words,</span> ed. W. Gurney Benham, London: Cassell and Co., 1914, p. 737). Perhaps you are correct in saying that God is not like you have been told, but how can you know that there is no God? Did he reveal it to you? Have you been there to make sure? All you can really know is that you don’t know there is a God, and that is an admission of ignorance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-voice-of-the-lord-is-unto-all-people.p6" pid="XzyjEHt9KEWHqBlZukCamg" hash="Ehq3lQ">Two Russians went around the world in a spacecraft a time or two and declared that they had gone to heaven and God was not there. This is a pretty weak argument for atheism. It isn’t even scientific. It reminds me of the blasphemous remark of a scoffing acquaintance of my brother who said, “I dreamed I saw God and he was a horse.” My brother’s comment was, “Certainly. That is perfectly logical to a jackass.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-voice-of-the-lord-is-unto-all-people.p7" pid="zGnRRK85l0-fkjp9Z4GJFA" hash="6o-6oA">All the evidence is on our side. You cannot prove God away from us. To know that there is no God you would have to go everywhere and know everything.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-voice-of-the-lord-is-unto-all-people.p8" pid="J3oGZLfeKUqF_x5h-cNrZQ" hash="k2zdAw">The prophet declares that God lives and that he is speaking to us in these last days. As witnesses we know this. God has been seen, heard, and felt. With the declaration that the gospel has been restored is the promise that the Holy Ghost will also witness the fact to you, and then you will know. If that doesn’t happen after you have earnestly and prayerfully listened, you are free from all obligation to believe.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-voice-of-the-lord-is-unto-all-people.p9" pid="Ozyr8FFNukG0iVnZH2iC8g" hash="MdKavw">What about you who believe in God but don’t believe in prophets or revelation? Why not? How can you know about God without revelation? Is it bad to have a prophet? Is there some rule against it? Don’t we need a prophet? Wouldn’t it be comforting, for example, if the president of the United States were a prophet? Wouldn’t it be wonderful for this country if God would just tell us what we ought to be doing? As a matter of fact, he is telling us. The only trouble is that by and large we won’t listen. It is just the same as in ancient times when other prophets spoke. You would rather commit adultery, play on Sunday, drink your whiskey, and let someone else tend to the problems of society and the world. God is trying to straighten all these things out by the words of his prophet. And only when you have enough faith will you be able to hear the message.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-voice-of-the-lord-is-unto-all-people.p10" pid="uNBdXl1ERUqTXDjHLGKsTQ" hash="_TPfyg">Now, to the most foolish of all, those of you who belong to the Church and who say you are not interested. You say that you are not religious and you don’t enjoy going to church. Some people who are sick physically don’t like their medicine either, but they take it so they may be well. Do you remember when your parents urged you to eat your vegetables? Now you are doing the same with your children. Let me tell you about your spiritual vegetables. You have been brought up in light. You know about God. You know about the Savior. You know they appeared to Joseph Smith. You know the angel Moroni gave the Book of Mormon to Joseph Smith. You have it in your home. You believe in the Bible. That is a great deal to throw away just so you can go fishing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-voice-of-the-lord-is-unto-all-people.p11" pid="VxYZ8rxnWE25YppkWezCcA" hash="Ke2BQQ">I have a friend who one time went on a family outing to Yellowstone Park. While he was faithful to his commitments as a member and leader in the Church, some of his relatives tended to scoff at his “straitlaced” religious nature. They persuaded him, one Sunday morning, to go out in the boat fishing with them. Suddenly a strong wind arose, and they found themselves in such danger that they feared for their lives. The taunting and skepticism were suddenly gone. In plaintive unison they looked to my friend, saying, “Please, can’t you pray for us?” They evidently had little confidence in their own petitions or perhaps sensed their unworthiness to call for divine aid. The irony of the situation is that my friend, having been tempted against his better judgment to do something of which he felt the Lord would not approve, says of his predicament: “I had no prayer to offer. All I could think of was the headline in the newspaper saying, ‘Stake President Drowns While Fishing on Sunday.’”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-voice-of-the-lord-is-unto-all-people.p12" pid="cRC-2nPe_Eq4fVz8xgtuvw" hash="TbcTWQ">God went to quite a bit of trouble so that you could have the gospel, and now the prophet is telling you that you had better pay attention because these things are for your happiness and that the “rebellious shall be pierced with much sorrow” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.3" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:3</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-voice-of-the-lord-is-unto-all-people.p13" pid="69Urh_OboE-LI7hZHIr9jQ" hash="VzJTvw">We find joy in the Church in singing with fervor the great hymn “We Thank Thee, O God, for a Prophet” (<span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 196). I have something to say now to those who call themselves faithful and devoted to the gospel. While we are being thankful for a prophet, are we sure we have really listened to what he said? I know we go home from each conference feeling inspired and touched by the messages he has given and by the sermons of all the General Authorities. The real test, however, is what we do after we get home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-voice-of-the-lord-is-unto-all-people.p14" pid="LNkNbW40TUG3668EEeikQg" hash="ApW7Lg">President Kimball spoke four years ago at the closing session of a general conference stating how impressed he was by the messages and instructions given in the various sermons, that he had made a listing of all the things he needed to remember, and that as soon as he returned home he intended to perfect himself according to all that had been said (see <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1975, p. 111). Why shouldn’t we all do that? Do you have your garden? Are you providing for the present and future needs of your family? Are you getting out of debt? What is your relationship with the Savior? Do you pray? Do you read the scriptures? Do you pay your tithing? Do you fight with your neighbors? or your wife? or your children?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-voice-of-the-lord-is-unto-all-people.p15" pid="vGqa6LVpr020dkut87yGUQ" hash="Mo5HZA">We can ask some special questions of leaders of the Church. It would be a disgrace to criticize you, knowing of your devotion and sacrifice, but let me ask you, Are you really listening to what the prophet says? We know that some of you do more than others. It is five years now since he said that every boy should go on a mission (see <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1974, p. 87). Why are half of them still at home? Quorum presidents and home teachers, Why are there still so many diseased and sick in spirit? Why have you not “bound up that which was broken, neither … brought again that which was driven away, neither … sought that which was lost” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ezek/34.4" class="scriptureRef">Ezek. 34:4</a>)? The Lord has called you through his prophet. Listen to what he says. How you listen to the prophet makes the difference between being a Laman or Lemuel or a Nephi. There are some Lamans in the priesthood of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-voice-of-the-lord-is-unto-all-people.p16" pid="cX_7y2L1QEGXg23jZI1-nA" hash="NfGOUQ">To all of you of whom I have made mention—unbelievers; nonmembers; members of the Church, both faithful and those not so devoted; and to the leaders; and all who bear the holy priesthood—I declare as one who knows and has authority, that Spencer W. Kimball, President of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, is the prophet of God to all the inhabitants of the earth. He is the direct successor to Isaiah; Malachi; Peter, James, and John; and to Joseph Smith and others in between. He is the chief Apostle of Jesus Christ on the earth and is authorized to announce that the gospel has been restored to the earth in these, the last days, in preparation for the Second Coming and that these are the days to prepare. His is a voice of gladness in the glorious news he bears and a solemn warning to us all. I so testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-303c.jpg" alt="First Presidency occurred on 7 November 1837" pid="GgYLc2u4Ck61uqE5uFHaJQ" hash="O8GYZw" />
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1979/10/the-voice-of-the-lord-is-unto-all-people</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1979-general-conference/1979-10-1030-elder-w-grant-bangerter-64k-eng.mp3" length="5416971" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 1979 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching by the Spirit</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1980/04/teaching-by-the-spirit?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Central to the calling to administer the gospel to all people, living and dead, is the power of the Holy Ghost. My experience tells me that many who labor in the callings of the priesthood lack insight into this great agency and are unable to be as e</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/teaching-by-the-spirit" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03122_000_021" doc-version="2" hash="Uf7qrQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/teaching-by-the-spirit.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="GjD5eM1HMk2fvCVuCTM0yw" hash="8sOs9A">Teaching by the Spirit</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="bVVQs8IOe0GaKAszkoUqwg" hash="-Spxuw">W. Grant Bangerter</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/teaching-by-the-spirit.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2e68.jpg" alt="Elder W. Grant Bangerter" pid="tuI1xABCqUGB6jl0fD7Y1w" hash="UQU9fA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/teaching-by-the-spirit.p1" pid="4dtUx7G3R0KMPJyRb7P3XA" hash="9557gA">Central to the calling to administer the gospel to all people, living and dead, is the power of the Holy Ghost. My experience tells me that many who labor in the callings of the priesthood lack insight into this great agency and are unable to be as effective as they ought to be.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/teaching-by-the-spirit.p2" pid="zCybAz13cUi-UW30xPUGjw" hash="DDCR2A">I pray that I may be blessed to give some helpful instructions about this most potent and sacred influence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/teaching-by-the-spirit.p3" pid="HOABIvDJSk21WQwGEDl_VA" hash="aVZLpw">Obviously, if I do not have the Holy Spirit, I may as well not speak tonight.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/teaching-by-the-spirit.p4" pid="ekCaVt7knE2EdeGRWQc9Aw" hash="ri-Q7A">Most of our work is done in the form of teaching. This takes place in classes such as priesthood quorums, Sunday School, and seminary; many times in interviews; by missionaries as they present the gospel in their discussions; by home teachers to the families of the Church; and, of course, in sermons such as this one.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/teaching-by-the-spirit.p5" pid="-OqY0INUFUK96kiFJhzfcQ" hash="jz6AXA">So I’m speaking to stake presidents, bishops, and quorum leaders, to missionaries, auxiliary leaders, home teachers, and class instructors.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/teaching-by-the-spirit.p6" pid="3MN90hX1hUGzcSUjr63opw" hash="a7eGnA">How can we teach by the Spirit? Brethren, try to detect the influence of the Holy Spirit in the following experiences.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/teaching-by-the-spirit.p7" pid="kvCS3Ojcb0SyIDjCIvTopA" hash="bTR9AA">While I was serving as stake president, my counselors and I invited a certain brother for an interview where we presented to him his calling to be the president of the stake Young Men organization. This man had not been fully active. He liked to spend his weekends, including Sundays, camping and fishing, and it was reported that he and his wife did not always obey the Word of Wisdom. There was some question as to whether we should consider him for such a position, but because of the prayerful discussions we had held in the presidency and the high council we concluded that he should be called. As we advised this brother of his appointment, he responded that he was not interested and that he did not feel worthy or qualified. We then told him how we had come to choose him over all the members of the stake. We explained that we needed a strong and capable leader of youth in our stake and that both the presidency and the high council had offered earnest prayers, asking the Lord to indicate the person who should fill the position. We said: “The answer was clear. You are the man the Lord has chosen. It is for you to decide, of course, but you do have an obligation to go home and discuss the question with your wife. The only request we make of you is that thereafter you kneel down with her and ask the Lord what he wants you to do.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/teaching-by-the-spirit.p8" pid="aBoNbSA5XEqiC-pmpylyDw" hash="hE5Ryg">Three days later I received an unhappy telephone call from this same man. He reluctantly informed me that he would accept the position with all its implications. He gave powerful service in his calling, and when that assignment was finished, he became a member of the high council, and he has been happy about the gospel ever since.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/teaching-by-the-spirit.p9" pid="Yd40-ftQ6E6l-v_8zYpEyQ" hash="_QZo7Q">We had a similar experience when we called another man to be the president of our stake mission. Through some discouraging experiences in Church service, he thought himself halfway on the road to apostasy and not at all sure of his testimony. He resisted his appointment vigorously, saying that it would deprive him of time to do some of the most enjoyable things in life. We explained to him how once again we had sought the direction from the Lord about who should preside over the mission. We told him that he was not being forced to accept the call, but that he should ask his Heavenly Father whether or not it was right for him to serve. The Lord gave him a powerful assurance that he was called to the work. The following year he, with his missionaries, baptized nearly ten percent of all the nonmembers in our stake. Later on, he was called to be a bishop.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/teaching-by-the-spirit.p10" pid="XiD54zTAv06krVpmyZYnJA" hash="h1rZVg">On certain occasions I have approached young men of missionary age and informed them that they have been called to serve a mission. Sometimes they explain that they have no desire to go on a mission. I then tell them that it is immaterial to me whether they serve a mission or not. Of course, it isn’t all immaterial; but I say I am only informing them of the calling the Lord has already given them. And I’ll explain how I know that. I was present the day President Kimball made the announcement that all young men should go on a mission. The Holy Spirit told me that the principle was true.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/teaching-by-the-spirit.p11" pid="XjcWWHjleU6pXX2HAS1pXg" hash="zOa2Pw">Later on, I was talking with a humble, but inspired, patriarch who is here tonight. He informed me that he was not trained nor educated to give patriarchal blessings and that he could only say the things the Lord told him to say. I thought that sounded about right. He then added: “You would be interested to know how many young men who come for their blessings are told that they will go on missions.” With that statement, I again felt revelation and saw light, and I knew that President Kimball had not called them on a mission. He had merely made the announcement. But the mission had been ordained by the Lord himself, and every young man who belongs to the Church has an obligation to labor to build up the kingdom.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/teaching-by-the-spirit.p12" pid="A3gJnlQWME27KHp3U8nIqw" hash="qmSs_Q">There has been no difficulty, therefore, for me in telling young men that I know they have been called on a mission. And when they respond that they are not interested, I merely say: “Don’t tell me; tell the Lord. You go and pray and ask him what he wants you to do.” Almost always they return from that experience saying: “Well, I suppose I had better go on a mission.” For some of them it is then time to say: “Now we both understand that you are not quite prepared, so let us begin to take the steps by which you will be qualified to go.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/teaching-by-the-spirit.p13" pid="GLpXdVAHG0yicBsD4AS2QA" hash="UyLtyg">Here’s another situation. I have watched missionaries over many years, as they teach the gospel, find that some of their best investigators tell them that they have decided not to join the Church. Most missionaries at this point are discouraged and disappointed. The missionary who understands the Holy Ghost, however, takes that moment as his great opportunity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/teaching-by-the-spirit.p14" pid="0Cufr3HJpkObvu33jVP0vQ" hash="mmf3Vg">He even welcomes it, because he knows what to do. And he might say: “Very well, if that is your wish. However, please allow us a moment just to tell you how much the gospel means to us. Do you remember how Joseph Smith knelt one evening in his room and prayed to the Lord to know of his standing before God? As a result, an angel appeared and said: ‘Joseph, I have come to you from the presence of God to tell you that the Lord has a work for you to do, by which your name will be known for good and evil among all men’ [see <a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.33" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:33</a>]. What did Joseph Smith say? Did he say: ‘Oh, no thanks, Mr. Angel. I don’t want to go on a mission. I only wished to know if the Lord loves me!’ Of course, he couldn’t have said that. We want to tell you that we know this work is true just as surely as if we had knelt there by the side of Joseph Smith, because God has revealed it to us. He will reveal it to you, too. We don’t think you should decide not to join his church until you have knelt down and asked the Lord what he wants you to do.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/teaching-by-the-spirit.p15" pid="JOvh6V9m1k6IcuLjgSWRaw" hash="hehcyw">And the investigators, as they pray, respond saying: “Of course, the Lord wants us to join the Church.” The next step, naturally, is to prepare for their baptism.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/teaching-by-the-spirit.p16" pid="StfD2AyGokq_fuDs-N93fg" hash="CmS9gw">What has taken place in all of these situations? It is simply that the Holy Ghost has come into the presence of those who are teaching and those who are listening and has given them a witness of the mind and will of God. They have felt something they never understood or knew before. Did you notice? You felt it, too, as I told you these experiences, and I felt it. This is explained in the Doctrine and Covenants: “Wherefore, he that preacheth and he that receiveth, understand one another, and both are edified and rejoice together” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/50.22" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 50:22</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/teaching-by-the-spirit.p17" pid="Kd2pmsMWXEW1Hp__qHhvlQ" hash="g_msCA">We are further told: “The Spirit shall be given unto you by the prayer of faith; and if ye receive not the Spirit ye shall not teach” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/42.14" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 42:14</a>). Prayer is the principal means by which this Spirit is obtained and felt.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/teaching-by-the-spirit.p18" pid="sqh1dFGBA0GKRWoXjiCEog" hash="L8Pzeg">We must prepare ourselves to work with the Spirit of the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/teaching-by-the-spirit.p19" pid="R-nIkjFrwE-UxCXvo_gjrg" hash="zUGdQQ">Certain principles must accompany our teaching through the influence of the Spirit: First, we are to be holy men. This does not mean like the Marlboro man or the macho man—<span class="emphasis">holy</span> men. Then we need confidence in the Holy Ghost; believe in it and expect its presence to be with us. And when it comes, we need to recognize its presence and be able to help others to feel the influence that it brings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/teaching-by-the-spirit.p20" pid="a4nBUVexgU2V6GIZtA1PAw" hash="W7AyjQ">One of our great missionaries said: “I bear them my testimony. Then I bear them their testimony. And then I have them bear their testimony back to me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1980/04/teaching-by-the-spirit.p21" pid="ZP3pavgeDUq1suK-tr_noQ" hash="51rkoQ">That’s the process. Alma did the same thing when he had explained to the people of the city of Gideon about the coming of Christ and the redemption that would be provided for those who would accept Him and be baptized, he said: “And now my beloved brethren, do you believe these things? Behold, I say unto you, yea, I know that ye believe them; and the way that I know ye believe them is by the manifestation of the Spirit which is in me” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/7.17" class="scriptureRef">Alma 7:17</a>). To this I bear testimony, after many wonderful experiences of the influence of the Holy Ghost, in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1980/04/teaching-by-the-spirit</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1980-general-conference/1980-04-3060-elder-w-grant-bangerter-64k-eng.mp3" length="5406932" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 1980 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Temples Are For</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Others today here have spoken about the temple, but last November, at the dedication of the Jordan River Temple, we held three services a day for five days, and we didn’t say it all. This is a good time to talk about temples, and I would like to expl</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03148_000_031" doc-version="2" hash="wu_WXg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="0orJaInPx0q6577MQD_SZQ" hash="sh1Jzw">What Temples Are For</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="EpoyV85cakCJb6fILWNiaA" hash="-Spxuw">W. Grant Bangerter</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26f0.jpg" alt="Elder W. Grant Bangerter" pid="KJCIk52JeEyNtJJIY9qwJQ" hash="5EvrWA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.p1" pid="K0Noc7VBZkGCklthn4fUsQ" hash="tg3FHg">Others today here have spoken about the temple, but last November, at the dedication of the Jordan River Temple, we held three services a day for five days, and we didn’t say it all. This is a good time to talk about temples, and I would like to explain what temples are for. As a people, the Latter-day Saints have accomplished a magnificent work in the temples. They serve with commendable devotion to find the names of deceased relatives, to work in extracting names from the records, and then to perform the ordinances for the redemption of the dead as well as for themselves. Over sixteen thousand temple workers give voluntary service in the temples, thus approaching in numbers the force of full-time missionaries who are proclaiming the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.p2" pid="pQLyUQfbh0y2XEPa31dacA" hash="eDD2fg">This is a day of prophetic fulfillment. As Isaiah said twenty-seven hundred years ago:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.p3" pid="ze1aquXVMU6TX-_xCEzsfA" hash="skBlrw">“It shall come to pass in the last days, that the mountain of the Lord’s house shall be established in the top of the mountains, and shall be exalted above the hills; and all nations shall flow unto it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.p4" pid="9CQl_hqvVUGqFyo18QK7Aw" hash="hD0ygQ">“And many people shall go and say, Come ye, and let us go up to the mountain of the Lord, to the house of the God of Jacob; and he will teach us of his ways, and we will walk in his paths: for out of Zion shall go forth the law, and the word of the Lord from Jerusalem.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/2.2-3" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 2:2–3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.p5" pid="n7Q3ebUHjEOZZ9AYS5herA" hash="NPSADQ">The meaning, depth, and power of that expression can only be perceived by those who know about temples.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.p6" pid="miFK0mRBeUq_22Uw9Z-OLA" hash="VlRO4w">We are passing through a remarkable period in connection with the temples. Four more new temples were announced last week. The past two years have seen the number of temples, including those in operation and those in planning or under construction, increase from twenty-one to forty-one. Three of these have been dedicated and have commenced their operation in the same period. Nothing of like nature has taken place in the entire history of the Church. The stake conferences now being conducted throughout the Church are to teach the Latter-day Saints more about our mission to serve in the house of the Lord.</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.f2">
	<p pid="kroEKOd1BU6sCaSwcfKXRg" hash="y14b5w">I think it will serve a purpose, however, to mention some generalizations and misconceptions about temples which have developed which show a less than perfect understanding. For example, it is sometimes said:</p>
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="ya339Uy2pEiL1keDEtbblA" hash="Qpyfhg">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="KvgPgwpEhku7SiiywWYVyA" hash="joUTLQ">My genealogy has all been done.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="jVKyaKOgy0ymUDDN0dEXvA" hash="eaRslQ">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="YTMi8f4Sx0GNTwNhLLrXwA" hash="fGaoow">Computers and the name extraction will do the work for me.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="cwjMBI1cxkm4Zj4twG_2hA" hash="1sO8zg">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="Fhu1QhYaKUaFYOnxIuKLyw" hash="Y8r9zg">Temple work is for the dead.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="TlQfMqMcKEC4A4c8lajPLg" hash="Fdz3fg">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p pid="ukbTizv6_0SdNCmgox2UYQ" hash="iSQk1w">Temple work is for old people.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="UtDzc3SLtECYzVK3HWAs4A" hash="KLleeA">
          <span class="label">5.</span>
          <p pid="Pz1NI5NIL0eKRdBrl2slpw" hash="KNRDgg">We go to the temple to do a name.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="G0Qjun4Ga0W5etdzSDDpfA" hash="we0jqw">
          <span class="label">6.</span>
          <p pid="cFqEFaP-6UaEANibdFKMzQ" hash="LzNwXg">Going to the temple is optional.</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.p7" pid="L4Wge1CjWEmUOnZDc9lirQ" hash="dBqfOg">As we study the scriptures, we learn that the doctrine of the temple requires the following of the Latter-day Saints:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.p8" pid="qqKTmiwKgkyTqexQJ4u94A" hash="OZpKyA">First, the building of temples.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.p9" pid="UaKTXdeUGU-TlNDmWJ4hVg" hash="z9Akqw">Second, going to the temple for our blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.p10" pid="8Ip2NUYn7UqVVra7iYJ-6w" hash="CxN5Fg">Third, returning to perform the ordinances for deceased relatives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.p11" pid="5dY3ofqGBUeYcgEguqLQsA" hash="xTWTuA">Fourth, doing the work for others as well.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.p12" pid="NMqEyZT6gkW4EnIfVGZZ1g" hash="Xk5MCA">Fifth, frequent attendance for personal spiritual benefit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.p13" pid="u45l3h4X-0mBH0a6EB898A" hash="vSGuRA">What are all these temples for?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.p14" pid="7hqOeBs4tEC2m2q81TdyFw" hash="3XlCeg">First: <span class="emphasis">Temples are for the living members of the Church.</span> Going to the temple is <span class="emphasis">not</span> optional. Temples are “a place of instruction for all those who are called to the work of the ministry … that they may be perfected in [their] understanding … in all things pertaining to the kingdom of God on the earth.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/97.13-14" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 97:13–14</a>.) “Therefore, verily I say unto you, that your anointings, and your washings, … your solemn assemblies, … and … your oracles in your most holy places … [are] for the glory, honor, and endowment of [Zion’s] municipals [or in other words, her citizens, and] are ordained by the ordinance of my holy house, which my people are always commanded to build unto my holy name.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/124.39" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 124:39</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.p15" pid="U5cgJ1BsKUuMgcvoINQDHA" hash="e3HnIA">The endowment in the temple is a necessary and sacred blessing as essential for the members of the Church as baptism. Thereafter come the sealings of wives to their husbands and of children to their parents. Without these blessings there is no fulness of the gospel. Without them, said Moroni, the “earth would be utterly wasted at his coming.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/2.3" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 2:3</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.p16" pid="7GxsbqcpNUS0zRhXkGRUWg" hash="p1B4_w">Countless families in distant areas have never had this privilege. Even in areas where temples have been established for generations, half of the families have never been sealed together. <span class="emphasis">Temple work is for the living members of the Church.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.p17" pid="_ed2fWhkAU-ue-F6R0DIaw" hash="eerdBA">Second: <span class="emphasis">Temple work is for the redemption of the dead.</span> The scriptures and the doctrine, however, refer more specifically to a particular group of the dead. Malachi spoke about “binding” fathers to children and children to fathers. (See <a href="/scriptures/ot/mal/4.6" class="scriptureRef">Mal. 4:6</a>.) Joseph Smith emphasized temple blessings for our <span class="emphasis">kindred</span> dead, <span class="emphasis">our</span> dead. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/124.32-36" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 124:32–36</a>, <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/127.5-6" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 127:5–6</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/128.8,14-15" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 128:8, 14–15</a>.) The emphasis is on the family. The priority is to seek out our own deceased relatives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.p18" pid="dNhS0aBSlEiogVuH_VTv5w" hash="LQW8oQ">
        <span class="emphasis">Your genealogy has not all been done.</span> My own grandparents performed “all” the temple work for their deceased relatives fifty-five years ago. Since that time our family has discovered sixteen thousand others. In areas where new temples are being built, this work is just beginning. The controlled extraction process being carried on in many of the stakes of the Church with such great devotion and success does not touch those of the more recent generations and will not save those of our own close relationship. It is, however, of immeasurable value as the more distant generations are reached.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.p19" pid="ngyNVXjme0ySFdH1K2Gulw" hash="s6zKVQ">And may we always remember that we perform the temple ordinances for people and not for names. Those we call “the dead” are alive in the spirit and are present in the temple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.p20" pid="OyEw3fOyQUmpN_LWAAVRZA" hash="2eIQdA">The purpose of the Church, then, is to have a prepared people, ready to receive the temples as they are completed. It would be unfortunate to build temples around the earth and have them stand largely idle. One way to prepare people is to give a strong sermon. Sometimes the result is that we feel guilty. Then after two weeks this feeling wears off, and we get over it. The answer to having a prepared people lies with the leadership of the priesthood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.p21" pid="hNdQyvadN0yWqYjEUBOA-w" hash="iQPknw">In Chile, for example, where I served at the time the temple in Santiago was announced, it was found that among one hundred thousand members only three thousand men had been ordained to the priesthood. Thus, since they must have the priesthood to enter the temple, only a limited number would be qualified. We determined, therefore, that we would prepare at least ten thousand men to be thus ordained so that they with their faithful companions could then go to the temple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.p22" pid="FG16qsgrOUiOdKopTRLsNQ" hash="OysIFA">The Saints in Chile have also undertaken the responsibility to prepare one hundred thousand names of their deceased relatives to take with them to the temple by the time it is ready. Similar preparations are being made in other areas.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.p23" pid="KAox2_kn6k-hUyOVw8X30w" hash="bqWNtA">Now, where temples have long been established, it is time for a renewed and continuing preparation. This is the work of home teachers, quorum presidents, bishops, and especially high priests, as well as all others involved in teaching the gospel. I remember one elders quorum president who determined that his leadership objective would be to help every member in his quorum to go to the temple. His initial report stated that all but six had qualified. He later reported that all but three had gone before he was released. After his release, however, they “got” the other three.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.p24" pid="8DbP2ggpIU6fGcLdoUsjag" hash="FG8gVA">Having the privilege of working each day in the administration of the temples, I am constantly impressed with the richness, the holiness, and the glory of the blessings administered there. Questions come to us about the ordinances performed in the temple. We, of course, are not permitted to discuss them outside the temple, because of their sacred nature. Others press for a preparatory orientation so that those who enter the temple will not be confused. I want to emphasize that <span class="emphasis">the preparation to enter the temple lies in the gospel.</span> Nothing is said or done in the temple which does not have its foundation in the scriptures.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.p25" pid="3GmvqWXdxU6NgDEcRgBFFw" hash="5h_uWQ">The gospel is <span class="emphasis">faith in the Lord, Jesus Christ.</span> This implies a willingness to accept His doctrine and take upon us His name, being obedient to His commandments. <span class="emphasis">The gospel is repentance</span> and a cleansing from all iniquity. <span class="emphasis">It is baptism</span> whereby we have made the covenant and promise. It is the right to have the <span class="emphasis">companionship of the Holy Ghost,</span> which, when we have a correct frame of mind, will teach us as we go through the temple. <span class="emphasis">The gospel is the scriptures.</span> The answer to almost any appropriate question about the temple will be found in the scriptures for those who seek it. <span class="emphasis">The gospel is prayer, humility, teachableness, charity.</span> It is <span class="emphasis">commitment</span> and it is <span class="emphasis">covenant</span> and <span class="emphasis">ordinances.</span> It is also <span class="emphasis">blessings.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.p26" pid="W5WNCEIDJ0e0TOq6078BkQ" hash="vEHfCw">Now may I give some counsel to teachers, bishops, and stake presidents. No one, of course, will learn all about the temple by only one experience; but if you want to prepare your people for the temple, teach them the gospel. Don’t try to teach them what goes on in the temple—we go to the temple to learn about that. If these gospel principles are properly established in our lives, we will understand the temple all right. If they are not in place, nothing else can help, and those lacking that knowledge ought not yet to go.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for.p27" pid="f10-fjHREUitFILJWg_FQQ" hash="y9wfqA">May God bless this people to embrace the blessings and perform the sacred service provided in the temples, is my sincere prayer in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1982/04/what-temples-are-for</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1982-general-conference/1982-04-5060-elder-w-grant-bangerter-64k-eng.mp3" length="5491356" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1982 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
