<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Walter F. González</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Walter F. González.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Walter%20F.%20Gonz%C3%A1lez.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Walter F. González.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2001 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2001 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Writing Gospel Principles in Our Hearts</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2001/10/writing-gospel-principles-in-our-hearts?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Knowledge alone is not enough. We must take time to apply the principles in our lives.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/writing-gospel-principles-in-our-hearts" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029371_000_014" doc-version="2" hash="If0nng">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/writing-gospel-principles-in-our-hearts.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="MBN3jwKqPE22FevO7c24Ww" hash="kxiEcg">Writing Gospel Principles in Our Hearts</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="o8thTxlIT0mkf1eOWFJxog" hash="87_Gmw">Walter F. González</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="QT15j2pV90ySbdHPQSZkgQ" hash="eWucbA">Knowledge alone is not enough. We must take time to apply the principles in our lives.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/writing-gospel-principles-in-our-hearts.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-621.jpg" alt="Elder Walter F. González" pid="1_kQCLvEokWXHQk6O_BW8w" hash="xAAIZQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/writing-gospel-principles-in-our-hearts.p1" pid="3equZ1BGxUqAXRSD50EadQ" hash="ZRU7pQ">English is the language of the Restoration, and in this conference session, English spoken with an accent symbolizes Church growth all over the world. I’m from South America, where the Church has grown tremendously. When I joined the Church 30 years ago, we had 108,000 members and 6 stakes. At that time we had no temple on our continent. Now we have 2,600,000 members and 557 stakes. Eleven temples are functioning, and two are under construction. Nephi, the son of Lehi, said: “But I, Nephi, have written what I have written, and I esteem it as of great worth, and especially unto my people. For I pray continually for them by day, and mine eyes water my pillow by night, because of them” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/33.3" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 33:3</a>). This heartfelt cry is being answered in our day through the Book of Mormon. Nephi was praying that the word he had “written in weakness would be made strong unto” us, “for it persuadeth them to do good; it maketh known unto them of their fathers; and it speaketh of Jesus, and persuadeth them to believe in him, and to endure to the end, which is life eternal” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/33.4" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 33:4</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/writing-gospel-principles-in-our-hearts.p2" pid="g1evh34hWEal86VlIw7crA" hash="XJRYlg">I have seen how the doctrine and gospel principles are guiding more and more members in South America. Our task both in South America and everywhere continues to be seeking for the principles found in the scriptures and the teachings of the prophets and writing them “not with ink, but with the Spirit of the living God; not in tables of stone, but in fleshy tables of the heart” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-cor/3.3" class="scriptureRef">2 Cor. 3:3</a>). Such establishing of gospel principles requires time. Time is required both to be exposed to the truths of the gospel and to apply them in our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/writing-gospel-principles-in-our-hearts.p3" pid="kU_A9yb5jEeC6eHdMBlebw" hash="LutKuA">For most South American members, our exposure to gospel principles started with devoting time to hearing the discussions and testimonies from the missionaries. We took time to listen, and now we cannot help but feel profound gratitude to the missionaries who served in our countries. Our deep gratitude is not only to the missionaries but to the families from which they came. (Now thousands of South Americans are sending their own children to serve missions to share the glad tidings of the restored gospel.) Those of us who are first-generation Church members also feel great gratitude for our nonmember parents who took time to teach us righteous principles which prepared us to recognize and welcome the gospel message.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/writing-gospel-principles-in-our-hearts.p4" pid="b9tRJv8sqEqArn5hRZ3ZGA" hash="Q8jSCw">Missionaries initiated the task of learning doctrine and gospel principles; however, maintaining the gospel in our hearts is an ongoing task which requires time. Knowledge alone is not enough. We must take time to apply the principles in our lives. For example, Nephi knew that the Lord answers our prayers. He applied his knowledge centuries ago and thus brought everlasting blessings upon us today. If we read carefully, we see that Nephi prayed with great faith unto God because he knew that God was going to hear his “cry” (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/33.3" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 33:3</a>). How grateful we are for Nephi’s taking time to apply his knowledge. How grateful we are that Nephi wrote this knowledge in his heart “not with ink, but with the Spirit of the living God.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/writing-gospel-principles-in-our-hearts.p5" pid="TZcjjBOdbkGYzrHn2M80Cg" hash="-GQNuw">Like scholarship, discipleship also requires time. Sometimes we recognize that a principle is true, but we don’t change our priorities to make time to live the principle. In so doing, we miss valuable opportunities to develop a change of heart as we are taught by the Holy Ghost. Consider for a moment the example of Enos, who delayed the application of the knowledge he received from his father. He eventually took time to live up to that knowledge; a number of blessings flowed to us because he did. Enos tells us that it was when he went to hunt beasts in the forest that his father’s teachings about eternal life and the joy of the Saints deeply touched his heart, so he decided to devote time to praying (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/enos/1.3-4" class="scriptureRef">Enos 1:3–4</a>). In divine response to his prayer, the Lord covenanted with Enos that He would bring the records forth unto the Lamanites in His own due time (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/enos/1.16" class="scriptureRef">Enos 1:16</a>). God answers our prayers. Enos took this principle from the stone tablets and wrote it in the fleshy tablets of his heart, thus obtaining a higher level of knowledge. This brought blessings both upon him and us in this dispensation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/writing-gospel-principles-in-our-hearts.p6" pid="Sh2LZKjbsE21kc0YpXDpxg" hash="H0GzyA">A number of things hinder our good intentions of devoting time to learning and especially to living a gospel principle. For example, the abundance of information about any specific subject which comes from various media can be overwhelming. Such an abundance of information may cause some to be “ever learning, and never able to come to the knowledge of the truth” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-tim/3.7" class="scriptureRef">2 Tim. 3:7</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/writing-gospel-principles-in-our-hearts.p7" pid="fSTGX-LwvUGfB4Mh5oDtsA" hash="3pRw3g">Each of us can evaluate ourselves, determine which things are preventing us from taking time to live a gospel principle, then repent and make the necessary adjustments so that we can have time to apply that gospel principle in our lives. If we do so, the Lord has promised that we’ll have an increased understanding of His truths as Enos did. The Savior declared, “If any man will do his will, he shall know of the doctrine, whether it be of God, or whether I speak of myself” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/7.17" class="scriptureRef">John 7:17</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2001/10/writing-gospel-principles-in-our-hearts.p8" pid="cjOjBjp6H0i6QipWEJLTOw" hash="LOnjeg">Making time in our lives to learn, to ponder, and especially to practice gospel principles will bring us the joy and peace which come from the Spirit. The Church will continue to blossom in South America and other parts of the world because more and more members will continue to write gospel principles not with ink, but with the Holy Ghost; not in tablets of stone, but in the fleshy tablets of their hearts. I testify that scriptural truths can develop from intellectual appreciation to our becoming Christlike as we take time to incorporate those truths into our lives. I know the Savior is the Living Christ. Of these things I testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2001/10/writing-gospel-principles-in-our-hearts</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2001-general-conference/2001-10-2060-elder-walter-f-gonzalez-64k-eng.mp3" length="3787543" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2001 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Today Is the Time</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2007/10/today-is-the-time?lang=eng</link>
      <description>What are we doing today to engraven in our souls the gospel principles that will uphold us in times of adversity?</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/today-is-the-time" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00008332_000_021" doc-version="2" hash="dVfalg"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/today-is-the-time.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="TG_VqFZKGkGryRcNc-ccqA" hash="hBrOYw">Today Is the Time</h1><p class="authorName" guid="c35624fb-9c3b-4705-a858-7c921871391d" pid="h6YSp6l1FEGzhDvrPNNOUQ" hash="87_Gmw">Walter F. González</p><p class="kicker" pid="Pu47mDgc4kuUbr387IoCBw" hash="p1vcnQ">What are we doing today to engraven in our souls the gospel principles that will uphold us in times of adversity?</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" guid="a354b63d-8415-4574-a295-dfda3474893c">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/today-is-the-time.t1">
      <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/GONZALEZWF_01.jpg" alt="Elder Walter F. González" guid="37f81593-4a8e-45a3-82ae-51fe49a847f1" pid="Lv4BMzOhokauJ9pJr4pS-A" hash="2wuxsg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/today-is-the-time.p" pid="3k5r_mSD3EqwcLmuJIYGzA" hash="Wy8sfg">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="53"></span>When President James E. Faust informed my wife and me that we would be transferred to Lima, Peru, we had no clue that on August 15, 2007, only a few days after our arrival, we would witness a devastating earthquake. More than 52,000 houses were destroyed by its sheer strength. Worse yet, it left more than 500 dead. Nine of them were members of the Church. Members in the Ica and Pisco stakes and the Cañete and Chincha districts suffered the brunt of the tremor’s aftermath.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/today-is-the-time.p" pid="Gb31_NXUukyoJDSLox0Rpg" hash="VRODug">The Church provided immediate relief to its members and those of other faiths. The morning after the quake, our members in the disaster area were receiving food and clothing, and before noon the Church was donating humanitarian aid to the nation’s civil defense. Many members who were left homeless were sheltered in our meetinghouses. Despite how unexpected the catastrophe was, the priesthood organization functioned very well to bring relief to those less fortunate.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/today-is-the-time.p" pid="ci7OyiCY8Eed0yKE8UimHw" hash="uApItA">Stake and district presidents along with bishops went out to help their members only minutes after the earthquake. The terrible situation in which these priesthood leaders went out is worth highlighting: it was nighttime; the lights were out; destruction abounded; and the earth would not stop shaking. These magnificent priesthood leaders left their families secured and walked out into the darkness, among people who wept, surrounded by destroyed houses. Thus our leaders went out during the night and the following days, facing frequent, strong aftershocks and a tsunami warning. They searched among the rubble, in the midst of commotion, risking their own lives to get to all the members. A bishop declared, “Without as much as a second thought, I ran in search of my Church brothers and sisters and leaders.” He found them. That’s how he spent most of the night.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/today-is-the-time.p" pid="vSmOUQlG50Kgk0I-Nbix8g" hash="hKmuHQ">What motivated these leaders to go out and help others, even to the risking of their own lives? Certainly it was their great faith in the Savior and His Church. It was their understanding of their calling as leaders in the priesthood. It was gospel principles engraved in their lives before the earthquake, not during the crisis—<span class="pageBreak" page-number="54"></span>engraved not with ink but with fire by the Spirit in the fleshy tablets of their hearts (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/2-cor/3.3" class="scriptureRef">2 Corinthians 3:3</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/today-is-the-time.p" pid="JAmj4HR9okCviylU3Q6q0w" hash="ivZAQg">The possibility of an earthquake was always there. When or how it would hit no one knew. When it came, it was devastating. But under the direction of the priesthood, the moment’s challenge was faced. In many cases, when members were unable, the Lord made up the difference. Some members tell of seeing men in white helping to save their lives. Others heard guiding voices. Years of Church service were a preparatory school to becoming organized and helping one another.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/today-is-the-time.p" pid="Y5YLOk5W10aPzLqiHfp0sw" hash="clrqEA">The same happens in our lives. We don’t know when or how earthquakes will hit us. They likely won’t be literal shakings of the earth, as happened in Peru, but rather quakes of temptations, sin, or trials, such as unemployment or serious sickness. Today is the time to prepare for when that type of quake comes. Today is the time to prepare—not during the crisis. What are we doing today to engraven in our souls the gospel principles that will uphold us in times of adversity?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/today-is-the-time.p" pid="wSpcV62mhESxuL7suW7k_A" hash="DcNMeA">For example, what did Joseph who was sold into Egypt plant in his soul to reply, “How then can I do this great wickedness, and sin against God?” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/39.9" class="scriptureRef">Genesis 39:9</a>) when avoiding pressure from Potiphar’s wife to break the law of chastity? What had Nephi planted previously in his soul so that when faced with a commandment from God he was able to answer, “I will go and do, … for I know”? (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/3.7" class="scriptureRef">1 Nephi 3:7</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/today-is-the-time.p" pid="RZ86pzNSSUOoqzLzpZA13A" hash="0a5YbQ">What these great leaders did was allow the Spirit to write gospel principles in their souls. This writing doesn’t happen overnight. Profoundly exposing our souls to the principles of righteousness will make a difference in our preparation for spiritual quakes. This exposure can be enhanced by pondering and by cutting off bad influences.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/today-is-the-time.p" pid="s4ZXFaZKtkGGNDTpxkzksw" hash="tex5hw">Eternal principles will take root in us as we take time not only to read the teachings of the prophets and the scriptures but also to ponder them in the spirit of prayer. Nephi, for example, took time to sit and ponder. By so doing, he was exposed to doctrinal pearls (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/11.1" class="scriptureRef">1 Nephi 11:1</a>). Take the time to do what the Lord has directed us to do: “Treasure these things up in your hearts, and let the solemnities of eternity rest upon your minds” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/43.34" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 43:34</a>). In a world that increasingly demands more of our time, it is essential that we take time to ponder in our homes, so that we may understand divine doctrine and its principles. As the Savior said, “Go ye unto your homes, and ponder upon these things … that ye may understand, and prepare your minds for the morrow” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/17.3" class="scriptureRef">3 Nephi 17:3</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/today-is-the-time.p" pid="T_MBfj0-aEyPMeEfWjnWKQ" hash="lUaHfA">By so doing, our exposure to doctrine and its principles will continue to be enhanced if we also hearken to the Lord’s admonition about bad influences. It is very likely that there are people who pressure us to act or think in a way such that future quakes will find us inappropriately prepared. Regarding this, the Savior gave us a key which will help us better prepare today for the coming vicissitudes. He said, “Therefore, if thy hand offend thee, cut it off; or if thy brother offend thee and confess not and forsake not, he shall be cut off” (Joseph Smith Translation, Mark 9:40).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/today-is-the-time.p" pid="xGSLO5U4D0qYlu6GiUflzg" hash="IFt8qg">Fortunately, the Savior Himself <span class="pageBreak" page-number="55"></span>taught the meaning of cutting off our hand. It’s not about self-mutilation but rather about removing from our lives today those influences that keep us from preparing for tomorrow’s earthquakes. If I have friends who are bad influences for me, the advice is clear: “It is better for thee to enter into life without thy brother, than for thee and thy brother to be cast into hell” (Joseph Smith Translation, Mark 9:41). The Lord applied this same principle when warning Nephi to depart from his brethren who became a dangerous influence (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/5.5" class="scriptureRef">2 Nephi 5:5</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/today-is-the-time.p" pid="Rl9OiVqHy0O54mp7AiwxOg" hash="doQBvQ">It follows that such cutting off refers not only to friends but to every bad influence, such as inappropriate television shows, Internet sites, movies, literature, games, or music. Engraving in our souls this principle will help us to resist the temptation to yield to any bad influence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/today-is-the-time.p" pid="HphoTKbxmEeA6dEWYeUejg" hash="oBh2FA">Enhancing our exposure to doctrine and its principles will make us priesthood holders with deep-rooted gospel values. We will be better prepared to face the tremors that will come without warning, when least expected. As priesthood holders, we will feel the promise made to the prophet Jeremiah extended to us: “For, behold, I have made thee this day a defenced city, and an iron pillar, and brasen walls against the whole land” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/jer/1.18" class="scriptureRef">Jeremiah 1:18</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/today-is-the-time.p" pid="ff8ZV8uoak-OPfPvhk2yTg" hash="x6hbEg">Then we’ll be able to express our gratitude as did Sister Linda Cruzado in Ica. After spending all night exposed to the elements, she wrote, “At daybreak the next day, our Heavenly Father showed His love through a warm sun that came up very early, and at night He comforted us with a very starry night.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/10/today-is-the-time.p" pid="_6qDPXf7S0KabQNF1T1C4Q" hash="IvQIhw">Today is our time to be valiant and decide to give our souls a serious, profound exposure to our Savior’s teachings. I know that He lives, and after we do all we can, He will make up the difference. I so testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div><div class="resources">
    <img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/gospel-library/magazine/GONZALEZWF_01.jpg" alt="Elder Walter F. González" guid="37f81593-4a8e-45a3-82ae-51fe49a847f1" pid="8_I50iCkg0So4zKC9lNdEw" hash="2wuxsg1" />
    <unknown name="digitalAssets" guid="">
      <unknown name="assetGroup" guid="">
        <unknown name="path" guid="37f81593-4a8e-45a3-82ae-51fe49a847f1"></unknown>
      </unknown>
    </unknown>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2007/10/today-is-the-time</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2007-general-conference/2007-10-3040-elder-walter-f-gonzalez-64k-eng.mp3" length="4587244" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2007 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Becoming More Powerful Priesthood Holders</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2009/10/becoming-more-powerful-priesthood-holders?lang=eng</link>
      <description>We can become more powerful in blessing the lives of our Heavenly Father’s sons and daughters, more powerful in serving others.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/becoming-more-powerful-priesthood-holders" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50019113_000_019" doc-version="2" hash="e26fgA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/becoming-more-powerful-priesthood-holders.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="dz9-NGvbpEiF29pcbnpPUw" hash="KvaKYg">Becoming More Powerful Priesthood Holders</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="qmWA3XwSv0-Ol1PH4d_8rA" hash="87_Gmw">Walter F. González</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="26BZbFguMEeCTVb4-bCCVQ" hash="6dTNnA">We can become more powerful in blessing the lives of our Heavenly Father’s sons and daughters, more powerful in serving others.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/becoming-more-powerful-priesthood-holders.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/becoming-more-powerful-priesthood-holders.p1" pid="RnFdm2TeU0OOnnffTyLr0Q" hash="1b25wA">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="50"></span>Many years ago a certain group of worthy priesthood holders taught with great power and authority. One of them was so powerful that it was impossible not to believe his words.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> These priesthood holders helped the people learn about the Savior and His doctrine and helped them find happiness. Their teachings and examples provided a means whereby the people experienced a mighty change of heart. We learn that thousands were led by them to be baptized and make covenants to endure to the end.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> I am speaking about the great Book of Mormon missionaries who were powerful priesthood holders.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/becoming-more-powerful-priesthood-holders.p2" pid="3AolWnqTW0OsWmnnZ2gKTA" hash="nyJ0eA">We can learn a great deal from these children of Lehi. By doing what they did, we can become more powerful in blessing the lives of our Heavenly Father’s sons and daughters, more powerful in serving others, more powerful in rescuing others, and more powerful in becoming more Christlike men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/becoming-more-powerful-priesthood-holders.p3" pid="872wGtV2B0y9zdKxBWz5FQ" hash="ShPMfA">Alma the Younger teaches us one of the things they did to become so successful: they used the records from which the Book of Mormon was taken. When he gave the record that would eventually become the Book of Mormon to his son Helaman, he taught that without these plates, “Ammon and his brethren could not have convinced so many thousands … ; yea, these records and their words brought them unto repentance.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/becoming-more-powerful-priesthood-holders.p4" pid="g0sgjObFLUOOrDFYD5GyCQ" hash="xfmceg">God showed His power through the plates by fulfilling one purpose, “even … the restoration of many <span class="pageBreak" page-number="51"></span>thousands … to the knowledge of the truth.” Alma then prophesied that God would “still show forth his power in them unto future generations.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> Thus, the records were preserved, and you and I are part of those future generations. Just as in the days of old, we can be more powerful priesthood holders by using the Book of Mormon.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/becoming-more-powerful-priesthood-holders.p5" pid="nAg3QOu4mUOG1RtQAJ7dcw" hash="zCbn6Q">The process of bringing to light the Book of Mormon cannot be compared to any literary work by any author in human history. We could say that it is a book that was shepherded by the very finger of our God. During His visit to the ancient Americas, the Lord asked Nephi to bring the records that they were keeping and place them before Him. Jesus then looked at them and commanded that certain events and passages be added.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> “And [the Savior] saith: These scriptures, which ye had not with you, the Father commanded that I should give unto you; for it was wisdom in him that they should be given unto future generations.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> I feel everlasting gratitude to belong to those future generations. I am a member of the Church thanks to the Book of Mormon. I will never forget my feelings when, as a young boy in Uruguay, I read this sacred book for the very first time. I did not have to read much in 1 Nephi to experience such a joy that it cannot be expressed with words. It was as if the book was permeated with the Spirit of the Lord and made me feel closer to God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/becoming-more-powerful-priesthood-holders.p6" pid="rdAoMsekf0-apObcR98C8A" hash="e3gDBg">This experience added meaning to the statement made by the Prophet Joseph Smith about this book when he declared that “a man would get nearer to God by abiding by its precepts, than by any other book.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> I also recognize the relevance of President Thomas S. Monson’s promise when he said that “as we read the Book of Mormon and the other standard works, as we put the teachings to the test, then we will know of the doctrine, for this is our promise; we will know whether it be of man or whether it be of God.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/becoming-more-powerful-priesthood-holders.p7" pid="diBlT0dg7EKtSQYGuVSxbA" hash="pOBQhQ">These promises bring us joy now and in our future. Once I received a testimony of the Book of Mormon, the natural feeling that followed was a desire to apply the teachings of the book by making covenants. I made covenants by being baptized and confirmed a member of the Church. These covenants, made through priesthood ordinances, along with knowledge gained from the Book of Mormon changed my life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/becoming-more-powerful-priesthood-holders.p8" pid="vGCcbckNPEa2X4eQSe98Nw" hash="TUu8pA">It is not surprising that when the Savior visited the ancient Americas, besides teaching doctrine, He gave Nephi and others the power to baptize.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> In other words, the doctrine and the ordinances stood side by side. The full application of the teachings of the Book of Mormon does require priesthood ordinances with their associated covenants.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/becoming-more-powerful-priesthood-holders.p9" pid="vyvE61NL50SWmn6cVeGIMQ" hash="EbWVKw">There are books that are released to the market and quickly become best sellers. Sometimes they generate so much interest that people eagerly await their release. Such books seem to flood the market right away, and you can see people reading them everywhere. God, in His infinite wisdom, reserved the Book of Mormon for our benefit. Its purpose is not to become a best seller. Nevertheless, we can turn this sacred book into a best-read and best-applied book in our life. Let me suggest three activities that can help us turn the Book of Mormon into the best-read and best-applied book, which will empower us today to become more powerful priesthood <span class="pageBreak" page-number="52"></span>holders, even as those in ancient times.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/becoming-more-powerful-priesthood-holders.p10" pid="PFRmoyDTQkKHgpQ2R5zq_w" hash="Hd8Cog">First, feast upon the words of Christ. We must read the Book of Mormon in order to “feast upon the words of Christ; for behold, the words of Christ will tell you all things what ye should do.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> Feasting upon the words of Christ is a unique experience. When we read and look for principles and doctrines that will help us in our daily lives, we will have a renewed enthusiasm. For example, when the rising generation faces challenges in coping with peer pressure, we can read the book looking specifically for teachings that will help them with this kind of challenge. One of those teachings could be taken from Lemuel’s experience. Lemuel made some wrong choices because he yielded to Laman’s pressure.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> He did not do the right thing because he “knew not the dealings of that God who had created them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> A principle that we can draw from this incident is that learning doctrine about how God deals with us will help us to cope with peer pressure. The Book of Mormon has more teachings and examples about this topic, and we are the generations who can benefit from the teachings of this book.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/becoming-more-powerful-priesthood-holders.p11" pid="ipCVJePv1UOWvpsLLa-bGw" hash="Gu3O7A">Second, apply in our lives all that we learn about Christ. Reading the Book of Mormon and looking for attributes of Christ is a great edifying experience. For instance, the brother of Jared recognized that the Lord was a God of truth; therefore, He could not lie.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> What great hope this attribute brings to my soul! All the promises in the Book of Mormon and the promises given by the living prophets today will be fulfilled because He is God and cannot lie. Even in these turbulent times, we know that things will be OK if we follow the teachings learned from the Book of Mormon and the living prophets. Once we learn about an attribute of Christ, such as the one recognized by the brother of Jared, we should work to implement it in our own life. This will help us to become more powerful priesthood holders.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/becoming-more-powerful-priesthood-holders.p12" pid="nsDRM-N710iIFt05MT6e_g" hash="Zae0Ow">Third, teach the doctrine and principles found in the sacred pages of the Book of Mormon. We can teach anyone from this book. Can you imagine the additional “convincing power of God”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> when missionaries and family members quote, read, or repeat by heart the book’s very words?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/becoming-more-powerful-priesthood-holders.p13" pid="3WjzqaSvckWydJ4lQ41PCQ" hash="3EM_fA">I remember a mission in Ecuador whose missionaries used the Book of Mormon in all their comings and goings. Because of them, thousands experienced a mighty change of heart and decided to enter into covenants through sacred priesthood ordinances. The Book of Mormon is a golden instrument in finding and converting the honest seekers of truth and in rescuing many of our brothers and sisters back into gospel activity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/becoming-more-powerful-priesthood-holders.p14" pid="OX44YO5O3Ua9p6sD2nB5EA" hash="Zvu3Kw">I know that families will be fortified by implementing the teachings of this great book in their lives. Many of our children will be saved because they will remember, as Enos did, the words which he had often heard his father speak concerning eternal life, and because of this, he came to know that his sins were forgiven through the Atonement of Christ.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2009/10/becoming-more-powerful-priesthood-holders.p15" pid="XFBZp_BdGkOcYRqDnbI-hg" hash="7k2tiQ">You and I, as part of those future generations spoken about, can be more powerful priesthood holders by using the Book of Mormon and honoring our priesthood covenants. The Book of Mormon testifies of Jesus Christ, of whom I also testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2009/10/becoming-more-powerful-priesthood-holders</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2009-general-conference/2009-10-3020-elder-walter-f-gonzalez-64k-eng.mp3" length="5484160" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2009 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Followers of Christ</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2011/04/followers-of-christ?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Followers of Christ pattern their lives after the Savior to walk in the light.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/followers-of-christ" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD50028768_000_1040" doc-version="2" hash="C2eFrw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/followers-of-christ.head1">
    <h1 class="title" pid="Y0umhPs9xEKl4z0v75-9ug" hash="3c4Naw">Followers of Christ</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="9siZcx2mcUOoayauCXik7w" hash="87_Gmw">Walter F. González</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="KzvxTKy16EWfIS51b-5Z-g" hash="_0xwoQ">Followers of Christ pattern their lives after the Savior to walk in the light.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/followers-of-christ.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/followers-of-christ.p1" pid="qSTzsI2fIE6LaODz6VZ59A" hash="k-EunA">Last October my wife and I accompanied Elder and Sister Neil L. Andersen for the groundbreaking of a new temple in Córdoba, Argentina. As is customary, a press conference followed the ceremony. A journalist, not a member of our church, commented that she had observed how well the men treated their wives. Then she unexpectedly asked, “Is that real or fiction?” I am sure that she saw and felt something different among our members. She might have perceived the desire of our members to follow Christ. Members all over the world have such a desire. At the same time, millions who are not members of the Church also have a desire to follow Him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/followers-of-christ.p2" pid="rM8DeXX96EmsbzyssWj0Yg" hash="E_oG3Q">Recently my wife and I were impressed by the people we saw in Ghana and Nigeria. Most were not members of our church. We were happy to see their desire to follow Christ expressed in many of their conversations in their houses, on their cars, on their walls, and on their billboards. We had never seen so many Christian churches next to one another.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/followers-of-christ.p3" pid="LL3BMXngpUGjyYypU_QkoA" hash="GFyxuw">As Latter-day Saints, ours is the duty to invite millions such as these to come and see what our church can add to the good things that they already have. Any person from any continent, climate, or culture can know for himself or herself that the Prophet Joseph Smith saw the Father and the Son in a vision. He or she can know that heavenly messengers restored the priesthood and that the Book of Mormon is another testament of Jesus Christ. In the words of the Lord to Enoch, “Righteousness [has been sent] down out of heaven; and truth [has been sent] forth out of the earth to [testify of the] Only Begotten [of the Father].”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/followers-of-christ.p4" pid="CcInxT7YkEicQEAB9izFKA" hash="G3xyzw">The Savior has promised, “He that followeth me shall not walk in darkness, but shall have the light of life.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> Followers of Christ pattern their lives after the Savior to walk in the light. Two characteristics can help us recognize to what extent we follow Him. First, followers of Christ are loving people. Second, followers of Christ make and keep covenants.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/followers-of-christ.p5" pid="YfAiCdB7q0KjHqe9Reg2vQ" hash="XBnsSg">The first characteristic, being loving, is probably one thing the journalist in Córdoba noticed among our Church members. We follow Christ because we love Him. When we follow the Redeemer out of love, we are following His own example. Through love the Savior was obedient to the will of the Father under any circumstance. Our Savior was obedient even when it meant great physical and emotional pain, even when it meant being whipped and mocked, even when it meant that His enemies would torture Him while His friends abandoned Him. The atoning sacrifice, which is unique to the mission of the Savior, is the greatest expression of love ever. “The chastisement of our peace was upon him; and with his stripes we are healed.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/followers-of-christ.p6" pid="x-AdMbjLkkeSrQ3NU2M0kg" hash="a1XCDA">As Christ followed the Father under any circumstance, we should follow His Son. If we do so, it matters not what kind of persecution, suffering, grief, or “thorn in the flesh”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span> we face. We are not alone. Christ will assist us. His tender mercies will make us mighty under any circumstance.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/followers-of-christ.p7" pid="og64O_C5t0eZ-W4QUXURwA" hash="-Dwhtg">Following Christ may mean forsaking many dear things, as Ruth the Moabite did. As a new convert, out of love for God and Naomi, she left everything behind to live her religion.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/followers-of-christ.p8" pid="zlTh7xD3GEyq5mAKPp1Yow" hash="Qk1Wag">It may also mean withstanding adversity and temptation. In his youth Joseph was sold into slavery. He was taken away from everything he loved. Later he was tempted to be unchaste. He resisted the temptation and said, “How then can I do this great wickedness, and sin against God?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> His love for God was more powerful than any adversity or temptation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/followers-of-christ.p9" pid="42tzVHOs5k2fdlbDYDFhtw" hash="LWcjrw">Today we have modern Ruths and Josephs all over the world. When Brother Jimmy Olvera from Guayaquil, Ecuador, received his mission call, his family was struggling greatly. The day he was leaving, he was told that if he walked out the door, he would lose his family. With a broken heart he walked out that door. While he was on his mission, his mother asked him to stay longer in the field because they were receiving so many blessings. Today Brother Olvera serves as a stake patriarch.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/followers-of-christ.p10" pid="CJDTtUZf7kimDYaF0iwjHA" hash="uJL1eQ">Truly loving Christ provides the required strength to follow Him. The Lord Himself showed this when He asked Peter three times, “Lovest thou me?” After Peter reaffirmed his love for Him out loud, the Lord told Peter about upcoming difficulties. Then the admonition came: “Follow me.” The Savior’s question to Peter can also be asked of us: “Lovest thou me?” followed by the call to action: “Follow me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/followers-of-christ.p11" pid="QQFR9POznk-DKR-VToxGjQ" hash="kzsAsQ">Love is a powerful influence in our hearts in our effort to be obedient. Love for our Savior inspires us to keep His commandments. Love for a mother, father, or spouse can also inspire our obedience to gospel principles. The way we treat others reflects to what extent we follow our Savior in loving one another.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span> We show our love for Him when we stop to assist others, when we are “perfectly honest and upright in all things,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> and when we make and keep covenants.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/followers-of-christ.p12" pid="50NnHiyTpUOKt0xSc-4jvQ" hash="xXHPCw">The second characteristic that followers of Christ have is making and keeping covenants, as He did. Moroni pointed out that “the shedding of the blood of Christ … is in the covenant of the Father unto the remission of your sins, that ye become holy, without spot.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/followers-of-christ.p13" pid="CwMaRetUE0iVRKx2zDzTsg" hash="cOLU9Q">The Prophet Joseph Smith taught that even before the organization of this earth, covenants were made in heaven.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> Ancient prophets and patriarchs made covenants.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/followers-of-christ.p14" pid="5c_7-ONt90m5LoUg2baqOQ" hash="-FKjPA">The Savior Himself gave the example. He was baptized to fulfill all righteousness by one with the proper authority. Through His baptism, the Savior witnessed unto the Father that He would be obedient in keeping all the Father’s commandments.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> As in days of old, we also follow Christ and make covenants through priesthood ordinances.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/followers-of-christ.p15" pid="7ID_rjzeT0W9QN2CN-VrsA" hash="bGOrTA">Making covenants is something that millions who are not members of our church can add to the very good things that they already have. Making covenants is an expression of love. It is a way of saying to Him, “Yes, I will follow Thee because I love Thee.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/followers-of-christ.p16" pid="H83TzH5Rg02QiejgoGAL-w" hash="aEcROg">Covenants include promises, “even of life eternal.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span> All things will work together for our good if we remember our covenants.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> They must be made and kept to fully receive the promises they provide. Love for the Savior and remembering our covenants will help us keep them. Partaking of the sacrament is one way to remember them.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> Another way is to attend the temple often. I remember a young married couple in South America who wanted to separate because they could not get along. A priesthood leader counseled them to attend the temple and pay specific attention to the words and promises of the covenants made there. They did so and their marriage was saved. The power of our covenants is greater than any challenge we face or we may face.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/followers-of-christ.p17" pid="1454CpfRFUiaR3NhFRCs_w" hash="Bu7P4Q">To those members who are not active in the gospel, please come back. Feel the blessing of remembering and renewing covenants through the sacrament and temple attendance. Doing so is an expression of love and shows a willingness to be a true follower of Christ. It will qualify you to receive all the promised blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/followers-of-christ.p18" pid="4EfYK18NbEypo5BntW3LNw" hash="p-Judw">To those who are not members of our church, I invite you to exercise faith, repent, and qualify to receive the covenant of baptism in The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. By doing so, you will show your love to our Heavenly Father and your willingness to follow Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2011/04/followers-of-christ.p19" pid="p2hH4L8UGEaVnspsyPh3Fw" hash="jUUKqw">I testify that we are happier when we follow the teachings of the gospel of Jesus Christ. As we strive to follow Him, the blessings of heaven will come unto us. I know His promises will be fulfilled as we make and keep covenants and become true followers of Christ. I testify of His great love for each one of us, and I do so in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2011/04/followers-of-christ</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2011-general-conference/2011-04-1040-elder-walter-f-gonzalez-64k-eng.mp3" length="5030194" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning with Our Hearts</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2012/10/learning-with-our-hearts?lang=eng</link>
      <description>One way to come unto Christ is by seeking to learn essential truths with our hearts.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/learning-with-our-hearts" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10491_000_44gonzalez" doc-version="2" hash="dzmCFQ"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/learning-with-our-hearts.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="zDWQS87_eEeXVNZ7ZeH6IA" hash="bcs_iw">Learning with Our Hearts</h1><p class="authorName" pid="sQHmFBQKZkK6xJGb3rPltg" hash="0TBNcw">By Elder Walter F. González</p><p class="kicker" pid="7E-SvO8DNk20SItACsrf8w" hash="jz5Ixw">One way to come unto Christ is by seeking to learn essential truths with our hearts.</p></div><div class="bodyBlock" pid="5o69w-zSHEKtcE5t_KmklQ" hash="ChHmfw">
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/learning-with-our-hearts.p5" pid="BSUDk63lykuSLPh5hQc_Vw" hash="3H2k-w">
      <span class="pageBreak" page-number="81"></span>“Come unto me, that ye might feel and see.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span> This was a commandment that the Savior extended to the inhabitants of ancient America. They felt with their hands and saw with their eyes that Jesus was the Christ. This commandment is just as important for us today as it was for them in their day. As we come unto Christ, we can feel and “know of a surety”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span>—not with our hands and eyes but with all our heart and mind—that Jesus is the Christ.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/learning-with-our-hearts.p6" pid="tXAkTlqa8EeXxP6VLY07xA" hash="O-70ag">One way to come unto Christ is by seeking to learn essential truths with our hearts. As we do so, impressions that come from God will give us knowledge that we cannot get by any other means. The Apostle Peter knew of a surety that Jesus was the Christ, the Son of the living God. The Savior explained that the source for Peter’s knowledge was not “flesh and blood … but [the] Father which is in heaven.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/learning-with-our-hearts.p7" pid="BEiDinnCkEOzJnd-g2jzEw" hash="QNcoKA">The prophet Abinadi explained the role of the feelings that come from God to our hearts. He taught that we cannot understand the scriptures completely unless we apply our heart to understanding.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/learning-with-our-hearts.p8" pid="K7lP0tXw-kSK8O__fqyo_w" hash="gXwZog">This truth was well stated in a children’s book, <span class="emphasis">The Little Prince</span> by Antoine de Saint-Exupéry. In the story, the little prince became friends with a fox. Upon parting, the fox shared a secret with the little prince. He said, “Here is my secret … : It is only with the heart that one can see rightly; what is essential is invisible to the eye.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span></p>
    <span class="story">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/learning-with-our-hearts.p9" pid="Lykn2YCkzE2d2QTC4iP7Ag" hash="WntE-A">Eighty-eight-year-old Brother Thomas Coelho is a good example of one who saw with his heart essential things. He was a faithful member of our high council in Paysandú, Uruguay. Prior to joining the Church, he had an accident while riding his motorcycle. While he was lying on the ground unable to stand, two of our missionaries helped him stand up and return to his home. He said that he felt something special when the missionaries came to his rescue. Later he experienced strong feelings again when the missionaries taught him. The impact of those feelings was such that he read the Book of Mormon from cover to cover in just a few days. He was baptized and served tirelessly from that day forward. I remember him riding his motorcycle up and down the streets of our city, even in the cold and rainy winters, to bring others to church so they could feel, see, and know of a surety as he did.</p>
    </span>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/learning-with-our-hearts.p10" pid="IGmJiM4cOUOKEVBc9rEpFw" hash="1Fwl0A">Today, surrounded by so much information, we might think that navigating millions of web pages will give us all that we need to know. We can find good and bad information on the web, but information alone is not enough. God has given us another source for greater knowledge,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> even knowledge sent from heaven. Our Heavenly Father can give us such knowledge when we navigate the celestial web in our hearts and minds. The Prophet Joseph Smith said that he had “the oldest book in [his] heart, even the gift of the Holy Ghost.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/learning-with-our-hearts.p11" pid="IIBfrRF_ZkOWKHu6fa6itw" hash="xZvaxw">We access this celestial source when we do things such as reading the scriptures, hearkening to the living prophet, and praying. It is also important to take time to be still<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span> and feel and follow the celestial promptings. When we do this, we will “feel and see” things that cannot be learned with modern technology. Once we have some experience in navigating this celestial web, we will discern the truth, even when reading secular history or other topics. The honest seekers of truth will know the truth of all things by the power of the Holy Ghost.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/learning-with-our-hearts.p12" pid="uL1095N1OEadtbxnR2jMqg" hash="49f9HQ">Now, a word of caution: access to this celestial web is marred by iniquity and forgetting the Lord. Nephi told his brothers that they “could not feel [the Lord’s] words” because they were “swift to do iniquity [and] slow to remember the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span> Iniquity hampers our ability to see, feel, and love others. Being quick to remember the Lord by praying “with all the energy of heart”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span> and bringing to mind our spiritual experiences <span class="pageBreak" page-number="82"></span>expands our ability to see and feel the things of Christ. Now I ask you:</p>
    <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/learning-with-our-hearts.f1"><ul class="bullet" guid=""><li pid="_-voT6iriUqZxawWdSEucA" hash="PPgBGw">
        <span class="label">•</span>
        <p pid="4vVE8iEyT0iJhbgv9709ng" hash="oVeHbg">Do you remember the peace you felt when, after much tribulation, you cried out unto the Father in mighty prayer?</p>
      </li><li pid="eK_KU-F2qkiZ5tjT4JDCsA" hash="Yfz8DA">
        <span class="label">•</span>
        <p pid="5muvYct5SEaA07a478h0rQ" hash="bi76sw">Do you remember changing your to-do list to follow a prompting in your heart?</p>
      </li></ul></div>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/learning-with-our-hearts.p15" pid="Ovo2RfsGoUCufNyyHC0a-g" hash="gCdN6w">The great men in the Book of Mormon fostered access to a greater knowledge by bringing to mind their key spiritual experiences. Alma fortified and strengthened his children by reminding them about his conversion experience.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> Helaman taught Nephi and Lehi to remember—to remember that it was upon the rock of Christ that they had to build their foundation so the devil would have no power over them.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> We must do the same. Remembering God helps us to feel and live. This gives deeper meaning to the words of King Benjamin, who said, “And now, O man, remember, and perish not.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/learning-with-our-hearts.p16" pid="vTnG0JE2VUWFJjfHNgLR-g" hash="1_rW-Q">One of the most sacred memories I cherish is the feeling I had when I came to know the Book of Mormon was the word of God. I learned that we can experience a joy that words fall short to express. That very day, on my knees, I felt and knew of a surety the things that I could not have learned in any other way. Such a memory is reason for everlasting gratitude and strengthens me in hard times.</p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/learning-with-our-hearts.p17" pid="Hd8gSN0cKUSHptvxmcKsqw" hash="0C2sUA">Those who receive knowledge not from flesh and blood but from our Heavenly Father do know of a surety that Jesus is the Christ and this is His Church. That very knowledge provides strength to make necessary changes to come unto Christ. For this reason, we invite every soul to be baptized, repent, and turn unto Him now.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/learning-with-our-hearts.p18" pid="eKI1fbAWiUWDyxfyHOhHNw" hash="WvkuDw">By coming unto Christ, every soul can see, feel, and know of a surety that Christ suffered and atoned for our sins that we may have eternal life. If we repent, we will not suffer needlessly.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span> Thanks to Him, wounded souls may be healed and broken hearts may be mended. There is no burden that He cannot ease or remove. He knows about our infirmities and sicknesses. I promise and testify to you that when all doors seem to be closed, when everything else seems to fail, He will not fail you. Christ will help and is the way out, whether the struggle is with an addiction, depression, or something else. He knows “how to succor his people.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> Marriages and families that are struggling for whatever reason—economic challenges, bad media influences, or family dynamics—will feel a calming influence from heaven. It is comforting to “feel and see” that He rose from the dead “with healing in his wings,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> that because of Him, we will meet and embrace again those beloved ones who have passed away. Verily our conversion unto Him is rewarded with our healing.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span></p>
    <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2012/10/learning-with-our-hearts.p19" pid="M4QBY4tR7kCnFhv_DbFNaA" hash="OiMGVQ">I know of a surety that all of this is true. For this reason I join my voice with that of the early inhabitants of ancient America, exclaiming: “Hosanna! Blessed be the name of the Most High God!”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> He gives us salvation. I bear witness that Jesus is the Christ, the holy Messiah. He is the Lord of Hosts, our Savior and Redeemer. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2012/10/learning-with-our-hearts</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-2012-general-conference/2012-10-4040-elder-walter-f-gonzalez-64k-eng.mp3" length="5013997" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
