<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By William R. Bradford</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by William R. Bradford.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/William%20R.%20Bradford.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by William R. Bradford.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 1975 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>We Are Sent for the Last Time</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1975/10/we-are-sent-for-the-last-time?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters, I’m overwhelmed by this occasion and the circumstances that bring me here. A few nights ago my wife and I stood together over a telephone in Santiago, Chile. We were holding each other and weeping openly after having rec</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/we-are-sent-for-the-last-time" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03063_000_026" doc-version="3" hash="-9nVfA"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/we-are-sent-for-the-last-time.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="0mzVWQRS50KSOxCT_RPB1Q" hash="E35HVA">We Are Sent for the Last Time</h1><p class="authorName" pid="dWbtLrIq6Ua3IhdqTRgMXA" hash="zkXG1g">William R. Bradford</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/we-are-sent-for-the-last-time.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2ba2.jpg" alt="Elder William R. Bradford" pid="Mmnk1KSGGEWDejnA8DeZmA" hash="FEz8Ug" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/we-are-sent-for-the-last-time.p1" pid="lTB3VsebqES8XVl39LTEXg" hash="un9JYA">My dear brothers and sisters, I’m overwhelmed by this occasion and the circumstances that bring me here. A few nights ago my wife and I stood together over a telephone in Santiago, Chile. We were holding each other and weeping openly after having received a call from President Kimball to serve in this sacred quorum.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/we-are-sent-for-the-last-time.p2" pid="couTGiCMzEiFrNFVykfaLQ" hash="fV2oSw">I confess my weakness before you. I know, however, that the Lord will build a strength of armor and power around those who seek his Spirit. Throughout my life, my decisions have been influenced by a whispering voice saying, “Come, follow me.” It is a great honor and privilege to obey as the Spirit directs. I assure you that the channel is open that this might happen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/we-are-sent-for-the-last-time.p3" pid="_w4E-F_AokWQYU6PEC-RpA" hash="HltVUA">I pay homage to my family and forefathers for their devotion in caring for the gospel in its infancy, from the Restoration until now, and for their struggle to preserve Zion in some of its tender moments. I pray that I might always honor their sacred and holy names. My father and mother will leave in just a few days to start their third full-time mission. Their love and example have had profound influence on my life. My father taught me not to be a toe-dipper, but to plunge into the good things of life, to bathe all over in the sea of the gospel. My mother has taken me to that seashore every day of my life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/we-are-sent-for-the-last-time.p4" pid="Ekw1K43JGU2hwDnIbUta3A" hash="um5jyw">How can a man put into words the love in his heart for his eternal wife and sweetheart and for the priceless joy that the children she gives him bring. This is a sacred joy. It’s the joy the scriptures tell us about when they say, “And men are, that they might have joy.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.25" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:25</a>.) Our companionship brings great tenderness to this mortality.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/we-are-sent-for-the-last-time.p5" pid="NYb_damiRUKxhXqgJTdGcA" hash="V5h3lg">During the new mission presidents’ seminar which was held in June, my wife and I had the privilege to be taught by President Kimball and many of the other General Authorities. President Kimball penetrated our minds with the fact that this is a time for reaping: the harvest is upon us. The hour has come to gather the wheat from among the tares. Most of my life I have been closely associated with planting and harvesting. I know the anxiety in the heart of the planter when the tares are overtaking the wheat.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/we-are-sent-for-the-last-time.p6" pid="1qqA3JTlLUqnaR5k78UIhg" hash="09wSOw">The Lord has said, “Therefore, let the wheat and the tares grow together until the harvest is fully ripe; then ye shall first gather out the wheat from among the tares, and after the gathering of the wheat, behold and lo, the tares are bound in bundles, and the field remaineth to be burned.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/86.7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 86:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/we-are-sent-for-the-last-time.p7" pid="1Tx2wxEpYU6DEOw619Uuhg" hash="7GOXDQ">The harvest is fully ripe. We are now sent for the last time to gather it in. The sickle is in our hands. We must use it while the day lasts. I feel the word of the Lord being fulfilled. In the Chile Santiago Mission, 120 missionaries, thirty-two of them native Chileans serving in their own land, baptized 220 people during the month of September. Among these there were forty families. The missionaries in Chile love to follow the prophet.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/we-are-sent-for-the-last-time.p8" pid="A67iMmH560mBrHISGJyyBA" hash="peuXhA">I am honored to be one of the workers. I take great comfort in knowing that the Savior directs this work, that his direction comes when the living prophet and those who follow him listen and hear the voice as it is dictated by the Holy Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/we-are-sent-for-the-last-time.p9" pid="ajghELktvEyNJAbL78Ce4w" hash="-b-7sQ">I bear solemn witness that this work is true, that President Kimball has the vision of its completion. With a repentant spirit I present myself to the Lord. I dedicate all my strength and whatever gifts the Lord has blessed me with to be used in his service, as I am directed by the prophet and by the holy men who serve in these general quorums. I testify to you that they are holy men, called to direct the reaping down of the harvest. I express my profound love for the prophet and tell you that I know in a very special way that he takes direction from a true and living God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/we-are-sent-for-the-last-time.p10" pid="yE5GtZ8rMU6zxB1ZJpMcpw" hash="J3iHeg">I am drawn to the Lord’s words to Joseph Smith and Oliver Cowdery when he said, “Fear not to do good, my sons, or whatsoever ye sow, that shall ye also reap; therefore, if ye sow good ye shall also reap good for your reward.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/we-are-sent-for-the-last-time.p11" pid="-81Th48RJkehziVFZAViNA" hash="6GacFA">“Therefore, fear not, little flock; do good; let earth and hell combine against you, for if ye are built upon my rock, they cannot prevail. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/we-are-sent-for-the-last-time.p12" pid="e827m7dbVE6l9I-_Sx0ZVw" hash="cQ9zGw">“Look unto me in every thought; doubt not, fear not.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/we-are-sent-for-the-last-time.p13" pid="VRYqTH1KVE-eidBh5BQKhw" hash="iSRvXg">“Behold the wounds which pierced my side, and also the prints of the nails in my hands and feet; be faithful, keep my commandments, and ye shall inherit the kingdom of heaven.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/6.33-34,36-37" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 6:33–34, 36–37</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/10/we-are-sent-for-the-last-time.p14" pid="9uhlp_AFgEWUuw1EHSTLgw" hash="0V5teQ">I bear solemn witness that this church is true, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1975/10/we-are-sent-for-the-last-time</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1975-general-conference/1975-10-4050-elder-william-r-bradford-64k-eng.mp3" length="6017824" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 1975 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are We Following Christ’s Pattern?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I commend unto you all these great men who have radiated the brilliant light of the truths of the gospel of Jesus Christ during the proceedings of this conference. The truth that has been shown forth here during these proceedings of this conference s</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03070_000_043" doc-version="2" hash="EA6_cQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="PkGP1zA5RUGdvXucrrcT6A" hash="EcKncg">Are We Following Christ’s Pattern?</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="hnj1KNYFaESjuzMnYCxenQ" hash="zkXG1g">William R. Bradford</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2ba2.jpg" alt="Elder William R. Bradford" pid="eMNWYCPb-kWNCv7kAtGWoA" hash="FEz8Ug" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p1" pid="DHYWi6tcs0uEqaUKMf-EAg" hash="_42MFQ">I commend unto you all these great men who have radiated the brilliant light of the truths of the gospel of Jesus Christ during the proceedings of this conference. The truth that has been shown forth here during these proceedings of this conference should gladden the hearts and calm the souls of all those who will set their course in life by it, that they might travel in perfect safety through a world that is darkened by the teachings of Satan.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p2" pid="XZfsTX0fQ0qCC__P_iTuJw" hash="PTcCcg">The Master Jesus Christ has set the pattern in all things. He has called all men to follow his pattern with this decree:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p3" pid="5bpaHId4rkWphQHAyYGRCw" hash="FsHqrQ">“Verily, verily, I say unto you, this is my gospel; and ye know the things that ye must do in my church; for the works which ye have seen me do that shall ye also do; for that which ye have seen me do even that shall ye do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p4" pid="vjT5Gc3oRkaKD4EYJgPbUg" hash="VC7sCA">“Therefore, what manner of men ought ye to be? Verily I say unto you, even as I am.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/27.21,27" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 27:21, 27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p5" pid="FRnSSN4CoEm0Q2ZU6vtPow" hash="muNuDg">Now may I ask you, does your life follow this pattern? May I point out to you a few parts of the pattern and suggest that you compare your life to them?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p6" pid="lalUPr4tVUu52VhJnT9heQ" hash="vmK75A">By what name are you called?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p7" pid="wa_pPlsl0kidcKT1OLlFrg" hash="KOz8vA">“Behold, Jesus Christ is the name which is given of the Father, and there is none other name given whereby man can be saved.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/18.23" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 18:23</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p8" pid="89mvB-t17ke0u1ciNrvK0w" hash="yOlDVg">Do the things which you think and do entitle you to bear the name of Jesus Christ? Does your love for that holy name inspire and lift you to lofty heights and cause desires within you to want all the world to know of him and receive for themselves his sacred name? Do you feel a sharp pain, as if a dagger had pierced your heart, when you hear the name of the Son of God taken in vain? Do you ever walk through doors where he would never enter? Have you kept his name unsullied and spotless so that because of you it has not been allowed to come in contact with that which is base and unbefitting? In his name are you builders of his kingdom? No man can serve two masters. Men must either declare themselves as Christ’s servants, take upon themselves his name, and do his work, or fall victim to the enticing trap of Satan, helping him in his work of destruction.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p9" pid="ZbplQCHw60ChtNChDZhOhg" hash="xVkSIQ">What about your love for the Father? Christ loved the Father. He prayed to him. He praised him. He represents him in all he does. He serves him and delights to do his work. He obeys perfectly his every instruction. If we would be like Christ, we too must do these things, for hasn’t he said, “For that which ye have seen me do even that shall ye do”? (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/27.21" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 27:21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p10" pid="uLomeLZfAkOhPv2BB6maFA" hash="-7X5dA">What is your relationship with your fellowman? The Master again has set the pattern:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p11" pid="7kCN6gkKAkCOgcbfHshOPA" hash="hfAxBQ">“Wherefore, hear my voice and follow me. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p12" pid="6k27ArQ2IkuV9Zb60xiFlQ" hash="dYQ7Jw">“And let every man esteem his brother as himself, and practise virtue and holiness before me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p13" pid="cL4HD62BkEW9uddmO3hRIQ" hash="X5QXXQ">“And again I say unto you, let every man esteem his brother as himself.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p14" pid="47dsPKUr-UOVpsz1cuGtaQ" hash="s7cgRA">“… I say unto you, be one; and if ye are not one ye are not mine.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/38.22,24-25,27" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 38:22, 24–25, 27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p15" pid="Bf5QHmxmN06SFlheiUvGnw" hash="po95dw">Do you really love the people around you? Love is the only element that can tenderize the human heart. The love that Christ has for us caused that he become a willing sacrifice, to suffer and die for us. It should humble the most proud when they ponder the magnitude of what he did for all mankind as he suffered in the garden. As he revealed that event, he said to us, “Which suffering caused myself, even God, the greatest of all, to tremble because of pain, and to bleed at every pore, and to suffer both body and spirit—and would that I might not drink the bitter cup, and shrink—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p16" pid="61ODxP3yoUqvCcOpXBOcAg" hash="1m1hWQ">“Nevertheless, glory be to the Father, and I partook and finished my preparations unto the children of men.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/19.18-19" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 19:18–19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p17" pid="X8wfFvXlOEuru9mroYUKrw" hash="laRekw">How much of yourself do you give to your fellowmen?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p18" pid="uhYDq4_RFUqe0g2UFsu53A" hash="u9JBOQ">Have you followed the pattern Christ set for baptism? He taught the absolute need for all men to be baptized:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p19" pid="3GKR3kU4ikKmjnnlWaIPPA" hash="3WP-Ig">“And whoso believeth in me, and is baptized, the same shall be saved; and they are they who shall inherit the kingdom of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p20" pid="lFBFVPpGKkmyRfBdoYVEpQ" hash="UswSJA">“And whoso believeth not in me, and is not baptized, shall be damned.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.33-34" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:33–34</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p21" pid="rAtvnjD4I0aixx6f1QC2Cw" hash="90HNFQ">There are many who mock and scoff at this vital ordinance. It has been changed to fit the convenience of men or, in some instances, has been cast aside entirely as a thing of no significance. Much of the world embraces the false and wicked teachings of Satan, who says God is dead, and therefore, his church is dead, and its ordinances are not of any value. And thus, only a comparatively few have taken upon themselves the name of Christ and entered into his kingdom through the waters of baptism.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p22" pid="tNnyN65vP0KmQCKBv_FGaw" hash="ajskkA">The message of this church to all men everywhere is the same as has been preached by Jesus Christ from the beginning.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p23" pid="9D8mZniH4ECPv2OKAd9Lqg" hash="paImwg">Repent and be baptized. Christ was. And “what manner of men ought ye to be? Verily I say unto you, even as I am.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/27.27" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 27:27</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p24" pid="4gENE1xEs0q-WOPOmufO5A" hash="OSchbw">To be like Jesus Christ demands that men change. In all earnestness and sincerity of heart, I exhort you to change and be like the Master.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p25" pid="HXv6pnmx2Eaw4ZmXT5pq8A" hash="KqSltg">You fathers, change and direct the affairs of your families as if Christ were at the helm.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p26" pid="oTiPceAjXkWWjJIUWtsDvw" hash="9xOrBQ">You mothers, give love, honor, and respect to your husbands and practice Christlike acts. Expel the ungodly from the confines of your home, and maintain it as a sanctuary where your children will learn of God by word and deed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p27" pid="W_X0CEdLFEOQd11RyISnqg" hash="oIoKyA">You children, make following Christ the “in” thing to do. Reject the filth of pornography and the poisons of drugs and alcohol. Be a companion with Christ, and he will draw near unto you and be your best friend. There is no better friend than Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p28" pid="CG_cbI0XlkG15J5ybgwVnQ" hash="4X_-Vw">You young adults, you are the best of any generation. Maintain your purity. Be the standard bearers in the great move to bring all men unto the Master. Prepare your minds by filling them with the eternal truths contained in the holy scriptures. Be obedient to parents and to God. Listen to and sing the music of heaven. Reject the vulgar and base sounds and beats of Satan’s music. He would like to gain your favor with his sensual and carnal rhythms and thereby lead you down to hell. Resist temptation by building a strong relationship with Jesus Christ. No other relationship will give you greater joy and happiness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p29" pid="GKn9AEG8iUaJam3r5UYf0g" hash="YciGkA">To all of you within the sound of my voice who are not following the pattern of the Master, change. Open your hearts to his love. Open your doors to his servants. Let them come into your homes and teach you what you must do to be like him. To reject his servants, who are sent forth to do his work and teach his pattern for salvation, will cause you to be left in darkness and despair in a troubled world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern.p30" pid="LIG8GIbhKUmoObgKgiRlvw" hash="-16FVw">I testify that Jesus Christ directs the righteous affairs of this earth, that Spencer W. Kimball is a living prophet and receives and follows the instruction of the Master for the salvation of all men who will follow him. That we may do so is my constant prayer, in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1976/04/are-we-following-christs-pattern</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1976-general-conference/1976-04-7020-elder-william-r-bradford-64k-eng.mp3" length="9948454" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 1976 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Safety of the Gospel Law</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law?lang=eng</link>
      <description>On this occasion I speak with a profound desire that what I say will in some way help us to gain peace in this world and eternal life in the world to come.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03089_000_026" doc-version="2" hash="7WZ5Kw"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="vIq7BtSRLkGDuJTxmdWs1A" hash="E4NJPA">The Safety of the Gospel Law</h1><p class="authorName" pid="KuSX7mjIg0meGg4WhQ5L-w" hash="zkXG1g">William R. Bradford</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2ba2.jpg" alt="Elder William R. Bradford" pid="Jz4itaS6jEi6AKVxf2k93g" hash="FEz8Ug" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p1" pid="NwOJMhnBrEOF_itlAM5ZTQ" hash="D-Hx-w">On this occasion I speak with a profound desire that what I say will in some way help us to gain peace in this world and eternal life in the world to come.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p2" pid="8ObNu_rG50yA_jfhzgDIHg" hash="eV6-0g">All men are brothers in the spirit. The Tower of Babel had no effect on the language of the Spirit. Therefore, if I speak by the Spirit and you listen by the Spirit, the weakness of my spoken word will be transcended, and we will understand together.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p3" pid="tzvcGzd3YkOm9ZvocN_w0Q" hash="066JPQ">I’m not a scientist, but this I have learned since those first totterings and falls as a babe that the law of gravity exists. I have never seen gravity, only its effects. Even so, it is obvious to me that it is in all things, that it is above all things, below all things, round about all things, and that all physical things are held in their positions and controlled in their spheres by this law.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p4" pid="iWmi7rutvEKwVC6FsLrrYQ" hash="nnukdA">The law of gravity has its limits and conditions. All of the inventions and movements of man take into account these conditions. If a man falls from a high place, he must descend; it matters not his motives. He may have jumped or it might have been an accident; it matters not. For the law of gravity cannot be frustrated, and so he must fall and suffer the destructive consequences.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p5" pid="vkMQtUqMZk-iVbE1EXtuSQ" hash="4vjH1w">Men who jump from airplanes have discovered a saving device. It is called the parachute. With proper study and application of this device, man, falling through space, can be saved.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p6" pid="KrZ5FFI_iUqlUNhErwiMqw" hash="x0c2-A">If a man jumps from an airplane without a parachute, he must fall to his destruction. It matters not that he <span class="emphasis">knows</span> the saving power of the parachute. If he does not have one on and open it as he falls, he will not be saved, for the law of gravity cannot be defied. By this we can clearly see that not only is the knowledge of a saving law necessary for salvation but also the application of it in our lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p7" pid="0_P9Rba6_kCo3rwzItKhFA" hash="lhJMuA">Consider what would happen if the law of gravity were suspended from over the face of the earth for twenty seconds. An awesome thought isn’t it, considering that it would cause the total disorganization of all things that exist hereon?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p8" pid="Vc3ELEz7qU2N-ukELkK9hw" hash="j0QE8g">No, I am not a scientist, but I know, like you, that gravity is in all things, above all things, and that it surrounds all things. I have never seen it, but I have seen and felt its effects.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p9" pid="AnqMWBeTLEWvLd_vrrXTLw" hash="CRTtxg">There is another law of which I will speak. It is a greater and more encompassing law than gravity. In fact, the law of gravity is only one among a totality of laws encompassed within it. It is the law of the gospel of Jesus Christ. I have never seen this law, but, like gravity, I have seen its effects and felt its powerful influence in my life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p10" pid="0uGiI3sGbkGAPUpLXTDzPQ" hash="UqUVyw">This is the law of the Son of God, even Jesus Christ, “The light and the Redeemer of the World; the Spirit of truth, who came into the world, because the world was made by him, and in him was the life of men and the light of men.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p11" pid="rOOk7o33q0qU7S9PoRd6QA" hash="H7gaWQ">“The worlds were made by him; <span class="emphasis">men were made by him;</span> all things were made by him, and through him, and of him.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/93.9-10" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 93:9–10</a>; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p12" pid="G1GkI7RU80KiK55cfafHIA" hash="Urd_Qg">He would have us know that “that which is governed by law is also preserved by law and perfected and sanctified by the same.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.34" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:34</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p13" pid="fc1pR0DdJ0652iILHyL6cQ" hash="qbCVsQ">But he adds this stem caution, that “that which breaketh a law, and abideth not by law, but seeketh to become a law unto itself, and willeth to abide in sin, and altogether abideth in sin, cannot be sanctified by law, neither by mercy, justice, nor judgment. Therefore, they must remain filthy still.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.35" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:35</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p14" pid="N1_0JM5SaU6KcBH0z_zCPg" hash="z0T4Fw">“He comprehendeth all things, and all things are before him, and all things are round about him; and he is above all things, and in all things, and is through all things, and is round about all things; and all things are by him, and of him, even God, forever and ever.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.41" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:41</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p15" pid="TQKm10xpkE6LTIk1MRm5TQ" hash="lAwOcw">Suppose the law of the gospel of Jesus Christ was suspended from over the face of the earth for twenty seconds. An awesome thought isn’t it, considering that all other laws—even the law of gravity—are encompassed within this all-inclusive law and that it would cause the instantaneous disorganization of all that exists hereon.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p16" pid="Xpta146kg0-P9gufuxVsww" hash="7Ryu-g">But the law of the gospel of Jesus Christ will not be suspended from over the face of the earth, because “the works, and the designs, and the purposes of God cannot be frustrated, neither can they come to naught.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/3.1" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 3:1</a>.) And so that which is governed by law will continue to be preserved by law, and that which will not obey the conditions of law will not be justified in salvation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p17" pid="WpGKpOA-X0ObkO8lS0YsUg" hash="OH1L2g">Jesus Christ “hath given a law unto all things, by which they move in their times and their seasons.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.42" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:42</a>.) And, “Unto every kingdom is given a law; and unto every law there are certain bounds also and conditions.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.38" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:38</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p18" pid="Kk86dPabIk-_2L4nJljBTQ" hash="y7eA6Q">“All beings who abide not in those conditions are not justified.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.39" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:39</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p19" pid="rEZ9j-D8m0-GQE_oPJbQzw" hash="B9ogaA">The law of the gospel of Jesus Christ has decreed that every man must repent and be baptized by immersion, after the pattern of the Lawgiver, or he cannot be saved.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p20" pid="eRq0phQH-0itGdK9h9bufA" hash="RcyjXw">Is a man, therefore, justified if he holds himself outside the conditions of this law?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p21" pid="-w_QYd6FUkC_TZH6HQHMvQ" hash="KSvZ6Q">Parents are required by the law of the gospel to teach their children to understand the doctrine of repentance; to have faith in Christ, the Son of the living God; and pray and walk uprightly before the Lord; and to go into the waters of baptism at the age of accountability.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p22" pid="iDVS8Dpt3kKk5SgNEb80-w" hash="ed9WsA">Wherein, then, is the justification for the parents who abandon this sacred law and, as though it were the accepted thing to do, abdicate their would-be thrones, whereon, had they been faithful and obedient, they might have reigned as gods, with their own children as the princes and princesses of their kingdom?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p23" pid="i1JaFE7zDU6EbuKjWD-GBA" hash="yPjQYQ">As a binding clause to the law, the Lord has commanded, “Send forth the elders of my church unto the nations which are afar off; unto the islands of the sea; send forth unto foreign lands; call upon all nations, first upon the Gentiles, and then upon the Jews.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/133.8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 133:8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p24" pid="tjBS4wZ51EODeah0gz32gg" hash="W5X98w">Will it, therefore, be justified for any who are these designated elders to put self before the law and shirk the clarion call from the prophet, who is the mouthpiece of God, who would send them out empowered to teach a falling world the saving laws of the gospel of Jesus Christ? And what of those called to prepare them for their hour of departure if they are not faithful in their charge?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p25" pid="TeHojB6h1EyH9tXZk3RiiA" hash="JGNI_w">Saddest of all, perhaps, are those who will not study the law of the gospel contained in the holy scriptures. They are like the optimist who, having fallen from a high building, said as he passed each window, “So far everything’s all right” or like the man sliding down the roof saying “Help, Lord, I’m falling! Help, Lord, I’m falling! never mind, Lord, I’m caught, caught on a nail.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p26" pid="KdlfSfJExUSWQx_fLLB-mg" hash="rX-gcg">We could talk about the law of sacrifice and service to one another, moral cleanliness, tithes and offerings, honesty. Indeed, we could review all the many laws that together comprise the law of the gospel. But perhaps enough has been pointed out to draw focus on their exactness, the protection and salvation they provide us if we obey, and the serious consequences for noncompliance.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p27" pid="nz1Lfo1k8kykrQYVURQoqg" hash="Pyd9aA">Now, my beloved brothers and sisters, does the law of gravity exist? Does it have effect in your life? If you jump from a high place, will your body not fall? Can you defy gravity? Can you step outside of its control?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p28" pid="Yn09B7f7UEmb2A8O2O_Fiw" hash="QKNwrw">Does the law of the gospel of Jesus Christ exist? Does it have effect in your life? If you disobey its limits and conditions, will your spirit not fall? Can you defy the law of the gospel of Jesus Christ? Can you step outside its control?</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="QEA-MYfqbUG5CmM9FOC8Yw" hash="q4kVYA">
            <span class="emphasis">Oh that man could really see</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="dOCxf8Yr2kKHqg2VWRsGpQ" hash="Zk0y_Q">
            <span class="emphasis">The glories of eternity,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="9EhS5FHpJEqGFeTLpxfnJg" hash="OIHY7g">
            <span class="emphasis">And marvel at the things he saw</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="OgYGILCbEEmfuDGImd2oOg" hash="hUNgVw">
            <span class="emphasis">Encompassed by eternal law.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="AGBWC3LSXEmgdWx27lDv2A" hash="UIgh8w">
            <span class="emphasis">That he could somehow comprehend</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="GH2bjhjT90SgLmzOhgFuPQ" hash="gZWP3A">
            <span class="emphasis">God’s work from its beginning to its end.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="LtRS4T0B9kO6jZTnXNZqFw" hash="mRB5JA">
            <span class="emphasis">That he is in and over all</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="DvFit5r6_0KM1dMCs0-3bQ" hash="bw9UEw">
            <span class="emphasis">And those who heed him not must fall.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="L7pEZNQ3bUqNUv6nutOFvg" hash="SqfBJQ">
            <span class="emphasis">For his designs and law profound</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="JN_Lzcj5vU-qAT6qY7n1gQ" hash="VDtWKg">
            <span class="emphasis">Is truth and one eternal round,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="lehQnYSPBU60_eDDzfaGqQ" hash="e8blgw">
            <span class="emphasis">And although men may set at naught</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="ojEku2bFK06GAJcPKITKGw" hash="WcUI_A">
            <span class="emphasis">The holy laws which he has taught,</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="8-iuZNwqvka_lvR-c96A4A" hash="8nJRgA">
            <span class="emphasis">And step outside their sacred bounds</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="DI0LwXyh10Cs89Tcna-mnQ" hash="6G1wpQ">
            <span class="emphasis">To follow after Satan’s sounds;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="yfboL6Zs_kaAzQ__1WrIrA" hash="AEp8jw">
            <span class="emphasis">They must retrace the path they trod</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="pKe1YxxejUaGlNV6wnCrRg" hash="kgdnOw">
            <span class="emphasis">Or n’er again return to God.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p29" pid="FQNY939hV06mbYO-mUX2Lg" hash="hg3Nog">The great overriding theme contained in the Book of Mormon, which holds the law of the gospel, is summarized by the ancient prophet Moroni, who delivered it to us in this dispensation. It is: “come unto Christ, and lay hold upon every good gift, and touch not the evil gift, nor the unclean thing. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p30" pid="C43hss3sY0KZ-JlAIw8OOg" hash="-RgE8A">“That thou mayest no more be confounded, that the covenants of the Eternal Father which he hath made unto thee … may be fulfilled.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p31" pid="RcZ0hKUp3UCMVFCfvaOxWw" hash="yqlsmQ">“Yea, come unto Christ, and be perfected in him, and deny yourselves of all ungodliness; and if ye shall deny yourselves of all ungodliness and love God with all your might, mind and strength, then is his grace sufficient for you, that by his grace ye may be perfect in Christ; and if by the grace of God ye are perfect in Christ, ye can in nowise deny the power of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p32" pid="wlIL3FgOrkiKpPlHhO03AQ" hash="CXRtzw">“And again, if ye by the grace of God are perfect in Christ, and deny not his power, then are ye sanctified in Christ by the grace of God, through the shedding of the blood of Christ, which is in the covenant of the Father unto the remission of your sins, that ye become holy, without spot.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.30-33" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 10:30–33</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law.p33" pid="NJCC8nTW2kWPgyF0qHX4eA" hash="4dx29w">May God bless you in your thoughts and actions, that they may ever be in tune with this holy law, I pray in the name of him who sitteth upon the throne and governeth and executeth all things, even Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1977/10/the-safety-of-the-gospel-law</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1977-general-conference/1977-10-5020-elder-william-r-bradford-64k-eng.mp3" length="6437448" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 1977 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Governing Ones</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brethren, this is a thrilling hour. At no time has there been a gathering such as this of the elect sons of God. Were it not for the power of the Spirit, I could not bear up the weight of this moment.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03115_000_016" doc-version="2" hash="Qw5K2w">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="1Aq3uu0AAEergPvQeqeNTQ" hash="zLoeCA">The Governing Ones</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="pfVMVfLlaEiF39oNhj5P3Q" hash="zkXG1g">William R. Bradford</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2ba2.jpg" alt="Elder William R. Bradford" pid="w349B8cy4ki2hGnkS1Sjxg" hash="FEz8Ug" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p1" pid="b9pkFTwr10W4PoFPbEyNzQ" hash="xq6oCw">My dear brethren, this is a thrilling hour. At no time has there been a gathering such as this of the elect sons of God. Were it not for the power of the Spirit, I could not bear up the weight of this moment.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p2" pid="ZgnOdtO0skiWVTSwrDcJeA" hash="aMyi7w">I feel impressed to express my profound love for you my brethren. My confidence in you can only be compared to my confidence in the Master, whom we follow. The knowledge that we are brothers brings me great joy.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p3" pid="WqMSKIvcrEmQNz7JszAZvg" hash="BRBbiA">I would never criticize you, but because I love you and because we <span class="emphasis">are</span> brothers, I feel I can talk openly and directly to you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p4" pid="FxxS2HPjV0GmqgiTPJzP6A" hash="HSfgvQ">The fact that you bear the priesthood is not a casual matter. It manifests that you have passed through the waters of baptism. You have been interviewed by Israel’s judges and found qualified to be <span class="emphasis">God’s governing ones.</span> Your status as the governing ones has been, and remains, conditional upon compliance with the terms set forth by the Father and his Son, Jesus Christ, in our premortal life. You accepted those terms then, and by virtue of your ordination and present worthiness you have accepted them here. Nothing about this is casual. It is serious business. It is so serious that God’s affairs on earth and the salvation of all mankind rest upon it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p5" pid="icwl42WhzUupr0juUgcZGQ" hash="AQAGag">In order that you might understand more fully what it means to be the governing ones, let me point out your involvement in governing the Church at three levels: the <span class="emphasis">individual,</span> the <span class="emphasis">family,</span> and the formal <span class="emphasis">institutional church.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p6" pid="HB9ag691fkCSGaSeBs-eXg" hash="hnvrbQ">You, as an individual, are the Church. The Lord made a covenant with his faithful sons that they would become “<span class="emphasis">the church</span> and kingdom, and the elect of God” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.34" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:34</a>; italics added). You, then, through your faithfulness as a priesthood bearer, become the Church. The Church will be governed only as you govern yourself.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p7" pid="QgDVIJokzkiGkFWIVSelqg" hash="2FNPzQ">The most basic, fundamental principle of truth, that upon which the entire plan of God is founded, is free agency. As an individual you have the right to govern yourself. It is divinely given to you to think and act as you wish. It is your decision.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p8" pid="PqOGZxYNaky2gBHo_x8uEg" hash="19aUoQ">It must be pointed out, however, that although you have the free agency to choose for yourself, you do not have the right to choose what will be the result of your decision. The results of what you think and do are governed by law. Good returns good. Evil returns evil. You govern yourself by subjecting yourself to the discipline of law. If you are obedient to God’s law, you remain free. You progress and are perfected. If you are disobedient to God’s law, you bind yourself to that which restricts your progress. You become defiled and unworthy to be an associate with those who are more clean and pure.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p9" pid="9CfKW_tacE61gWYQ46Femg" hash="yIhxAA">Let me project this principle of governing oneself into your life just a little. I don’t think it would surprise you to hear that a very high number of both Aaronic and Melchizedek Priesthood bearers, as well as our sisters, are exercising their free agency in such a way that they have developed extensive television habits. Many have reached twenty hours or more a week.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p10" pid="xPqwKezdS0uzD38Xht7ibQ" hash="RDmKxQ">God’s plan dictates that we spend our time on this earth engaged in work. Work means putting yourself mentally and physically into action. Many hours a week of being indoctrinated by television, much of which is satanic, hardly seems to fill this requirement.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p11" pid="kW-zEQFN-UiuUSnTSzc14Q" hash="RKQN2A">Even if television were not filled with foolishness, violence, immorality, and filth, its entertainment value would still not justify the time drain. You are here to work to govern the Lord’s affairs, not to be entertained. The Apostle Paul talked straight when he wrote to Titus and said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p12" pid="64iyXJuvukGz1tcAv1cqnw" hash="RpV3Nw">“Unto the pure all things are pure: but unto them that are defiled and unbelieving is nothing pure; but even their mind and conscience is defiled.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p13" pid="wDiR7cdAQkWEXmIF_ZFppw" hash="RifQ_g">“They profess that they know God; but in works they deny him, being abominable, and disobedient, and unto every good work reprobate” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/titus/1.15-16" class="scriptureRef">Titus 1:15–16</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p14" pid="zwhJXHqiYECGBpKT3JCpqg" hash="PDpb_g">Holding the priesthood means being commissioned by the Lord to act as he would act if he were here personally. Is your television habit compatible with that holy commission? If you have a twenty-hour-a-week television habit and would repent and convert it into a gospel-study habit, in one year you could read the Book of Mormon, the Doctrine and Covenants, the Pearl of Great Price, and the entire Bible. In addition, you could read <span class="emphasis">Jesus the Christ, The Articles of Faith, Gospel Principles,</span> the basic priesthood manual, the basic women’s manual, the basic children’s manual, all three volumes of <span class="emphasis">Doctrines of Salvation, The Miracle of Forgiveness, The Promised Messiah,</span> and <span class="emphasis">Essentials in Church History,</span> and could then reread the Bible, Book of Mormon, Doctrine and Covenants, and Pearl of Great Price. This would still leave time to read the <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> the <span class="emphasis">New Era,</span> and the <span class="emphasis">Friend</span> each month and the <span class="emphasis">Church News</span> each week. This is based on your ability to read only ten pages an hour. The average person can read twenty pages or more an hour. If you are average, this leaves you with ten hours a week to govern yourself in other kingdom-building activities, such as keeping a personal journal, genealogy and temple work, improved home teaching, welfare services, civic and patriotic involvement to protect our freedom, and much more. I repeat: “Unto the pure all things are pure: but unto them that are defiled and unbelieving is nothing pure; but even their mind and conscience is defiled.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p15" pid="ccRZOAobPU63EnmZRJa3SQ" hash="RifQ_g1">“They profess that they know God; but in works they deny him, being abominable, and disobedient, and unto every good work reprobate” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/titus/1.15-16" class="scriptureRef">Titus 1:15–16</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p16" pid="vfzGHmuwOUKgbH7P8tzpSg" hash="JOwc2g">Each of you is a member of the most basic unit of the Church, the family. Some of you are not yet fathers but are in preparation to become so. As a father you have the divine right and the divine responsibility to govern your family after a pattern set forth by the Lord. Since the family is the basic unit of the Church, <span class="emphasis">as the family is governed so is the Church governed.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p17" pid="YeKypzjEYEqubQu-PmDc_g" hash="QflKjw">The Lord expects you to govern a home- and family-centered gospel-living system. The challenge of governing the family is to so love, teach, and motivate its members that their personal decisions will be to unite one with another in the common purpose of following God’s plan.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p18" pid="JLGTkutYc0ih7vOIddPhmg" hash="sZ7zYw">Fundamental to this is developing faith in the Lord Jesus Christ. Without faith no individual will respond positively to the pattern of life Christ taught.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p19" pid="HBFUN2F5Ik6x8w5EHhcouA" hash="1z7AMw">Faith in Christ is developed by fasting and prayer, which brings spiritual communion, and by studying Christ’s teaching as contained in the holy scriptures.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p20" pid="y6TbQtERgEyWH-jme0DtJg" hash="6gL1ow">As faith begins to develop and Christ’s pattern for life begins to be understood by the individual, the need to understand and follow the steps of repentance will also become evident.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p21" pid="Pfg0G1nsvESk_S0JwlZAVA" hash="DyUyDA">Since some of the decisions of the family members will be wrong and will stop their progress and defile them, there must be a way for them to be cleansed and put back on the proper course. They will need to know how to <span class="emphasis">recognize</span> sins of both commission and omission and be so spiritually in tune, because of their faith and confidence in Christ, that they feel <span class="emphasis">remorse</span> for that sin. They must know the process of <span class="emphasis">confession</span> and be motivated to make <span class="emphasis">restitution</span> and to <span class="emphasis">resolve</span> to abandon the sin.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p22" pid="eigW4nZh8Uu-Mezr-SnVvQ" hash="Tc3BEg">The natural product of an individual who is developing faith in Christ and is living the steps of repentance is that he will strive to keep the commandments. The actions of his life will become more Christlike. A Christlike person will be united with other family members and will render service to them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p23" pid="4B0w1e_kRUmGcjP5VIMlyQ" hash="vRzd-g">How, then, do you govern the family? By virtue of the priesthood. “By persuasion, by long-suffering, by gentleness and meekness, and by love unfeigned;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p24" pid="PjGQMZxv_kCaBIPYTLT7cQ" hash="yGGnbQ">“By kindness, and pure knowledge, which shall greatly enlarge the soul without hypocrisy, and without guile—</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p25" pid="ZyFMBw9sc0W4lZJa6XheXA" hash="jOFHRw">“Reproving betimes with sharpness when moved upon by the Holy Ghost” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/121.41-43" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 121:41–43</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p26" pid="J1EvyCiMHECNiHttK4O-XQ" hash="jZisYw">You teach fasting and prayer. You teach the doctrine contained in the holy scriptures and encourage individual private study of them on a regular basis. You involve yourself in and teach the steps of repentance. You obey the commandments and teach them. You serve one another. The pattern of a home- and family-centered gospel-living system is then established: faith in Christ, repentance, keeping the commandments, and rendering service to one another. This system meets all of the temporal and spiritual needs of the family members at every age level.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p27" pid="1SrFQGn8RU-7BSuhQkvNcw" hash="A_1kQg">The formal organization of the Church consists of a divine, orderly system by which we as individuals and as families can meet together in an organized way to be taught God’s plan for our salvation, take upon ourselves covenants, and administer the saving ordinances to one another using priesthood power and authority.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p28" pid="SW9N6-oYqkyGSOYG2WZnIw" hash="A4cRmA">This is the institutional Church. It organizes the volunteer services of the members of the Church into programs and auxiliaries designed to be a resource to individuals and families. These programs and auxiliaries are to be governed by and be auxiliary to the priesthood. Members called to serve in them should submit to this government. These programs should never become powers unto themselves. If they do, we create a chapel-centered gospel-living system, rather than a home- and family-centered gospel-living system. This is not the Lord’s way. He has taught the process. His charge is to teach, expound, exhort, baptize, and watch over the Church. Visit the house of each member, and exhort them to pray vocally and in secret and attend to all family duties. Be with and strengthen them, and see that there is no iniquity in the Church, neither hardness with each other, neither lying, backbiting, nor evil speaking. And also see that all the members do their duty (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.50-51,53-55" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:50–51, 53–55</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p29" pid="S8dzC0ypdEqkjvT6RAz2ZA" hash="1TVH7w">As the governing ones, make no mistake about it, this decree was made to the priesthood. We love and need the auxiliaries. They are staffed by great, faithful servants. But the very name by which they are called, <span class="emphasis">auxiliary,</span> which means “helper,” should make it clear to us that the full weight of governing the Church rests squarely upon the priesthood.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p30" pid="n3DnGo3MlkOgwX6Wqczkmw" hash="EINOFA">If an individual or a family needs help in the process that will bring about their temporal and spiritual salvation, it is the responsibility of the priesthood. As the priesthood needs help in this work, and it will, it will call upon the resources of the auxiliaries.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p31" pid="dx75sP7q7UOdSz_XHfZCkg" hash="C-QaBw">The time must quickly come when, as the governing ones, we fully shoulder our responsibility as the shepherds of Israel. Our work must not be done by the restrictions of the calendar or as convenient to the schedule of our habits, but on a need basis.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p32" pid="4BWLIdQ58UaMbP8JJCpFLg" hash="TV01sw">Brethren, in some things there remains a considerable distance between what we are and what we should become.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones.p33" pid="80jFHOl92k6TDWFMCYs5gA" hash="cMNQgw">That we may understand and fulfill our roles as the governing ones, in lockstep with our living prophet, who is the mouthpiece of God, I plead, in the name of Jesus Christ, the Master, amen.</p>
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-304c.jpg" alt="First Presidency, 13 Sept 1898" pid="Ip80WEhApkC2AQq_YcJeyw" hash="gKzRZA" />
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1979/10/the-governing-ones</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1979-general-conference/1979-10-3020-elder-william-r-bradford-64k-eng.mp3" length="6328376" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 1979 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sanctification through Missionary Service</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I solemnly testify to you that God the Eternal Father and His Son, Jesus Christ, have appeared in this dispensation. These two glorious personages actually stood before and spoke to the young man Joseph Smith.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03141_000_021" doc-version="2" hash="09dlPQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="7j07FM2DGEqrUjzfgukqvA" hash="77WsUA">Sanctification through Missionary Service</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="vzJdQmH_H0WHN8QSxhiVGA" hash="zkXG1g">William R. Bradford</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2ba2.jpg" alt="Elder William R. Bradford" pid="sKDTfQgCS0K2yPKBlgIQKQ" hash="FEz8Ug" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p1" pid="prCUi99VaEuJcSMbN_AC_g" hash="g0J8dw">I solemnly testify to you that God the Eternal Father and His Son, Jesus Christ, have appeared in this dispensation. These two glorious personages actually stood before and spoke to the young man Joseph Smith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p2" pid="-Trc8B_dNEWsy00M-wkCMw" hash="AcDtOw">This occurred in 1820. Since then the heavens have remained open. The fulness of the gospel of Jesus Christ has been restored by revelation. Angels have been sent as holy messengers. We have been given records of God’s dealings with His children. The Holy Spirit has poured out the truths of God’s plan for the exaltation of His sons and daughters.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p3" pid="Xw2Zu6aJOECiNPSUAZw-Dg" hash="vE_zkg">The true church, The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, has been organized under the direction of Jesus Christ Himself.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p4" pid="8CXD1b48uU-CRD3zZz4nhQ" hash="ScS0Iw">Prophets and Apostles have been called. They have been given power from on high. They are special witnesses of Jesus Christ in all the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p5" pid="PDq_G-L7H0KRM5D60tQSRQ" hash="fmwngQ">They are sent out, holding the keys, to open the doors for the proclamation of the gospel of Jesus Christ. By their work the doors are being opened. The gospel is being proclaimed throughout the world.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p6" pid="WFeASJulgUah76xaObXqyQ" hash="qcRrRw">Being inspired and directed by the Lord, these prophets, seers, and revelators have called upon the disciples of Jesus Christ and have sent them forth by commandment, which commandment is:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p7" pid="HfN3Os3JnEqSv695iVxmhw" hash="O4J9oQ">“And the voice of warning shall be unto all people, by the mouths of my disciples, whom I have chosen in these last days.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p8" pid="uOOPrRpUm0ab7H2f6qI45g" hash="7_20oQ">“And they shall go forth and none shall stay them, for I the Lord have commanded them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p9" pid="ImURPS0jsEyxUPXO_S0TTg" hash="OnqLGg">“Wherefore, fear and tremble, O ye people, for what I the Lord have decreed in them shall be fulfilled.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/1.4-5,7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 1:4–5, 7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p10" pid="6sfeq8NCLki8ddOf19Hc8Q" hash="meqTXg">Presently there are about thirty thousand missionaries serving in 188 missions. They are proclaiming the restored gospel in 82 nations, territories, and possessions in 48 different languages.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p11" pid="qSthlK-h6UGsoP11J17WJQ" hash="FzyW9g">Thousands of our Father’s children are hearing the gospel, are obtaining testimonies of its truthfulness, and are being baptized into His true church. There are now some five million members.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p12" pid="166FCu0NC0WHD2FkS_0Rgw" hash="2t0fOg">We are humbled and greatly pleased with the success that attends the labors. We acknowledge the hand of the Lord and the dedication of His disciples in what has been accomplished up to now. But there is still much left to be done.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p13" pid="OQvq1wblSkmNbmQDcpU3yg" hash="tYPsqA">We feel a great urgency for the work and wonder if we could cause it to be accelerated.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p14" pid="K68WjZ5ye0O8aS1TMB5RZQ" hash="fQajng">There is concern as to whether all of those who should and could participate in this work really understand and believe the basic principles and purposes for which God’s firm decree, to declare this gospel to all the world, was given.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p15" pid="Ymj2CLX_bkWwWSf2lOFlWQ" hash="Zgz4Xg">Although there are thirty thousand missionaries now serving, there should and could be many times that many. If they would prepare themselves and step forward to do that which is their decreed duty, the work could be done at a rate and in dimensions beyond our highest expectations.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p16" pid="M--h2Oh7_UGHd7gnYhlMDQ" hash="RfECbg">I have pondered and prayed about this matter. I have searched for words and pleaded to the heavens for power to say them so as to motivate those who should be faithful in this work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p17" pid="WS2cRiQtQUKC7Og6hyo18w" hash="vRK1iQ">The words have come into my mind. They are simple words. They have oft been taught. To say them is to repeat what you have heard over and over again.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p18" pid="HtTX616xqUS9fcSwh2wysA" hash="zjgbXQ">They invite us to come unto Christ and be perfected in Him. This is done by serving Him with all of our heart, might, mind, and strength. If we do this, we receive a remission of our sins and become holy and without spot and may return to our Heavenly Father to dwell again with Him, to live the kind of life He lives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p19" pid="tSy1UFiVIkiI6PA7xArggg" hash="r5YM9w">The Savior stands with His hands extended, offering us glorious blessings if we will serve Him. As we study what He means by this service we come to understand that it is fundamentally the service of teaching the truths of His gospel to those who do not know it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p20" pid="RqH9ADvha0WWTwQl5A0viA" hash="Wl7oRw">But even with the simplicity of the words and the divine source from which they come, and even with the sure promise of blessings, there are still those who should and could serve who choose not to serve.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p21" pid="OiI4MFR9C0CvGQlFzkQ50Q" hash="OrsQnQ">It causes me to wonder if they really understand and believe the twofold nature of the purpose of missionary work: first, to sanctify the missionary himself, and second, to bring converts to a knowledge of the truths of the restored gospel of Jesus Christ and to baptism into His Church—which is the sure and natural product of a missionary who is in the process of sanctification.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p22" pid="pk3Jw5nACkOgHC3Gz96CaA" hash="52xvrg">Satan is attempting to block this work. His influence is insidious and persistent. Many who should and could do this work are falling victim to his influence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p23" pid="NM7rIKAzTUeHAEkXI2BHkQ" hash="MvUUkg">Some are being deceived and are slipping away from that which is true to experiment with that which is false and foolish.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p24" pid="luFkEfBNFkyP_4qCh64TBQ" hash="PSr8tQ">May I talk to you young men who are approaching or are now the age to be called into missionary service.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p25" pid="_IzQ7tkRT0GxJomEBEdeFA" hash="SAdqfw">Some of you say in your minds, “Oh well, you just don’t understand my case. My situation is different. I plan to be a great lawyer, or doctor, or athlete, or some other great person. Surely neither you nor the Lord would expect me to leave my studies at such an important time. A mission would interfere with my future plans.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p26" pid="kI36WnpJ7U2NR5AGpR569w" hash="9H4N0g">Others are thinking, “Yes, I know about missions, but if you had a girl friend like mine, you’d never leave her. What will happen to her while I’m gone?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p27" pid="6SBLjDjzNUyRJ5VBgVqYxA" hash="YrPRdw">Yet others of you are thinking, “Missions cost so much. I just got this job. I just purchased a car and a stereo. It’s just the time of life when I’m starting to get things together for myself. I can’t drop all that now. I just can’t afford it.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p28" pid="MwbgTXcgUkuJJD1e-oGJjw" hash="US2MsA">Then there are also those who are thinking, “My situation disqualifies me. I have fallen into transgression and am not participating in the Church. I had always planned on being a missionary, but I slipped and now I don’t live the standards required of a missionary.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p29" pid="-58QFzFBH0e7_EIoy2FqOQ" hash="vyDnpw">If I could listen to you separately, each case would unfold with one thing in common. All would justify yourselves in not doing your duty to God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p30" pid="XbgkUgKNUkiOzArhA_VIBw" hash="1-ltHQ">Many of you are attempting to justify yourselves even against the correct counsel and teachings of your parents. They love you. They would support you in every way to do what’s right if you would allow it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p31" pid="blN3VpsD10uzD9Q-3c8nQw" hash="syUl7g">But unfortunately there are also parents who side with you in your justification. They have made plans for your future, and those plans do not include missionary service. They say, “My son is going to be a great lawyer or doctor or star athlete. He can’t interrupt his studies to go gallivanting out in the world for two years. Let someone else’s sons do that. My son is special.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p32" pid="Z_atpxTuC0iNCWG0foSV2A" hash="DbhVCw">If I could speak separately to each of you young men and your parents who so justify, I would say with all the power of speech I could generate, “Just who do you think you are? What right do you have to match your wisdom with that of God, who through His prophets has issued a firm decree, a solemn mandate, that the restored gospel must be declared to all the world by the voice of His disciples? This means you!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p33" pid="nF7G0F3mHUWnjzY_Z63blg" hash="qthPYg">I would remind you of the Lord’s own words as He addressed those who “doeth not anything” and who have doubtful hearts.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p34" pid="6Fzse6tSLUmn6F19Ggb_zg" hash="QxMA9w">“Who am I that made man, saith the Lord, that will hold him guiltless that obeys not my commandments?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p35" pid="_RNdtiZWl0akxjodZI3SGg" hash="0T-WpA">“Who am I, saith the Lord, that have promised and have not fulfilled?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p36" pid="Vtfx1VS3wUK_1OXxukx1eQ" hash="s83y1g">“I command and men obey not; I revoke and they receive not the blessing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p37" pid="AUo9XQlgeEeK1DcsI7tcYQ" hash="GlB5sA">“Then they say in their hearts: This is not the work of the Lord, for his promises are not fulfilled. But wo unto such, for their reward lurketh beneath, and not from above.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.29-33" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:29–33</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p38" pid="Z43aTXe0Bku2sDgVXVW5pw" hash="tMyj1g">Do you really believe that earthly fame and title, tied to earthly positions and occupations, can compare with God’s promises to the faithful? He has promised “thrones, kingdoms, principalities, and powers.” He has promised “exaltation and glory in all things.” He has promised “a fulness and a continuation of the seeds forever and ever.” He has promised eternal life. (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/132.19" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 132:19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p39" pid="XiaP8gJxWEGHpJj4cxSYyA" hash="X9ob5Q">I would say to you that you are left without excuse and without justification and that you have placed your eternal salvation in grave danger.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p40" pid="vzxW3PlhjEO0JQBO3M4-QA" hash="fI85yA">Your education can wait. The Lord will open the doors of education and a proper vocation for you when you return from your missionary service.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p41" pid="cqG6Ns8oKUWSVtUfTtSerw" hash="w9hblw">And speaking of your girl friends, the Father wants to give you one of His elect daughters, one who is loved and cherished by Him, one who is pure, one who understands eternal values and is striving for exaltation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p42" pid="C9z-ekIEbk6AGUfTvfUVfA" hash="1qYfnQ">Surely you cannot expect this to happen if you are not faithful in doing that which would make you worthy of her as an eternal companion. It is after your missionary service has helped to sanctify you that this can happen.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p43" pid="7GKORiGTO0e4CHBukEzcqA" hash="4mvApQ">Lest I be misunderstood, may I say to you young women, this also applies to you. Many of you say, “What will I ever do if he leaves me?” You hold him back. You allow your association with him to go beyond where it should. You often contribute to his decision not to serve. You sometimes even contribute to his unworthiness to serve. By so doing you are also disqualifying yourself from your intended blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p44" pid="fYymK9cMakSN7thlJ2wXPw" hash="26Z6CQ">Let him go. Don’t just let him go, but encourage him! You are perhaps the strongest single influence on him at this time in his life. You can make all the difference. Help keep him clean. Help him to be prepared.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p45" pid="BQOpCTzDP02EM7sDZ9nlcw" hash="3AZsYg">Perhaps you would also like to, and should, serve as a missionary. Many lady missionaries are now serving. The same blessings promised to young men are extended to you. Although your most important role in this life is motherhood, it may be appropriate for you to serve a mission first.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p46" pid="fmIshuBEOkqTCGj6C5ITOA" hash="Jx6ktA">For those of you who feel you cannot serve because you have slipped into transgression, I would say, “Don’t despair. There is a way back. The plan of repentance really works. You can take steps to return to full worthiness. You can make acceptable restitution and place yourself in the service of the Lord.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p47" pid="-sbxN3V2rU2c_OQOHnl7_g" hash="gQKF5A">If I could speak separately with each bishop and stake president about those who should and could be serving as missionaries, I would say, “You have a most important obligation. It is your sacred duty to work with them and their parents until they understand, and do, their duty.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p48" pid="wOa3OiIc5k6PNtuzPOffIQ" hash="h_42TQ">“You cannot leave them hanging as fruit on a tree, maturing, ripening, and then falling to the ground to spoil or be devoured, with no one concerned for conserving the harvest. If you do, you will assuredly be held accountable. The day will come when you will stand before the judgment bar of God to give account for them, name by name, every one.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p49" pid="AGNwlQcYG0Kgds82JcGovw" hash="KM9KVQ">This is a marvelous plan. It is a process of sanctification. When a missionary is placed in a mission environment of order and discipline where all that is done is in harmony with the Spirit, the missionary experiences a great transformation. The heavens open. Powers are showered out. Mysteries are revealed. Habits are improved. Sanctification begins. Through this process the missionary becomes a vessel of light that can shine forth the gospel of Jesus Christ in a world in darkness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p50" pid="LvPjePo-VUy3GsxnUBw7vg" hash="Ve-hDQ">There is much to do. You are the royal generation that has been “hid from the world with Christ” to come forth in this day to do the work. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/86.9" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 86:9</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p51" pid="50CQYcREuUqwwUmypNefmg" hash="QTLj9Q">You must prepare. You must now make yourselves worthy and available. If you do not, the work will go on without you. It will go on at a slower pace, but it will go on. If you are not part of it, if you do not do your duty, what will happen to you? How will you be sanctified?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p52" pid="v3VgOD6tmEOwUAsMqO4hIQ" hash="wjD3LQ">If you do not do your duty, those whom you could have taught but did not will eventually have their opportunity to hear the gospel from someone else, but what of you? How will you be sanctified?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p53" pid="W2KwMhQwBEW_OdGGuId1jg" hash="W2LQmw">Missions are for missionaries. It is a marvelous gift of time, a time given when you can experience glimpses of heavenly life here on earth. It is a time of cleansing and refreshing. It is a special time when the Holy Ghost can seal upon you the knowledge of the great plan for your exaltation. It is one of your best opportunities to become a celestial candidate.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p54" pid="7tH6NlkLGEWx06c_7J09sg" hash="6w4YBg">The teaching and conversion of others is the natural product of this process. To sanctify yourself you must serve others. The highest of all service to others is to teach them truth and bring them into the kingdom of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p55" pid="Jj92FXLVAkC6Rs52VLrzBA" hash="yl2JCA">Thus the decree: Send forth the elders and preach my gospel to every kindred, tongue, and people. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/133.8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 133:8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service.p56" pid="RkIBv7M0wEucAT7fzDaBoQ" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1981/10/sanctification-through-missionary-service</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1981-general-conference/1981-10-4020-elder-william-r-bradford-64k-eng.mp3" length="7139377" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 1981 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Do You Know?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I proclaim unto you that I know there is a God in the heaven. He is our Father. We are His children, begotten in His image and likeness. We are His seed and have the potential within us to become as He is.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03167_000_029" doc-version="2" hash="eCOlWA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="r1Fin5md00ST3NUfPgfHcw" hash="B_5xGA">How Do You Know?</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="js-x44Rx3UGgGN88OeXK_Q" hash="zkXG1g">William R. Bradford</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2ba2.jpg" alt="Elder William R. Bradford" pid="nsDdgcJZBUaJZL10rteD5w" hash="FEz8Ug" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p1" pid="CrCTSLExY0iefmq98jtw1Q" hash="sta3Mg">I proclaim unto you that I know there is a God in the heaven. He is our Father. We are His children, begotten in His image and likeness. We are His seed and have the potential within us to become as He is.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p2" pid="PHfuZ4tyIk--wzBpJHY8Jw" hash="ICaChQ">For this to happen, our Heavenly Father prepared a plan. An earth would be created upon which our spirits could be born into physical bodies, a place where we could have experiences that would teach and test us, a place to develop the godly potential within us. Here we, the seed of God, can mature into the product of the harvest of the Father’s work, which is “to bring to pass the immortality and eternal life of man.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/1.39" class="scriptureRef">Moses 1:39</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p3" pid="UDOLki6_LUW2YzbPScQhrA" hash="dFMuYw">The plan provides us with the needed resources and instruction to become as He is. By obedience we may become lawful heirs to the quality of life He lives and to a fulness of that which He possesses.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p4" pid="u67Fh9jZC0e9rejoLdExUg" hash="pdct6g">Our Father taught us the plan in our pre-earthly life. He gave us free agency to choose for ourselves whether or not we would accept the plan. The fact that we are here on the earth with physical bodies is prima facie evidence that we did accept it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p5" pid="lDDxC3bnq0y1efaG0pSlHg" hash="iBxnlg">However, others of God’s children chose not to accept the plan. Led by Lucifer, they rebelled against our Father and sought to gain power and glory through force. They were defeated in this attempt and were cast out of the Father’s presence. They are here upon the earth without physical bodies. They are still led by Lucifer, who became Satan, the devil. They are not involved in developing godly potentials; rather, they are continually struggling to influence man to misuse the resources and to disobey the instructions of our Father. Even more insidious is their relentless influence to deceive man into doing nothing with the resources and remaining ignorant of the instructions. Through this influence have come sin and transgression: sins of commission and sins of omission.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p6" pid="HaL4NU7j3k6rIfn_sjB9cw" hash="pPb3AA">We refer to the instructions the Father has given us as commandments. It is because of sin and the transgression of these commandments that man becomes sensual, devilish, and fallen man. (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.20" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:20</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p7" pid="vDbWTWyVGUu42jZFL2hLWQ" hash="kLUkSw">“Fallen man” means that man is subject to death and separation from God. When death comes to the physical body, the spirit body lives on, separated from the presence of God. Thus, the condition of fallen man is death and separation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p8" pid="BDQtMZF7LkqUsDkOqNUxPQ" hash="HwCdaw">What I have said, I declare in soberness to be true. I declare it to the receptive ear, to those who also know it is true. I declare it, unashamedly, to the doubting ear, to those who would mock and scorn, as we can imagine could have been the case when the declarations fell from the lips of Noah and the people surely demanded from him an answer: “How do you know? How do you know?” I declare it to the slumbering, who, in their ignorance of God’s plan and their darkness of mind, can but think the question, “How do you know? How do you know?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p9" pid="0iZ_u00B_kyHacaSWMmP8Q" hash="pRn96g">I hold in my hand the Book of Mormon, another testament of Jesus Christ. This book has cost the sacrifice, even the lives, of countless thousands to preserve and bring forth. Its coming forth is part of the marvelous restoration by God of His resources and His instruction to His children.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p10" pid="PFCUfqrCU0OUIgT57X-7mw" hash="2fKr4g">Now that we have the Book of Mormon, which has been inspired, protected, and delivered by divine powers into our hands—now that we can read it—to our amazement we find that one of the two major messages it contains for us is the record of a fallen people.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p11" pid="JP9dpj1QzEGKCEfib8ithQ" hash="FH2j5A">In this book, page after page, story after story, character by character, we are taught that there is a God in the heaven; that He framed the heaven and the earth; that we are His children and He is our Father; that we are begotten in His image and after His likeness; that there is a plan for our becoming as He is; that the plan was challenged by him who rebelled against the Father and who was cast down to the earth to become Satan, the devil, the father of lies and transgression; that our Father allowed our spirit bodies to come to this earth to take upon them physical bodies; that here on earth we may, if we will, obey the Father’s commandments, which will qualify us to return to His presence and live the glorious style of life He lives. “But by the transgression of these holy laws man became sensual and devilish, and became fallen man.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.20" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:20</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p12" pid="T9gUrWOII0aPInf6u0U5gQ" hash="nwlGmQ">Yes, it is with amazement that we discover that one of the two major messages in the Book of Mormon is the record of a fallen people; but that amazement turns to gratitude as we realize that God is explaining the truism that “you can’t know the solution if you don’t first understand the problem.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p13" pid="_tXznuMUUEGAHeyAVa5s2A" hash="6znguw">The problem is that man has transgressed the holy commandments of God and has become fallen man, to suffer death and everlasting separation from the presence of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p14" pid="s7P7mq69UUC7KfWC5mhwrQ" hash="67S4Ug">But this Book of Mormon contains a second message. It contains the solution. It contains the fulness of the gospel of Jesus Christ. Just as the doctrine of fallen man lays before us the fulness of our fallen condition, so does the gospel of Jesus Christ lay before us the fulness of the way to overcome that condition. It is the solution.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p15" pid="N8zr0d4WZ0iVsXzuj6R3UA" hash="tljInA">Central to the gospel of Jesus Christ is the plan of redemption. God gave His children commandments that they “should love and serve him, the only living and true God, and that he should be the only being whom they should worship.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.19" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:19</a>.) By the transgression of these holy laws came the Fall; “wherefore, the Almighty God gave his Only Begotten Son.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.21" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:21</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p16" pid="H3D-haGV7Uyy3YkCu-DrFQ" hash="JnwwZg">He came to the earth and did a work. He fulfilled the requirements of the plan of redemption. The work He did brought about the resurrection, meaning the reuniting of our spirit bodies with a renewed physical body.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p17" pid="vZrqKfU7B0ewBCk6Xv9akg" hash="EG5f1Q">The work He did was an atonement which opens again the way for us to reach our potential as the seed of God. Now, although we have become fallen man, if we repent and obey the commandments, we can return to our Father’s presence:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p18" pid="iRd90w4ZvUG1R4zmIqibvQ" hash="7tBJsw">“And since man had fallen he could not merit anything of himself; but the sufferings and death of Christ atone for their sins, through faith and repentance, and so forth; and that he breaketh the bands of death, that the grave shall have no victory, and that the sting of death should be swallowed up in the hopes of glory.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/22.14" class="scriptureRef">Alma 22:14</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p19" pid="Uoc4QB7Pf0a0G1Q0P4df5A" hash="psBDig">If you had a son, your very own seed, would you not want him to mature into the fulness of his potential? While he was yet young and tender, would you not give him teachings, instruction, even commandments? Would these commandments not be to protect him from harm and evil, even death?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p20" pid="QwkeyPE3z0q4h6DDs25AnQ" hash="lNti4g">If, by his disobedience to your teachings and commandments, he fell into a situation from which he had no power to extract himself—a situation in which he would surely die, a situation from which, without help, he could not return to be in your companionship—would you not do all in your power to bring about his salvation?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p21" pid="lwQlj3F8pk6jF0Xt8-QEfg" hash="IsTQOg">God is our Father. We are His children. In our state as fallen man, He has sent a savior. He is Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p22" pid="-YfLsDt7WUS_PP63nfoAqg" hash="Izaq0g">Since all men have sinned, there is not one who can return to the Father except through Jesus Christ. He is the only one of the Father’s children who has not transgressed the holy laws. If He had, He too would have become fallen man. If this had happened, who would be our savior? But Christ is sinless, and He has brought about our atonement on the terms of our repentance and obedience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p23" pid="-ay4KMZmaUOHjgcEYLNBaA" hash="oHoQ-w">His own declaration comes to us by way of stern commandment:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p24" pid="foYChrxrukit84kTMf-bJQ" hash="I8ETAg">“Wherefore, I command you to repent, and keep the commandments which you have received by the hand of my servant Joseph Smith, …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p25" pid="vqtPZP6sUEe7bOVXrUQIdA" hash="-Bm_aQ">“And it is by my almighty power that you have received them.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/19.13-14" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 19:13–14</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p26" pid="g8K5XJKyfEKvwwn9Ie2g-A" hash="Gwb9WQ">Did we not receive the Book of Mormon from the Lord by the hand of Joseph Smith, God’s mighty prophet of the Restoration?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p27" pid="64QRlH5FakiosiV6JjoTdA" hash="cra10g">Christ, speaking to the Nephite nation as revealed to us in the Book of Mormon, gave us further instruction regarding the steps we must take to overcome our condition as fallen man. Said He:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p28" pid="4e8O2fKneUiYq6EY2M0IyA" hash="lhY7Pg">“And I bear record that the Father commandeth all men, everywhere, to repent and believe in me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p29" pid="lIUxJvA7hka7cEZoAMBgMg" hash="3WP-Ig">“And whoso believeth in me, and is baptized, the same shall be saved; and they are they who shall inherit the kingdom of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p30" pid="IDGIU5glF0OE3bwuvTCvMQ" hash="QuzMzg">“And whoso believeth not in me, and is not baptized, shall be damned.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.32-34" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:32–34</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p31" pid="SzEu1n_v20m1W5H0lXUKkA" hash="msfNAQ">To be damned simply means to be stopped in your progress. It means to remain in the condition of fallen man.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p32" pid="xkY0tgDkaEyxPiV4Hh1Edw" hash="xOigzw">Christ continues:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p33" pid="eXUZeJXX0E6NfTX3CL0S2g" hash="BoJsig">“Verily, verily, I say unto you, that this is my doctrine, and I bear record of it from the Father; and whosoever believeth in me believeth in the Father also; and unto him will the Father bear record of me, for he will visit him with … the Holy Ghost” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.35" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:35</a>)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p34" pid="v0Dt6VpW6EKLndXRl30v7g" hash="cDT3jA">I ask you to ponder the question, “How can anyone understand the role of, or the need for, a savior if he does not first understand what it is he must be saved from?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p35" pid="hc3ZZe7enEi5Ea_wMJfg7g" hash="Euxz5Q">The Book of Mormon contains the record of a fallen people. It outlines how man got into a condition which subjects him to death and separation from God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p36" pid="kfUJ03Ge1EaQ8zwqQaS5mQ" hash="gqNetg">The Book of Mormon also contains the fulness of the gospel of Jesus Christ. It outlines for us in perfect clarity what has been done for us and what we must do ourselves to overcome our fallen condition and return to the presence of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p37" pid="q1vxCceR3kW4q31RLReE4w" hash="OKvOZw">Now, O fallen man, with so great a witness, do you yet dare to ask, “How do you know? How do you know?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know.p38" pid="AfeCym08S0G_4L_oW-g-kQ" hash="lJHWdQ">The Book of Mormon holds out to us a fulness of what we must be saved from. It gives us a complete understanding of the role of, and the need for, a savior. It is another testament of Jesus Christ, which I proclaim and testify in the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1983/10/how-do-you-know</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1983-general-conference/1983-10-5030-elder-william-r-bradford-64k-eng.mp3" length="5857236" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 1983 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selfless Service</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The young people of a certain ward had worked to earn the large sum of money needed to go on an adventure trip.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03219_000_027" doc-version="2" hash="KEbJuQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="DgrtsVn2_UeUFJ2ZnT37SQ" hash="v30t0w">Selfless Service</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="4A1wH9XXsEakm_-qNso_8w" hash="zkXG1g">William R. Bradford</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2412.jpg" alt="Elder William R. Bradford" pid="-Wf5bXeR3UiWp2FwMnydtg" hash="4Hy0Rw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p1" pid="6SYm37ZcKEmu_UbHy4BXKw" hash="Ikc6og">The young people of a certain ward had worked to earn the large sum of money needed to go on an adventure trip.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p2" pid="ZW0RAEnFiE2zvdqdDmh1eQ" hash="-Xm8_A">I had had some acquaintance with their bishop. He called and asked if I would help him get some news publicity so these young people would be recognized for the fine things they were doing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p3" pid="Z0Pp00mTXE-oTNdndhf6zw" hash="HX-R1w">I said I would not help him. He was surprised and asked why. I answered that although it was commendable that the young people had worked hard to earn this money, some things are interesting while other things are important, and that there may be a higher purpose for the funds they had obtained from all the energy they had expended.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p4" pid="Dz8W5lquhEGI7n1cOjSFfQ" hash="Ggc02w">He was even more surprised and asked what I meant. I explained that my ministry takes me into countries where the people are less privileged than where he lives. I know of their challenges and sacrifices. I told him of the struggles of young people in those areas to obtain the needed funds to support themselves on missions. For the family to have enough food is often a challenge. Clothing is shared and worn out. Fashion is whatever is available, and in many cases that is not much. I explained that the amount of money these fine young people had earned would keep several of these missionaries in the field for their entire missions. We talked about the relative value of an adventure trip as compared to that of missionary service.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p5" pid="FFpa4JbLGU2AJh9vyOg1pQ" hash="W-Yp8A">He said, “Are you asking me to have these young people donate these funds to the general missionary fund of the Church?” I said, “No, I have not asked you to do that. I have just said that there are finer things to do.” I explained that I was not against the kind of project they were planning, but there must be a balance, and, by comparison, some things are interesting and enticing while other things are important.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p6" pid="q4mZPQU4XES_30cIL4yMBg" hash="bPLLRg">Later, the bishop said he had talked to the young people and they had caught the vision and spirit of our previous conversation. They wanted to sacrifice their adventure trip and donate all the money to the general missionary fund. They asked if they could come and bring the check and have their picture taken with me as they made the donation, and could they have the picture and an article put into the news?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p7" pid="WjpHGDxz3EqleSKhxHEmJg" hash="oC2U7g">I surprised him again. I said no. Then I said, “You might consider helping your young people learn a higher law of recognition. Recognition from on high is silent. It is carefully and quietly recorded there. Let them feel the joy and gain the treasure in their heart and soul that come from silent, selfless service.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p8" pid="ZZEZUIbyHEqkSSsqztJvpQ" hash="muBw5Q">They did this, and now, as a reward, each has a memory and a pride which they recognize as one of the finer and more important things that they have ever done.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p9" pid="fXKloRb_FUmGgzzmIP763w" hash="iEm96w">In a refugee camp in Bataan, Philippines, I watched as one of our lovely lady missionaries sat down on the dirty floor beside an old woman who was weeping and confused and afraid. She gently pulled this woman’s head over onto her shoulder and smoothed her hair with one hand as she put her other arm around her to comfort her.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p10" pid="MoeFfVwGdkK6EpTZ3eD33Q" hash="75e9ig">I learned that this woman had been driven from her home. Some of her family members had been killed. She had been abused and driven through the forests and jungles and finally out of her own country. She could not even speak the language of her present benefactors.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p11" pid="mY4nd2KGXUKjc9odBNF3Tg" hash="K3xzTw">Later, as we talked of the work she was doing, the lady missionary said, with tears running down her face, “This is the finest thing I have ever done.” Many things are only interesting and enticing, while other things are important.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p12" pid="fsOJV2PYE0-noMVzzyGqyQ" hash="Qakf9w">Sometimes, because of the pressures of the world around us, our service projects become <span class="emphasis">self</span> service projects rather than <span class="emphasis">selfless</span> service projects.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p13" pid="ns3a403RS0iHmRrhJVqabg" hash="47yqZA">Selfless service projects are the projects of the gospel. They have continuity. They are not one-time special events based on entertainment and fun and games. They need not be regimented nor regulated. Selfless service projects are people-to-people projects. They are face-to-face, eye-to-eye, voice-to-ear, heart-to-heart, spirit-to-spirit, and hand-in-hand, people-to-people projects.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p14" pid="Gl9N8frslUSWhP1qc2WmJw" hash="C3_83g">We must remember that we are social beings. Our eternal destiny is welded to the destiny of our fellows. Within this social system, there is always a desire for recognition, and this is as it should be, if that desire is kept within its bounds.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p15" pid="udbjlAAaR0uPhB6GL11gOA" hash="gkdBKg">Elder Marvin J. Ashton once related that during a meeting a woman seated behind him passed him a note. It simply said, “Would you please turn around and look at me?” Then he said, “Everyone needs to be looked at.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p16" pid="tsgDJPiZ10Wdc4KFigRRNw" hash="V6pe7g">Within each of us there is an intense need to feel that we belong. This feeling of unity and togetherness comes through the warmth of a smile, a handshake, or a hug, through laughter and unspoken demonstrations of love. It comes in the quiet, reverent moments of soft conversation and in listening. It comes from a still, small voice reminding us that we are brothers and sisters, the children of a Heavenly Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p17" pid="uXsEJNINbkyDrNnr2zESGw" hash="_ZKKOg">To get recognition and the praise of men can become an obsessive goal in one’s life. It can lead from one act to another until life is filled with egotism and selfishness. The momentary pleasure that recognition and the praise of men bring almost always causes people to want more. If they can’t get it in one way, they will try another. If it can’t be obtained by being one’s natural self, they will try to get it acting out a life that is unnatural. The longing to be popular, to be praised by one’s peers, and to receive the recognition of men is a very powerful force.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p18" pid="kNeCLtYh9E-_a0B9e4zTSw" hash="GLceHw">It is vain to seek the praise or recognition of men. This vanity comes of evil because it springs forth out of selfishness. Christ clearly taught this as he spoke of those who “set themselves up for a light unto the world, that they may get gain and praise of the world; but they seek not the welfare of Zion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p19" pid="MXVWDDObf0K28vcAMWQaJA" hash="Ez5KPw">“Behold, the Lord hath forbidden this thing; wherefore, the Lord God hath given a commandment that all men should have charity, which charity is love. And except they should have charity they were nothing. Wherefore, if they should have charity they would not suffer the laborer in Zion to perish.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p20" pid="UrKcC4qIT0WDGWqn5iu5EQ" hash="Nv4n0A">“But the laborer in Zion shall labor for Zion” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/26.29-31" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 26:29–31</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p21" pid="-9bUOIpQ2UOgFoa44LclQw" hash="rxywew">Selflessness is righteousness. It embraces the true spirit of companionship. It is the very essence of friendship. It is the portrayer of true love and oneness in humanity. Its reward is the freeing of the soul, a nearness to divinity, a worthiness for the companionship of the Spirit. Every requirement that God’s plan for our salvation places upon us is based on the giving of one’s self.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p22" pid="hKSl4hb-6kWcmBFUSfQQVA" hash="4caz1g">The only way under the heavens whereby a person can be sanctified is in selfless service.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p23" pid="c0YzshdKGUaE_znwtVYMlQ" hash="d0EZcw">Where the proper focus on gospel-centered, selfless service is not developed, selfishness takes over. Of all influences that cause men to choose wrong, selfishness is undoubtedly the strongest. Where it is, the Spirit is not. Talents go unshared, the needs of the poor unrequited, the weak unstrengthened, the ignorant untaught, and the lost unrecovered.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p24" pid="MNCWLH4gM0GQzdbUEqj9QQ" hash="6UcFgQ">Selfishness, viewed in its true sense, is the absence of empathy and compassion, the abandonment of brotherhood, the rejection of God’s plan, the isolation of one’s soul.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p25" pid="byA5p8-v1kWga6xTZM6_tg" hash="qy7TaQ">As I have said, many things, in fact most, are interesting, and many are enticing. But some things are important. The limits of time dictate that we must prioritize what we do. The divinely given and heaven-protected gift of agency allows us to determine to what degree we will serve others and allow them to serve us. The depth of involvement in that which is important, rather than just interesting, is our own choice.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p26" pid="JWrTIXg9C0yH0P2Dw7tgbA" hash="8OlkvA">As we make these choices, we might consider that the glitter and excitement of festive, fun-filled projects are interesting, but the shut-ins, the lonely, the handicapped, the homeless, the latchkey kids, and the abandoned aged are important.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p27" pid="IAFg3-KeOk2-2BY1pd2FyQ" hash="v-P2Uw">Worldly magazines, tabloids, and much of the multi-mass media mess of fast-track information we are receiving is interesting and enticing, but the scriptures are important.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p28" pid="PjRPfV4xNUKgmCGA47ygHw" hash="Dwv12g">The RVs and the TVs and retirement ease make it interesting to wander and play, but people’s needs for selfless deeds are important. There is concern that “wander and play” have replaced “ponder and pray.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p29" pid="OnwBJhLj9UqAHjL4YHMhmg" hash="d5pnYQ">A focus on fashion and getting and spending and the accumulation of things for our enjoyment and comfort is interesting and enticing, but a focus on devoting one’s means and time and one’s very self to the cause of proclaiming the gospel is important.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p30" pid="3R7di3LI9k22YW6zIw0oZQ" hash="njE9Hg">The meetings and materials and planning are all interesting, but the doing is important.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p31" pid="oQ0qQdc0bkyLvMEv_fEhHQ" hash="8qYUyQ">With the constant exhortation to come unto Christ is the promise that we can be perfected in him. If we do all that we can do by loving and serving God with all of our might, mind, and strength, then is his grace sufficient for us. By his grace, after all that we can do, we may become perfect in Christ. Shall we not then strive for the recognition of that Almighty God who is our Father, through our selfless service?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p32" pid="SertAViKZECv-qoyAsFyKQ" hash="CGNcVA">“And when he had called the people unto him with his disciples also, he said unto them, Whosoever will come after me, let him deny himself, and take up his cross, and follow me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p33" pid="kOfOOZx8vEyVNVlwFDA-7g" hash="GySt2A">“For whosoever will save his life shall lose it; but whosoever shall lose his life for my sake and the gospel’s, the same shall save it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p34" pid="e8VIoDSOZEGDwg-EdnKTLg" hash="hXB4TA">“For what shall it profit a man, if he shall gain the whole world, and lose his own soul?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p35" pid="KryIXdlVpkejhpwUFCLGuw" hash="wI8NkQ">“Or what shall a man give in exchange for his soul?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/8.34-37" class="scriptureRef">Mark 8:34–37</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service.p36" pid="3MJCb89LAU2pznHq6eHrYA" hash="RbrjOw">In the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1987/10/selfless-service</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1987-general-conference/1987-10-5030-elder-william-r-bradford-64k-eng.mp3" length="5918049" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 1987 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unclutter Your Life</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life?lang=eng</link>
      <description>On our present assignment, my wife and I live a long way away from our children. This means the letters go back and forth. I would like to read a paragraph from a letter one of our daughters recently sent:</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_92905_000_015" doc-version="2" hash="tMy7SQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="XAgLGFc_SUWLK-dI-OjGaQ" hash="ZJnQ2w">Unclutter Your Life</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="SZv36njUsk2VN5KcoaNgDA" hash="zkXG1g">William R. Bradford</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2412.jpg" alt="Elder William R. Bradford" pid="YFudgsQHekSWQIyOoYfxQg" hash="4Hy0Rw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p1" pid="FcCDSzwiXEWzVo6It-XigA" hash="lkR86g">On our present assignment, my wife and I live a long way away from our children. This means the letters go back and forth. I would like to read a paragraph from a letter one of our daughters recently sent:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p2" pid="zYB8CEu1OkOG1iFbxD1NAg" hash="yfIOGQ">“I’ve become a nurse. Four of the six kids have the flu. I’m changing my ambitions from psychiatrist to nurse. Anyway, nobody in this family is sick in the head, we are just all sick. I hate it when the kids are sick.” Then in capital letters, “I WANT MY LIFE BACK!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p3" pid="XlWGeNs27ky7sx2Cn1palA" hash="WUj6mA">When we read the letter, we gave each other a knowing smile. All of our children are caught up in a very busy life. It is what they call “the fast lane.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p4" pid="yaxwzOxjhE6r2Mzc9onjcw" hash="Kv2PsQ">But those last words, “I WANT MY LIFE BACK,” have stuck in my mind, and the more I have thought about them the more concerned I’ve become. This concern has persuaded me to say something about uncluttering our lives and getting back to basics.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p5" pid="09S7X1-UYkeDhYR2caMobQ" hash="FHOf_w">The story is told of a boy who arrived home from school and found his father standing at the open door looking into a very cluttered house. “Is Mother home?” asked the boy. His father answered, “I can’t see her, but I know she’s in there somewhere. I can hear sobbing.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p6" pid="ZassRg8800W4Ad3M5tEE_g" hash="LiAs7g">This would be funny if it were not true in so many cases. I believe that a cluttered life can create a great deal of sorrow and sadness and be the cause of much sobbing. I also believe that there are a great many people in the so-called “fast lane” that want their lives back.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p7" pid="Oo796T4XSk6jbESwIr4lug" hash="bwbRrQ">A cluttered life is a life that you do not have control of. It is a life in which the things you have surrounded yourself with, and allow to use up your time, are controlling you and negatively influencing your happiness and eternal progress.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p8" pid="6HAdbXY7B0O7cDPEvnfn0Q" hash="ZGwZQQ">Our lives can become cluttered by many things. Some are obvious, such as material things, the stuff we collect. I really wish I were able to give a lesson on how to prioritize the material things, how to sort them, dispose of some, and put the rest in order, but I’m not qualified.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p9" pid="y_v4mxlRUUqSfkUKvP3pEg" hash="BSUJHQ">The last time I worked on that kind of a project, I spent nine hours moving things around, changing them from one box to another, stacking some here and some there. When I was finished I was so proud of myself. Then I realized that all I had really done was move them from one place to another.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p10" pid="VUtalVP-8U-89aA1E2424A" hash="UZKj6w">My wife says that I have a subconscious rule that I must move things from one place to another at least a hundred times before I can bring myself to give them away. Suffice it to say, if you need help in this, there are better experts than I to teach you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p11" pid="Viqzw_9Xa0uzltGSzzlSuA" hash="BLTW1w">But how well I know that we can surround ourselves with the material things to the extent that we have no time for the spiritual. Look around and you will see all the gadgets and toys and the nice and the fun things that cause us to squander and pay and to wander and play.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p12" pid="dMYt6wJYFEmzsydJIhrlaw" hash="TaC97A">Other things that clutter our lives and use up our time are not as obvious as the material. They are more subtle and just seem to evolve, taking control of us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p13" pid="z5WeA2vTeEKdqbVJemKPjQ" hash="JYid_w">Whenever I think of something subtle—you know, kind of hidden, something we know is there if we stop to think about it but do not suspect it of cluttering up or negatively influencing our lives—whenever I think of something subtle like this, I know that Satan is busy at his work.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p14" pid="uVMXYvJHfUWqtB5rPHN1Bg" hash="Ujll7Q">Nothing suits the devil better than to become a silent partner with us. He knows that we have agency and are at liberty to make choices for ourselves. He also knows that while in mortality we are subject to time. If by his subtle means he can become our silent partner, he can then influence us to make wrong choices that use up our time unwisely and prevent us from doing that which we should.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p15" pid="9HC2g_8FU0C6zQhMg-c7bg" hash="XUoiGQ">We give our lives to that which we give our time. As I have said, while here in mortality we are subject to time. We also have agency and may do what we will with our time. Let me repeat: We give our lives to that which we give our time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p16" pid="eI7lS9bWVEKkY0rkm8tFcg" hash="BKgn8Q">I have learned that it is very difficult, if not impossible, to unclutter one’s life by starting at the top of the pile with the idea that the solution is to just get things sorted and better organized. It is nice to get better organized, but that is not enough. Much has to be discarded. We must actually get rid of it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p17" pid="AufVrzfMC0iKD81hJ_VPUg" hash="jMLX6A">To do this we need to develop a list of basics, a list of those things that are indispensable to our mortal welfare and happiness and our eternal salvation. This list must follow the gospel pattern and contain the elements needed for our sanctification and perfection. It must be the product of inspiration and prayerful judgment between the things we really need and the things we just want. It should separate need from greed. It must be our best understanding of those things that are important as opposed to those things that are just interesting. It should have nothing to do with trying to stay in the fast lane.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p18" pid="BIseTN73RE-yqYk2LmdM1Q" hash="kOkf9Q">We need to examine all the ways we use our time: our work, our ambitions, our affiliations, and the habits that drive our actions. As we make such a study, we will be able to better understand what we should really be spending our time doing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p19" pid="gCvWz0vpOU-hsSktAAuc3w" hash="ATMixQ">At the top of our list of basics, we will surely have the family. Next only to our devotion to God, the family comes first. Their temporal and spiritual well-being is of vital importance, and so there must be work to provide for it. This means hard work. Although there has to be a balance and time for the fun things, they cannot outweigh the need for a cooperative effort by all the members of the family to provide for their spiritual and temporal needs. To work is a commandment from God. It is the pattern for the happiness of individuals and the family and is the strength of both the Church and society.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p20" pid="97hUKNxv4k21fgSIDdVBgw" hash="qiWxJg">A mother should never allow herself to become so involved with extras that she finds herself neglecting her divine role. A father must not let any activity, no matter how interesting or important it may seem, keep him from giving of himself in the one-on-one service and close, constant care of each member of the family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p21" pid="8rqN8J3fJUeuOZz1YIsd9Q" hash="Wzoz9w">The titles of Mother and Father will persist after this life. All that we may acquire and any titles we may earn which are worldly will pass away. In the meantime, they may be cluttering up our lives and affecting our eternal outcome.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p22" pid="7zKyTh-iZU-DPV6XOiTwyQ" hash="CZs3vg">Young people must learn that none of the exciting and entertaining and fun things are worth it if they take you off from the path that will lead you back home to your Heavenly Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p23" pid="0CkCJkG_5UeWtGHl8z_bOw" hash="LNg73w">We must remember that a person who is not living the basics of the gospel of Jesus Christ is not living them, no matter who or what has caused it. We must also remember that a family divided is a family divided, no matter who or what divides it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p24" pid="iksWcWFvTkeG8-cNkI-UJw" hash="tB5YcA">There are, then, some serious and soul-searching questions that we must ask ourselves. One of these questions would surely be, do I have time for prayer? I don’t mean just an occasional, quick, repetitious prayer that is like giving a wave of the hand to your Father in Heaven as you pass Him on your way to something important. I mean sincere, honest, “from the depths of a contrite spirit and a broken heart” prayer; kneeling in humility, demonstrating to the Holy Father that you really love him; private prayer which involves you in the process of repentance and pleading for forgiveness and allows time for pondering and waiting for the answers to come.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p25" pid="rE6Gb7s-g0GNDIX1tVYpgg" hash="fZ4tiw">As you examine your list of basics, the next question would be, do I study the scriptures? If you do, you know that Lehi saw a rod of iron, which, interpreted, means the word of God. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/11.1-23" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 11:1–23</a>.) Those who held to the rod, using it as a guide at all times, came safely through the mist of darkness and arrived at the tree of life and partook of its glorious fruit. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/8.19,30" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 8:19, 30</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p26" pid="gQpgDMxQj0CQg7Rl6SQx7g" hash="XRmqRg">Now the question again: do you study the scriptures? I solemnly testify that the holy scriptures are the word of God. Constant study of them is the act of holding to the iron rod. They will guide you to the tree of life. If you are one who has said, “I want my life back,” I exhort you to go to the tree of life, where you will find the pure love of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p27" pid="7lIhgIJolUa9YKB1Aot_Jg" hash="eRqPOg">With an uncluttered life, you will not be so busy doing terrestrial things that you do not have time to do those things which are celestial. God’s plan is a plan of simplicity. It involves being obedient to simple laws, laws that have within them an automatic blessing and happiness for obedience and an automatic punishment and unhappiness for their disobedience.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p28" pid="oCyc0qH6h0S3K8ZKLBQmCw" hash="VqS_sw">I urge you to clear away the clutter. Take your life back. Use your willpower. Learn to say no to those things that will rob you of your precious time and infringe upon your agency to choose to live in exactness to God’s plan of happiness and exaltation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p29" pid="CoFBLIpLn065SMABFJuWng" hash="EtR7sQ">Don’t let the subtle influences of Satan take away any part of your life. Keep it under your own control and operated by your own agency. This life is a probationary period. It is a marvelous gift of time during which we can learn to be like our Heavenly Father by following the teachings of His Son, Jesus Christ. The path He leads us on is not a cluttered path. It is simple and straight and lighted by the Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p30" pid="eiW_Jy6kgUyCdgyQBvXWRg" hash="cN0-Vw">It is my humble prayer that by our choices we may preserve our individual agency from the subtleness of Satan and live our lives bright and clear and on the path that leads us back to the presence of our Holy Father.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life.p31" pid="IivbojHe2k6YDBOk6c4w6A" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1992/04/unclutter-your-life</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1992-general-conference/1992-04-2060-elder-william-r-bradford-64k-eng.mp3" length="5566624" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 1992 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Righteousness</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1999/10/righteousness?lang=eng</link>
      <description>No other feeling in the soul of man can bring the joy and happiness than that of knowing you are doing all you can to become righteous.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/righteousness" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_99265_000_034" doc-version="2" hash="yRAvAA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/righteousness.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="i3OhnuUqEkSwOiyeeTKiqQ" hash="XLPf9g">Righteousness</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="mwcD-bDWAkW05ME_wiczAw" hash="zkXG1g">William R. Bradford</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="Tphotm-idU663DJyPpZavQ" hash="ARl2lA">No other feeling in the soul of man can bring the joy and happiness than that of knowing you are doing all you can to become righteous.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/righteousness.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-a4b.jpg" alt="Elder William R. Bradford" pid="ShlKojDPRkqejQaDYoom6A" hash="NCBHOg" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/righteousness.p1" pid="H82usOn1P0y1MJfvxvltqg" hash="5dCkkg">We live in a time when many men and women do not prescribe morality to their actions, and so they believe that what they do has only social consequences. In this they deny God, and they also deny that things are either right or they are wrong.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/righteousness.p2" pid="uN71axd200qyQhMJPCyBdg" hash="dB43pg">Each of us at one time or another has heard the statement, “Okay, have it your own way,” and so it is with the way that many in the world live.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/righteousness.p3" pid="0gKqxkJkMUypr16faf46SQ" hash="rDNxeA">I witness to you that there is a better way. It is to live a life of righteousness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/righteousness.p4" pid="MAB2soIPBUi2E9pbCcPiMw" hash="grH3GQ">The word <span class="emphasis">righteousness</span> is a most interesting and unique word. It is an umbrella word that spreads out and covers all the attributes of God. A person, then, who is righteous is Godly or Godlike.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/righteousness.p5" pid="C1uCFNOigUmFGdMSQuc3fQ" hash="CU-8aQ">Right and wrong do exist and are opposite to each other. The actions of mankind do have moral consequences. The gospel of Jesus Christ defines for us the difference between what is good and what is bad. That which is good comes from God. Christ has said: “And whatsoever thing persuadeth men to do good is of me; for good cometh of none save it be of me. I am the same that leadeth men to all good” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/ether/4.12" class="scriptureRef">Ether 4:12</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/righteousness.p6" pid="kZtc3HPzlkaq0VxSTrheng" hash="JwDPGg">Righteousness is a composite of all that is good. It embraces the principles of heavenly power and law by which all things of God are handled and controlled and governed.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/righteousness.p7" pid="60NLIOs_E0GOgWj1grmrsA" hash="3ZbNcQ">In righteousness there is great simplicity. In every case that confronts us in life there is either a right way or a wrong way to proceed. If we choose the right way, we are sustained in our actions by the principles of righteousness, in the which there is power from the heavens. If we choose the wrong way and act on that choice, there is no such heavenly promise or power, and we are alone and are destined to fail.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/righteousness.p8" pid="7InE-acGDUiBwomqego14Q" hash="NQOi2g">The question arises: How can we know which is right and which is wrong? Just as our Heavenly Father sent His Son, Jesus Christ, to create this earth and to execute and govern all things pertaining to it, so He sent the Holy Ghost to act in providing the light of the Spirit to men on the earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/righteousness.p9" pid="puVPJBegv0KM_tRS1Ql_FA" hash="43alMA">The light of the Spirit is organized as a communication system to transmit concepts of truth into the minds of the children of God. The Holy Ghost, by way of the Spirit, will enlighten our minds and give us clarity of understanding of concepts of truth if we obey the laws which govern the use of the Spirit. This is the way that our Father in Heaven teaches us right from wrong. If we are willing to learn His ways and follow them, we will never have to guess, but we will always know for sure the difference between right and wrong.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/righteousness.p10" pid="y_owfHvNCkmR7ZG1EQ-S7g" hash="WKDEWg">In righteousness there is the fulfillment of faith and hope. Every blessing that God has promised to His children is predicated upon obedience to His laws and commandments. Obedience to His laws and commandments is what makes us righteous, and that righteousness qualifies us to be worthy of the promised blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/righteousness.p11" pid="7-DMzlMXL0Kpmkjl7UD6vw" hash="kOAi9g">Each of us lives with his or her own situation. There are challenges with health, economy, literacy, singleness, loneliness, oppression, abuse, transgression, and a never-ending list of existing conditions. The solution to all these challenges is righteousness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/righteousness.p12" pid="7tzwRU5-FU6SjeFz7-ruCg" hash="8X8jcQ">Where there is disobedience to God’s laws and commandments, in benevolence He has given us the law of repentance. If we act upon this marvelous law, we will be forgiven of our disobedience and become more righteous; thus repentance leads us to righteousness. Many, in fact most, of the challenges that we have in mortality can be solved by repentance. They can all be solved finally by righteousness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/righteousness.p13" pid="ip2Q_nk040CATF5eAUaB3g" hash="sT9g5g">There is great joy and happiness in striving to live righteously. In simple terms, the plan of God for His children is that they come to this earth and do all that they can to learn and live in obedience to laws. Then, after all they can do, the redeeming work of the Savior, Jesus Christ, is sufficient to do all that they could not do for themselves.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/righteousness.p14" pid="yq4G3_cKAkizBC4YG0Lb5w" hash="QDIsrQ">The ancient Prophet Moroni, as he ended his work and closed the abridgment of the record of God’s dealings with His people, which is the Book of Mormon, said it this way: “Yea, come unto Christ, and be perfected in him, and deny yourselves of all ungodliness; and if ye shall deny yourselves of all ungodliness, and love God with all your might, mind and strength, then is his grace sufficient for you, that by his grace ye may be perfect in Christ” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.32" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 10:32</a>). Moroni’s way of saying do all that you can is to love God with all your might, mind, and strength.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/righteousness.p15" pid="JfvxnVlxn0aXymujgCRCyw" hash="GGbDJw">Striving to live righteously is attempting to do all that we can in obedience. With this comes the inner peace and comfort that in doing all we can, the plan of God will be accomplished in our behalf. No other feeling in the soul of man can bring the joy and happiness than that of knowing you are doing all you can to become righteous.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/righteousness.p16" pid="NZcyB8Kt8ES38E8xVsAqGA" hash="VE5smg">In righteousness there is safety and security. With it we bind up the Lord. He has said: “For the names of the righteous shall be written in the book of life, and unto them will I grant an inheritance at my right hand. And now, my brethren, what have ye to say against this? I say unto you, if ye speak against it, it matters not, for the word of God must be fulfilled” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/5.58" class="scriptureRef">Alma 5:58</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/righteousness.p17" pid="LStkdp2dFEGc-mAhTimmvQ" hash="Ljq16Q">In a world where transgression, corruption, and terrorism strike fear into men and women, where can we turn for safety and security? There is no safety and security except in righteousness. There is no place to hide. There are no walls to keep out the adversary and his campaign of opposition. There is no defense against the uncertain and unknown except righteousness. Fear in the hearts and minds of men and women can be turned to peace only by replacing that fear with an understanding of God’s plan of happiness and the knowledge that they are doing all they can to become righteous and worthy to qualify for eternal salvation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/righteousness.p18" pid="mfpgsYxX8Uem-gurGog43w" hash="c4wsuQ">As the forces of good and evil polarize more and more, those who have not prescribed a moral consequence to their actions will find their lives in such chaos that their style of life will be unbearable to them. Then the prophecies will be fulfilled which say, “And all things shall be in commotion; and surely, men’s hearts shall fail them; for fear shall come upon all people” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/88.91" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 88:91</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/righteousness.p19" pid="_Wmn_K97nUCylOmGVvo3Cw" hash="pkt0qQ">When that day comes, the righteous Saints of God will be the only well-governed people unto whom the world can turn. It will be there and there only that they will find stability and steadfastness. They will come, not knowing the doctrine of the righteous, but it will be as foretold: “For, behold, I say unto you that Zion shall flourish, and the glory of the Lord shall be upon her; And she shall be an ensign unto the people, and there shall come unto her out of every nation under heaven” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/64.41-42" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 64:41–42</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/righteousness.p20" pid="A40d66ZLrUqM5bbMfEucDQ" hash="4sVA5w">Righteousness is the better way. Finally, it is the only way. In righteousness is the power to provide the joy and happiness and the safety and security that men and women have longed for and searched for through all the generations of time.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/righteousness.p21" pid="3Bjym8Yu70SuhnCLS4Ik-Q" hash="ctxz9Q">It seems like such a simple solution, but the reality is that “Satan is abroad in the land, and he goeth forth deceiving the nations” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/52.14" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 52:14</a>). There is opposition. Right and wrong do exist. Our actions do have moral consequences. There is no right way to do a wrong thing.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/righteousness.p22" pid="5qD5Uy_BhkOdPg1XyHTn7A" hash="moQOSA">As one called as a witness of Jesus Christ and to declare His gospel, I plead that you will not delay in doing all that you can. That you will strive to come to know His laws and commandments and work with urgency to obey them. By this you will be in a process that will make you righteous and thus worthy of the promised blessings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1999/10/righteousness.p23" pid="HdCgkkjzOUiNuU5Ln-tlRQ" hash="swIexQ">Jesus Christ is at the head of this work. He is a God of righteousness. In His gracious mercy He has provided us with a righteous Prophet, whom if we follow, we will be doing what is right. To the truth of this fact and the words which I have spoken, I testify in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1999/10/righteousness</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1999-general-conference/1999-10-5050-elder-william-r-bradford-64k-eng.mp3" length="5283584" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 1999 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
