<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By William R. Walker</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by William R. Walker.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/William%20R.%20Walker.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by William R. Walker.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2002 14:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2002 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>I’ll Go Where You Want Me to Go</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2002/04/i-ll-go-where-you-want-me-to-go?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I love Him. I want to do all that I can to serve as He would have me serve.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/i-ll-go-where-you-want-me-to-go" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10029598_000_035" doc-version="2" hash="qM_wRA">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/i-ll-go-where-you-want-me-to-go.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="37Xage2RBkOGI40aTXt-Bg" hash="5J7JvQ">I’ll Go Where You Want Me to Go</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="vyQC5zf5O0e6Q7caQgyZ9g" hash="_f8rhw">William R. Walker</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="Juk7R6Ah40C_0JwUv4ug3g" hash="6cCD3Q">I love Him. I want to do all that I can to serve as He would have me serve.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/i-ll-go-where-you-want-me-to-go.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-ee1.jpg" alt="Elder William R. Walker" pid="kO_RayGq8EOhjFCIl23YpQ" hash="RH-eHw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/i-ll-go-where-you-want-me-to-go.p1" pid="a13M_BxaZU6eufAE1mCpaA" hash="1sUZng">My beloved brothers and sisters, it is with deep humility and great appreciation that I stand in this holy place. As a little boy growing up in Raymond, Alberta, Canada, I loved it every time we sang, “I’ll go where you want me to go, dear Lord” (see <span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 270). Those words, each time we sang them in a sacrament meeting or Sunday School, burned commitment into my heart and soul, that I always wanted to go where the Lord wanted me to go, to say what He wanted me to say—“I’ll be what you want me to be,” dear Lord. That commitment seems appropriate to restate today.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/i-ll-go-where-you-want-me-to-go.p2" pid="-CWfyrdSZ0itWfTkgMfgmQ" hash="NlFb2w">I’m grateful for the sustaining vote of yesterday, and with you I sustain President Gordon B. Hinckley and his counselors, President Monson and President Faust, and President Packer and all of the Twelve as prophets, seers, and revelators. I bear witness that indeed they are prophets, seers, and revelators.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2002/04/i-ll-go-where-you-want-me-to-go.p3" pid="nBCB5GWhtkSYzH5A-RAvOg" hash="nHzuGQ">I love the Lord. I love this Church. I love the wonderful, faithful Saints throughout the world who do all that they can to honor their commitments and to live their religion. I bear witness that God lives and that Jesus Christ, His Son, is our Savior and our Redeemer. I love Him. I want to do all that I can to serve as He would have me serve, and I say these words and bear my witness to the truthfulness of these things in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2002/04/i-ll-go-where-you-want-me-to-go</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2002-general-conference/2002-04-5070-elder-william-r-walker-64k-eng.mp3" length="1043832" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2002 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three Presiding High Priests</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Wisdom and strength will come to us as we look to the First Presidency as our ideal and our pattern of leadership.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00009475_000_016" doc-version="2" hash="CU200Q">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="7nzV_ezQ40qqdLyfLfwcYA" hash="SUs5jQ">Three Presiding High Priests</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="mPZMomIq_EO07_cjQQjetg" hash="Rl6lnw">Elder William R. Walker</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="zXV-gFYjcUGM0CtmUeENEw" hash="rywiVQ">Wisdom and strength will come to us as we look to the First Presidency as our ideal and our pattern of leadership.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.t1">
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p1" pid="QOXoeP-wKUW0rU49Jx78AQ" hash="mElSOg">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="37"></span>What a blessing and privilege it is for us to sustain President Thomas S. Monson, President Henry B. Eyring, and President Dieter F. Uchtdorf as the new First Presidency of the Lord’s Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p2" pid="4NAyzWagTE2_GBsWJ-QUVA" hash="kd2YAQ">I first learned the importance of the First Presidency as a boy growing up in Western Canada. When I would go to Grandma and Grandpa Walker’s home, I was greeted in the entry by a framed photo of the First Presidency of the Church. I remember it well. It seemed that they stood as sentinels, greeting all who entered.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p3" pid="T4op53FmkUysX2bl0fvlFQ" hash="hIK7cg">The beautiful color photo was of President George Albert Smith with his counselors J. Reuben Clark Jr. and David O. McKay. The photo showed them standing together by a large world globe. I loved the picture. They were such handsome and dignified men; I knew them as the prophet of God and his counselors.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p4" pid="jJZVhi4eFkGbYWYLPp0c6A" hash="PjqXUw">That picture hanging in the front foyer of my grandparents’ home had a powerful influence on me. I lived in the small prairie town of Raymond, where my grandparents lived. I could walk to their home, so I visited often. I remember frequently standing quietly alone in the foyer, reverently looking at that picture of the First Presidency. I remember thinking about why my grandparents thought it was so important to honor the First Presidency and have that picture prominently displayed in their home. All who entered would see it. Perhaps most importantly, for their children and grandchildren it was a constant reminder of what was deeply important in the hearts and lives of Grandma and Grandpa.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p5" pid="mcWdVMWqykmYMEapGFnF8w" hash="15I54Q">Years later I concluded that displaying the picture of the First Presidency was equivalent to Joshua’s beautiful expression: “Choose you this day whom ye will serve; … as for me and my house, we will serve the Lord” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/josh/24.15" class="scriptureRef">Joshua 24:15</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p6" pid="xBy2P2RUskia1nhxbHh89A" hash="HXbUiw">All who entered the home of James and Fannye Walker knew that written <span class="pageBreak" page-number="38"></span>upon their hearts were the words “As for us and our house, we will serve the Lord.” As their grandson, I knew it, and I have never forgotten it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p7" pid="g0PtZ9-O80WG8DJImqTDPA" hash="R9sRbQ">As a boy I didn’t understand so well the significance of there being three in the First Presidency rather than having one President. I knew, of course, that Jesus had selected Peter, James, and John, not just Peter. I knew that my father was one of three men in the bishopric, serving as a counselor to Bishop J. O. Hicken. I knew my grandfather was the stake president and that he had two counselors who stood beside him (President John Allen and President Leslie Palmer).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p8" pid="Rm4oOmRFx0O8kv2RVrZn9w" hash="1phg1A">In every case<span class="emphasis">—a presidency—</span>not just consisting of one man as the leader but as three who led together.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p9" pid="73aDtZC7_UWMVMUjPBmTqw" hash="odUQ1A">In Primary I had learned the Articles of Faith and grew to love them. The Articles of Faith give our youth comfort and confidence as they learn the fundamental doctrines of the Church. I then knew that “a man must be called of God, by prophecy, and by the laying on of hands by those who are in authority, to preach the Gospel and administer in the ordinances thereof” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/a-of-f/1.5" class="scriptureRef">Articles of Faith 1:5</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p10" pid="_lxYAsh2WkuFCpv00XE7ng" hash="AkLFfQ">In 1835 the Lord revealed to the Prophet Joseph Smith the proper order of presidencies in the Church:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p11" pid="LJJhrOjZpESmldrm-H1MhQ" hash="0SgTGA">“Of necessity there are presidents, or presiding officers. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p12" pid="QK5O-TlOHkmJ7PyzXG1SFg" hash="xAHBTw">“Of the Melchizedek Priesthood, three Presiding High Priests, chosen by the body, appointed and ordained to that office, and upheld by the confidence, faith, and prayer of the church, form a quorum of the Presidency of the Church” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/107.21-22" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 107:21–22</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p13" pid="TMPsiEfeOUWFvysyyPR8og" hash="HRi0Ag">“A quorum of three presidents” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/107.29" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 107:29</a>)—not a president and two vice presidents but three presiding high priests. A quorum of three presidents—the First Presidency of the Lord’s Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p14" pid="NKFIJzC9JUS1G0f54Sqkpg" hash="lSCy2A">The world does not organize itself this way, but this is how the Lord organized and structured His Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p15" pid="Niaj71S0qUeKR7O29rKmuw" hash="a0dbRA">It brings to mind the scripture:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p16" pid="MsQXfJQR_0ihIM69LGBb-g" hash="8ZWgYg">“For my thoughts are not your thoughts, neither are your ways my ways, saith the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p17" pid="uAJi8bsRQkahtY6NpSAwHA" hash="QZuHqg">“For as the heavens are higher than the earth, so are my ways higher than your ways, and my thoughts than your thoughts” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/55.8-9" class="scriptureRef">Isaiah 55:8–9</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p18" pid="YcGs5JtlzkqI4fE298sbeg" hash="4Dj8ng">At about the time of my seventh birthday, I learned a little about succession in the Presidency when President George Albert Smith passed away. Sometime later the picture in Grandma and Grandpa’s foyer was replaced by a beautiful picture of President David O. McKay and his counselors Stephen L Richards and J. Reuben Clark Jr.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p19" pid="jY7JhLXxlkixHaDmq_FxRw" hash="cGaMXg">As a boy I certainly didn’t understand the deep significance or the process of succession in the Presidency—but I knew that the prophet had died and that we were led by a new prophet of God, with two counselors at his side.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p20" pid="HuBprjqTu0OeDJ5-9Fu71g" hash="lxvtng">At age 13 I was called into Bishop Murray Holt’s office, and he extended a call to me to serve as the president of the deacons quorum. He told me I needed to go home and pray about who my counselors should be. He taught me that the Lord would help me decide. He did. I then learned about counselors, and I began to see why the Lord has His Church directed by presidencies, not just presidents. I loved my counselors in the deacons quorum, and we prayed and worked hard to help the boys in our quorum. Bishop Holt taught me the pattern of presidencies and taught me how a presidency should operate and function in the Lord’s Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p21" pid="cOfKXECrV0uVwAjILjzjbA" hash="VVJMng">When I later served as president of other quorums, I already knew the importance of counselors, and I knew that the Lord would help me choose them—just as my bishop had taught me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p22" pid="9NdVlrTNXUqVQNXNy-ZO1A" hash="MgRH5A">As a deacons quorum president and later as a bishop and stake president, I knew that whatever wisdom, understanding, or capacity I had, it would be magnified considerably when I included my counselors in any decision that needed to be made. I learned that the benefits of serving together as a presidency were magnificent and magnifying.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p23" pid="czqYYIRwXEK2pECiorvABA" hash="JDwETw">I came to understand why the Lord appointed that His Church should be led by three presiding high priests and why that form of leadership would be prescribed <span class="pageBreak" page-number="39"></span>throughout most of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p24" pid="RuhlpKoYwUK7SZanZn8VNg" hash="Nn4jfg">The Lord said, “I will give unto you a pattern in all things, that ye may not be deceived” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/52.14" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 52:14</a>). He has given us the pattern of leadership. President Gordon B. Hinckley taught: “Every organization in the Church is presided over by a presidency of three, except the Seventies [and the Twelve]” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of Gordon B. Hinckley</span> [1997], 94).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p25" pid="RzecKk_IHE2oq0XdlA8JbQ" hash="SFoB2g">Additionally, the auxiliaries at all levels are led by a president and two counselors. All the blessings and benefits of serving together as a presidency apply to auxiliaries as well as to the priesthood quorums.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p26" pid="CDNVBKYIaE2FkTbLFCEKGg" hash="0-MXlQ">Every one of us who serve in presidencies anywhere in the Church should look to the First Presidency as our pattern and the example that we seek to follow as we carry out our stewardships. We should strive to be like them and to work together in love and harmony as they do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p27" pid="7kXBNsCf3EOFphOXHMtq8g" hash="Tf33mw">President Gordon B. Hinckley often spoke of the importance of counselors. He said, “The Lord put [counselors] there for a purpose” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of Gordon B. Hinckley, </span>94).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p28" pid="4l0RwJP7l0qVKqv5GxHiPQ" hash="nopURg">President Hinckley further instructed us: “Every morning except Monday, the First Presidency meets, when we are in town. I call on President Faust to present his business and we discuss it and make a decision. Then I call on President Monson to present his business and we discuss it and make a decision. Then I present the items which I wish to present and we discuss them and make a decision. We work together. … You can’t be a one-man operation in a presidency. Counselors—what a wonderful thing are counselors. They save you from doing the wrong things, they help you to do the right things” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of Gordon B. Hinckley,</span> 95; see also “In … Counsellors There Is Safety,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> Nov. 1990, 48–51).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p29" pid="4e1Lx-8ETkuLaDKwPpEilg" hash="WHZbiA">A counselor to President Joseph F. Smith once described how the First Presidency deliberated: “When a case came before [the President of the Church] to judge, he and his counselors would talk it over and give it their <span class="emphasis">careful consideration until they came to the same conclusion”</span> (Anthon H. Lund, in Conference Report, June 1919, 19; emphasis added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p30" pid="RCYGXWKrbEywtc2QBQ4z9g" hash="eSeJ7A">That should be our pattern in presidencies.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p31" pid="OcRR23n5eUegtiJYA60_0A" hash="8wXy5A">The revelations teach us to make our decisions in quorums and presidencies “in all righteousness, in holiness, and lowliness of heart, meekness and long suffering, and in faith, and virtue, and knowledge, temperance, patience, godliness, brotherly kindness and charity” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/107.30" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 107:30</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p32" pid="zDOsLubCs0GlBOyi-em36g" hash="X5yjFw">The Lord has given us the pattern.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p33" pid="2pEbBd8ilU6nrY3FaMcVSA" hash="SV97ZQ">We have sustained today the new First Presidency of the Church. They will teach us and show us the pattern that we should follow. Wisdom and strength will come to us as we look to the First Presidency as our ideal and our pattern of leadership.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p34" pid="ON8MX8ME1E63N1zQCkKAGQ" hash="FY4CCg">Great blessings will come to our families as we teach our children and grandchildren to love and sustain the leaders of the Church. As a young boy standing in my grandparents’ home, I knew that we were led by men of God, whom the Lord had placed there to guide us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests.p35" pid="GDFkJa-K4Ue93IdIW-aCWQ" hash="X3xXhQ">And I know it now. I bear witness that this is the work of the Lord Jesus Christ and that we are led by His apostles and prophets. I bear witness that the senior apostle, President Thomas S. Monson, has been called of God and that with his two noble counselors at his side, they will lead us in accordance with the mind and will of the Lord, whose Church this is. In the sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2008/04/three-presiding-high-priests</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2008-general-conference/2008-04-2070-elder-william-r-walker-64k-eng.mp3" length="4471126" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2008 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Live True to the Faith</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith?lang=eng</link>
      <description>William R. Walker encourages Latter-day Saints to live true to the faith, honoring the legacy of their faithful ancestors.
		</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith" dup-conf="false" dup-mag="false" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_10985_000_52walker" doc-version="2" hash="H73h_A">
	
	<div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.head1">
		<h1 class="title" pid="H-tPXRx2KEywLbUh76eIYA" hash="BqB31w">Live True to the Faith</h1>
		<div class="byline">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p" pid="q6bwDIMvkkOIpDjuS1dnGg" hash="LVNHWg">By Elder William R. Walker</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p" pid="UfJecHYrskOvIQ7DEEhHfw" hash="sSmk3g">Of the Seventy</p>
		</div>
		<img src="https://www.lds.org/bc/content/shared/content/images/leaders/william-r-walker.jpg" altText="Elder William R. Walker" pid="vVGsFdbbOE-Gtx5kXvzC3w" hash="65rhHQ" />
		<p class="kicker" pid="7zZ3G22AikSy1goWY1GSYw" hash="PHUWYQ">Each of us will be greatly blessed if we know the stories of faith and sacrifice that led our forefathers to join the Lord’s Church.</p>
		<p class="authorName" pid="wn5LAb8BQ06BtRF7NCKWbQ" hash="LVNHWg1">By Elder William R. Walker</p>
	</div>
	<div class="bodyBlock" pid="nIHyTcvCF0KXhsj-o3Xorg" hash="naK9Cg">
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p5" pid="ysz8ePkAgUagQ40AXkUUDw" hash="aagJlg">I love Church history. Perhaps like many of you, my own faith is fortified when I learn of the remarkable dedication of our forefathers who accepted the gospel and lived true to the faith.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p6" pid="BcmZtpc56kyd-wZ_iRClnQ" hash="nIdMFA">One month ago, 12,000 wonderful youth from the Gilbert Arizona Temple District celebrated the completion of their new temple with an inspiring performance, demonstrating their commitment to live righteously. The theme of their celebration was “Live True to the Faith.”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p7" pid="nm6vWS948UqYtqMP_oab9g" hash="lzVyuA">Just as those faithful Arizona youth have done, each Latter-day Saint should commit to “live true to the faith.”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p8" pid="j8vcNC6N-EyNpVhOIoNmWA" hash="KjXDEQ">The words of the hymn say, “True to the faith that our parents have cherished” (“True to the Faith,” <span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 254).</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p9" pid="xtDFXKYkTUuCCB5C9rPkDA" hash="lY0jsw">We could add, “True to the faith that our grandparents have cherished.”</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p10" pid="hLRc7eCpBki4PLaiHY_23g" hash="iCx6sA">I wondered if each of those enthusiastic Arizona youth knew their own Church history—if they knew the history of how <span class="emphasis">their</span> family came to be members of the Church. It would be a wonderful thing if every Latter-day Saint knew the conversion stories of their forefathers.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p11" pid="2sB7vqgcg0eOC3vD-P_y2A" hash="ROKERw">Whether or not you are a descendant of pioneers, the Mormon pioneer heritage of faith and sacrifice is your heritage. It is the noble heritage of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.</p>
		<span class="story">
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p12" pid="oGC-JmV6bUCCUu5lR6lXFA" hash="WeLs4g">One of the most wonderful chapters in the history of the Church occurred when Wilford Woodruff, an Apostle of the Lord, was teaching the restored gospel of Jesus Christ throughout Great Britain in 1840—just 10 years after the establishment of the Church.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p13" pid="OjIX2-CRCEKFVPZIDijWSg" hash="JvTj6Q">Wilford Woodruff and other Apostles had focused their work in the Liverpool and Preston areas of England, with considerable success. Elder Woodruff, who later became President of the Church, was constantly praying to God to guide him in this very important work. His prayers led to the inspiration to go to a different place to teach the gospel.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p14" pid="sU6Rb65zKkOadgaHay6vtA" hash="RlTvqw">President Monson has taught us that when we get the inspiration from heaven to do something, we do it now—we don’t procrastinate. That is exactly what Wilford Woodruff did. With clear direction from the Spirit to “go … south,” Elder Woodruff left almost immediately and traveled to a part of England called Herefordshire—farming country in the southwest of England. Here he met a prosperous farmer named John Benbow, where he was welcomed “with glad hearts and thanksgiving” (Wilford <span class="pageBreak" page-number="98"></span>Woodruff, in Matthias F. Cowley, <span class="emphasis">Wilford Woodruff: History of His Life and Labors as Recorded in His Daily Journals</span> [1909], 117).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p15" pid="aGKjdo8rGk2aCHR-_O2j0Q" hash="L7IZ1w">A group of over 600 people, who called themselves the United Brethren, had been “praying for light and truth” (Wilford Woodruff, in <span class="emphasis">Teachings of Presidents of the Church: Wilford Woodruff</span> [2004], 91). The Lord sent Wilford Woodruff as an answer to their prayers.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p16" pid="abIbS_RUDketbE_9Ibp7SA" hash="CY0sKQ">Elder Woodruff’s teaching bore fruit immediately, and many were baptized. Brigham Young and Willard Richards joined him in Herefordshire, and the three Apostles had remarkable success.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p17" pid="UKTg3rq-e061revUl9d-DQ" hash="RfOr_g">In only a few months, they organized 33 branches for the 541 members who had joined the Church. Their remarkable work continued, and ultimately almost every one of the members of the United Brethren were baptized into The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p18" pid="iwn3DoFaQUaISb0cUy9LSA" hash="S65oHg">My great-great-grandmother Hannah Maria Eagles Harris was one of the first to listen to Wilford Woodruff. She informed her husband, Robert Harris Jr., that she had heard the word of God and that she intended to be baptized. Robert was not pleased to hear his wife’s report. He told her he would accompany her to the next sermon given by the Mormon missionary, and he would straighten him out.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p19" pid="s3IoKmLWpk-B45uvIqLvMQ" hash="eurLxw">Sitting near the front of the assembly, with a firm resolve to not be swayed, and perhaps to heckle the visiting preacher, Robert was immediately touched by the Spirit, just as his wife had been. He knew the message of the Restoration was true, and he and his wife were baptized.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p20" pid="p99O7kSS_0-qRWPxHKAdqQ" hash="jqOL2A">Their story of faith and devotion is similar to thousands of others: when they heard the gospel message, they knew it was true!</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p21" pid="duC4gf_3q0WDj-L7dqoQLA" hash="OtuaEw">As the Lord says, “My sheep hear my voice, and I know them, and they follow me” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/10.27" class="scriptureRef">John 10:27</a>).</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p22" pid="I8e406MswE-ev8N6bgZ_Lw" hash="A4AfDQ">Having heard the voice of the Shepherd, they fully committed their lives to living the gospel and following the direction of the Lord’s prophet. Responding to the call to gather to Zion, they left behind their home in England, crossed the Atlantic, and gathered with the Saints in Nauvoo, Illinois.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p23" pid="50PK-LNZ0kSVzWYIEBhoOA" hash="bV0JfQ">They embraced the gospel with all their hearts. While trying to get established in their new land, they assisted in the building of the Nauvoo Temple by tithing their labor—spending every 10th day working on the construction of the temple.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p24" pid="tqrBzCrkpEKbUfx8CGrLUQ" hash="Fh2zKw">They were brokenhearted at the news of the death of their beloved prophet, Joseph Smith, and his brother <span class="pageBreak" page-number="99"></span>Hyrum. But they carried on! They stayed true to the faith.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p25" pid="knxEt9vWCUeRMNiIh-5LGw" hash="TEe6Ww">When the Saints were persecuted and driven from Nauvoo, Robert and Maria felt greatly blessed to receive their endowments in the temple shortly before they crossed the Mississippi River and headed west. Although they were uncertain of what their future held, they were certain of their faith and their testimonies.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p26" pid="OYUJd2aJXkKQ_jogCJOz7g" hash="Qlp9mw">With six children, they slogged through mud as they crossed Iowa on their way west. They built for themselves a lean-to on the side of the Missouri River at what came to be known as Winter Quarters.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p27" pid="4BpgkNZvUkKkZZFrvtZ8RQ" hash="BUzsKg">These intrepid pioneers were waiting for apostolic direction on how and when they would be heading further west. Everyone’s plans were altered when Brigham Young, the President of the Quorum of the Twelve, issued a call for men to volunteer to serve in the United States Army in what came to be known as the Mormon Battalion.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p28" pid="IsWS9p7Pn0KoWiVmXrEMww" hash="r8XLzw">Robert Harris Jr. was one of over 500 Mormon pioneer men who responded to that call from Brigham Young. He enlisted, even though it meant he would leave behind his pregnant wife and six little children.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p29" pid="MX8GSjG7l0CocFlCn_KQVA" hash="TfNJnw">Why would he and the other men do such a thing?</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p30" pid="YG8xzoTao02Mk-FHaaoUpA" hash="nnnV8g">The answer can be given in my great-great-grandfather’s own words. In a letter that he wrote to his wife when the battalion was on its way to Santa Fe, he wrote, “My faith is so strong as ever [and when I think of the things that Brigham Young told us], I believe it about the same as if the Great God had told me.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p31" pid="wkawR-8s_ky1BCiJJqtSOg" hash="L4WvNw">In short, he knew he was listening to a prophet of God, as did the other men. That is why they did it! They knew they were led by a prophet of God.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p32" pid="QUStAw12skmWPADnHcMr1w" hash="wlwTwQ">In that same letter, he expressed his tender feelings for his wife and children and told of his constant prayers that she and the children would be blessed.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p33" pid="2dxnfhW3NU2-8DaTPc7wVw" hash="yMauyw">Later in the letter, he made this powerful statement: “We must not forget the things which you and I heard and [experienced] in the Temple of the Lord.”</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p34" pid="3ZokWXfC8EilEOQKuM0tdw" hash="EzKl9A">Combined with his earlier testimony that “we are led by a Prophet of God,” these two sacred admonitions have become like scripture to me.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p35" pid="4UMySCra6EW9a5ixWgcg9Q" hash="Bmwotg">Eighteen months after departing with the battalion, Robert Harris was safely reunited with his beloved Maria. They stayed true and faithful to the restored gospel throughout their lives. They had 15 children, 13 of whom lived to maturity. My grandmother Fannye Walker, of Raymond, Alberta, Canada, was one of their 136 grandchildren.</p>
			<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p36" pid="nlXzYUvDxU6SmP5FkY-BWg" hash="Dnp9Hg">Grandma Walker was proud of the fact that <span class="emphasis">her</span> grandfather had served in the Mormon Battalion, and she wanted all of her grandchildren to know it. Now that I am a grandfather, I understand why it was so important to her. She wanted to turn the hearts of the children to the fathers. She wanted her grandchildren to know of their righteous heritage—because she knew it would bless their lives.</p>
		</span>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p37" pid="T6t2gWP6oEiI9F-NPqDcfQ" hash="xoczpA">The more connected we feel to our righteous forefathers, the more likely we are to make wise and righteous choices.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p38" pid="92qPoz-hGUarJoqPerEMpA" hash="OFaS1Q">And so it is. Each of us will be greatly blessed if we know the stories of faith and sacrifice that led our forefathers to join the Lord’s Church.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p39" pid="Af3SfRdw5U2wz88Btiw-ZA" hash="avrBcA">From the first time Robert and Maria heard Wilford Woodruff teach and testify of the Restoration of the gospel, they knew the gospel was true.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p40" pid="3qvhHhqCwE6rD7phe2QgfQ" hash="_FTpIw">They also knew that no matter what trials or hardships would come to them, they would be blessed for staying true to the faith. It almost seems that they had heard the words <span class="pageBreak" page-number="100"></span>of our prophet today, who said, “No sacrifice is too great … in order to receive [the] blessings [of the temple]” (Thomas S. Monson, “The Holy Temple—a Beacon to the World,” <span class="emphasis">Ensign</span> or <span class="emphasis">Liahona,</span> May 2011, 92).</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p41" pid="GOmnLkNr_ECNixef3VhpLw" hash="aIKOow">The two-pound coin of the United Kingdom has inscribed on its side “Standing on the Shoulders of Giants.” When I think of our great pioneer forefathers, I feel that we are <span class="emphasis">all</span> standing on the shoulders of giants.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p42" pid="e6arwFkwyEC4wDGarrBE5A" hash="bbOh2Q">Although the admonition came from a letter from Robert Harris, I believe that countless forefathers would send the same message to their children and grandchildren: First, we must not forget the experiences we have had in the temple, and we must not forget the promises and the blessings that come to each of us because of the temple. Secondly, we must not forget that we are led by a prophet of God.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p43" pid="oZhawknPWEiTnp--dajR-A" hash="UZ9Srg">I testify that we <span class="emphasis">are</span> led by a prophet of God. The Lord restored His Church in the latter days through the Prophet Joseph Smith, and we must not forget that we have been led by an unbroken chain of prophets of God, from Joseph to Brigham and through each succeeding President of the Church to our prophet today—Thomas S. Monson. I know him, I honor him, and I love him. I testify that he is the Lord’s prophet on the earth today.</p>
		<p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith.p44" pid="aRZPorkBCUGxYwXxgjs4Lw" hash="dbGGZQ">It is the desire of my heart that, along with my children and grandchildren, we will honor the legacy of our righteous forefathers—those faithful Mormon pioneers who were willing to put everything on the altar to sacrifice for and defend their God and their faith. I pray that each of us will live true to the faith that our parents have cherished. In the holy and sacred name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
	</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2014/04/live-true-to-the-faith</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2014-general-conference/2014-04-5020-elder-william-r-walker-64k-eng.mp3" length="5370472" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2014 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
