<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By William Grant Bangerter</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by William Grant Bangerter.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/William%20Grant%20Bangerter.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by William Grant Bangerter.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 1975 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>The People Who Influence Us</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1975/04/the-people-who-influence-us?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I feel like the young mother who was being wheeled into the delivery room and said, “I don’t believe I’ll go through with it.”</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-people-who-influence-us" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03057_000_019" doc-version="2" hash="eSQvhg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-people-who-influence-us.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="-QC6WKSX2kCiI9NBvNpIzQ" hash="QUXMkw">The People Who Influence Us</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="n6jZ2luuEkem-ax_ckytUw" hash="SWMJYw">William Grant Bangerter</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-people-who-influence-us.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2e68.jpg" alt="Elder William Grant Bangerter" pid="Z2yGvdUCoECa39WuHIN4vA" hash="UQU9fA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-people-who-influence-us.p1" pid="pOuwV9W6FkW3kxY88Vvy3Q" hash="ft-1Ng">I feel like the young mother who was being wheeled into the delivery room and said, “I don’t believe I’ll go through with it.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-people-who-influence-us.p2" pid="wlHWD_xCEU2HDKLRXOmjKA" hash="-jXuZQ">The brief interview my wife and I had the other day with President Kimball indicated that the service that we have enjoyed in the years past now has the expectation of being expanded so that we may have contact, and hopefully influence, throughout the entire world. It’s amazing to the two of us how suddenly, in the space of a few brief moments, the greater part of our personal plans, ambitions, and world desires has been swept away, never to return in this life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-people-who-influence-us.p3" pid="MaWJQNqs6kuJ5VGyy_UmiA" hash="opTD7A">I wakened one morning many years ago with the realization that it was my 35th birthday, and the thought crossed my mind, “You are now old enough to be President of the United States.” Then the second thought came right behind it, humbling, and said, “Yes, and that is the only qualification you have.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-people-who-influence-us.p4" pid="tml2KOfBi0CkrOS_XDpfLA" hash="ST-4SA">My one qualification today, possessed and treasured by all Latter-day Saints, is a sweet assurance given to me by the Holy Ghost that God really does live—the knowledge that I have talked with him in prayer and that he has answered me many times and given me the influence of his Holy Spirit.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-people-who-influence-us.p5" pid="-ECuLW8A1kS9guh9zGcmkg" hash="n0OKXg">On an occasion, again many years ago, when I was called to be a stake president, Elder Mark E. Petersen of the Council of the Twelve interviewed me searchingly as to my worthiness to serve, and he persisted with one question: “Brother Bangerter, do you believe the gospel?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-people-who-influence-us.p6" pid="y8ed7qxC5ku5a8w-RIz1Gg" hash="hfLltw">I responded that I did insofar as I understood it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-people-who-influence-us.p7" pid="wQqMMJJjakStNtj6hw7u1Q" hash="K9X6bA">He said, “No, I mean do you believe the gospel according to President Joseph Fielding Smith?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-people-who-influence-us.p8" pid="f6GoSdgtF0mSsPfuovTGJw" hash="s_bREA">Most of you know that because of the strictness with which President Smith taught the doctrines of the gospel, this was a question that could separate the sheep from the goats. I am grateful that there has been an influence in my life near to me which has made it easy for me to accept the great truth that the gospel really has been restored in the last days to the earth, and that the president of this Church is in reality a prophet of God with the priesthood and the authority of Jesus Christ to organize his kingdom and direct it here on earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-people-who-influence-us.p9" pid="6qivEzSBLEmthwbBWJQ90g" hash="9QCSCA">Perhaps some of my qualifications are adequate. I am by trade a carpenter. I remember how Brother James E. Faust said a short time ago that he had to repent of being a lawyer to take this position. I don’t feel the need to repent of that, but I have been repenting just the same.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-people-who-influence-us.p10" pid="wg3Limac70yHFlwlYQZ5aQ" hash="mTQS8w">I know that my parents reared me and all of their eleven children to be worthy of this or any other calling of service. I have felt since childhood that my mother, who is a great soul, carried with her the spirit of Hannah, the mother of Samuel of olden time—that whatever else her children might become, she had already dedicated them to the Lord and to his service. We were raised to go on missions, to work hard, to pray often, and to give our lives over to service. More than all other people put together, the influence of my parents has led me to this position. William H. Bangerter and Isabel Bawden are sacred names to me, as are, in connection with them, my brothers and sisters and other relatives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-people-who-influence-us.p11" pid="iCiF8l2DXE-mijXYh4drHA" hash="uiOXig">No one’s life belongs to him alone. My circle of close friends and loved ones encompasses the earth and includes many who are now departed, beginning with my dear wife Mildred, who went years ago into eternal life, who gave us our first four children, one of whom is with her. And my wife and beloved companion Geraldine, a partner and a miracle worker. She was described, in my feelings, by Elder Perry in his wonderful testimony yesterday. She has added seven other children to our family—all vibrant, loving, and devoted to each other and to us—and our lives are very rich. Six of them are waiting for us to return to Europe. Others in our circle include childhood and youthful companions; great missionary companions; and I must refer again to Brother Faust, who labored with me in the mission field; fellow workers in Church service in bishoprics, stake and mission presidencies, high councils—their numbers so vast now I can hardly recall; these beloved associates who are Regional Representatives, many who have been released, and the General Authorities of the Church with whom I have had the privilege to associate from time to time, sometimes on a close personal basis; many others in and out of the Church to whom we owe so much. And I would especially like to mention the tremendous experience that has been from time to time a part of my life over many years to associate and labor among the people in Brazil. Their representatives are here today, and it is difficult to describe how much I have enjoyed and loved my association with them, and now with others across the sea. There are many hundreds of missionaries who have been close to us as if they were our own family, and we appreciate and love each of them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-people-who-influence-us.p12" pid="0kmzVtrWLkiwyoAdtykZEg" hash="4dzZ0Q">Brother Peter Mourik, who gives devoted service to the Church as the real estate agent in Europe, was telling us the other day that while he was sitting on an airplane ready to depart, a woman, who appeared to be wealthy, entered and took the only remaining seat next to him. Since the man in the seat ahead was bathing them in clouds of cigar smoke, Brother Mourik commented to the woman, “I hope to see the day when I can enter an airplane without the necessity of being suffocated by tobacco smoke.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-people-who-influence-us.p13" pid="N5ATi2hsJ0-Har9gXNnP6Q" hash="Vnhd7w">The woman replied, “Amen to that.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-people-who-influence-us.p14" pid="uLu5pq50Skan-Ftk0zMYCQ" hash="lttBTA">Then without further thought or reason—this was several years ago—Brother Mourik said, “Joseph Fielding Smith is a prophet of God.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-people-who-influence-us.p15" pid="_Suu4hH7fUqu0oJtqIe3Rw" hash="G2f7yQ">The woman turned to him and repeated almost to herself, “Joseph Fielding Smith is a prophet of God? Joseph Fielding Smith is a prophet of God? Now I remember,” she said. “I was sitting looking at television and there was some sort of conference or religious assembly taking place, and I saw this old man speaking, and he looked right at me. He told me to repent of my sins and to keep the commandments of God. I think they said his name was Joseph Fielding Smith.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-people-who-influence-us.p16" pid="kOjenp1XcE60fnrImjNSaQ" hash="jNftjw">By such power the Spirit of God moves among men, and so now I must tell you, realizing that what I say may be reaching many tens of thousands of people, that Spencer W. Kimball, now in the place of Joseph Fielding Smith and other prophets who have died, is a prophet of God. I can say this because when he was presented to the Church to become our president a year ago, the Spirit of the Lord said distinctly and almost audibly, “He is speaking as a prophet of God.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-people-who-influence-us.p17" pid="LvVps6KbZUiUCoRnnxASEA" hash="uRRrsw">I know that as I tell you this the Spirit of the Lord also tells you that it is the truth. He is not merely the prophet of God to the members of this Church; he is God’s prophet to the whole earth. And he has for us all the words of eternal life as he tells us again that the gospel has been restored and that we are in the work of building God’s kingdom in the last days so that mankind need not be wasted and destroyed by the calamities and the destructions that have been predicted and will surely come to pass unless we repent and turn unto him.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1975/04/the-people-who-influence-us.p18" pid="cf5ll7hPJUWrL_Z3MzESPA" hash="T7Ee3g">I do testify to the truth of these things in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1975/04/the-people-who-influence-us</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1975-general-conference/1975-04-3030-elder-william-grant-bangerter-64k-eng.mp3" length="4925160" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 1975 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relationships</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1976/04/relationships?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My brethren and sisters, like many of you I was surprised after my marriage to discover the extent of my wife’s relatives. Having come from an extensive family myself, it was nothing new to me to be surrounded by a large family. Nevertheless, as I be</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/relationships" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03070_000_032" doc-version="2" hash="8cWrPg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/relationships.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="qZXb355j80WjbMhqJVgSfw" hash="b6ozUQ">Relationships</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="t3oAFBSaLkuP9dhnkVHL9A" hash="SWMJYw">William Grant Bangerter</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/relationships.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2e68.jpg" alt="Elder William Grant Bangerter" pid="0flw_tAZM0a5PDJW5J0O6Q" hash="UQU9fA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/relationships.p1" pid="0TvaFiw_rUqC5pzBeRwGDg" hash="yArTIw">My brethren and sisters, like many of you I was surprised after my marriage to discover the extent of my wife’s relatives. Having come from an extensive family myself, it was nothing new to me to be surrounded by a large family. Nevertheless, as I became acquainted with the connections into which I had married, I had my eyes opened.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/relationships.p2" pid="wgsRP9Jxn0qvKi_Zg9BgHw" hash="5oLxEQ">I served as a Regional Representative in Wyoming. Her parents grew up there and it seemed that everyone was her relative. The same thing was evident when I was transferred to southern Utah. Her family connections are everywhere. I find them in Texas and in Arizona. We even found them in Egypt and in Saudi Arabia when we visited there two months ago. I have found myself in constant competition to find relatives of my own. I don’t know whether I should say this, but I’ve always laid a certain claim to fame from the fact that Sister LaVern Parmley, who was president of the Primary, was my cousin. But you know, Sister Bangerter arranged to have her released. And then she had Sister Barbara Smith, who is <span class="emphasis">her</span> cousin, sustained as president of the Relief Society.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/relationships.p3" pid="-t_xWG6mGku-KCZTn7OhNQ" hash="weRLmA">Several years ago while I was conversing with a man from southern California who was visiting for the first time in Salt Lake City, he commented that the members of this Church seem to be a unified people. He mentioned that this was foreign to his experience. Even though he was a member of a church in Los Angeles and attended regularly, he rarely did more than greet the man who sat behind him and speak “good morning” to the one in front. He said, “I have no close friends in a congregation of 1,200 people.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/relationships.p4" pid="zXtY9ZR2_0WjD0Cr_Ss3uA" hash="AaOXrA">I responded that while I had been to Los Angeles only two or three times, I was sure that if I were to visit any one of the fifty or hundred congregations of our Church in that city, within twenty minutes I would find someone I knew or someone who was acquainted with friends of mine, or perhaps even a relative. If not that, certainly one of my wife’s relatives.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/relationships.p5" pid="Mkzq9Av5xkakcRysT6Omxw" hash="4n95Gw">I have often been impressed with these extensive relationships which are common to those of us who are members of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/relationships.p6" pid="_zhQIhB8N06Pv8ENAknhsA" hash="6tpb-w">We have other examples of the extensiveness of our families. Last summer we were driving through Switzerland and were passing near the town from which my grandfather came. Immediately in front of us on the highway was a truck, on the tailgate of which was written the name <span class="emphasis">Bangerter</span> and the name of the town. I turned to my wife and said, “At last I have you outnumbered. All these people are my relatives.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/relationships.p7" pid="WqnbbH8RNUiS3r4ZPmdmdQ" hash="CTn3xw">In pursuing our genealogy, our family has extended many lines of our ancestry back in to the 1500s. One day I counted up the surnames on our pedigree. I found that I come from 226 known family lines. If each one of you whose family came from Switzerland or England would check your pedigree to the same extent, I am sure you would have some of the same names I do.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/relationships.p8" pid="LeN5iVv7IECWuWyaAyk6dg" hash="Dr9eOQ">This is an indication that we all have a real kinship based on blood relationship.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/relationships.p9" pid="9FRtYSYHt0uDTd8jJBS6Tw" hash="mDY0Mw">On my pedigree I counted up the names of 650 individuals who have been identified as my direct progenitors. But I have calculated that if I could fill in all the spaces on my pedigree chart only going back to about the year 1500, there would be between 15,000 and 20,000 individuals who are my direct ancestors. And if I were to add to those names the names of their children, I would have a genealogy of between fifty and sixty thousand people, <span class="emphasis">all</span> closely related to me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/relationships.p10" pid="-W4A3qgBw0-9hCryW59eJg" hash="Xs-wWQ">Because of the intensive efforts of my mother and other members of the family, several thousand names have been gathered of my close relatives who are dead. Following the doctrine of the Church, these names have been taken to the temple and ordinances have been performed for them so that when we meet them in the life after death we will recognize them, not only as members of our family, but also as brothers and sisters in the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/relationships.p11" pid="BkHLls0XGUm7khTgfrF50g" hash="JHWjXQ">I have also learned that even in a family where extensive work has been done in genealogy, the majority of this research is still ahead of us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/relationships.p12" pid="dldB1XMzHE6BAWyDzxdaTg" hash="GsTlOQ">There are other relationships in our lives not founded so closely on blood connection.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/relationships.p13" pid="V5xepSc740KiaFPqC5OI4w" hash="qnuvfw">I have listened to the testimonies of many people who have joined the Church. Invariably they speak of how they wandered in different philosophies and religions, but that when they joined the Church they found that they had connected with their true family. In a spiritual sense, they have come home.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/relationships.p14" pid="E6UwoEAHCU68E1wyMQx-Tg" hash="BVVYMg">I have had close association with a man in business who is a beloved friend. We have occasionally discussed religion; and although he has not shown interest in joining the Church, he has investigated many religious philosophies, including the Methodist Church, reincarnation, certain aspects of spiritualism, Pentecostal groups, and Christian fellowship associations. I told him one day that I was sure he would someday join the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/relationships.p15" pid="uKISiynTy0ChXpuOnmW-XQ" hash="UoWz-A">When he inquired with a smile how I knew that, I responded, “Anyone who is looking as earnestly as you are will never be satisfied until he finds the full answer. But when you do join the Church, you will feel like you have come home and you won’t be searching anymore.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/relationships.p16" pid="dl8A3bB3G0q3lK-nreD90Q" hash="-H7mCw">This is the feeling of the members of this Church. Since the days of Jesus Christ, the members of his Church have called each other <span class="emphasis">brother</span> and <span class="emphasis">sister.</span> This was not just happenstance—it was intended.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/relationships.p17" pid="pA0w5FyYskKhkBZlYp87lQ" hash="Qr59bA">The Savior taught us to pray to our Father who is in heaven. He spoke of himself as the Son of his Father and frequently referred to the members of the Church as the children of God. If this doesn’t indicate family relationship, I fail to understand the meaning of those terms.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/relationships.p18" pid="p-1Rqrtr7k2Hby9RcNxsfA" hash="I7h5Yg">When I first went to South America as a young missionary, I noticed that the people looked like foreigners. They spoke a strange language; they had a darker skin; their hair was dark; their eyes were dark; and I felt lost among them. I did not understand until later that I was the foreigner. But now after spending many years with those people, when I now go among them, I can no longer distinguish between them and North Americans or Europeans. I feel so much at home with them that I don’t even notice what color their hair is or the tone of their skin or the color of their eyes. I don’t even notice what language they speak.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/relationships.p19" pid="HDXIOGP_WE-s8KVwNrtN5Q" hash="r10e1w">They’re my brothers and sisters. I extend my full love to them, and they return it to me with ties as close as those that I have experienced in my own family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/relationships.p20" pid="K8dbsg-3TE2yI1klo8o7ng" hash="kypoOA">Now when I read the scriptures I understand better what the Savior meant. He was visiting in a certain home when a messenger came in and informed him that his mother and his brethren were waiting outside. He turned to the man, not to depreciate his family relationship but to teach a special lesson, and said, “Who is my mother? and … my brethren?” And then, turning to the group gathered before him, he said, stretching forth his hand toward his disciples, “Behold my mother and my brethren! For whosoever shall do the will of my Father which is in heaven, the same is my brother, and sister, and mother.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/12.48-50" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 12:48–50</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/relationships.p21" pid="KqZ30FoqGkqDvpSWIdnq6w" hash="KnpEDg">What I experienced in South America was described by Paul in his letter to the saints in Ephesus: “Now therefore ye are no more strangers and foreigners, but fellowcitizens with the saints, and of the household of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/2.19" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 2:19</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/relationships.p22" pid="VYRRx8BZmkScC1Vx6_fLJA" hash="IsNk-A">Does not this word <span class="emphasis">household</span> denote a family relationship?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/relationships.p23" pid="SXg8u8qIY0-8iIhElob0Xg" hash="uwXzAg">From these examples I infer that God the Father, after having scattered his children abroad in the earth for their experience, desires to bring them home again. We, who, as Peter said, “are given … exceeding great and precious promises” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-pet/1.4" class="scriptureRef">2 Pet. 1:4</a>), have ourselves promised to engage in a lifetime of service in behalf of our brothers and sisters who are not so favored.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/relationships.p24" pid="YRSZYDK6dkqoE_-1zZGSBQ" hash="e2Yn7w">Those relatives who have gone on to the spirit world without the blessings of the gospel cannot forever be neglected. A small number of Church members have been diligent. A new era is upon us now. At this very moment, instructions are going out to the high priests of the Church to mobilize their forces so that every member of the Church can be helped to find his family and bring the lost members home again. This year we are all called upon to prepare our own personal history and to organize our living family. Even without a temple or a library close at hand, everyone can do this. Next year we will be given other challenges and assignments until gradually the members of the Church everywhere will become proficient in preparing the records of their families who have died without the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/relationships.p25" pid="DzfQdwBhrkK5k08ky-zUvw" hash="nopvbA">If this work is true, we may shortly expect the day when we do things for the dead as extensively as we now do them for the living. This may conceivably require many members to devote years of their time, expending substantial amounts of money, just as we do now in missionary service.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1976/04/relationships.p26" pid="3Fir3Ik5RUO2EbVJYorLVw" hash="hQ9SCA">Putting the Lord’s family together on eternal terms constitutes the purpose for which the gospel was restored. This will even save nations and the world. We do it by uniting our homes and obtaining our blessings in the temple. We do it by inviting others to accept the restored gospel. We do it by extending our hands across the spiritual spaces to those many relatives who died without the gospel. Those who destroy homes commit a crime against eternity. If we do not put our family together, Moroni says the whole earth will be utterly wasted at Christ’s coming. (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/2.3" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 2:3</a>.) May God bless us to be saviors in the Lord’s family, rather than destroyers, I pray in the name of Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1976/04/relationships</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1976-general-conference/1976-04-5040-elder-william-grant-bangerter-64k-eng.mp3" length="11872651" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 1976 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
