<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Wm. Grant Bangerter</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Wm. Grant Bangerter.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Wm.%20Grant%20Bangerter.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Wm. Grant Bangerter.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 1984 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Coming through the Mists</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists?lang=eng</link>
      <description>President Kimball, I know that I echo the feelings of everyone here in telling you that we love you, as you have so often told us.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03174_000_014" doc-version="2" hash="p8KYFg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="VqYNDE6MuEamB7mxfnXpZw" hash="UmH5Pw">Coming through the Mists</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="a57KMQ2I-0iFRIAOYOflIg" hash="lfjMgA">Wm. Grant Bangerter</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26f0.jpg" alt="Elder Wm. Grant Bangerter" pid="vlPmsmnZPk-IPqgelkcJpA" hash="5EvrWA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p1" pid="fItSTF38nkCJNcqwKwvicg" hash="XkXrgg">President Kimball, I know that I echo the feelings of everyone here in telling you that we love you, as you have so often told us.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p2" pid="rBzxmR5-Zk2XSZyK8C7ObA" hash="BBXpTA">I believe I have a good subject, since so many have already used it today. I would like to say something about coming through the mists.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p3" pid="q3ta5983Hkeey34jnls0pA" hash="OrieNw">As I approach this assignment, I am brought back to some guidelines, an expression made years ago by President J. Reuben Clark, Jr., who said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p4" pid="l8PmiH1C3UG1tg8F3FzzHw" hash="vuF1Mg">“There are, for the Church and for each and all of its members, two prime things which may not be overlooked, forgotten, shaded, or discarded:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p5" pid="Wkl2OvrvYUqCdhoz94DAdw" hash="-99xyQ">“First: That Jesus Christ is the Son of God. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p6" pid="FohSMwAs0Ei7qgijsgOI0w" hash="Gt2lBQ">“Second … : That the Father and the Son actually … appeared to the Prophet Joseph in a vision … ; that the Gospel and the holy Priesthood … were … restored to the earth from which they were lost by the apostasy of the Primitive Church.” (“<span class="emphasis">The Charted Course of the Church in Education,</span>” an address delivered in Aspen Grove, Utah, 8 Aug. 1938, p. 3.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p7" pid="CUsCWuc5PU6LAmYK7zKWSA" hash="kgALUw">I testify that these stipulations are true because this knowledge has been revealed to me by the unquestionable Spirit of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p8" pid="_BK1B54B9EeJKpjf84mzmg" hash="I187Rw">In a time described in the scriptures as being filled with wickedness and vengeance (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/moses/7.60" class="scriptureRef">Moses 7:60</a>), the First Presidency has sent out the special message to the Church in our stake conferences: “Staying on the strait and narrow path by keeping our covenants.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p9" pid="y6rKlPKhlUqRyylCmvj9RQ" hash="KKx-ng">For us who claim leadership through prophets called of God, it is a good time to pay attention. For those who ignore the commandments, you may not receive many other warnings, “for wide is the gate, and broad is the way, that leadeth to destruction, and many there be which go in thereat.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/7.13" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 7:13</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p10" pid="Wdi83e6i6keVvKzKBmd9WQ" hash="oXv2DA">The warning is against unrighteousness. That means sin and wickedness. This is defined by Peter as if he were speaking of this present time. He speaks of “denying the Lord,” of covetousness to “make merchandise of you,” of the example of the iniquity of Sodom and Gomorrah, and of “the filthy conversation of the wicked, … having eyes full of adultery, and that cannot cease from sin.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-pet/2.1,3,6,7,14" class="scriptureRef">2 Pet. 2:1, 3, 6, 7, 14</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p11" pid="C7DSDBAVb0GRNFI6YvUwOQ" hash="lTucxQ">A moment’s reflection on the displays in the media and in advertising, the inducement to use drugs, alcohol, and so forth, makes it very plain that for the sake of making money there is an attempt to buy or sell our souls, making “merchandise of you.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p12" pid="2Fi6VRvdKEKz_L4M1idXWg" hash="zlMFBg">Newspaper articles and public expressions often carry the “filthy conversation of the wicked.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/2-pet/2.7" class="scriptureRef">2 Pet. 2:7</a>.) We call it what it is: “A wicked and adulterous generation.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p13" pid="_0MODA1zK0KbPQSm3n9ujA" hash="O4BCHQ">We are indeed constantly bombarded by a display of wickedness as it flashes before us, sometimes in ways that we cannot avoid.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p14" pid="i73SuW-DgUOfXvyFZX0qig" hash="v87PDw">Our society maintains the fiction that the display of such things as adultery, pornography, nudity, and licentiousness should be kept from the young people. Of course it should, but to set an age limit is pure hypocrisy. Perhaps greater corruption is being administered to the older and married generation. They are those who commit the adulteries. They are those who destroy the homes and violate the sanctity of families. The married ones obtain the divorces, break the covenants, cheat their spouses, and become dishonest in their commitments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p15" pid="EDyFveWrfEacz9Vctt86_w" hash="DTV-yA">And, of course, in doing these wicked things they suggest that it is not so bad anymore. Since so much of the world accepts these actions, if we resist them or speak out against them, we will be scoffed at. We will be called prudish, Victorian, puritan, and self-righteous, as if <span class="emphasis">we</span> had become the sinners. We will be accused of being evil-minded in our failure to appreciate the “beauty and naturalness” of the human body.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p16" pid="dDnn7vL_HEmFYJpka9TLVQ" hash="VnPhuw">A vivid example of the position of members of the Church in relation to the world was portrayed to us one evening in our sacrament meeting, now many years ago, when a man named Brother Smith came to speak. He told us of his experience in working to rehabilitate men in the state penitentiary. A mother had asked him to reach out to her boy who was in prison.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p17" pid="uTNvAXeYvUqpRxzl892brw" hash="nsLA5g">In approaching the young man, Brother Smith was rudely rebuffed: “Leave me alone,” was the tone. However, Brother Smith noticed a rather crude painting in the prison one day and on inquiry learned that this young man had drawn it. This inspired a new approach:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p18" pid="dNQQz5DLkU6xP5MlSynPWA" hash="S--fAQ">“Did you paint that picture?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p19" pid="zU4zJWRnXkmxotMv62V34A" hash="MR_7fA">“Yes, I did it.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p20" pid="RvXjEs8IqE63ZIXmPT6fMg" hash="RUkEsQ">“I was impressed with it. I wonder if you would paint something for me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p21" pid="tEfT_qq-j0O5An16gwm7Gg" hash="FIFVoA">“I don’t know. What picture do you want?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p22" pid="plCuQpKx9E-_0tvSxTUeow" hash="U_fF4w">“I have never seen it,” said Brother Smith. “I have only read about it.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p23" pid="BKBFJIXY_EW3PbsuHeyDxw" hash="S27e6w">“Where is it?” inquired the young man.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p24" pid="QWdz2ixiukmxIV0AF76vbQ" hash="q9unhg">“It is here in this book,” responded Brother Smith. “The Book of Mormon, 1 Nephi, chapter 8. Will you read it and see if you can see the picture?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p25" pid="X-fTDnZELk6UYFLUSIX4ng" hash="KNPnGQ">Later Brother Smith inquired if the young man had read it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p26" pid="JFgFG_4170Ggjzgukt61sA" hash="cNEvsA">“Yes, I read it,” he said.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p27" pid="x3pGk-5oVk-b5Y3gda3-ag" hash="0czddA">“Did you see the picture?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p28" pid="HZQ0GOt7iki1ll7HpP3Rgg" hash="zbHNPg">“Yes, I saw it.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p29" pid="GVEI97s4g0K3GhmtD1P7Mg" hash="5udZzA">“Will you paint it for me?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p30" pid="f9B6quzBS0qIwaozqn4N2Q" hash="9j0Bag">“I don’t know if I will or not.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p31" pid="CXy5PuJZ_EWB8Osxpriecg" hash="T-o3tQ">Brother Smith then obtained the necessary materials for painting a picture and presented them to the young man, who for the first time responded with warmth and appreciation to be able to use good equipment, and he painted the picture. Brother Smith brought it with him to our sacrament meeting, and so I have seen it. It is, of course, the picture of Lehi’s dream.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p32" pid="KF94R6Wz-EaM2Npq1nkVGg" hash="Oj0sBg">Now, will you try to see the picture in your own imagination? All you who have read 1 Nephi, chapter 8, will recall the scene. If you have not read it, I wish you would do so and get the feeling and the vision of this picture.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p33" pid="a-C_tZzg9kmU44TYkVSy-Q" hash="nnvC2A">The description is as follows: First, Lehi wandering through a dreary waste, then coming to a spacious field; the tree with the most desirable fruit to be happy, the love of God; Lehi’s desire to share the fruit with his family; the rebellion of two of his sons; the pressing forward of many people to receive the fruit; the mists of darkness, which arose to obscure the path; the river of water along the path, which could mean destruction; the rod of iron, which represented security in staying on the path; the huge building across the river filled with scoffing people; the susceptibility of those who had followed the path to succumb to the scorn and pride of those of the world; and the wandering away of those who had partaken of the fruit of the tree of life into forbidden paths of destruction.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p34" pid="02KR4gLYvUaAD2_y2mJx0w" hash="eq7tEA">I know of no more graphic description of the condition of those who call themselves Latter-day Saints in relation to the influences of the world than this great vision. This story is reality. It is a great prophesy. It is a vivid warning.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p35" pid="EZm7EIvXp06idOu5LSzZgQ" hash="Rj9Klw">Let me complete the story of the young man in prison. Brother Smith pointed to an angel the young man had painted hovering over the chasm of filthy water and asked him: “Where did you get that angel? I don’t remember any angel when I read about the picture.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p36" pid="hIFGmUGgC0aZZrHYG2q_iQ" hash="QwwGmQ">The young man replied: “I know. I put it there. It is my angel. As I painted the picture, I began to realize that God had placed an influence in my way which could bring me to safety and redeem me from the course I have been pursuing.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p37" pid="p0SCKqsu8kaW0lQfLBHIew" hash="bLuJ_A">This experience, of course, was the beginning of his recovery.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p38" pid="nb63UM9eIEiqW7Fh_UqKug" hash="ztBsiw">Yes, the voices and enticements of the world make good seem evil and evil, good. The false attractions to engage in immorality, to view that which is forbidden on your home video, to seek unbounded pleasure as if God did not exist, are, in reality, the yawning pit of hell, set there by the one who will try to bind you with his awful chains.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p39" pid="veEy4PVb5kGsKDt6ozzmzQ" hash="SwoeyQ">I learned once upon a time to fly airplanes. The instructor was flying straight and level. On the horizon was a range of mountains. Then he did something like this [demonstration of snap roll and spin] and I saw the mountain rise up and stand on end. It turned upside down and then continued to its normal position. He put the plane into a spin, and as we were falling and gyrating, I looked below and saw the whole earth turning as if it were a huge wheel. The vision was vivid. It looked so real. I have performed these maneuvers many times since: the snap roll and the spin. If I were to do them today, I could no longer make the mountain turn over or the earth gyrate. Why? Because experience has taught me reality, and now I cannot be deceived.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p40" pid="6AQxKujmTUOHP9Pzc_L8AQ" hash="Ysytgw">Reality for members of the Church is: “Jesus Christ is the Son of God. The Father and the Son actually appeared to the Prophet Joseph. The gospel has been restored to the earth.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p41" pid="D9ryK3shm0exr_1P7QjKyw" hash="4fjiPg">We have no excuse to deviate from the paths of righteousness. If we hold fast to the iron rod, we cannot be deceived.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p42" pid="Ns3e8VqsTUOjYZfOjQyy9Q" hash="E44PMw">In one of the hymns, we sing of Nephi, a seer of olden time. Nephi, of course, also saw the vision of his father Lehi.</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="d9tLYL5e1k-hMEOSG2eOlg" hash="6O0X-Q">
            <span class="emphasis">To Nephi, seer of olden time,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="NwXKwQw7vU-1HqflksbBQA" hash="5hBNdw">
            <span class="emphasis">A vision came from God.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="SiD4z9fNmU2RJqGMp6y33w" hash="3c8P8g">
            <span class="emphasis">Wherein the holy word sublime,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="v4iLNWCVOkWBp-RvY5NpOw" hash="0SU6mA">
            <span class="emphasis">Was shown an iron rod.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="-Gx4Op6f_keOaA5gTWhhoQ" hash="ZBOOnA">
            <span class="emphasis">While on our journey here below,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="Eim0Jl9ySUC2BA-hUbRDew" hash="yASaog">
            <span class="emphasis">Beneath temptation’s power,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="LaWramFwek-T69J8VP-zig" hash="apbiUw">
            <span class="emphasis">Through mists of darkness we must go,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="HMXeVvO0BEeUQ1MQNxG78w" hash="c9OSXQ">
            <span class="emphasis">In peril every hour.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="ZZNI2QE-xEiZcz-q3Gve-Q" hash="_2JX-Q">
            <span class="emphasis">And when temptation’s power is nigh,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="Lj7d_tFdF0y0Zb7vmXiK0Q" hash="yXJ5ZQ">
            <span class="emphasis">Our pathway clouded o’er,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="96VJQj-dHUu1FWZJVejLkQ" hash="eE4oWw">
            <span class="emphasis">Upon the rod we can rely,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="jEMElK56BU2cL8YupFSrzg" hash="8Yw-Fg">
            <span class="emphasis">And heaven’s aid implore.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="nj7xRU-QFEOVl6Kk0Ezh8w" hash="5P1UkA">
            <span class="emphasis">Hold to the rod, the iron rod;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="rvnwBggDFk2rMQqft_ZzeA" hash="c8UlWA">
            <span class="emphasis">’Tis strong, and bright, and true;</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="QEPRkzTPdUG6082R6ribdw" hash="3tBlsQ">
            <span class="emphasis">The iron rod is the word of God,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="2scv2D93kk-YoyFpqGMMrA" hash="qGhx0w">
            <span class="emphasis">’Twill safely guide us through.</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists.p43" pid="XUDuIVXN1EWNqImcxPEukg" hash="K0efJw">In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1984/04/coming-through-the-mists</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1984-general-conference/1984-04-2060-elder-wm-grant-bangerter-64k-eng.mp3" length="5888478" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 1984 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Spirit of the Gathering</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering?lang=eng</link>
      <description>The glory of Easter morning fills the souls of those who yearn for eternal life. A similar glory touched the majestic morning when the Father and the Son announced the dawning of the day of salvation in the last days.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03187_000_026" doc-version="2" hash="fO7IOQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="xECR2-UnWUe51w3EeTzL7g" hash="9jetaA">The Spirit of Gathering</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="yzYedSuJI0Co98kv4KEBbw" hash="lfjMgA">Wm. Grant Bangerter</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26f0.jpg" alt="Elder Wm. Grant Bangerter" pid="C-WINhNtDESHP3aiPeuZTQ" hash="5EvrWA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p1" pid="QNUF6YCpm0aQKsFjjr1gGg" hash="b_2ydw">The glory of Easter morning fills the souls of those who yearn for eternal life. A similar glory touched the majestic morning when the Father and the Son announced the dawning of the day of salvation in the last days.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p2" pid="MJalK60SekyZN9LWXQ5YXg" hash="q0G00Q">To contemplate what happened on those mornings of grandeur stirs the innermost feelings of the members of the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p3" pid="g1GS8T9cnUuFTl7j-VmMQQ" hash="kTB4tg">A mystic, spiritual force, similar to the magnetism of the lodestone, has drawn the Saints to seek the place where their longings can be satisfied. This is the spirit of the Gathering, foretold in the scriptures. It is the reason why each one of us is here today, as we have been drawn both literally and spiritually to Zion—an actual, tangible place where the soul’s yearning can be fulfilled in anticipation of salvation and eternal life in the kingdom of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p4" pid="d1Y0_epmtkKoHG9ZbXBtOQ" hash="d1QPkA">As I respond to the new appointment which has been given to me, I have deep feelings about the man whose passing away left the vacancy into which I have been called, Elder G. Homer Durham. Elder Durham married Eudora, the daughter of Elder John A. Widtsoe. Aside from their Church service, these two men, Dr. Durham and Dr. Widtsoe, have been outstanding in positions of leadership and responsibility, particularly in the field of education. Dr. Durham was the first commissioner of Higher Education in the state of Utah, and earlier presided over Arizona State University. He is greatly missed. Dr. John A. Widtsoe was the president of two universities before he was called to serve as a member of the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p5" pid="OdcVOxY3Wk-Wlq3pPL6Tbw" hash="DbGVsQ">Many years ago Elder Widtsoe told the story of his mother, Anna Karine Gaarden Widtsoe, who, one hundred years ago was caught up in the “gospel net.” Elder Widtsoe’s prologue is as follows:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p6" pid="MIh8Q_Oyi0-1cOu1XJLVpA" hash="K0pqkQ">“This is the story of a woman, a seeker after truth, who, tossed by the waves of mysterious fate, was caught by the Gospel net, and carried into a far country, where, through the possession of eternal truth, though amidst much adversity, she and her family found unbounded happiness.” (<span class="emphasis">In the Gospel Net,</span> Independence, Mo: Zion’s Printing and Publishing Co., 1941, Prologue.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p7" pid="ZR8vxMjlzkC8NgSXW_qh6Q" hash="kvIvcQ">The beautiful story concerning his mother, who came from an obscure island off Norway, has been repeated thousands of times in the lives of the Latter-day Saints. These experiences are the foundation of the faith of every member of the Church. As I make reference to some of the influences that have drawn us into the gospel net, I hope that every Latter-day Saint will reflect on the spiritual power which has brought us to the gospel.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p8" pid="4VCUL_Ga8kOLGJVVjEbWbQ" hash="V4urHA">Elder Widtsoe’s mother responded to the words of a humble shoemaker who had placed some tracts in her child’s shoes. Speaking to her with some hesitation as she was leaving his shop, he said, “You may be surprised to hear me say that I can give you something of more value than soles for your child’s shoes.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p9" pid="NRAm_weIVkaHXqjvzK1ScQ" hash="rzQjIQ">She responded, “What can you, a shoemaker, give me better than soles for my son’s shoes?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p10" pid="dIsK2AEaOUC8WXNZgs5sRg" hash="bAfxUA">He answered, “If you will but listen, I can teach you the Lord’s true plan of salvation for His children. I can teach you how to find happiness in this life and to prepare for eternal joy in the life to come. I can tell you whence you came, why you are upon the earth, and where you will go after death. I can teach you as you have never known it before, the love of God for his children on earth.” (See <span class="emphasis">In the Gospel Net,</span> pp. 54–55.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p11" pid="3XfHjtTk50Ktq8-zi3Gtng" hash="2FdbAw">The deep and powerful influence which has reached out across time and space, often into far and hidden corners of the earth, has the effect to snatch people from their normal life patterns and bring them to Zion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p12" pid="mzUQ_uC_Eky2961w8a2Z5A" hash="ctPRTw">Since the Church was organized in 1830, the gospel net has encircled and drawn together many millions of people who, either through their own personal experience, or through receiving the teachings of their parents and grandparents, have found the way to eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p13" pid="agpMbXcnMk2ruNHVQYarwg" hash="DMyWyg">This means that for those who receive the message, the confusion of ages about how to come to Christ has ended. The answers are at hand to the great questions, such as:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p14" pid="i7b4QY2rQEKZRMvqOxL3YA" hash="OhLAKw">What is the meaning of human life on earth?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p15" pid="rAHI3yXGeESzFL8VEhwKTg" hash="oLJGFw">Is there revelation from heaven?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p16" pid="-I1ECo9ic0-RFujwJSoUZg" hash="4GKQ2A">Where are the Apostles and prophets?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p17" pid="ktuxeQBdMkql_MX94S14BA" hash="F7Shtw">What about those who never heard of Christ?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p18" pid="wxBksH4mfk6digDI3-uTUg" hash="y85t1A">Which of the many churches is authorized by God?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p19" pid="rPh6uy3t7EuuUTwJzXGdKw" hash="7gTKVA">Who has authority to administer the gospel?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p20" pid="JfQwIsbuKUeWhcO-o1cZuw" hash="kQruZw">How can I know what God wants me to do?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p21" pid="GIcmP6EuXUKxeoh2KfSbZQ" hash="tOMM3g">There is only one way these questions could ever be answered. God would have to tell us. To do so he has called a latter-day prophet. He has sent heavenly messengers to confer the true priesthood and authority. He has revealed the Book of Mormon to support the witness of the Bible that Jesus is Christ. He has reestablished the ordinances and restored the everlasting covenant. The sure way to eternal life is again in place.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p22" pid="SgARwYEz4kKxBEKERtJvhQ" hash="mC61CQ">My own membership in the Church is in response to this powerful influence. My own grandparents in Switzerland were also led by the Spirit in the midst of ridicule and persecution to find the path by which they could rear their children with the sure knowledge of divine truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p23" pid="DBR4f7MGqk2pW_zcT7Dmsg" hash="K_gemQ">My mother’s grandparents were among the first in England to respond to the teachings of Heber C. Kimball and Willard Richards in 1837.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p24" pid="483BjLiQyUW8etOlV68_kA" hash="hHpFfw">They vibrated to the thrilling news that the kingdom of God had been brought back to the earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p25" pid="bhnpAdq7P0Si7joBTAXzsw" hash="pnS8sw">The human soul, to be spiritually alive, requires a vision, a yearning, a longing, a desire. The spirit of America reaches out to that longing: the great vision of liberty, the spirit of freedom, the land of opportunity and hope.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p26" pid="9wE7Vke4S0WNrnNBmeWVSg" hash="0bNhJQ">Sister Bangerter and I recently stood at the feet of the Statue of Liberty in New York harbor with President and Sister McGregor of Caldwell, New Jersey. They pointed out Ellis Island as the entry point into this land for hundreds of thousands of immigrants, including my grandparents and also Elder Widtsoe and his mother. We read again the inspiring words of Emma Lazarus announcing the beacon to wandering souls. Referring to the ancient statue on the Greek island of Rhodes, she speaks of “The New Colossus”:</p>
      <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.f2">
        <div class="stanza">
          <p class="line" pid="EDWpXSjCFUqIDRm5OTvV7Q" hash="65F9xA">
            <span class="emphasis">Not like the brazen giant of Greek fame,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="Q8IdRssuU0W0fr1UAfi2qg" hash="e-4enA">
            <span class="emphasis">With conquering limbs astride from land to land:</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="aJEkdVQS9kKhbnoBI_lQIA" hash="VkTeCQ">
            <span class="emphasis">Here at our sea-washed, sunset gates shall stand</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="BXTZ124msEmWW7Xz8XveTg" hash="2OUwTQ">
            <span class="emphasis">A mighty woman with a torch, whose flame</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="rl44-Z7MOUKljmAJMM-nGw" hash="AX5zpw">
            <span class="emphasis">Is the imprisoned lightning, and her name</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="XhYj0itEskqW5j2jGz8UFw" hash="OTnekw">
            <span class="emphasis">Mother of Exiles. From her beacon-hand</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="7lPAQJcq-EaMdZxxIA3NlA" hash="Tiueog">
            <span class="emphasis">Glows world-wide welcome: her mild eyes command</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="HuIeZOs4E0-3t2YaBPHUag" hash="6xUs6A">
            <span class="emphasis">The air-bridged harbor that twin cities frame.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="2FvO7RN1YkmJlTZs9c6DkQ" hash="8gVETw">
            <span class="emphasis">“Keep, ancient lands, your stored pomp!” cries she</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="c7QleDdg3ECXjYJ9P8px0Q" hash="3Hlrpw">
            <span class="emphasis">With silent lips. Give me your tired, your poor,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="uq353yv0eEWItlUGpKpBow" hash="5x9s_w">
            <span class="emphasis">Your huddled masses yearning to breathe free,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="oCG1kpc-yEGMLP0NaoTWqg" hash="PC5lsw">
            <span class="emphasis">The wretched refuse of your teeming shore.</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="v4-4KvcZbUms6Sahzh-edw" hash="fYTMlw">
            <span class="emphasis">Send these, the homeless, tempest-tost, to me,</span>
          </p>
          <p class="line" pid="9NPcQA8XQEyg6kTkyQPXqw" hash="yaJZCQ">
            <span class="emphasis">I lift my lamp beside the golden door!</span>
          </p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p27" pid="gu89F8sndEmNr7EbsBKmqA" hash="1kICkA">Then President McGregor coupled this feeling to the words of Lehi:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p28" pid="ORn5TYXCnEqQfdZxpaFxfg" hash="TOY68g">“Wherefore, this land is consecrated unto him whom he shall bring. And if it so be that they shall serve him according to the commandments which he hath given, it shall be a land of liberty unto them; wherefore, they shall never be brought down into captivity; … but unto the righteous it shall be blessed forever.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/1.7" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 1:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p29" pid="8d4T4QcssEKhU-NzEyCHIg" hash="GzCsIg">The yearning of ancient Israel was to Jerusalem. During their captivity, the soul of the people was expressed in the 137th Psalm:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p30" pid="15rf9Gf9FkW694P8xdaljw" hash="oJnaOQ">“By the rivers of Babylon, there we sat down, yea, we wept, when we remembered Zion. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p31" pid="4l-x2l1F8EmuF_EnkvbCNA" hash="KbNrDg">“For they that carried us away captive required of us a song: and they that wasted us required of us mirth, saying, Sing us one of the songs of Zion.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p32" pid="8nHePeIqhECs6s2NRavWUg" hash="0A6pxQ">“How shall we sing the Lord’s song in a strange land?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p33" pid="-rSHjJ0W7E6FKN9Sa6k2Bg" hash="gJclOg">“If I forget thee, O Jerusalem, let my right hand forget her cunning.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p34" pid="J-rd5jV9Y0qdbq4Caw_TVw" hash="LTfZkA">“If I do not remember thee, let my tongue cleave to the roof of my mouth; if I prefer not Jerusalem above my chief joy.” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/ps/137.1,3-6" class="scriptureRef">Ps. 137:1, 3–6</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p35" pid="BsJrS9h-mkCG3CDlgZcbPQ" hash="B4OqCg">All of us should reflect on what we have joined and what power has captured our faith. Hundreds of thousands living today have in their own lifetime personally found the pearl of great price. They are the grandparents of the future whose names will be blessed by their posterity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p36" pid="gkzNVRbQJUOQ14gp0emhtA" hash="P273ug">For forty-five years I have had close association with the land of Brazil. Many tens of thousands have joined the Church in that country. I had great joy yesterday in hearing of the call of Elder Helio da Rocha Camargo, our companion and fellow member of the Church. Brother Camargo and his wife were stalwart, faithful people before they joined the Church. They had been brought up in the nurture and admonition of the Lord. Brother Camargo was a graduate of the military academy of Brazil. Later, still a young man, he became a Methodist minister. He told me something of his experience with the “gospel net.” One evening two young men called at his home. He said that the first thing he noticed was the huge feet of one of the young men. He looked upward from the feet until he found the face of the tallest North American he had ever met. He was not at first impressed with the beauty of either the feet or the face. However, he invited the young men in, and in the process of their presentation they left him a copy of the Book of Mormon.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p37" pid="MxSwx8sg7UK7t_7QQx6JnA" hash="qwe15Q">On a subsequent visit they inquired if he had read the book. He explained that he had read considerable, making notes of the things with which he did not agree. The elder then suggested that it was not in keeping with a book of scripture to read it to see what was wrong with it, but that it should be read as Moroni says, “with a sincere heart” and “real intent,” having “faith in Christ” and desiring to know the truth of the book. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/10.4" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 10:4</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p38" pid="q2Mtpl8sqEi_QUgOn-XPWw" hash="ayz5kQ">Brother Camargo said he found it necessary to read the book again. In the process the Spirit witnessed to him that it was the true word of God, and he joined the Church with his family. He sometimes refers to the scripture in <a href="/scriptures/ot/isa/52.7" class="scriptureRef">Isa. 52:7</a> which says, “How beautiful upon the mountains are the feet [those huge missionary feet] of him that bringeth good tidings, that publisheth peace; … that saith unto Zion, Thy God reigneth!” The truth he has found has brought similar beauty to the feet of three of his sons as they have served as missionaries. All of his children were married in the temple covenant, and he and his wife have great joy and rejoicing in their posterity. One of his sons is present at this conference today as a stake president.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p39" pid="cC3m3dhcAE2IwaDqECy2yA" hash="lM3sSw">President J. Reuben Clark, Jr., captured the spirit of this drawing power in his memorable address in 1947 “to them of the last wagon”—our pioneers who endured the hardships of their great journey:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p40" pid="YO2niiwp5kKutiDw6bKMBA" hash="4XnMzQ">“They had,” he said, “their testimony burning always like an eternal fire on a holy altar, that the restored gospel was true. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p41" pid="B8q-LFahgUK6Zs6vgMhjGw" hash="7eOiMA">“When in the evening the last wagon creaked slowly into its place in the circle corral, and the Brethren came to inquire how the day had gone with the mother, then joy leaped in their hearts, for had not the Brethren remembered them? New hope was born, weariness fled, fresh will to do was enkindled; gratitude to God was poured out for their knowledge of the truth, for their testimony that God lived, that Jesus was the Christ, that Joseph was a prophet, … and that for the righteous a crown of glory awaited that should be theirs during the eternities of the life to come.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p42" pid="q01J_sNcJEuacYc3T-CPZg" hash="OFXZKQ">He states that at the conclusion of their journey, “[they] all sank to their knees in the joy of their souls, thanking God that at last they were in Zion. ‘Zion, Zion, lovely Zion, beautiful Zion, Zion, City of our God.’” (in Conference Report, Oct. 1947, pp. 157–58.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p43" pid="vWmodYUD3kyR2Aky3RAitA" hash="o4ULmg">What a thrill of joy must have moved Andrew as he said to Peter, “We have found the Messias.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/1.41" class="scriptureRef">John 1:41</a>.) Along with countless thousands, it has “come to pass that the righteous shall be gathered out from among all nations, and shall come to Zion, singing with songs of everlasting joy.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/45.71" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 45:71</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering.p44" pid="6_9lDh6H6ECsRgYKyfEvEg" hash="FO5VkQ">May we lift our souls this beautiful Easter morning with the assurance that through the mystic call of the restored gospel we have come to the threshold of Zion and the gateway to eternal life. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1985/04/the-spirit-of-the-gathering</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1985-general-conference/1985-04-4030-elder-wm-grant-bangerter-64k-eng.mp3" length="14942127" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 1985 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What It Means to Be a Saint</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I would like to speak about what it means to be a saint. Some people call us Mormons. Some call us a sect or a cult. We call ourselves Saints. What do these designations signify?</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03213_000_005" doc-version="2" hash="p6x43Q">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="nCn52hqOl0CUbD2M96Sllg" hash="Uc70eQ">What It Means to Be a Saint</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="aGKF0PzbXUu3udP_bEBQeQ" hash="lfjMgA">Wm. Grant Bangerter</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26f0.jpg" alt="Elder Wm. Grant Bangerter" pid="i0SI4lG7YkGLxb2CSCZ5iQ" hash="5EvrWA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p1" pid="kKFDLY0690OrTrj5WPfTIA" hash="Iv65cg">I would like to speak about what it means to be a saint. Some people call us Mormons. Some call us a sect or a cult. We call ourselves Saints. What do these designations signify?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p2" pid="uJethLgNlEyc7k_iukVUdw" hash="zAQy8w">A Mormon could be any kind of a person who has membership in the Church.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p3" pid="kWK0KuLx00O1Wm2_8Gt3Jw" hash="_DQqLw">A sect is a body of persons following certain principles or doctrines. The earliest followers of the Savior were called a sect.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p4" pid="QHb2hZnZQku7_2Ak-h7HJA" hash="zC7TnA">A cult is described as a particular system of religious worship having a fixed veneration for a person.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p5" pid="FL6I4bRIb0SAsNiAXJ8C0g" hash="EM6vYw">A saint is one who follows Christ in holiness and devotion with a view fixed on <span class="emphasis">eternal</span> life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p6" pid="KpuUX9kZpEmVkuwIGeqlnA" hash="in5-Cw">With proper understanding, there is nothing wrong with any of these designations. When they are used to imply ridicule and slander, they can all be offensive.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p7" pid="LCsqwAfank2E6QxWb4Q_qg" hash="OGzqLg">Many members of the Church become upset when those terms are used by name-callers. Calling people names to ridicule them or to offend them is an old, childish practice. Children respond by chanting with some truth: “Sticks and stones may break my bones, but names will never hurt me.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p8" pid="CUte2XjYyU2fOYrtKgRInQ" hash="FFiqHw">It isn’t very important what impolite people call this Church and its people. Name-calling has been an age-old pastime among people who profess to be religious. The words <span class="emphasis">heretic, blasphemer, bigot, Jew, hypocrite,</span> and <span class="emphasis">heathen</span> have all had their day.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p9" pid="15d587SIAEqEbrdw8A9Sjw" hash="n34uLQ">What really matters is what we ourselves believe, what we do, and most important, what we are. “Are you a born-again Christian?” Well, in the sense that some others think of it, perhaps not—that is, if the phrase means something like to have “confessed Christ” as the only requirement for salvation. On the other hand, if this question is considered in a literal and doctrinal sense, we might reflect on a positive answer.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p10" pid="r_0LdNjOc0-OHAyodlWgrg" hash="itc5nw">Brother Carmen Bria, a neighbor of ours converted from another church, was assisting prisoners as a social worker. A certain young prisoner became interested in the gospel. His father, a minister from another church, visited the boy and was very upset that his son was studying Mormon doctrine, even more than he was by the fact that his son was in prison.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p11" pid="AnUa3lGgrECyHjPav35ZKQ" hash="jznOTA">Brother Bria approached the father and asked why he was so distressed. The father replied, “You are not saved.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p12" pid="J6aOnqpd1E2MX91xve-tyw" hash="xrgmxA">“Why do you say that?” asked Brother Bria.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p13" pid="nuoosm2ypkqH9MVKrIyaEQ" hash="NSXNfg">“Well,” said the father, “you have not taken Christ as your personal Savior. You have not been born again in Christ.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p14" pid="Qf-XbAehiUOPDB-7qYd_aA" hash="I64G-A">Brother Bria responded, “Sir, let me explain it to you. We may not say it just the way you do, but we most certainly do believe in a literal salvation through Jesus Christ. We <span class="emphasis">have</span> accepted him as our personal Savior, have taken upon us his name, and we have been born again in Christ.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p15" pid="jJtT4uZxNUGH7hv92DfAzg" hash="bDpsVA">As Paul said: “Therefore we are buried with him by <span class="emphasis">baptism</span> into death: that like as Christ was raised up from the dead by the glory of the Father, even so we also should walk in newness of life” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/rom/6.4" class="scriptureRef">Rom. 6:4</a>; italics added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p16" pid="rsmWzXteD02znepVH2oeJA" hash="pu1WHg">Members of the Church should know that they are born again—“redeemed of God,” as the Prophet Alma said, “[to] be numbered with those of the first resurrection, that ye may have eternal life” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/18.9" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 18:9</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p17" pid="ADOTT9DQcEOgQ__kWNzK3A" hash="G1Z8Rg">King Benjamin said: “And now, because of the covenant which ye have made ye shall be called the children of Christ, his sons, and his daughters; for behold, this day he hath spiritually begotten you; for ye say that your hearts are changed through faith on his name; therefore, ye are born of him and have become his sons and his daughters” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/5.7" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 5:7</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p18" pid="Awt6TzWbYECyGfoAk7OXHg" hash="gVUSwg">If, then, we understand that we are born again, having taken upon us the name of Christ, the big question is: Do we act like it?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p19" pid="1-kpQHgXaEuv4uKqBiCqcQ" hash="BjfR4w">A saint is one who follows Christ in holiness and devotion. This is the commitment of a Latter-day Saint.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p20" pid="oxnSqXk9GEC0FE6trwY4Sw" hash="NBP4wA">Another question: Are we perfect? As a response to that question, I repeat a story about the speaker who said to his congregation, “If there is anyone here who is perfect, will he please stand.” One man stood, and the speaker inquired, “Sir, do you really believe that you are perfect?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p21" pid="0pGnC9kOyUuk7pUiYP8r2Q" hash="7d87Yg">The man responded, “Oh, no. I am not standing for myself. I stand as proxy for my wife’s first husband.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p22" pid="sib16qZfIkuV0GqQgMJc7A" hash="xuJN0A">Few members of the Church would claim to be perfect, although it should always be our goal. What we do is to strive with faith and devotion onward toward perfection in order to obtain eternal life.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p23" pid="gRqMWMxK7EupQ_ABsH4PFA" hash="AS23dQ">There are many ways to be imperfect. After a long sermon of admonition, King Benjamin said: “I cannot tell you all the things whereby ye may commit sin; for there are divers ways and means, even so many that I cannot number them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p24" pid="RZ6tTkEwNkGB8lzbcSkoXQ" hash="3QqmkA">“But this much I can tell you, that if ye do not <span class="emphasis">watch yourselves, and your thoughts, and your words, and your deeds, and observe the commandments of God, and continue in the faith</span> of what ye have heard concerning the coming of our Lord, even unto the end of your lives, ye must perish. And now, O man, remember, and perish not” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/mosiah/4.29-30" class="scriptureRef">Mosiah 4:29–30</a>, italics added).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p25" pid="cUY0gOdNvk-zmm42bKjE3Q" hash="LGIojw">The many imperfections which trouble our daily lives require us to be a repenting as well as a repentant people. We should pay attention to the gentle admonitions as well as the thundering warnings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p26" pid="KYNydqUHbESHRSdu1-0_5g" hash="oE2XhQ">At the conclusion of the October 1975 general conference, President Spencer W. Kimball said: “While sitting here, I have made up my mind that when I go home from this conference this night there are many, many areas in my life that I can perfect. I have made a mental list of them, and I expect to go to work as soon as we get through with conference” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign, </span>Nov. 1975, p. 111).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p27" pid="kaD58X3PDUOh_ENBdgr1YQ" hash="4puvqw">So this mortal part of our eternal life is a time of probation. We desired the experience before we were born. Now we are in the midst of the great test. “And we will prove them herewith,” said the Lord, “to see if they will do all things whatsoever the Lord their God shall command them” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.25" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:25</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p28" pid="OU6nIt0uHkG_i3lGF6YvAw" hash="v8d11A">Great numbers of the Saints throughout the world are doing very well. They take their probation seriously. They have established happy, righteous homes. Children grow up in the “nurture and admonition of the Lord” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/enos/1.1" class="scriptureRef">Enos 1:1</a>). Their theme song is “Love at Home.” Home evenings, love for the scriptures, association in meetings with their brothers and sisters, payment of their tithes, plans for education and missionary service are the direction of their efforts with their faces steadfastly turned toward the temple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p29" pid="atZiRTg730aubQFPpnqOpg" hash="ksYONA">This is far different from “confessing Christ” as the one single requirement for salvation. <span class="emphasis">Saints</span> take literally the parable in the twenty-fifth chapter of Matthew about the Judgment Day (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/25.31-46" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 25:31–46</a>). They reach out to one another and to the poor and distressed. Thus, they may be found on the right hand of God. No matter who you are and what you may think, God has established certain conditions or requirements to return to his presence. “They who keep their first estate shall be added upon; … and they who keep their second estate shall have glory added upon their heads for ever and ever” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/abr/3.26" class="scriptureRef">Abr. 3:26</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p30" pid="XPNR5M443EWSQP-e4sgU1w" hash="cEg2tQ">Saints go beyond the required righteous living to enter into the covenants and receive the ordinances of the gospel. These are taught and administered through his authorized servants by the power of the holy priesthood. <span class="emphasis">Holy</span> priesthood is not man-made. The ordinances and covenants belong to <span class="emphasis">this</span> priesthood. Beyond baptism, without which the Lord said we “cannot enter into the kingdom of God” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/3.5" class="scriptureRef">John 3:5</a>), are further gifts and blessings which are received in the temple. There we enter into solemn covenants with God. Through the priesthood we receive the ordinances which direct us toward the veil, that we may enter again into his presence.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p31" pid="thLRYnxDek-pdWOTAYteSA" hash="lbnaxQ">Now, of course the ordinances alone do not make us saints. Our actions do that, but even saints have not the power to return to God’s presence without Christ’s infinite atonement. That is why we enter into the covenants.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p32" pid="UXOZTKFXTEiaJyMBl0KVfA" hash="_e5dnA">In this second estate, is our perspective short-range or is it eternal? Elder Spencer W. Kimball, then a member of the Quorum of the Twelve, drew this to our attention in 1968: “One day,” he said, “a friend took me to his ranch. He unlocked the door of a large new automobile, slid under the wheel, and said proudly, ‘How do you like my new car?’ We rode in luxurious comfort … to a beautiful new landscaped home, and he said with no little pride, ‘This is my home.’</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p33" pid="XuJqya3Ke0GxOYH0S_8lPA" hash="ClLHnA">“He drove to a grassy knoll. The sun was retiring behind the distant hills. He surveyed his vast domain. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p34" pid="mV6uXf4HNEC1POqMPjXtUQ" hash="TBkMKg">“With a wide sweeping gesture he boasted, ‘From the clump of trees, to the lake, to the bluff, and to the ranch buildings and all between—all this is mine. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p35" pid="UhroU2UlpEyBZEkp5rmB-g" hash="Gf1yOg">“I saw him lying in his death,” said President Kimball, “among luxurious furnishings in a palatial home. His had been a vast estate. … I spoke at his funeral, and I followed the cortege … to his grave, a tiny, oblong area the length of a tall man, the width of a heavy one.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p36" pid="8syKfMt9iE6U-7SaayHpOw" hash="Kzgg_w">“Yesterday I saw that same estate, yellow in grain, green in lucerne, white in cotton, seemingly unmindful of him who had claimed it” (<span class="emphasis">Improvement Era,</span> June 1968, pp. 81–82).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p37" pid="uW7MXfnaYUykzS_0QV3M2Q" hash="B7lUcw">The earth is the Lord’s. We are only stewards.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p38" pid="dfnxMVRHMUejDhQzlp1s1w" hash="F2G6hA">Some who have made the covenant do not take it seriously. Having received baptism as a form and not as a covenant, they scarcely advance to the sacrament table. Saints will take it seriously. The ordinances of the priesthood and the covenants entered into in the temple direct us toward the consecrated life God expects of those who have taken the name of Jesus Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p39" pid="BHGkceuyW0GLFUMBrKYl0w" hash="kBjfFQ">Speaking in Logan in 1984, President Ezra Taft Benson taught that Adam and his posterity were commanded “to enter into the order of the Son of God. To enter into the order of the Son of God,” he said, “is the equivalent today of entering into the fullness of the Melchizedek Priesthood, which is only received in the house of the Lord” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign, </span>Aug. 1985, p. 8).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p40" pid="btHLI6mLYE-gxVQE7OqnYA" hash="pGoGYQ">“For without this no man can see the face of God, even the Father, and live” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.22" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:22</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint.p41" pid="vCtPYJ34bEaLTLn6UOpSWQ" hash="V1Jhbw">That the Saints will accept this priesthood, receive its ordinances, and keep the covenants, I pray through Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1987/04/what-it-means-to-be-a-saint</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1987-general-conference/1987-04-1030-elder-wm-grant-bangerter-64k-eng.mp3" length="6053438" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 1987 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Quality of Eternal Life</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Coming near the end of the conference, I feel advance approval for my remarks, since much of what I had planned to say has already been used by previous speakers.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03232_000_031" doc-version="2" hash="2xfY1w">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="J2-RF88BjkOzuVo6v2U-zA" hash="AZSTIA">The Quality of Eternal Life</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="mMhIAHkv10a8xsu8sqo5ng" hash="lfjMgA">Wm. Grant Bangerter</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-26f0.jpg" alt="Elder Wm. Grant Bangerter" pid="jYZ4glVlVUOm1exOSjNH-g" hash="5EvrWA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p1" pid="DXJoYDLopEixMlIxH49dMg" hash="WVDLdw">Coming near the end of the conference, I feel advance approval for my remarks, since much of what I had planned to say has already been used by previous speakers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p2" pid="LypuykXBUki3QlEgLNrgnA" hash="XG0GaQ">The great preoccupation of humanity is with dying. The general tendency, of course, is to try to avoid it. From time immemorial, the dream has been to extend life indefinitely. There have been potions and elixirs which would supposedly protect a person from death. Legends of the fountain of youth have led men to the ends of the earth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p3" pid="KgFR8tKrnEatheiiQ_MzPg" hash="ShhRXg">Things are not so different today. From wrinkle creams to vitamins to exercise programs; from preoccupation with cholesterol, climate control, or health resorts to innovations in clothing and food preparations and supplements—all promise an extension of our years.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p4" pid="dLktiFFWaEWTQWowbuD99Q" hash="yqSOtA">The medical profession is dedicated to saving human life, as are the countless laws, regulations, and customs of our society.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p5" pid="eXjWfpreQ0ukGNje_qAr_A" hash="pcKFPQ">It is true that many of these lifesaving efforts have a beneficial effect on the quality of life. The end result, however, is that we die anyway. From Adam to Abraham, from Peter and Paul to Henry VIII, George Washington and the rest—all have departed with their generations, and so will we.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p6" pid="tH-omkEixUG_eR48_3EL3A" hash="NsdL7Q">Where did they go, this countless flowering of humanity?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p7" pid="FHiyaJypoU2mekiuFZpEhw" hash="izcFVg">Is there a purpose in such a temporary existence? Some say there is not. The great question of Job haunts us all: “If a man die, shall he live again?” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/job/14.14" class="scriptureRef">Job 14:14</a>.) Of course he will! The answer is found in the doctrine of eternal life. It is the gospel of Jesus Christ, the good news, the glad tidings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p8" pid="78vE0BTWTkayw_Vx_qwHIQ" hash="C9Hhiw">Even those who don’t think they will live again or who don’t want to live again will nevertheless arise from the grave and live again. There is nothing they can do to stop it, since life is eternal.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p9" pid="mCcU2vzCLUewWSqjYOhRgg" hash="K0LztA">A dear friend told of the passing away of his atheistic father. As he bid good-bye to his family who had gathered around, he expressed no hope of any future, saying, “No, this is the end.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p10" pid="XjnAjehK9kmJ9gRtUfW_8g" hash="SwERzg">Then, as the last moment came, he suddenly opened his eyes and said distinctly, “Mother, how good to see you! Sister, you look lovely. How beautiful it all is!” Then he died. What a surprise it must have been for him! I hope he was happy about it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p11" pid="xejvzTz6kESecyY5aIjQcw" hash="OH5RpA">Now, in view of the almost universal concern over the quality of <span class="emphasis">mortal</span> life, and since some people seem to be happier than others, we might ask the question about <span class="emphasis">eternal</span> life: “How can I be sure to have a happy experience there?” And remember, eternity is a long, long time. Well, you can listen to those who know about it. Atheists don’t know about it. Careless, worldly, materialistic people don’t know about it or, at best, they are unconcerned.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p12" pid="cDs2BorOqUy_SJ2NRYticA" hash="oaVS1A">Who does know? Well, God knows. He is the Eternal Father. And Christ knows. He controls the plan which can bring the quality of happiness. And his prophets know. And so do those who listen to the prophets and understand the scriptures. Even in the Church the doctrine of eternal life is not always well understood or appreciated. If it were, many members would do more about it. After all, the quality of that eternal existence is in our own hands. Lehi said in the Book of Mormon:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p13" pid="8vaohbmINka9nqlu5z0jUw" hash="ME6RfQ">“Wherefore, how great the importance to make these things known unto the inhabitants of the earth, that they may know that there is no flesh that can dwell in the presence of God, save it be through the merits, and mercy, and grace of the Holy Messiah.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/2.8" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 2:8</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p14" pid="808W9Lt1TUWuXOzGLaD7YA" hash="BcKFjw">For the Savior said, “I am the way, the truth, and the life: <span class="emphasis">no man</span> cometh unto the Father, but by me.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/14.6" class="scriptureRef">John 14:6</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p15" pid="iDSAPVF6BEKc7xB7XwoFcw" hash="XGF_Mw">The night the angel Moroni appeared to Joseph Smith “he said there was a book deposited, written upon gold plates, giving an account of the former inhabitants of this continent, and the source from whence they sprang. He also said that the fulness of the everlasting Gospel was contained in it, as delivered by the Savior to the ancient inhabitants.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.33-34" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:33–34</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p16" pid="Bm_XMQHQ9UGi1a1CI--XAQ" hash="sOyi6w">You would think that everyone would want to know what the Savior said to the inhabitants on the American continent. The truth is, however, that many don’t. They don’t want to hear revelations, and they don’t want the gospel to be restored.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p17" pid="S-TbAn7i8UamAlIv0DAXWQ" hash="oo7jkg">I had an interesting experience years ago as we were returning from South America on a ship. Three ministers were on board, and soon each one came to me and asked if there might be an opportunity to talk together to learn what the Mormons believed. One was a Methodist, one a Presbyterian, and one a Disciple of Christ.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p18" pid="z8BHz8WtikW6gVWx_bRvjg" hash="yjBUJg">We arranged a visit together and spent a pleasant hour, they asking questions and I giving answers. Our visit was warm, friendly, and congenial. After about the first ten minutes, they began to look at each other and say: “Isn’t it interesting—he has an answer for every question.” And they repeated this comment over and over.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p19" pid="XxL8sz7G6E6geDVmxsA8xA" hash="7DDyVg">A day or two later the Methodist brother stopped to talk with me, saying, “I have been thinking of what you told us the other day. I think you know too much. I wonder if God wants us to know everything.” I could tell that he was offended at my knowledge of the revelations.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p20" pid="6jyUcN0WXUmNADU4zaqINw" hash="wLvIcQ">Other people are simply not interested, having been carried away by selfish interests and material possessions.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p21" pid="dMvkFTAlM0W0cDnguwJp1A" hash="VG2E0g">Elder ElRay Christiansen told of a wealthy man in Denmark who was converted to the gospel and had migrated to Utah. His commitment caused the loss of much of his fortune, but, after settling here, he again had the ability to amass riches and, in the process, lost his faith and testimony. As his brethren tried to counsel him about his eternal purpose, he would not listen. Finally one of them said to him, “Lars, it is not good to think only of money. You cannot take it with you, you know.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p22" pid="h8pTisfjdEC8pZXEN68KeA" hash="7WAHZw">Lars answered, “Vat is that you say?” and he was told again, “I say you cannot take it with you.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p23" pid="tQU8Z1W1EkaRjqPaJSQQGA" hash="cYYvnQ">Lars responded, “Vell, den, I vill not go.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p24" pid="5XeoxQ3oWEGVRYAZmcZCfw" hash="kQOQGg">Elder Christiansen’s report was that he had gone anyway. And we will go as well.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p25" pid="Ern65fLHUEasCUrdR2YKRw" hash="CWylJQ">Joseph Smith tells us that “happiness is the object and design of our existence; and will be the end thereof, if we pursue the path which leads to it.” (<span class="emphasis">Teachings of the Prophet Joseph Smith,</span> sel. Joseph Fielding Smith, Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1938, p. 255.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p26" pid="gNZ12sflOk-L6bvooYAShg" hash="Jmjvig">There are several fundamentals which those who seek to enjoy quality in their eternal existence would want to consider.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p27" pid="pJ7HvmhUkEyEvGnm3oLUzA" hash="XuVW-g">We begin by knowing of Jesus Christ and determining to follow him. Peter said: “Repent, and be baptized every one of you in the name of Jesus Christ for the remission of sins, and ye shall receive the gift of the Holy Ghost. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p28" pid="xpzZwG-gyU2E0562GIkNSA" hash="t2fPCw">“And with many other words did he testify and exhort, saying, Save yourselves from this untoward generation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p29" pid="OgTwgWFZo0O9_viGfA06Tg" hash="O76oyw">“Then they that gladly received his word were baptized: … three thousand souls.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/2.38-41" class="scriptureRef">Acts 2:38–41</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p30" pid="7WYHqe5Sx0yTEo_mXHaxEA" hash="yQxghQ">Then, we “press forward with a steadfastness in Christ … and endure to the end, [and] thus saith the Father: Ye shall have eternal life.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/2-ne/31.20" class="scriptureRef">2 Ne. 31:20</a>.) We are to take upon us His name and always remember Him and keep His commandments. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/4.title" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 4</a>; <a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/5.title" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 5</a>; <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/20.77-79" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 20:77–79</a>.) That seems to be keeping our repentance up to date.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p31" pid="ULbHWI4N4UaVJtORM7S1IA" hash="2gaOjw">Now comes the call to serve. We serve God and our fellowmen. The parable of the Good Samaritan came in answer to the lawyer’s question: “What shall I do to obtain eternal life? … Thou shalt love the Lord thy God … and thy neighbour as thyself.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/luke/10.25,27" class="scriptureRef">Luke 10:25, 27</a>.)</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.f2">
	<p pid="hW1wwLN2kUubjD5pnNeyfg" hash="lDDDgA">In the portrayal of the Judgment Day in the twenty-fifth chapter of Matthew, we are called to serve those who are</p>
	<ul class="bullet">
	  <li pid="NztZQINSJEWEDM07V-C_7w" hash="Zwq0zg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="V8YdCKOnGE6cLZ_SemIREg" hash="ma7mXg">an hungred</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="qwpt-5MdxkyxzhZ7I-aboA" hash="VLNhPQ">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="67tbBfzkUUyZUAhBYf2ayg" hash="RSazIA">thirsty,</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="4Dduk1EaL0-I14Xjx6HGgw" hash="YiyOvA">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="bD3wrVj3806pYs_z4HCLjA" hash="yM9Ycg">a stranger</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="3lXiOml4AkGXp4IgwY5SUA" hash="203rJg">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="cMfAqqm8-ka-4kq98dOtAg" hash="RlG1KA">naked</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="u6fwr31HrEGF0kWqNBDd7Q" hash="oC4rrA">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="GutcsXCJQ0aJMicggJA0Og" hash="fi9SuA">sick</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="D9lAo27MAUekDofJsbqqPw" hash="5xa4GA">
          <span class="label">•</span>
          <p pid="gcHko_KgZkmFNkfNjARbeA" hash="4yDWEQ">or in prison. (See <a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/25.35-36" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 25:35–36</a>.)</p>
        </li>
	</ul>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p32" pid="HGbQH2QpRkiS5WBA_ugXNw" hash="N3eJdA">Evidently those who do not undertake this service will not qualify. As the Lord says, “Inasmuch as ye did it not to one of the least of these, ye did it not to me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p33" pid="WslZYHBp30alMXWMf2skKg" hash="B5F4BA">“And these shall go away into everlasting punishment: but the righteous into life eternal.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/25.45-46" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 25:45–46</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p34" pid="iJWxYBwMxUG6gAHO0Wqt5w" hash="npDDgA">To receive the blessings that accompany this service we are given the priesthood and its power. It has been called “the Holy Priesthood, after the Order of the Son of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/107.3" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 107:3</a>.) “And without the ordinances thereof, and the authority of the priesthood, … no man can see the face of God, even the Father, and live.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.21-22" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:21–22</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p35" pid="CKSJayBZtkKkJqTuJ7URAA" hash="i7suxw">And furthermore, “Wo unto all those who come not unto this priesthood.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/84.42" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 84:42</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p36" pid="lYNGJkYtpkqxhbZlqZehbg" hash="XsbK6A">Now, the way of God leads us to the temple. In the past eight years the number of temples in the Church has increased from seventeen to forty-one, with six more in the process of preparation. These sacred edifices fulfill an eternal purpose.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p37" pid="8EjB6_2_xEmiNvECxWh1HA" hash="OlNqug">Just as the ancient Israelites looked to the temple for their salvation, even so will those who are in earnest find in the temple the pathway to the presence of the Father and the Son. There they receive holy ordinances as they covenant to keep the commandments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p38" pid="V1HBBB4rR0uaCknJw5MKRA" hash="y3MN4A">The doctrine of salvation teaches us that we do not step into the vestibule of the gospel merely by confessing Christ or by being baptized. If we take it seriously, we will reach for all the blessings. Remember, Laman and Lemuel turned their back on the tree of life. They joined the world and lost the promise.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p39" pid="mxQWk-rMnEOqYgIAOFgv5A" hash="bIaJ4w">Finally, understanding the doctrine of salvation makes it clear that the plan of God is to redeem all his children on the basis of their repentance—even those who died without a knowledge of the truth.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p40" pid="lUy4juacOUCsnLEF1LaVMw" hash="0bmshw">And so, once again, we come to the temple and, according to the promise of Malachi, we provide the ordinances by proxy for those who did not have the privilege of knowing the gospel on earth. We know that the teaching of the gospel and the opportunity to repent and be worthy of baptism is provided for those who are now in the world of spirits.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p41" pid="tOgJjZyjP0qOJAa6TJRlog" hash="0MuXRQ">The privilege of returning to the temple helps us to obtain the spirit of the work performed there. We perform this service especially for our ancestors. Moroni also said to Joseph Smith, quoting the words of Malachi, “I will reveal unto you the Priesthood, by the hand of Elijah the prophet.” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.38" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:38</a>.) The hearts of us, the living children, will turn to our fathers—those ancestors who have died—and will provide them with the ordinances without which their redemption would not be possible.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p42" pid="aBLdjqhP8E-R0iqogh_WjA" hash="eNgIDg">Immortality or the resurrection will happen to us all. It is an unearned benefit made possible through the grace or free gift of Christ. Eternal life in happiness and glory in association with those we love will be the reward only of those who exercise faith in Jesus Christ through obedience to his commandments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life.p43" pid="HEKsbh3UdkqXfJaHJ6abbQ" hash="HM0oyg">I have known of Jesus Christ since before I can remember. I was taught to pray to God in his name since infancy. I don’t believe there has been a single day of my life when I have not openly sought for his blessings, his spirit, and his protection. I want his type of eternal life. It has come to mean everything to me. I know that the gospel is true, since I have heard the voice of God through his Spirit confirm and witness it to me. In the name of Jesus Christ, the Lord, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1988/10/the-quality-of-eternal-life</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1988-general-conference/1988-10-5040-elder-wm-grant-bangerter-64k-eng.mp3" length="6910429" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 1988 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
