<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks By Yoshihiko Kikuchi</title>
    <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    <description>General Conference talks by Yoshihiko Kikuchi.</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>Speakercast</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/covers/Yoshihiko%20Kikuchi.jpg</url>
      <title>General Conference talks by Yoshihiko Kikuchi.</title>
      <link>http://philip.lundrigan.org/Speakercast/</link>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 1977 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <itunes:category text="Religion &amp; Spirituality">
      <itunes:category text="Christianity"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Why Me, O Lord?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1977/10/why-me-o-lord?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I’m grateful to President Romney for trying to pronounce my name. When I go to the next world I will ask my father if I can change my name. Thank you, President Romney.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/why-me-o-lord" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03089_000_030" doc-version="2" hash="klHMew"><div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/why-me-o-lord.head1"><h1 class="title" pid="poyz371uBEaJ2wR70CXrlQ" hash="EfWLNw">Why Me, O Lord?</h1><p class="authorName" pid="9x7rUuJY80WJt1m8KFtn5Q" hash="R_EqkQ">Elder Yoshihiko Kikuchi</p></div><div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/why-me-o-lord.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2a70.jpg" alt="Elder Yoshihiko Kikuchi" pid="SveS52y8NUibgzvtMGcfKQ" hash="K_zPtA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/why-me-o-lord.p1" pid="fp2nLV4gR0KfC5PAdn0khg" hash="rfkjGA">I’m grateful to President Romney for trying to pronounce my name. When I go to the next world I will ask my father if I can change my name. Thank you, President Romney.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/why-me-o-lord.p2" pid="2d-n5aqtBEy4smsGnhh7Xg" hash="pVRa4w">President Kimball, and all the Brethren of the General Authorities, and my beloved brothers and sisters in the gospel of the Lord Jesus Christ, today I stand before you, humbly, to bear my testimony of the divinity of the gospel of the Lord Jesus Christ. First of all, I express my deep, sincere appreciation to those who have helped me and have been so kind to me and motivated me, built me and taught me and guided me—wonderful help, wonderful influence in my life. I’m grateful for my wife, Toshiko, and for my children. President Kimball and all the brethren of the gospel and sisters, we need your prayers.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/why-me-o-lord.p3" pid="VHn_qR53UUmd9aR6mdyUKQ" hash="TSdShQ">Elder Gordon B. Hinckley gave me a special blessing when I was a green, green bean of a missionary which has guided me in my life. My dear brothers and sisters, I never expected to be called to such a heavy responsibility. I’m still asking myself and the Lord, “Why me, O Lord? Why me, O Lord?” Yet, my brothers and sisters, still within my soul I hear in the bosom of my heart, “I will go where you want me to go, dear Lord, over mountain, or plain, or sea.” (See <span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 75.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/why-me-o-lord.p4" pid="909g4KvkvkaJhi-pN87G_Q" hash="EelmlA">Yet another voice is saying, “I will go and do the things which the Lord hath commanded.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/3.7" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 3:7</a>.) Another voice saying, “O that I were an angel, and could have the wish of my heart, that I might go forth and speak with the trump of God, with a voice that shakes the earth, and cry repentance unto every people of the nations.” (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/29.1" class="scriptureRef">Alma 29:1</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1977/10/why-me-o-lord.p5" pid="Kk3r283Rd0yylr8rceLNRA" hash="0LdraA">My dear brothers and sisters, I love—I love our Heavenly Father. I know—I know within my whole heart that God lives. I know that there is a living prophet of God today, even Spencer W. Kimball. I love him. I will support him with all my heart. The Book of Mormon is true, the true word of God. Brothers and sisters, I leave you my testimony. I humbly do this in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ. Amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1977/10/why-me-o-lord</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1977-general-conference/1977-10-5060-elder-yoshihiko-kikuchi-64k-eng.mp3" length="2584029" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 1977 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Send Missionaries from Every Nation</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1979/10/send-missionaries-from-every-nation?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I am seeking for the guidance of the Holy Spirit today. President Kimball, President Tanner, President Romney, President Benson, all of the Brethren of the Twelve, all the other General Authorities, and brothers and sisters, on behalf of the Saints i</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/send-missionaries-from-every-nation" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03115_000_013" doc-version="2" hash="nNQ0Xg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/send-missionaries-from-every-nation.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="L04X6CLd706dhx6mDlrMzw" hash="gpXBPg">Send Missionaries from Every Nation</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="jRawwke7ikeKVlOsKkRY8w" hash="R_EqkQ">Elder Yoshihiko Kikuchi</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/send-missionaries-from-every-nation.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2a70.jpg" alt="Elder Yoshihiko Kikuchi" pid="QOcVK6up40ySBhZTzdxVUg" hash="K_zPtA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/send-missionaries-from-every-nation.p1" pid="bsYhoZbZPkWdx0ljYShvAA" hash="r7hi1g">I am seeking for the guidance of the Holy Spirit today. President Kimball, President Tanner, President Romney, President Benson, all of the Brethren of the Twelve, all the other General Authorities, and brothers and sisters, on behalf of the Saints in Japan and Korea, I would like to extend our warm and sincere appreciation for the angelic voices of the Mormon Tabernacle Choir. During their recent trip to Japan and Korea, they were magnificently accepted by both members and nonmembers. Their wholehearted appreciation can be seen in the excellent comments of the reviews in some of our most important newspapers. I would like to share these comments.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/send-missionaries-from-every-nation.p2" pid="i50SZo5GNECu7tMae8a3aw" hash="sRO_gg">One reviewer wrote: “You could find beauty and the profound sound of completeness or perfection” (<span class="emphasis">Yomiuri Tokyo,</span> 8 Sept. 1979). Another wrote: “They gave us a taste of the glorious quality and power of music” (<span class="emphasis">Kobe News,</span> 10 Sept. 1979). And still another wrote: “The choir found its way to the depths of our hearts, leaving us with the most indescribable sense of beauty and feeling.” (<span class="emphasis">Kyoto News,</span> 11 Sept. 1979). The president of Chukyo Television, a major sponsor for the trip and of course he is a nonmember, said that the eyes of the choir members were so beautiful and pure that he and his associates were left deeply touched. As our beloved prophet, President Spencer W. Kimball, has told us before, “As we incline our hearts to our Heavenly Father and his Son Jesus Christ, we hear a symphony of sweet music sung by heavenly voices proclaiming the gospel of peace” (<span class="emphasis">Ensign,</span> May 1974, p. 46).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/send-missionaries-from-every-nation.p3" pid="W113Xj4z0ESNxT8PEtQlvg" hash="l2s2oA">Brothers and sisters, today I would also like to express my appreciation to the many missionaries who have come to our land and to the Land of Morning Calm. When I see their wonderful works, my heart turns to their parents who sent them and to those who are giving great sacrifices now that their sons and daughters may go on missions. I met a mother who was driving a taxi in this city as a part-time job so she could send her son on his mission. She spoke very proudly of her son, who was on his mission serving his Father in Heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/send-missionaries-from-every-nation.p4" pid="HAlkv3HLaEGsaKRvAW9v9g" hash="8qpmFA">May I share with you a beautiful missionary experience I encountered recently? I saw a miracle performed by one of your missionary sons who so dearly loved an investigator. I met this gentleman at a special fireside. He said, “I appreciate very much the young Mormon missionary who taught me the most important thing in life and gave me happiness. Sometime I would like to extend my sincere appreciation to the parents who taught him to so live the gospel.” With tears in his eyes, and as he was holding my hands, he said, “Oh, Elder Kikuchi, I thank our Heavenly Father for this glorious gospel,” and then he related the following story:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/send-missionaries-from-every-nation.p5" pid="DTphuM5Rr0i-eKrcAXnKVA" hash="593iyg">“One day eight years ago, on my way home from work, I was hit by a hit-and-run driver. For eleven days I was unconscious, and for two years I was in a hospital. When I was finally released from the hospital, my wife had left me and had taken the children with her. We had had a fine family life before the accident, but my life became a total wreck. I was lonesome and depressed, for I had lost my most precious possession—my family. I attempted suicide many times. My only living came from welfare. I was emotionally and physically exhausted; I had become a living vegetable. I couldn’t walk, so I would transport myself by rolling over on the floor and crawling on all fours.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/send-missionaries-from-every-nation.p6" pid="z95osfhBkUu9Gv_aBRUrkA" hash="0b4scA">“One evening I went to the hospital to see my doctor for the final results of a series of operations. He told me there was no hope for recovery. Though I had expected him to say so, it was still very shocking for me. All was lost. As I approached a railway bridge on my return from the doctor’s, I wept to see my own face in the wet reflection on the pavement. It was a pitiful sight.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/send-missionaries-from-every-nation.p7" pid="t0KwuRgLHEG9Ob5fdFKg1Q" hash="QLcCug">Brothers and sisters, just when he was about to jump in front of the oncoming train, he met one of your missionary sons.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/send-missionaries-from-every-nation.p8" pid="GzxzvToMSU2YeXMYtW-WVg" hash="FR5_DQ">It reminds me that the Savior said, “I am the good shepherd, and know my sheep, and are known of mine” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/10.14" class="scriptureRef">John 10:14</a>). “My sheep hear my voice, and I know them, and they follow me” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/10.27" class="scriptureRef">John 10:27</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/send-missionaries-from-every-nation.p9" pid="qzuUrlRtfUuAqRdSVHNAHg" hash="V2WpTg">Cottage meetings began immediately. In them, Mr. Sugiyama learned that the gospel is true, that Jesus Christ is our Savior, Joseph Smith was a prophet of God, and the true church of God has been restored in this last dispensation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/send-missionaries-from-every-nation.p10" pid="HvpUNnzlvEyo1ne6be7lEw" hash="GWsoMQ">As usual, missionaries invited him to church; however, because he couldn’t walk, he said he wouldn’t be able to come. But on the morning of the Sabbath, he awoke early and bravely headed for the church. Though it was close, it took him nearly three hours to traverse the distance between his home and the closest station to the Yokohama chapel. The Yokohama chapel is situated high upon a hill. From the station to the church it took him almost an hour, although ordinarily it would take a person only five minutes. He would cling to the wall, then fall down, only to struggle again to his feet. He finally reached the chapel where the sacrament was in progress. The missionaries had never expected him to come to church. But Brother Sugiyama felt the pure love of God from the missionaries and members and felt himself drawn to it.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/send-missionaries-from-every-nation.p11" pid="DHAZm-T_KUiQ9ay2ub3rOQ" hash="lPdTWA">The Savior said, “A new commandment I give unto you, That ye love one another; as I have loved you” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/13.34" class="scriptureRef">John 13:34</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/send-missionaries-from-every-nation.p12" pid="Mx1drFhZGUKS9shzSlwcSQ" hash="eQRL4w">Shortly afterward, Brother Sugiyama followed the Lord’s commandment by becoming baptized.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/send-missionaries-from-every-nation.p13" pid="IgBZp-zhlEGfGAnves38mQ" hash="Qhq2MA">The Lord said: “Except a man be born of water and of the Spirit, he cannot enter into the kingdom of God” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/3.5" class="scriptureRef">John 3:5</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/send-missionaries-from-every-nation.p14" pid="1rDY7wX4EEyUDr_IcgWamw" hash="uEA0sg">The morning following his baptism, he woke up bright and early. He stretched his legs out in preparation to roll over as usual. But this time, brothers and sisters, something was different. He felt strength in his legs, and his whole body surged with power. He sat up and gradually, eventually, stood on his feet. He hadn’t stood in years without other supports. He walked away that morning! He found that his body had been made whole.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/send-missionaries-from-every-nation.p15" pid="ODEdPVHc8kCu9qXlVCGXig" hash="r5QJGQ">Said the Savior to a similar one who had been healed by faith, “Thy faith hath made thee whole; go in peace” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/5.34" class="scriptureRef">Mark 5:34</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/send-missionaries-from-every-nation.p16" pid="TSNm_SwYJkCGGaFzxGFqiA" hash="96TNZg">Brother Sugiyama said, “Love hath made me whole, and I will go in peace in the Lord’s way.” Brothers and sisters, miracles are not the only evidences of the true Church of God, but we can learn much from the miracle performed by the Lord through a great young Mormon missionary who loved his investigator so much.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/send-missionaries-from-every-nation.p17" pid="WIhkHRym0UGIPznNaN0roQ" hash="l8BDVg">Love precedes the miracle. Love is a process; it is not a program. The love of Christ can overcome any of the worries of our lives and heal any human affliction. To all my friends wherever they may be, let us come unto Jesus and “be born of water and of the Spirit” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/3.5" class="scriptureRef">John 3:5</a>). For as the Lord said, “Whosoever believeth on my words, them will I visit with the manifestation of my Spirit; and they shall be born of me, even of water and of the Spirit” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/5.16" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 5:16</a>).</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/send-missionaries-from-every-nation.p18" pid="Uj3Ok6fu5kiTCHfN1ZMXAg" hash="PXNcYA">Oh, how I appreciate my own missionaries who taught me the most glorious message that we can hear. Elder Law and Elder Porter, I thank you. Oh, how many lives have been touched by missionaries like them? Oh, may we continue to send great missionaries from every nation as our prophet has asked us to do. And may we members of this true Church have enough courage to stand before the world to share this great message of the everlasting gospel, the restored gospel of Jesus Christ, with “every nation, kindred, tongue, and people” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/77.8" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 77:8</a>). Brothers and sisters, we must be “the light of the world” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/5.14" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 5:14</a>). There, someone is waiting for you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/send-missionaries-from-every-nation.p19" pid="NBIQzKNdQ0icz_3pEdpdew" hash="ZBKLJw">I bear you my testimony of the divinity of this gospel. I know that God lives and that Jesus Christ is the Savior of the whole world. There is no other name under heaven whereby we might be saved (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/acts/4.12" class="scriptureRef">Acts 4:12</a>). Only through Jesus of Nazareth can we be saved.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1979/10/send-missionaries-from-every-nation.p20" pid="fSRIcJ9CKU-hzmYKkAXSTg" hash="u85Azg">I know that Joseph Smith was a prophet of God and that the Book of Mormon contains the true word of God. This Church is true. I know that President Spencer W. Kimball—a modern Job—is a living prophet of God today. I love him with all my heart and sustain him with all my soul. In the name of our Savior, Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-3048.jpg" alt="First Presidency, 10 Oct 1880" pid="yVHb4uxasEKAD6YFXneJBg" hash="lhaq0w" />
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1979/10/send-missionaries-from-every-nation</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1979-general-conference/1979-10-2060-elder-yoshihiko-kikuchi-64k-eng.mp3" length="6118120" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 1979 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“My Sheep Hear My Voice”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I feel very humble and privileged this afternoon to be in your presence, brothers and sisters. I hope and pray that the Spirit of the Lord will be with me so that I might be able to communicate with you.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03141_000_027" doc-version="2" hash="n74Qxg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="ZzbrT7rwfEequyLgg0Z7VA" hash="ez4ADg">“My Sheep Hear My Voice”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="bV6urRGaXEeIq5aJKv6CjA" hash="R_EqkQ">Elder Yoshihiko Kikuchi</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2a70.jpg" alt="Elder Yoshihiko Kikuchi" pid="yGcijWOXH0yPEZTun_jGsQ" hash="K_zPtA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.p1" pid="L2tz_-wXxk2G9PFhP7ZXXA" hash="u19u5g">I feel very humble and privileged this afternoon to be in your presence, brothers and sisters. I hope and pray that the Spirit of the Lord will be with me so that I might be able to communicate with you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.p2" pid="XB3YRkdZ302MERYaDPcdYQ" hash="7VJtIQ">
        <span class="emphasis">I know with all my heart and soul that our Heavenly Father lives. He truly lives. I know our Heavenly Father is there, and he is ready to answer our sincere prayers.</span> He has spoken to his children in the past; he has spoken to us in our day, to our people in his last dispensation. Our Father introduced his Son, Jesus Christ, to the people who lived on the American continent.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.p3" pid="isNPDC7Oakmx02I7dxKNkw" hash="N2r28Q">The Book of Mormon testifies: “They heard a voice as if it came out of heaven; and they cast their eyes round about, for they understood not the voice which they heard; and it was not a harsh voice, neither was it a loud voice; nevertheless, and notwithstanding it being a small voice it did pierce them that did hear to the center, insomuch that there was no part of their frame that it did not cause to quake; yea, it did pierce them to the very soul, and did cause their hearts to burn.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.p4" pid="mmh9z2EYLU-wczcghKjQZQ" hash="6bNb2w">“And again the third time they did hear the voice, and did open their ears to hear it; and their eyes were towards the sound <span class="emphasis">thereof;</span> and they did look steadfastly towards heaven, from whence the sound came.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.p5" pid="Mhu42_EEF0u3nCuj6FU7KQ" hash="dkdc-A">“And behold, the third time they did understand the voice which they heard; and it said unto them;</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.p6" pid="JYW79MTpv0uHIJPcErsLug" hash="VWcDeg">
        <span class="emphasis">“Behold my Beloved Son, in whom I am well pleased, in whom I have glorified my name—hear ye him.”</span> (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.3,5-7" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:3, 5–7</a>; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.p7" pid="qj85fuDnMECDdtcy-YH43g" hash="6NViDA">I know that the same Father spoke to the Jewish people in the eastern hemisphere. When our Lord Jesus Christ was baptized, the Bible testifies, “And, lo, the heavens were opened unto him, and he saw the Spirit of God descending like a dove, and lighting upon him:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.p8" pid="5rcLohMcREi22L95LYH8yA" hash="ZiqaHg">“And lo a voice from heaven, saying, This is my beloved Son, in whom I am well pleased.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/3.16-17" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 3:16–17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.p9" pid="I3xuD4gE7UGbSCX6cpfzNA" hash="lsgNaw">
        <span class="emphasis">I know that early one morning in the spring of 1820, in the state of New York, the Father and the Son appeared to the boy Joseph Smith.</span> Joseph Smith testified: “I saw a pillar of light exactly over my head, above the brightness of the sun, which descended gradually until it fell upon me.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.p10" pid="4XPy1nJ3FES8mPShEcDc9A" hash="jQObPA">“… When the light rested upon me I saw two Personages, whose brightness and glory defy all description, standing above me in the air. One of them spake unto me, calling me by name and said, pointing to the other—<span class="emphasis">This is My Beloved Son. Hear Him!</span>” (<a href="/scriptures/pgp/js-h/1.16-17" class="scriptureRef">JS—H 1:16–17</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.p11" pid="N2BZLlGPoU2ybIgxXXnzvQ" hash="oK9vxA">
        <span class="emphasis">I know Joseph Smith saw God, the Father, and his Son, Jesus Christ. And I know that Joseph was a true living prophet of God. Like Joseph Smith of our day and like the ancient disciples and Apostles of the western </span>and eastern hemispheres, I know that our Heavenly Father’s own testimony is true: Jesus of Nazareth is his Beloved Son, in whom he is well pleased. Hear ye him!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.p12" pid="lIzrOrwmXkqgCZvPgvKJ9Q" hash="ldvqFA">
        <span class="emphasis">I know that Jesus of Nazareth was born in the land of Judea,</span> that he walked by the Sea of Galilee and the fields and plains of Palestine. It is his own testimony that we should hear, the one he bore to Martha, the sister of his friend Lazarus. Yesterday Elder Monson referred to this scripture:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.p13" pid="R7n4nOOi5kSynKjsD_hVWA" hash="iSy8UA">“I am the resurrection, and the life: he that believeth in me, though he were dead, yet shall he live:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.p14" pid="iDsawmX0nEGribMstJho9g" hash="jm5gZQ">“And whosoever liveth and believeth in me shall never die. Believest thou this?” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/11.25-26" class="scriptureRef">John 11:25–26</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.p15" pid="Xt-N31RN8EK19gDvi59rmQ" hash="rLEhWg">Brothers and sisters, I believe this with all my heart and with all my soul. <span class="emphasis">I know that this same Jesus conferred upon Joseph Smith all the power and authority necessary to reestablish the kingdom of God upon this earth once again, so that every soul might have a chance to hear the Father’s Beloved Son.</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.p16" pid="a34X9apmXUCs2IG_84wxYg" hash="t6AW9Q">
        <span class="emphasis">I know that our Heavenly Father loves us so much that he has provided us, through his Beloved Son, a way for us to follow in our mortal lives.</span> Through the restoration of the gospel of the Lord Jesus Christ, he has provided the way to find eternal happiness, true happiness.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.p17" pid="-Ji0JgkqVkGpatrqPc2G1A" hash="AWQBGQ">Brothers and sisters, many of our Father’s children in Japan and Korea also believe our Heavenly Father’s testimony and listen to his Beloved Son.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.p18" pid="qV6i6HbA2k-Yh5gWOI0Mmg" hash="qgaagA">Shortly before coming to this conference, I received a beautiful letter from a woman who had lost her husband thirteen years ago. I will read it to you. She said: “I was left alone to raise my two sons. As I was attending the baptismal service of my eldest son, who is attending senior high school, I could not help but feel the beautiful atmosphere that surrounded me. I was so impressed by the sweet spirit of the Saints; how exuberant and humble I felt. I observed my son, dressed in white, going down into the water. The stake president’s wife, who was whispering to me, told me that his sins would be washed away. I was so overwhelmed by the beauty of this moment that I felt my tears well up and my heart cried for joy. At that moment I wanted to know about myself. What about me? What about me? Was it possible that I, too, could experience a washing away of my sins? If my sins could be washed away and made clean once more, I too wanted to be baptized.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.p19" pid="t87I6JF9pEaLHBUrYrT__Q" hash="NQKo7A">After four days of studying and praying with the missionaries, she too came to accept the Savior and was baptized. Shortly thereafter, her youngest son also entered into the waters of baptism. Now Sister Masako Anan and her two boys are preparing to go to the Tokyo Temple to be sealed as a family with their deceased father for time and all eternity. Oh, how glorious is the power of the gospel which can change the hearts of people from sorrow and despair to happiness and joy! Oh, how glorious it is to know that the power conferred upon Joseph Smith can change the hearts of the people!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.p20" pid="XrqisDYtVEOx5TPNPGZEKg" hash="N6Ru1g">
        <span class="emphasis">I know that the gospel has been restored</span> and that the true church of God has been reestablished here upon this earth. I humbly extend my invitation to all my friends everywhere, and I say humbly today, “Come partake of this living water. Believe the testimony of the Father: ‘[This is] my Beloved Son, in whom I am well pleased, … hear ye him.’” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.7" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:7</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.p21" pid="LWoL1CGNC0mS5GI0dWfM9Q" hash="QoF0sw">I know for those who wish to hear the Father’s beloved Son, the Book of Mormon like the Bible has a familiar voice. It is the word of God and has the power to change men’s souls.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.p22" pid="gCRQEO6gJk2EcxzCRKIGhg" hash="HA0S3Q">May I give you an example of a Korean brother who heard the Savior’s voice? Brother Choi had left his wife, two children, and his mother for nine months. One day our missionaries were tracting in the city of Kwang Ju, Korea. They found his family. The family began to study with the missionaries and were baptized shortly.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.p23" pid="pdLoLJfSn0mqyXGhhsEwbQ" hash="sfLkew">The missionaries started the family home evening program with this family.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.p24" pid="d-4NJkCwek24mIRPAi-yRg" hash="XjmqwQ">One day the seven-year-old daughter purchased a Book of Mormon from a missionary and sent it with her simple, yet beautiful testimony to her daddy. Two missionaries took that book to her father and bore their strong, firm testimonies of the truthfulness of the gospel and the importance of the family. Her father wondered why these people were so concerned and kind to him and his family. When evening came, he began to read, and heard a familiar voice of the Lord. He was so inspired and found it to be true. And also he found the testimony written by his daughter. I would like to share it with you, brothers and sisters. She said:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.p25" pid="8OxUpMt1ckaGZZpivpVqSA" hash="ED0GOg">“Aboji, Aboji, Aboji (which interpreted is “Daddy, Daddy, Daddy”), I want to have family home evening with you! Please come back! We love you! I love you! I need you! I want you to read this book! Heavenly Father loves you!”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.p26" pid="6f0oX9t1DU2q8WxanL4q_w" hash="u1fnKg">Brother Choi was so inspired and magnified by reading the Book of Mormon and touched by it and touched by his daughter’s testimony that he asked the missionaries to baptize him. Therefore this family was reunited, and Brother Choi is now the bishop of the Kwang Ju Third Ward. He sits in this hall today, a living example of one who heard the Savior’s voice from the Book of Mormon.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.p27" pid="xr3IaLdclkCVEC2gkis6wQ" hash="ZavWyQ">Oh, how we need the missionaries of the Lord to carry the Father’s testimony of his Beloved Son to every people, kindred, and tongue! There must be many Bishop Chois and there must be many Sister Anans in your own neighborhoods.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.p28" pid="n5tmX5FZYUWWiy5WY9sghg" hash="87VqSQ">I know Spencer W. Kimball is a prophet of the Lord. He is a living prophet. He instructs us that we should lengthen our stride, quicken our pace with a sense of urgency; do it now! President Kimball, you are a living prophet of the Lord; you are a man scorned and covered with scars like Job of old, and yet you are ready to move forward, to climb another mountain. We love you. We need you.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice.p29" pid="GEDvpCLBOkyhEkcPp8ECbg" hash="ofMmUQ">Brothers and sisters, why don’t we pay more humble attention to this servant of the Lord so that we can lengthen our own stride and share this beautiful gospel of the Lord Jesus Christ with another Bishop Choi and another Sister Anan. I humbly pray in the sacred name of the Lord Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1981/10/my-sheep-hear-my-voice</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/october-1981-general-conference/1981-10-5030-elder-yoshihiko-kikuchi-64k-eng.mp3" length="7137674" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 1981 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Count Your Blessings</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My friend, Milton, has six children. His lovely wife died in a traffic accident and left him with their beautiful children. One day his six-year-old daughter came to his bedside in tears. Milton thought she had had a fight with her brothers. “No, no,</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03174_000_032" doc-version="2" hash="XYuC6w">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="b9l-KB6jfkaqafZt2nENAA" hash="KEHiAg">Count Your Blessings</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="_N6QzE-8NESXnmlYPxi0YQ" hash="R_EqkQ">Elder Yoshihiko Kikuchi</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2a70.jpg" alt="Elder Yoshihiko Kikuchi" pid="zvFGhyWbKUiCv2aRseOfhw" hash="K_zPtA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.p1" pid="8Nm3jmlqbEGHEnIPcVpNVg" hash="5tAhbA">My friend, Milton, has six children. His lovely wife died in a traffic accident and left him with their beautiful children. One day his six-year-old daughter came to his bedside in tears. Milton thought she had had a fight with her brothers. “No, no, Daddy,” she said, “I feel lonely. Where is Mom? I want to see Mom.” Father embraced her and told her, “Your mom is with Heavenly Father now. We will meet Mom again.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.p2" pid="ybSfux42ME2CDFuhEKb5Lw" hash="MNYBjg">The other day, his four-year-old daughter came to her grandma and said, “Will my mom ever come home?” Her grandma embraced and kissed her, saying, “She is with Heavenly Father.”</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="XQdwy-2Od0yLSNC7Y0FWVg" hash="pyH-fg">“I Sobbed and Sobbed”</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.p3" pid="-Gx8cstSwkuCIjcA84mAJA" hash="nGTTjA">The mother of an eleven-year-old boy became very seriously ill. His father brought her to Salt Lake from Arizona. A few days later, this young boy wrote:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.p4" pid="vkT-pCkaKESuYWF-rF9aew" hash="WMnodQ">“We all feel now we will take better care of Mama if she comes home soon.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.p5" pid="W_b7jNNqhk6wwiEtfD7Shw" hash="V5NW8A">Later he wrote: “We are very lonely without you. … We are very busy around here. We received the telegram and were very glad to know that Mama was out of danger. … I think I will close for it is getting bed time. Sister Allen told us in Religion Class that we should go to bed at eight o’clock so we could have enough sleep. Now it is nearly half past eight. Good bye. Your loving Son. Spencer Kimball.” (Quoted in Edward L. Kimball and Andrew E. Kimball, Jr., <span class="emphasis">Spencer W. Kimball,</span> Salt Lake City: Bookcraft, 1977, p. 45.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.p6" pid="cWU422a5gEaRUyOr419abg" hash="mAsUpw">The very next day after he mailed this letter his mother passed away. The next day their bishop received a telegram, and all of the Kimball children were called out of school. They all ran home, and the bishop told them, “Your Ma is dead.” President Kimball later told of that incident:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.p7" pid="dbXaJdeCCESKrB0J4PAxAA" hash="GRFniQ">“It came as a thunderbolt. I ran from the house out in the backyard to be alone in my deluge of tears. Out of sight and sound, away from everybody, I sobbed and sobbed. Each time I said the word ‘Ma’ fresh floods of tears gushed forth until I was drained dry. Ma—dead! But she couldn’t be! Life couldn’t go on for us. … My eleven-year-old heart seemed to burst.” (<span class="emphasis">Spencer W. Kimball,</span> p. 46.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.p8" pid="sMVoXFvSME-pv2HEzjfcxQ" hash="LfGIGQ">Why death? Why sickness? Why tragedies? Why must I have suffering, and disappointment? Why must I have to face the “deep waters” of life? Why must I go through “the rivers of sorrow”? (See “How Firm a Foundation,” <span class="emphasis">Hymns,</span> no. 66.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.p9" pid="MiLSkvB4ukCsAbrACQjDJQ" hash="bw8v6w">When I was five, my father passed away, and we four children became fatherless, because of World War II. Our lives drastically changed; we became so poor. One day I clearly remember: I was playing at the park, and every boy was playing with his father, but I didn’t have one. I said to myself, “I wish I could have my father.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.p10" pid="rmuczBOB5E-z-251Xjavtw" hash="fxcG1g">We know little of the will of the Lord, yet we judge the Lord often with our small wisdom. I speak to those who now walk the deep water of life or the rivers of sorrow. I testify to you that the Lord loves you, and Jesus Christ will never forget you! The Lord has said, “My son [or daughter], … all these things shall give thee experience, and shall be for thy good.” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/122.7" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 122:7</a>.)</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="3NrIe4Zl9kmG7Rl-Bq8vGg" hash="1VsM-g">Suffering Can Make Saints</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.p11" pid="ioX1QRn2PEqFow12R5h7AQ" hash="2WRzjw">Elder Spencer W. Kimball said: “Being human, we would expel from our lives physical pain and mental anguish and assure ourselves of continual ease and comfort, but if we were to close the doors upon sorrow and distress, we might be excluding our greatest friends and benefactors. Suffering can make saints of people as they learn patience, long-suffering, and self-mastery.” (<span class="emphasis">Faith Precedes the Miracle,</span> Salt Lake City: Deseret Book Co., 1972, p. 98.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.p12" pid="sD0Ww6RWb0uMTekkbFs9Mw" hash="_CwivQ">I repeat: “Suffering can make saints of people as they learn patience, long-suffering, and self-mastery,” as long as we live righteously.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.p13" pid="uBVlV13700aPyKIpminFEg" hash="uPmhbw">Let’s all learn from my friend Mick. One day he was swimming at a party given by the company for which he was working that summer in Nebraska. He dove into the water and hit a shallow spot very hard. A broken neck was his diagnosis, and his whole body was immediately paralyzed. He even lost the capacity to breathe. The doctor said, “He may not make it through the night.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.p14" pid="NvyWbHVOBk2kyR1dMTuwCQ" hash="FLkhBQ">He had earned a B. A. degree in political science after serving a mission in Japan. At the time of this tragic accident he had just one year left in law school at BYU. He was married and had two children. This tragic accident changed his whole life, as if from day to night. He wasn’t sure whether he would make it until the next day. It was inconceivable, the emotional and physical pain that he must go through as a quadriplegic.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.p15" pid="wUzzHd2S2EuJelq1XiZ-LA" hash="_vXvRQ">Even though he was in this condition in the University of Utah Medical Center, he was determined to graduate from law school. It was an almost impossible task, but good friends, true Samaritans, brought him notes and taped lectures from Provo. Oh, God bless these true Christians. He turned pages by a mouthstick, and if his book flipped shut, he waited for a long time until someone came to help him.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.p16" pid="qgvHvn9KVUy4ekhjdJPFmg" hash="lvEqRw">Finally, he graduated from law school, passed the Utah bar exam, and became a licensed attorney. While he was studying, exercising, and maintaining doctor’s contact to gain strength, his wife took his two sons and divorced him. This was the most “sorrowful and very heavy” period of his life. (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/26.37" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 26:37</a>.) But he never complained and even blessed the leaving loved ones. In his heart he prayed, “Thy will be done, O Lord!” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/26.42" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 26:42</a>.) It was his own Garden of Gethsemane, and he took his own cup and drank it as his blessing.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.p17" pid="v5fl9Mht80SCwYoq5qIpyQ" hash="7Uqq5A">In the hymn “How Firm a Foundation” we sing these words:</p>
        <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.f2">
          <div class="stanza">
            <p class="line" pid="5_v9f9B2l0-1Qar9FVwY4g" hash="F_EMQg">
              <span class="emphasis">When through the deep waters I call thee to go,</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="SJiDhaJV3ESia8fDaCW8Fg" hash="RJLy9A">
              <span class="emphasis">The rivers of sorrow shall not thee o’erflow,</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="t3f3rShrmUmm-hjd0Mc4kw" hash="V9KBVA">
              <span class="emphasis">For I will be with thee, thy troubles to bless,</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="GFr3Vx_SQEWo8LXah6iLjA" hash="rZtGqQ">
              <span class="emphasis">And sanctify to thee thy deepest distress.</span>
            </p>
          </div>
        </div>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.p18" pid="vdJx7I920U2dhYgFoodoAQ" hash="JEe0kA">My friend Mick met a most beautiful lady, Cheryl. They married and now the greatest joy has come to their lives. His wife is expecting a baby. It is a miracle. The Lord said, “I will be with thee, thy troubles to bless.” Last Friday, they were sealed in the temple for time and for all eternity. It was my privilege to perform the ceremony for this beautiful couple.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.p19" pid="WZlni2imqky-zZFOYg9G1w" hash="cgdq0Q">His stake president, President Banks, described him as “a most humble person with strong faith,” and his secretary said of him, “Time has always been important to him. A span of a few brief seconds means the difference. He has no wasted time. He has accomplished more than ever.”</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.t4">
        <h3 class="title" pid="a1TeGOrRt0m-Ftj9za-10A" hash="FIfARw">The Power to Love</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.p20" pid="iPSWsv_OZ0uGVypDh6pw7A" hash="YAfOIg">The Lord said, “The power is in us.” (See <a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/58.28" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 58:28</a>.) You and I have that power, the greatest power, the power of love. We can feel the Lord’s love if we but listen. Our kindly Heavenly Father gave us—</p>
        <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.f3">
          <div class="stanza">
            <p class="line" pid="LYn_cgUA6UqBwzc9P-kSiA" hash="FIfARw1">
              <span class="emphasis">The power to love!</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="4dm49ZbzfUiAxaEE_DXtug" hash="eIptPA">
              <span class="emphasis">The power to think!</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="-KuCPVnjck-vnfiP98W9jg" hash="wEeqaA">
              <span class="emphasis">The power to have faith!</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="D1OIIMJ-_U2XkZuqFr_OmQ" hash="XLQnDg">
              <span class="emphasis">The power to pray!</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="1jSKhPRCBEKzVty5J27Tfw" hash="Rk7i0w">
              <span class="emphasis">The power to create!</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="nKKUPFEu702LJ-3MBL4B3g" hash="2PijFA">
              <span class="emphasis">The power to see!</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="o0dCjQwml02uKzgzT2qcdw" hash="v7XIlw">
              <span class="emphasis">The power to feel!</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="DH5SrOfLc0ipb_28cZTrxQ" hash="5ofbZg">
              <span class="emphasis">The power to touch!</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="axdwaS_uZE6NN-IesBJ1hw" hash="lRI0Zg">
              <span class="emphasis">The power to speak!</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="2cAoK-YwCEufZ_CfymhNbQ" hash="Z6G1Uw">
              <span class="emphasis">The power to care!</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="wr7jrMqR9EWqwfnXkdBKrg" hash="VBt1XQ">
              <span class="emphasis">The power to have concern!</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="0YhUkWBZCEGximH478l6rA" hash="p5Dx8Q">
              <span class="emphasis">The power to share!</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="DpHq1bZrUE-bgp8aM8oOiw" hash="xKy3pw">
              <span class="emphasis">The power to give!</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="TJALzfQoBU-0nq-YT7BM-w" hash="8MxSSw">
              <span class="emphasis">The power to thank!</span>
            </p>
          </div>
        </div>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.p21" pid="FVaSnrspek2-GQQPfnTI1w" hash="JtnJRA">Especially the power to love! Love is the greatest gift of God. Brothers and sisters, if you and I have this power, the power of love, we can walk with His Spirit, even through the “troubled waters.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.p22" pid="RRQEbBUIXUSf-98HgzvzCQ" hash="apg6Rg">Let us count our blessings:</p>
        <div class="poetry" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.f4">
          <div class="stanza">
            <p class="line" pid="oP9Uhv-4okawBhmT_X5Lug" hash="riyMVg">
              <span class="emphasis">When upon life’s billows you are tempest-tossed,</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="zLz65eiFaUaRaZp50B0cHw" hash="Bs6jZQ">
              <span class="emphasis">When you are discouraged, thinking all is lost,</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="8SlRFwNcU0-qTzm7thF1zQ" hash="aQVdlg">
              <span class="emphasis">Count your many blessings; name them one by one,</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="_koUCOrPXkCkVYLY4IBKyw" hash="657UGw">
              <span class="emphasis">And it will surprise you what the Lord has done.</span>
            </p>
          </div>
          <div class="stanza">
            <p class="line" pid="ovCFftxB802WgaL8WVDfgw" hash="KEHiAg1">
              <span class="emphasis">Count your blessings;</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="C1Ba5HAOnkGl8hGII3EKPQ" hash="IjaCUg">
              <span class="emphasis">Name them one by one.</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="jnPa74dkEEKNDD675NJTGw" hash="KEHiAg2">
              <span class="emphasis">Count your blessings;</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="2R6VWiAMkE2TQx4koMQagw" hash="MG_20w">
              <span class="emphasis">See what God hath done.</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="KsucwTJ_PEuRoNU6_dWzWw" hash="KEHiAg3">
              <span class="emphasis">Count your blessings;</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="TUHe90Dkok6lHMO0MfqC-Q" hash="IjaCUg1">
              <span class="emphasis">Name them one by one.</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="D_jpIGNrrUq6ZreCxwthYg" hash="2j0t1Q">
              <span class="emphasis">Count your many blessings;</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="_hmBQ15LKkyfX8T8FSXBJg" hash="MG_20w1">
              <span class="emphasis">See what God hath done.</span>
            </p>
          </div>
          <div class="stanza">
            <p class="line" pid="0IaL0adUY0CUlOV_IUYF4g" hash="3L_tPw">
              <span class="emphasis">Are you ever burdened with a load of care?</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="4u-sliYoQkyoUfTPKwaCqw" hash="_Fu1kQ">
              <span class="emphasis">Does the cross seem heavy you are called to bear?</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="v4diHqMNhUqPlo8dRnNslQ" hash="4inAHQ">
              <span class="emphasis">Count your many blessings; every doubt will fly,</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="NuDa647yaEmhixVGySz3VA" hash="fDoyZw">
              <span class="emphasis">And you will be singing as the days go by.</span>
            </p>
          </div>
          <div class="stanza">
            <p class="line" pid="Om5oHxf6X0Cwt4P1oQITUg" hash="MOzdJw">
              <span class="emphasis">So amid the conflict, whether great or small,</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="dQA6N9kKq0GxyupmQ_lWKg" hash="O_gM8w">
              <span class="emphasis">Do not be discouraged; God is over all.</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="Mjz_4WK0CkSHtdA0B9Rk5g" hash="5EdQKw">
              <span class="emphasis">Count your many blessings; angels will attend,</span>
            </p>
            <p class="line" pid="L5r1XWTUb0iea7nnBbyUEQ" hash="U6d-7Q">
              <span class="emphasis">Help and comfort give you to your journey’s end.</span>
            </p>
          </div>
        </div>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.p23" pid="pxHTmHdDe06GZrxFAJELqg" hash="QooLkQ">Let us not judge the Lord’s great wisdom with our small minds.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.t5">
        <h3 class="title" pid="8NMDXfIs-kGFfiG3X0TYmQ" hash="Byvl_Q">The Savior Is Extending His Loving Hands</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.p24" pid="epCQ8q0ERE-BAcoPsJFcRQ" hash="14mQAA">Are you unloved? Are you unhappy? Are you handicapped? Divorced? Are you paralyzed like my friend? Are you angry? Do you hate someone? Do you have bitterness toward someone? Are you a single mother because your husband just took off? Are you lonely because your husband passed away? The Savior said:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.p25" pid="K3BpX0zOFkqKXXTqlsMoOA" hash="MLNUqA">“Come unto me, all ye that labour and are heavy laden, and I will give you rest.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.p26" pid="BL7X3cVtWkiCwLIfHoDb5g" hash="NJrEVg">“Take my yoke upon you, and learn of me; for I am meek and lowly in heart; and ye shall find rest unto your souls.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.p27" pid="J158PIA_pEWpfKDScAMI8g" hash="lNKnWw">“For my yoke is easy, and my burden is light.” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/11.28-30" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 11:28–30</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.p28" pid="ZOvP5Ioau0y6AQtv2x-a2g" hash="LvlovA">I bear you my testimony that Jesus is the Christ, the Son of the Living God. He himself testified of his great, sacred mission when he appeared to the Nephites: “Arise and come forth unto me, that ye may thrust your hands into my side, and also that ye may feel the prints of the nails in my hands and in my feet, that ye may know that I am the God of Israel, and the God of the whole earth, and have been slain for the sins of the world.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/3-ne/11.14" class="scriptureRef">3 Ne. 11:14</a>.)</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings.p29" pid="PggAClDb50KR-wMSh3t5Tg" hash="CbF0Nw">I know that he lives; I know that he loves us; and I bear you my witness in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1984/04/count-your-blessings</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1984-general-conference/1984-04-5030-elder-yoshihiko-kikuchi-64k-eng.mp3" length="6335731" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 1984 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daughter of God</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god?lang=eng</link>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters, I bring greetings from the Saints and missionaries in the beautiful islands of Hawaii. I say to you, aloha!</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_03226_000_030" doc-version="2" hash="UCWNIw">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="w9XerQr3IEmyP9DFrvSYIA" hash="_wsZ2w">Daughter of God</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="LhtuXNdINUi3ksseSN7jPQ" hash="R_EqkQ">Elder Yoshihiko Kikuchi</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2410.jpg" alt="Elder Yoshihiko Kikuchi" pid="9N2XPuOeVEyo_uCRHG734Q" hash="n1QlnQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.p1" pid="BtsK-EgAIUa9Eix8leJg1w" hash="h0W3Tw">My dear brothers and sisters, I bring greetings from the Saints and missionaries in the beautiful islands of Hawaii. I say to you, aloha!</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.p2" pid="kigHXfqphUmjmMBEDi1LVg" hash="q9YOeA">Today, I would like to ask a question: My dear brothers, are we treating our wives as daughters of God? Are <span class="emphasis">you</span> treating <span class="emphasis">your</span> wife as a daughter of God?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.p3" pid="hN0qJJO7jU6IwbZniL1zgg" hash="gSTJew">
        <span class="emphasis">A daughter of God.</span> The words have a special feeling. Even as you say them, you feel a reverence. You may say, “Oh, Brother Kikuchi, of course I treat her as a daughter of God!” But my next question is, How <span class="emphasis">much</span> do you treat and honor her as a daughter of God? Let’s stop and think of your lovely companion. She was entrusted to you by Heavenly Father as a special daughter of God.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.p4" pid="UM2PfoB2ZU2LcNYSsgjf5A" hash="__XUgw">I believe that in this lifetime, the closest person or neighbor that you can have in your life is your sweet wife. She is your sweetheart! She is your love! She is your best friend! She is your lover! And she is a daughter of God!</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="XmBVOQoH2kKAbvCgAh-jlA" hash="ZgNcBg">Love Thy Wife</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.p5" pid="_Zig69NyJk6QLF41IHBl9A" hash="B5cWAQ">The Lord’s teaching to the lawyer was very clear:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.p6" pid="vYCGDCT080-nOImkxyiAUA" hash="aZeI9w">“Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy mind.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.p7" pid="eNZ4VND-m0-exUdE0dp1zQ" hash="pLnaTg">“This is the first and great commandment.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.p8" pid="ud4d8yAo8U-yoli60ubdOA" hash="gSeAnA">“And the second is <span class="emphasis">like unto it,</span> thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/matt/22.37-39" class="scriptureRef">Matt. 22:37–39</a>; italics added).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.p9" pid="KTOuEu5LOkivQHLfxaRDOA" hash="67cm4A">Yesterday, our beloved prophet, President Ezra Taft Benson, said that above everything we do in our lives, we must place the first commandment first—“Thou shalt love the Lord thy God.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.p10" pid="3A9KJ06q1UGHhV3smmAOdA" hash="8N_Z6A">The second is also like the first. The Lord said:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.p11" pid="pkTrw3yExE2EH34uXlkrAg" hash="L0PXQQ">“Love thy neighbour as thyself.” Brothers, among all the children of our Father in Heaven, don’t you think your wife is the closest neighbor that you can have?</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.p12" pid="qqxq9p3qUkS6zd6GBVJb9Q" hash="PxJgPg">The Lord said, “Thou shalt love thy wife with all thy heart” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/42.22" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 42:22</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.p13" pid="9ADUZMz4O0av9xLjToKBvw" hash="8DU-Cw">Truly, “marriage is ordained of God” (<a href="/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/49.15" class="scriptureRef">D&amp;C 49:15</a>). “Marriage is honorable in all” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/heb/13.4" class="scriptureRef">Heb. 13:4</a>).</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="50TQOJ-W_E2OYi8_hlLdaA" hash="0ASLdg">Abraham’s Commitment</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.p14" pid="X0gnciT4E0iriV5KtPntxg" hash="WwCU5g">When the Lord told Abraham to offer his only son, Isaac, on Mt. Moriah, Abraham took Isaac, two servants, and a donkey and built an altar (see <a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/22.2-3" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 22:2–3</a>). On the way, Isaac asked, “Where is the lamb for a burnt offering?” Though Father Abraham knew that Isaac was the one, he said, “My son, God will provide” (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/22.7-8" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 22:7–8</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.p15" pid="yjmZnumozEywc896-RiuUg" hash="YvBMuw">When the time came, Abraham was willing to offer Isaac, and Isaac did not run away (<a href="/scriptures/ot/gen/22.9-11" class="scriptureRef">Gen. 22:9–11</a>). Brothers and sisters, in our marriages, we need both the commitment of Abraham and also the spirit of Isaac.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.t4">
        <h3 class="title" pid="kaHjXaxIzEuz15Y0zt1fnQ" hash="gGISZw">Behold Thy Mother</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.p16" pid="aewTSemfKkmLMtGCsQFD9g" hash="6rT3aQ">At the time of his unendurable agony, the Savior looked down on his mother, Mary, and introduced John to her, saying, “Woman, behold thy son!” And to John he said, “Behold thy mother!” The scripture records that John “took her unto his own home” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/john/19.26-27" class="scriptureRef">John 19:26–27</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.p17" pid="gj1XVLyeeEONLxRUK1bi9A" hash="HhJGUw">Are we worthy to be entrusted by the Lord to take care of one of our Heavenly Father’s daughters?</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.p18" pid="n16ChF10jEmz8p2qAgStoA" hash="dKxqBw">The Savior must have a special feeling toward the women of the world, because the first person that saw the resurrected Lord was a woman, Mary Magdalene. Oh, how special that was! (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/john/20.title" class="scriptureRef">John 20</a>).</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.t5">
        <h3 class="title" pid="ZOKC_QdMrECIetSqzfpSBw" hash="CGuAUQ">Jonathon H. Napela</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.p19" pid="qwr8IcnMW06fG1T6kWDCCA" hash="yU5gEw">May I share today a story about a person who lived in such a way, <span class="emphasis">in an eternal,</span> loving companionship in Hawaii.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.p20" pid="rVXOxCACiUCy1_CELZWY2A" hash="3w1vCw">In 1850, Brigham Young sent ten missionaries to the Hawaiian Islands. Without understanding the language and culture, the missionaries found the work extremely difficult. Eventually they became discouraged, including the mission president. They became so discouraged that five of the ten left to go home. The youngest of the remaining missionaries, Elder George Q. Cannon, was determined to stay. He went to the Lord in prayer. The Lord inspired him to go to Lahaina on Maui. He did so.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.p21" pid="e9nb-4QxskuxZlIq6U1iwQ" hash="KP3D5Q">As he approached this town, two ladies went screaming into a nearby house and brought out a local gentleman. The previous night, this man had had a dream that a messenger of God was coming to his town and that he must feed him. Elder Cannon was invited to stay and preach in the home of this man, Jonathon H. Napela, who was a very well-educated man and the magistrate of that district (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/10.4" class="scriptureRef">Alma 10:4</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.p22" pid="PqdBKFrdwkWerTbdNA5I5A" hash="1F4lUQ">Subsequently, Elder Cannon and Jonathon Napela became very close friends, like Alma and Amulek in the Book of Mormon (see <a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/10.title" class="scriptureRef">Alma 10–15</a>). Because of the guiding hand of God and Brother Napela’s great help, along with the hospitality and kindness of the Hawaiian Saints, the missionary work began to excel in Hawaii, and the foundation was laid.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.t6">
        <h3 class="title" pid="ux1WEjc7w06Imb2GbIVUAw" hash="fdN6Rw">His Great and Deep Love</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.p23" pid="QxxUGSZOxUOVO1YWXEuABw" hash="vr-9gw">Many years later, in 1873, Kitty, the wife of this great man, Jonathon Napela, contracted leprosy. She was a beautiful and noble woman in the early days of the Church in Hawaii. Today modern medical knowledge has advanced so that this disease is no longer fatal, but at that time, there was no cure for this dreadful disease. In order to prevent the spreading of this disease, once you contracted it you were forced to live on one of the seashores in the leper colony on Molokai. The lepers were taken there by boat. The sailors were so afraid of this disease that they pushed the patients into the sea, forcing them to swim to shore.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.p24" pid="scGDzVpig0S8jsu3eBS4DA" hash="MqfCPw">Because his wife had to go to Kalaupapa, the leper colony, Jonathon, too, wanted to go. He took her hand and they went there together. Why would he do this? Because he loved her so much! He knew that life is eternal and love is eternal, even through days of “sickness and health.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.p25" pid="o3Mq8-w-tE-hZxKfkR7fAA" hash="x9HShA">Oh, how much do I love my wife? Oh, do I love her as a daughter of God, as Jonathon loved his wife? Would I be willing to go to a place like that to be with her? Would you be willing to demonstrate your pure love like Jonathon? Brethren, are we honoring our companions? Are we caring? Are we thoughtful? We must be, because God has joined us together (see <a href="/scriptures/nt/mark/10.9" class="scriptureRef">Mark 10:9</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.p26" pid="qTB9EFw-oECIzjdiobLjAA" hash="uFkEAA">History records that this valiant and giant man of God worked in the leper colony and fought to obtain government assistance for the lepers to have a more comfortable place to live. He was a giant in the pure love of Christ for his own people. Oh, I can almost hear the words of Paul to the Corinthians when he said, “Though I speak with the tongues of men and of angels, and have not charity, I am become as sounding brass, or a tinkling cymbal” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/1-cor/13.1" class="scriptureRef">1 Cor. 13:1</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.p27" pid="wqhe750GzEOP6Bez9wLCRA" hash="cCDaVQ">This good brother later contracted that same disease and died even before his wife passed away. She followed him two years later. Husbands, do you love your wife as a daughter of God? Oh, “husbands, love your wives” as daughters of God, “even as Christ also loved the church and gave himself for it” (<a href="/scriptures/nt/eph/5.25" class="scriptureRef">Eph. 5:25</a>).</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god.p28" pid="hq30zU2odkWRgiDeMr2Rsg" hash="eQAJcw">I know that God lives! This is his church. I know that the Savior lives! I know that Joseph Smith was a prophet of God, who restored this church. I know that our beloved prophet, even President Ezra Taft Benson, is the living oracle of God and an example to us. The Book of Mormon is true. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1988/04/daughter-of-god</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1988-general-conference/1988-04-5040-elder-yoshihiko-kikuchi-64k-eng.mp3" length="5093350" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 1988 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“The Pure Love of God”</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/1992/04/the-pure-love-of-god?lang=eng</link>
      <description>Brothers and sisters, my wife and I learned so many faith-promoting missionary stories about Elders George Q. Cannon and Joseph F. Smith, and many other missionaries’ wonderful spiritual experiences while we were serving in Hawaii. (See George Q. Can</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-pure-love-of-god" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_92905_000_006" doc-version="2" hash="lqqD7A">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-pure-love-of-god.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="qnzlHwNMwkCXNeHwgSWCWw" hash="CtZ7dw">“The Pure Love of God”</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="TIUAL9P1qkKl4LkevIhyrw" hash="6jZZYA">Yoshihiko Kikuchi</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-pure-love-of-god.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-2410.jpg" alt="Elder Yoshihiko Kikuchi" pid="Mc5JUgAslUSXrgD03Gsd6w" hash="n1QlnQ" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-pure-love-of-god.p1" pid="ZNL22mMI-UqOmIB7K-I2Gg" hash="ywUu4Q">Brothers and sisters, my wife and I learned so many faith-promoting missionary stories about Elders George Q. Cannon and Joseph F. Smith, and many other missionaries’ wonderful spiritual experiences while we were serving in Hawaii. (See George Q. Cannon, <span class="emphasis">My First Mission, </span>2d ed., Salt Lake City: Juvenile Instructor Office, 1882; and Joseph Fielding Smith, <span class="emphasis">Life of Joseph F. Smith, </span>Salt Lake City: Deseret News Press, 1938.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-pure-love-of-god.p2" pid="cYSvoItz7EaesfglWEDXww" hash="5ybkpw">I feel so strongly that I should share with you the missionary experiences of Elder Joseph F. Smith. He was sent by the Brethren as a missionary when he was fifteen years of age. At the age of five he had lost his father, and at fourteen he had lost his mother. The record shows that he labored in Maui and in Kohala on the Big Island. Then he was transferred to the island of Molokai as the presiding elder when he was sixteen years old. Every day he and his companion, Elder Thomas A. Dowell, visited the several small branches, proselyting, healing the sick, and casting out evil spirits. With the Saints, they read the scriptures and the beautiful teachings of the Savior, and retold the story of the Restoration. Many members were indifferent and had an apathetic attitude because of false reports about the Church and the Prophet Joseph Smith.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-pure-love-of-god.p3" pid="5MPkjdaZRUG3MvYlwMmMUA" hash="s1_p2g">The two companions traveled from the east to the west on Molokai. Their food was scarce, and they traveled about thirty miles every day under the hot sun, without water. One day, Elder Smith’s companion almost didn’t make it. That day, they finally reached the home of Mr. and Mrs. Myers, a German family. This couple treated them kindly and so lovingly and gave them food and lodging for several days. Not only that, but Mr. Myers furnished Elder Smith with a good riding horse so he could visit several branches. Elders Smith and Dowell were guided by the Spirit every day. They worked hard and brought converts, as well as bringing so many back into activity.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-pure-love-of-god.p4" pid="qXF3LAja6USNrM-F7MSJ9g" hash="OHpNRw">One day Elder Smith was taken desperately ill with a raging fever. He was given a priesthood blessing, but he remained ill. He almost passed away. His condition was very critical on many occasions. For the next three months, he was tenderly cared for by a native brother and his wife. This couple did everything possible to save the young missionary’s life and gave him the best they had through tender fatherly and motherly love, even fasting and praying for many days. This young missionary never forgot a kindness and never forsook a friend. He always treated and honored this wonderful Hawaiian lady, Ma Manuhii, as his own Hawaiian mother.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-pure-love-of-god.p5" pid="_KsKC-FhykanoWarEdyWmQ" hash="bumyIw">Many years later this boy again visited the Islands in the company of a member of the Presiding Bishopric, Bishop Charles W. Nibley, who later became a member of the First Presidency. As they landed in the harbor at Honolulu, many native Saints greeted them. They brought lots of leis and all kinds of beautiful native flowers. Both of them were loaded with leis upon leis. The young man, who was now an old man, had more than anyone else. A great Hawaiian band was playing a welcome to them, and even played Mormon music.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-pure-love-of-god.p6" pid="VR-MMdwVSEuYtir8nVygmA" hash="GMAKvA">Then Bishop Nibley explained in his journal one touching little incident:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-pure-love-of-god.p7" pid="eP7L8KQ5UU65lvVsJ_Qnrg" hash="EcwuxA">“It was a beautiful sight to see the deep-seated love, the even tearful affection, that these people had for him. In the midst of it all I noticed a poor, old blind woman tottering under the weight of about ninety years, being led in. She had a few choice bananas in her hand. It was her all—her offering. She was calling, ‘Iosepa, Iosepa!’ [means ‘Joseph, Joseph!’] Instantly, [when] he saw her, he ran to her and clasped her in his arms, hugged her, and kissed her over and over again, patting her on the head saying, ‘Mama, Mama, my dear old Mama!’ And with tears streaming down his cheeks he turned to me and said, ‘Charley, she nursed me when I was a boy, sick and without anyone to care for me. She took me in and was a mother to me!’”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-pure-love-of-god.p8" pid="ilRRdAajuU66HF57ZhBrdg" hash="TF93Bg">Bishop Nibley continued:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-pure-love-of-god.p9" pid="pfdKC_5kekuYWu3e0gFHYw" hash="iI9fTA">“O, it was touching—it was pathetic. It was beautiful to see the great, noble soul in loving, tender remembrance of kindness extended to him more than fifty years before; and the poor old soul who had brought her loving offering, a few bananas—it was all she had—to put into the hand of her loved Iosepa.” (<span class="emphasis">Life of Joseph F. Smith, </span>pp. 185–86.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-pure-love-of-god.p10" pid="zVJ9oQllwEGKENGQQ0cNFw" hash="N7AS5Q">Brothers and sisters, this Iosepa was President Joseph F. Smith, sixth President of the Church. What can we learn from this story? Sister Ma Manuhii had no idea that this little sixteen-year-old boy would someday be President of the Church. She didn’t expect anything from him. She helped him because she loved the Lord’s missionary with the pure love of God. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.47" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:47</a>.) This Hawaiian couple honored, respected, loved, and took care of the missionaries as the Lord’s messengers because they had the pure love of God. That respect and reverence remained with her until she died.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-pure-love-of-god.p11" pid="EAuxNMZ8Jk-gkQJ4qzgxPw" hash="sFLMTQ">Elder Smith was seasoned and matured by the Lord in the mission field, and his love, developed and cultivated by this beautiful Hawaiian mother, never left his heart. “With tears streaming down his cheeks … ‘Charley, she nursed me when I was a boy, sick and without anyone to care for me. She took me in and was a mother to me!’”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-pure-love-of-god.p12" pid="JOcln7t9nEKeU8cxr2x2OA" hash="2WrGtQ">Brothers and sisters, this type of love, kindness, and thoughtfulness must—MUST—exist in our missionary and reactivation work. This “love of God” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/11.22,25" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 11:22, 25</a>) is the spirit of missionary work, and the spirit of reactivation. This “love of God” is the spirit of conversion. This “love of God” is the spirit of nurturing. “It is the most desirable above all things” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/11.22" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 11:22</a>), and it is “the most joyous to the soul” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/11.23" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 11:23</a>). Brothers and sisters, let’s show our noble example like this beautiful Hawaiian mother, not only by feeding the missionaries, but by bringing this love as we take missionaries to part-member families, less-active members or nonmembers within the framework of the home teaching and visiting teaching programs. These people will be touched by this love. When Nephi saw the Savior, he exclaimed, “Yea, it is the love of God, which sheddeth itself abroad in the hearts of the children of men.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/11.22" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 11:22</a>.) With this love, when you and I work with full-time missionaries, combining our efforts, we can bring many converts and reactivated members to the temple. Your example will teach the missionaries. When they return to their wards and stakes, they will emulate your example.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-pure-love-of-god.p13" pid="5ZKrqn30Wk6a4FLWSSYnzg" hash="837JJw">Missionaries, you must be so <span class="emphasis">clean, pure, </span>and <span class="emphasis">diligent. </span>Obey and observe all the mission rules “with exactness.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/57.21" class="scriptureRef">Alma 57:21</a>.) Like Joseph F. Smith, be <span class="emphasis">studious </span>in the scriptures. (See <a href="/scriptures/bofm/1-ne/11.25" class="scriptureRef">1 Ne. 11:25</a>.) Exercise your “exceeding faith,” do “not doubt.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/57.26" class="scriptureRef">Alma 57:26</a>.) Put your “trust in God.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/alma/57.27" class="scriptureRef">Alma 57:27</a>.) Above all, you must cultivate the real missionary quality, “charity … the pure love of Christ.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.47" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:47</a>.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-pure-love-of-god.p14" pid="ybC2oHIn70OTSUKoXjCdJw" hash="LMCB5w">I testify to you that as Moroni promised us, when we “pray unto the Father with all <span class="emphasis">the energy of heart,</span>” we “may be <span class="emphasis">filled with this love, </span>which he hath bestowed upon all who are true followers of his Son, Jesus Christ.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/moro/7.48" class="scriptureRef">Moro. 7:48</a>; italics added.) When we work together—missionaries, leaders, and members—the Lord will bless us as he did Nephi and Lehi, the sons of Helaman.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-pure-love-of-god.p15" pid="F33LklcCGE-e78iK5QPOFg" hash="08tnTw">The scripture explains, “There was exceedingly great prosperity in the church … there were thousands who did join … and were baptized unto repentance. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-pure-love-of-god.p16" pid="CRAly01lyU6RqP4nC4tYsQ" hash="kXkU1w">“And … the work of the Lord did prosper unto the baptizing and uniting [to me, reactivating] to the church of God, many souls, yea, even tens of thousands. …</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-pure-love-of-god.p17" pid="0HxDpIvMZUa4la_dVloR_A" hash="Lc_AXw">“The Lord is merciful unto <span class="emphasis">all who will, in the sincerity of their hearts, call upon his holy name. …</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-pure-love-of-god.p18" pid="2yLvWctF9UGEdl0uJLg9Vg" hash="BSGYNg">“The gate of heaven [will be] open unto all, even to those who will believe on the name of Jesus Christ, who is the Son of God.” (<a href="/scriptures/bofm/hel/3.24,26-28" class="scriptureRef">Hel. 3:24, 26–28</a>; italics added.)</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/1992/04/the-pure-love-of-god.p19" pid="-Sy75opTckWWyysKacYTVw" hash="kz_kJw">Brothers and sisters, I humbly testify to you that God lives. Jesus is the Christ. He loves us. As we emulate his love, we can bring wonderful brothers and sisters back into this fold. This is his Church. President Benson is his prophet. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/1992/04/the-pure-love-of-god</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-1992-general-conference/1992-04-1040-elder-yoshihiko-kikuchi-64k-eng.mp3" length="5320619" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 1992 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heavenly Father Has a Special Plan</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan?lang=eng</link>
      <description>I know that your Heavenly Father has a special plan for you and your family to return to live with Him. Let’s go home.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD10033256_000_032" doc-version="2" hash="HtUtDQ">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="n0ywQKgJEE-3AfpX9KlMSw" hash="cc0GIg">Heavenly Father Has a Special Plan</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="F7h8IHEJKEWlsRRqAzyywQ" hash="R_EqkQ">Elder Yoshihiko Kikuchi</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="4uy4lN82h0aFblUQG29NpA" hash="TmwbzA">I know that your Heavenly Father has a special plan for you and your family to return to live with Him. Let’s go home.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.t1">
      <img src="ensignlp.nfo-o-1765.jpg" alt="Elder Yoshihiko Kikuchi" pid="9TYm8qFnhk-3liYMUdA83w" hash="4vDwOA" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p1" pid="Mch2hLb-tkCUA_CeJfiB9w" hash="gzVVrA">A few years ago, right before Christmas, I had a stake conference assignment in California. On the flight back to Utah, I decided to take a short nap. My seat was C, near the aisle. Just before the cabin door closed, a beautiful lady in her mid-70s stood beside me and said, “May I have my seat?” I said, “Yes, ma’am.” That was the end of my nap. She loved to talk.</p>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.t2">
        <h3 class="title" pid="PWrJY9smhUaSf3n9sE4v5w" hash="FbuKaw">You Have a Loving and Kind Heavenly Father</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p2" pid="GDpWLF3W90ymS-eURXrIqA" hash="Wdqztg">She said, “I don’t know why I should have to fly to a cold place like Utah at Christmastime to visit my grandchildren. I hate to leave sunny California.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p3" pid="9vr0DHCaS0KpO_xgRdtsTQ" hash="5Pcs5g">She went on to say, “Besides, there are strange and weird people in Utah. They call themselves ‘Mormons.’ My daughter married one of them.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p4" pid="bLrCfd6sJUGnkJkmLX775g" hash="lsxXRQ">I said, “I am sorry, but before you go any further, I should tell you that I am one of them.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p5" pid="4WXPqmAC6UGbE_srnyQMUQ" hash="IPaxsA">Then she said, “I am sorry—I didn’t mean that.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p6" pid="2l1-OcSkbkG_AVvg-lX7Sg" hash="ax_mPg">I said, “Oh, you really meant that, didn’t you?”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p7" pid="bJ5rWoOqE06bOmCxmWfFow" hash="FSq6WA">Our conversation went on until we were above Provo. We knew we would soon be landing in Salt Lake.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p8" pid="HN-w90n4eUyS6cHinbqEkg" hash="x6uDqA">“Patti”—that’s her name—“you have been talking for most of the flight. I feel like I have known you from the pre-earth life. Before we land in Salt Lake City, I’d like to ask you a few questions if I may.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p9" pid="xkhIlfZf00qNlnYhRnxaEA" hash="-xUNcg">I asked her sincerely,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> “Patti, your deceased husband—do you know you can see him again?”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p10" pid="UoDoGpazHEq0YiBFWMNivg" hash="sH28uw">She said, “Oh, is that possible?”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p11" pid="Z46FOHXW5kuQ68b9EEVaJQ" hash="ONbk-A">“Do you know your deceased son, Matt, who died as a baby—you will see him also in the future?”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p12" pid="yWAjujcJXUeC2-pDynld6A" hash="TzAeXw">Her eyes became moist, and her voice was shaking. The Spirit of the Lord touched her. I sensed she had missed them so much.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p13" pid="kjqYg6-A_0KeGZTTqwcCKQ" hash="JyXOPg">Then I prayerfully asked her, “Patti, do you know you have a loving and kind Heavenly Father, who loves you so dearly?”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p14" pid="_TwdnJmcckylTEktD_mekQ" hash="BYRzNw">She said, “Do I?”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p15" pid="aw_xOWwa_k-GlZ6eVX7_cw" hash="ATnCCQ">“Patti, do you know your Heavenly Father has a special plan for you and that your family can be forever?”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p16" pid="n51eJLsWck6a5RW-_aKeqw" hash="Lww9Hw">“Can we?” she replied.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p17" pid="90S_HNmUokiCA97pcf2MbA" hash="R9Rghg">“Have you ever heard the plan before?”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p18" pid="_sL1m-E8ukCgxN__7SEkKQ" hash="jqK9Vw">She said, “No.”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p19" pid="VVa3xzSEoEK02wU-ODQkIg" hash="s_WwmA">Very sincerely I asked her, “Would you like to know about it?”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p20" pid="DlnovMOGj0SQWcw-KXRAuA" hash="GLs6iw">“Yes, I would,” she responded.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p21" pid="MbYNA_T_nU6ASFkE4ToYjw" hash="H-pvCQ">The Spirit of the Lord touched her deeply. And the Lord promises us, “For mine elect hear my voice and harden not their hearts.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p22" pid="AXg7t9yBQE6FsQvWV-NXyw" hash="-oYkQg">He also said: “I am the good shepherd, and know my sheep. … My sheep hear my voice, and I know them, and they follow me.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.t3">
        <h3 class="title" pid="Sb4X_QCCPk2VQBG_vKXvkg" hash="pMFRgg">“It Is the Love of God”</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p23" pid="Xz4svnNimEa5YUM4cClcOQ" hash="eceNDA">Nephi desired to see father Lehi’s dream—the tree of life<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span>—and he did. Then Nephi also saw the beautiful baby Jesus.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span> And the angel asked, “Knowest thou the meaning of the tree which thy father saw?”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p24" pid="vIk5Dq23gEGRGqU-Ap94YA" hash="uc-eZw">Nephi replied, “Yea, it is the love of God, which sheddeth itself abroad in the hearts of the children of men; wherefore, it is the most desirable above all things.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p25" pid="Md9kVI_snEi112BY-74Sgw" hash="HaNxbQ">Before we came to this earth, our Heavenly Father gently and peacefully placed in our bosoms “the love of God.” In Heavenly Father’s eyes, you are a very special child. My friend Patti has the spark of divinity in her soul. When Patti heard the word of Heavenly Father, she was touched deeply and she responded to His voice.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p26" pid="Nubo9lhw7k6amgrDz5bT5Q" hash="EIXb-g">We were total strangers, but the Lord placed one of His precious daughters quietly next to me. I was praying earnestly, that the Spirit of the Lord would touch her and speak to her.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p27" pid="ZrK7EeR5eEiuMnGMHKjxEA" hash="gJT0Qw">How can you and I share the beautiful message of the Lord Jesus Christ?</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p28" pid="o3M0cgTpDk2w2D4UiI2Kdw" hash="UQvtBw">
          <span class="emphasis">First, cultivate an awareness; bring others to a knowledge.</span> President Gordon B. Hinckley teaches us: “Let there be cultivated an awareness in every member’s heart of his [or her] own potential for bringing others to a knowledge of the truth. … Let him pray with great earnestness about it. Let each member pray.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p29" pid="TibbrQ27P0SsuKeENXDrcA" hash="l4LDIA">President Hinckley quotes the testimony of Alma:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p30" pid="6e3AAQjCb0WeK5cFcY0Bjg" hash="qkPoaA">“O Lord, wilt thou grant unto us that we may have success in bringing them again unto thee . …</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p31" pid="pNTaWyS-00SeKrWPJseEfg" hash="9AOpOg">“Behold, O Lord, their souls are precious; … give unto us, O Lord, power and wisdom that we may bring these, our brethren, … unto thee.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p32" pid="xx1fhn6bM0mT7ohNhQUi4w" hash="iymyhg">In the LDS Bible Dictionary it states, “The object of prayer is not to change the will of God, but to secure for ourselves and for others blessings that God is already willing to grant, but that are made conditional on our asking for them.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p33" pid="Vr5qXR4p9kSPga0YJDtFOw" hash="A0ZWVA">
          <span class="emphasis">Second, a good example is our best tool.</span> President Hinckley taught us, “The most effective tract we will carry will be the goodness of our own lives.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_12">12</span> As we live the gospel, we will be like a lighthouse on a hilltop,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_13">13</span> “the light” and “the salt of the earth.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_14">14</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p34" pid="yJ-r6TwFRUmPcN3sOcwrOQ" hash="Ub2hUA">We can partake of “the love of God,” “the tree of life,” and drink from “the fountain of living waters”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_15">15</span> daily by communing with our Holy Father, immersing ourselves in the scriptures, and meditation. Then the Lord will bless us to be more sensitive to speak to those souls which He has prepared for us.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p35" pid="lk4cyziI3Ey_qhDZSAjxmQ" hash="a9xb_w">
          <span class="emphasis">Third, act at a time when you feel the Spirit.</span> Elder M. Russell Ballard taught us: “The key to success in bringing souls unto Christ is to act at a time when you feel the Spirit and you sense that your friend does also. … Through our faith, our trust in the Lord, and our good works, we can bring many souls unto the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_16">16</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p36" pid="lZH8Fc43WUWnpvGKSnu8XA" hash="86OZXg">As we seek and pray in faith,<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_17">17</span> the Lord will guide us, and His elect will soon embrace<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_18">18</span> “the glad tidings of great joy,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_19">19</span> to partake of the eternal and “infinite atonement”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_20">20</span> of the Lord Jesus Christ.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.t4">
        <h3 class="title" pid="cIjAI1XLhEm9GkmGvPYMIQ" hash="tk-btw">Found the Savior</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p37" pid="mrKn4uOK9U-lxSPO5P92Yw" hash="_OHCDQ">The missionaries taught Patti. Three weeks later, while she was staying in Utah, Patti called me: “Brother Kikuchi, this is Patti. I am going to be baptized. Would you come to my baptism services?”</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p38" pid="TYEBmxnL0UWFBnBEc0lcSw" hash="3uNybg">My wife and I went to her baptism. Many members were kindly fellowshipping her. Oh, I shall never forget her joyful countenance as she came out of the water!</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p39" pid="drqqmhcHS0OavxsnyCc6bg" hash="PiyWbw">I shall never forget her sweet tears at the sacred altar in the Salt Lake Temple a year later. I remember her peaceful and celestial glow when she was sealed to her deceased husband and son and living daughter who had become a member of the Church. She now knows her family is forever in the Lord. My friend Patti Louise Donaldson found the Lord Jesus Christ. Now she lives in Utah.</p>
      </div>
      <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.t5">
        <h3 class="title" pid="cAC9k660nUirJEEu7VFYoQ" hash="RrsbvQ">I’ll Draw Near unto You</h3>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p40" pid="ZfpKN8v-KEqANNw42iWUDw" hash="Ww-30Q">My dear friends who are within the sound of my voice, you are a son or daughter of Heavenly Father. You were once in His holy presence. I know that your Heavenly Father has a special plan for you and your family to return to live with Him. Let’s go home. Let us prepare to go home to our Heavenly Father’s place.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p41" pid="9mb8wVoEjUu9BlIRVvMa-A" hash="iPAK8w">We want to share with you your Heavenly Father’s love. You will find the love of God, which is “the most joyous”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_21">21</span> to your soul.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p42" pid="FiYrS5ZCLkqG23f26lYWRg" hash="-N06RA">My dear brothers and sisters, I testify to you that Heavenly Father sent His Only Begotten Son and that Jesus Christ died for you and me. He said:</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p43" pid="gnJfamDS-0-en_0IYMvLag" hash="KOt8fg">“How sore you know not, how exquisite you know not, yea, how hard to bear you know not.</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p44" pid="hzLKoo-QaEusEssFQ28rCw" hash="lTETmA">“For behold, I, God, have suffered these things for all, that they might not suffer if they would repent; …</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p45" pid="ZyKw1zIsxU-KSF--ZPUzWg" hash="UYmTrQ">“Which suffering caused myself, even God, the greatest of all, to tremble because of pain, and to bleed at every pore, and to suffer both body and spirit—and would that I might not drink the bitter cup, and shrink—</p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p46" pid="kAhKT7ZqqUeVODNQ-ofIyg" hash="bt26Wg">“Nevertheless, glory be to the Father, and I partook and finished my preparations unto the children of men.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_22">22</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p47" pid="yYuq90MAt0-OL6h1MDf5cg" hash="KJPWAA">He loves you. He knows you. He lives. In 1820 Heavenly Father and His Son, Jesus, came to the boy Joseph and established His kingdom so that we may be able to go home. By now, can you hear “the voice of the good shepherd”?<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_23">23</span> Your Savior is calling you. Come, come and partake of His love. He invites you, “Ye shall call upon me while I am near,” then He promises, “Draw near unto me and I will draw near unto you.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_24">24</span></p>
        <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan.p48" pid="rz5RHYZ2IUqUPhq2IJyNtQ" hash="txa2fg">I know that He lives. I know that President Hinckley is our prophet. In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2000/04/heavenly-father-has-a-special-plan</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2000-general-conference/2000-04-5030-elder-yoshihiko-kikuchi-64k-eng.mp3" length="5169930" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2000 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will a Man Rob God?</title>
      <link>http://www.lds.org/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god?lang=eng</link>
      <description>When you and I pay honest, true tithes to the Lord, the Lord will open the windows of heaven.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div type="article" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god" schema-version="1" doc-id="general-conference_PD00008333_000_037" doc-version="2" hash="JL47Bg">
  
  <div class="heading" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god.head">
    <h1 class="title" pid="ldjrkI1RdECA13N_Hk1sAw" hash="uSdI1g">Will a Man Rob God?</h1>
    <p class="authorName" pid="oLhNrb8Ct0S7AZhS8YpS_A" hash="R_EqkQ">Elder Yoshihiko Kikuchi</p>
    <p class="kicker" pid="MR49GhgKLkqlGwqthG73pA" hash="Yy4onQ">When you and I pay honest, true tithes to the Lord, the Lord will open the windows of heaven.</p>
  </div>
  <div class="bodyBlock">
    <div class="topic" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god.t1">
      <img src="KikuchiY_86-99.ob.jpg" alt="Elder Yoshihiko Kikuchi" pid="T-dPHS2adUy2NGUw_f83cQ" hash="GKs_kw" />
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god.p1" pid="i-BSDVZvHkOxnWDxXq8ogQ" hash="dfoeBw">
        <span class="pageBreak" page-number="97"></span>I would like to discuss the law of tithing. In the book of Malachi, the Lord asks:</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god.p2" pid="DiLF2lZkGE6ifftCgt_Z1w" hash="ckhwjg">“Will a man rob God? Yet ye have robbed me. But ye say, Wherein have we robbed thee? In tithes and offerings.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god.p3" pid="vmd5mlLCJU-tCH08OIimpw" hash="0DSn2Q">“Ye are cursed with a curse: for ye have robbed me, even this whole nation.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god.p4" pid="YyFug4XEyE2xvWVogecLjg" hash="MHeFdg">“Bring ye all the tithes into the storehouse, that there may be meat in mine house, and prove me now herewith, saith the Lord of hosts, if I will not open you the windows of heaven, and pour you out a blessing, that there shall not be room enough to receive it.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_1">1</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god.p5" pid="ikgaouZA3UqCpbitT_QbOA" hash="2F-KrA">Tithing is such an important commandment that when the Lord appeared on the American continent after His Resurrection, He repeated those same exact words.<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_2">2</span> And the Lord said in our day, “Those who have thus been tithed shall pay one-tenth of all their interest annually.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_3">3</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god.p6" pid="7lLTmmodB0y2tJGycmqAyw" hash="cMIwiA">In the book of Leviticus, the Lord stated three different times that tithing is “holy unto the Lord.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_4">4</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god.p7" pid="9tUpdf4IXkmvy2mUE3wPzQ" hash="eBtEnw">The Lord said, “Prove me now [or test me now] … , if I will not open you the windows of heaven.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_5">5</span> Many of us test the Lord in the right way; however, some do not.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god.p8" pid="xCcQhnL8H0iliZTpb0x16Q" hash="IvcXYw">Consider, for example, ten apples. Now, all ten of these apples actually belong to the Lord, but He asks us to return to Him only one-tenth, or one apple.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god.p9" pid="Ux-wZYJ1GEC-TBgZZW6sDg" hash="m--kjw">Are you offering only a small bite of that apple and keeping 90 percent? Are you willing to offer the Lord such a small portion?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god.p10" pid="ioJ87HBaKEaBr3T1cOns6A" hash="2GGYqQ">Are you ashamed, or do you try to patch up and hide the bitten portion of the apple and then offer that to the Lord?</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god.p11" pid="ZuczlvLer0W9aue2lYrQ2w" hash="cUMJ1A">We want our offerings to be full and clean. We have been taught: “Behold, the Lord requireth the heart and a willing mind; and the willing and obedient shall eat the good of the land of Zion in these last days.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_6">6</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god.p12" pid="ef480o49jkmYQWTAY1wfhA" hash="qH3AGQ">A few years ago I received the assignment to reorganize the Carey Idaho Stake. The plane landed at Twin Falls, and President Roy Hubert, who had served so well, met me there and drove me to his home. While we were driving, I asked him, “Is there anything I can do for you and your Saints?”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god.p13" pid="8wf9VvTSM0GHHfSUF7hUIQ" hash="yTmIFQ">He said: “Oh, we have had a terrible drought for the last few years. This year it is particularly severe, and many farmers have left town to find employment elsewhere.”</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god.p14" pid="MxqL3RdYuUiKU1dYIk1k-g" hash="ZdU7vQ">I was so disturbed for our faithful members who love the Lord and the Church yet were losing their farms.</p>
      <div class="figure" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god.f2">
	<p pid="n7YZF9e2kUShoCwXr2cR8w" hash="dmCeXw">A young bishop, R. Spence Ellsworth, was called to serve as the new stake president. During the Sunday general session, results of the drought weighed heavily on my mind. As I was speaking, a strong prompting came. I asked them to do the following:</p>
	<ol class="number">
	  <li pid="bPTVXHFXTUKATcdx9K8LNw" hash="VW9_Yw">
          <span class="label">1.</span>
          <p pid="HnQxtT60iU-yBXLJP2IkJA" hash="a69E1A">Faithfully pay an honest tithe, both young and old.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="8e-34PQM80aSSWV25e5cBg" hash="4j7JNg">
          <span class="label">2.</span>
          <p pid="sUozFwJiYEyz6hgwuHm8zQ" hash="42brJg">Humbly hold regular individual and family prayers.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="MkfnxkY52kKv5324RoQRdw" hash="OVmZYg">
          <span class="label">3.</span>
          <p pid="5oHwgLeYJE2WoIr1XcBc5A" hash="gY-Pew">Devotedly have daily personal and family scripture study.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="3J_9zz5UR0GR2o00r2t-RA" hash="4RdnYQ">
          <span class="label">4.</span>
          <p pid="VegOWT2HaUyEQM4LtwWokQ" hash="CQ9LJA">Thankfully keep the Sabbath day holy.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="_inyWrx-yEysimNMJrTKrw" hash="KNL9Eg">
          <span class="label">5.</span>
          <p pid="g5ShJtQPbk6mSUEL_HFkOA" hash="-l1CWQ">Gratefully go to the temple often, there offering thanksgiving.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="du4sWohCnkun_tIyY7pi4g" hash="X_j3zA">
          <span class="label">6.</span>
          <p pid="AO9my2RI-02w_S8eiM_pTg" hash="oITXTA">Willingly sustain and follow the new leaders.</p>
        </li>
	  <li pid="o6wPjNbFrEuleyvmx-6zgQ" hash="b1ABWQ">
          <span class="label">7.</span>
          <p pid="iBB598yw2US1xl14WQXISQ" hash="hZkPdA">Hold a stakewide fast, including everyone in the affected communities who would like to participate.</p>
        </li>
	</ol>
      </div>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god.p15" pid="17PBNnucvki8KxVq7ASAXg" hash="A0qN_A">For the next couple of days following the stake conference, many members planted their crops with complete faith, even though there was no forecast of rain.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god.p16" pid="JPW1YYXC90OYmZSU30J3OA" hash="UyLddA">On Wednesday, under the direction of President Ellsworth, the whole stake fasted. That same week many members, the leaders, and their spouses went to the Boise Idaho <span class="pageBreak" page-number="98"></span>Temple and offered their thanksgiving. While these faithful Saints were in the temple, rain began to fall on the entire community, though the weather forecast indicated no moisture for the next few weeks. The following Saturday, good rain fell again and continued for a few days. This happened late in the month of April. Significant snow fell in the mountains, providing enough moisture. In the Dietrich and Richfield communities, their reservoir had been under 30 percent, but after the people fasted, the reservoir was nearly full. The Carey water supply increased from about 44 percent to more than 100 percent of normal. Through the rest of the growing season, as members of the Carey Stake increased their faith by fasting a few more times, paying honest tithes, and attending the temple more frequently, the Lord heard and answered their prayers. Frost came late that year, so the farmers were able to harvest grain, sugar beets, alfalfa, potatoes, and other crops. From that day, and each year since, they have offered their thanksgiving prayers, and “because of … his tender mercies,”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_7">7</span> the Lord continues to bless them.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god.p17" pid="6qQx-ckSU0GRT_AUl0Venw" hash="oYdmHw">In the book of Chronicles, the Lord said, “If my people, … called by my name, shall humble themselves, and pray, and seek my face, and turn from their wicked ways; then will I hear from heaven, and will forgive their sin, and will heal their land.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_8">8</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god.p18" pid="6bLJ2HzBi0i_KT7LW0ln0Q" hash="zVUAew">Paying a full and honest tithe leads us to the temple. Tithing, I believe, is one of President Hinckley’s prophetic priorities.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god.p19" pid="O7DSJik99E-HhkIQc6fMcw" hash="1Ikeeg">Last week in the Young Women meeting, President Hinckley said, “While tithing is paid with money, more importantly it is paid with faith.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_9">9</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god.p20" pid="CwN-4_p4h0OQXt92uLt_Iw" hash="75z4BQ">Another time he said: “This is not so much a matter of money as it is a matter of faith. … I urge you, … every one of you, to take the Lord at His word in this important matter.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_10">10</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god.p21" pid="ndvNKWk2H0WtmHGKFNwK8A" hash="5pAg8w">It is a matter of commitment. The earth belongs to the Lord, and this includes our own lives. He allows us to use <span class="emphasis">everything</span> on this earth. He only asks us to return one-tenth. Tithing is a token of gratitude, obedience, and thanksgiving—a token of our willingness and dedication. Paying tithing, willingly, develops an honest and pure heart. Paying tithing increases our love for the Lord.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god.p22" pid="5UL9mh5JFkql_2QCPjQngQ" hash="N8q8cw">The Lord said, “It is a day of sacrifice, and a day for the tithing of my people.”<span class="noteMarker" ref="f_11">11</span></p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god.p23" pid="Jc2R92ISFUKJUSJyqag_-A" hash="4tB8WQ">Brothers and sisters, let us demonstrate our faith. Let us show our willingness to obey. I promise you, in the name of Jesus Christ, when you and I pay honest, true tithes to the Lord, the Lord will open the windows of heaven.</p>
      <p class="para" uri="/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god.p24" pid="rbQUrFvfBkuvQS9IxHIigg" hash="f8QaqQ">I know that Heavenly Father lives. Therefore, He will bless you. Jesus Christ is our Savior. Joseph saw Heavenly Father and His Son, Jesus Christ. This is His Church. President Gordon B. Hinckley is a living oracle of God. He asks you to come often to the temple. This is my humble prayer in the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>
    </div>
  </div>
  
</div>]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">/general-conference/2007/04/will-a-man-rob-god</guid>
      <enclosure url="http://media2.ldscdn.org/assets/general-conference/april-2007-general-conference/2007-04-5050-elder-yoshihiko-kikuchi-64k-eng.mp3" length="4396232" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
